<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title><link/> https://www.reuters.com/world/china/ <atom:link href="https://rsshub.app/reuters/world/china" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description><![CDATA[Reuters.com is your online source for the latest China news stories and current events, ensuring our readers up to date with any breaking news developments - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)]]></description><generator> RS集线器</generator><webmaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webmaster><language> zh-cn</language><image/><url> https://www.reuters.com/pf/resources/images/reuters/logo-vertical-default-512x512.png?d=116</url><title><![CDATA[China News | Today's Breaking Stories | Reuters]]></title><link/> https://www.reuters.com/world/china/<lastbuilddate> 2024 年 1 月 17 日星期三 08:05:50 GMT</lastbuilddate><ttl> 120 </ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Indian, Chinese troops clashed twice in 2022 even as peace talks were on]]></title><description><![CDATA[Indian and Chinese soldiers clashed at least two times in 2022 along their Himalayan frontier where they have been involved in a bitter standoff since 2020, according to new details that have emerged from the Indian Army's gallantry award citations.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 07:48:58 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> RBDNEVOICRPYLCKKH2YROSDM7I</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/indian-chinese-troops-clashed-twice-2022-even-peace-talks-were-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Krishn Kaushik]]></author><category>世界</category><category>亚太地区</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[First prosecution witness testifies against Jimmy Lai in Hong Kong]]></title><description><![CDATA[The first prosecution witness to testify in a landmark national security case against Hong Kong media tycoon Jimmy Lai said on Wednesday he had been instructed by Lai to call people to join protests in 2019 and draw the attention of western democracies.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 07:47:44 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> HHUMHRTOVBLJFMEEVO5TKJBXYY</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/first-prosecution-witness-testizes-against-jimmy-lai-hong-kong-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Jessie Pang, Edward Cho]]></author><category>世界</category><category>亚太地区</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tesla cuts Model Y prices in Germany after China price cuts]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tesla Inc has slashed prices of its Model Y cars in Germany, a week after the carmaker reduced its Model 3 and Model Y prices in China.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 06:22:10 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> MBX34M4IVRKSRDP2TPAF2TJWJI</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/tesla-cuts-model-y-prices-germany-after-china-price-cuts-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Hyunjoo Jin]]></author><category>商业</category><category>汽车与交通</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[China state media races to plant presence in Nauru after switch from Taiwan]]></title><description><![CDATA[A reporter from Xinhua landed in Nauru on Wednesday, the first from China's official news agency to step foot on the remote Pacific Islands nation after it ditched Taiwan for China, as Chinese state media raced to build up its local presence.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 06:16:39 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> DN5Y4AWBTVOXNO4Z4IAN4WIR2I</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-state-media-races-plant-presence-nauru-after-switch-taiwan-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Ryan Woo]]></author><category>世界</category><category>亚太地区</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[Breakingviews: China consumers keep Beijing, and world, on edge]]></title><description><![CDATA[All eyes will be on China’s consumers in 2024. The economy expanded 5.2% year-on-year in the fourth quarter, thanks to manufacturing. But maintaining the momentum will be tricky as local demand remains weak. Factories are starting to look abroad to cope with overcapacity, which will stoke global trade tensions. How Beijing spurs domestic consumption will be vital.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 04:36:32 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> V2OORHK6WNKQROUSLKUOTZIIXY</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/breakingviews/china-consumers-keep-beijing-world-edge-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Chan Ka Sing]]></author><category>突破性观点</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[China says threats of force over Taiwan not aimed at most Taiwanese]]></title><description><![CDATA[China's position that it will not renounce using force to bring Taiwan under its control is aimed at foreign interference and a tiny number of separatists, but Taiwanese need to be disabused of "biases" against China, the government said on Wednesday.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 04:22:51 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> GHTWF4TP5FMBDCDEXPP3SZYKHI</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-says-threats-force-over-taiwan-not-aimed-most-taiwanese-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author><category>世界</category><category>亚太地区</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[China helps Pacific Islands with policing, not defence - ambassador]]></title><description><![CDATA[China has a strategy to help Pacific Island nations with policing, not defence, and its growing presence in the region should not alarm Australia, China's ambassador to Australia said on Wednesday.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 04:03:19 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> 7DDJ7HCVQBNGVAFHIDU2KWPU3A</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-helps-pacific-islands-with-policing-not-defence-ambassador-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Kirsty Needham]]></author><category>世界</category><category>亚太地区</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[China's Cyberspace Administration is conducting review of Shein -WSJ]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Cyberspace Administration of China is conducting a cybersecurity review of online retailer Shein's data handling and sharing practices, the Wall Street Journal reported.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 03:48:21 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> 2GPI6Z7F5NKBVM6BHSOTRIQHPI</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/chinas-cyberspace-administration-is-conducting-review-shein-wsj-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author><category>技术</category><category>网络安全</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[Instant view: China's GDP expands 5.2% in Q4, misses market forecast]]></title><description><![CDATA[China's economy expanded 5.2% in the fourth quarter from a year earlier, official data showed on Wednesday, missing analysts' expectations slightly but still making it possible for Beijing to meet its annual growth target.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 02:34:48 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> PXJMLOJGIVM4NBRQCOB37PFKJE</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/world/china/view-chinas-gdp-grows-52-q4-misses-market-forecast-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Reuters]]></author><category>世界</category><category>中国</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oil falls as China's economic recovery disappoints, dollar strengthens]]></title><description><![CDATA[Oil fell on Wednesday as economic growth in China, the world's second-largest crude user, slightly missed expectations, raising concerns about future demand increases, while U.S. dollar strength dented investor's risk appetite.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 02:27:29 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> ABZRV3JDF5MRTPYD7B6HZIECXY</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/oil-prices-fall-stronger-dollar-offsets-red-sea-disruptions-risks-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Muyu Xu, Colleen Howe]]></author><category>商业</category><category>活力</category></item><item><title><![CDATA[China's 2023 GDP shows patchy economic recovery, raises case for stimulus]]></title><description><![CDATA[China's economy grew 5.2% in 2023, slightly more than the official target, but the recovery was far shakier than many analysts and investors expected, with a deepening property crisis, mounting deflationary risks and tepid demand casting a pall over the outlook for this year.]]></description><pubDate> Wed, 17 Jan 2024 02:09:20 GMT</pubDate><guid ispermalink="false"> C2X7QYM4GBMRRHQTSIBKOU7POI</guid><link/> https://www.reuters.com/world/china/chinas-q4-gdp-grows-52-yy-below-market-forecast-2024-01-17/<author><![CDATA[Kevin Yao, Ellen Zhang]]></author><category>世界</category><category>中国</category></item></channel></rss>