<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘The ball is in their court’: China silent on US request for defence chief talks, senior official says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3221910/ball-their-court-china-silent-us-request-defence-chief-talks-senior-official-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/2b485407-c2d0-4a24-85f6-3a6a56274f81_ad5c05c0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京尚未正式回应华盛顿提出的中国国防部长李尚福会谈要求据一位美国高级官员称，他和他的美国外长劳埃德奥斯汀将于下周参加香格里拉对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，美国助理国防部长在战略与国际研究中心发表讲话印太安全事务埃利拉特纳重申，华盛顿希望“畅通沟通渠道”，但中国尚未回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“几周前，奥斯汀部长和国防部发出要求会见李将军，”拉特纳说。 “这一请求尚未得到答复。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国和国防部在军事接触这个问题上伸出了手，我们还没有一个始终愿意合作的伙伴 [在中国]。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国的制裁是否应该归咎于与中国的军事接触陷入僵局？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;李和奥斯汀自 3 月晋升为国防部长以来尚未交谈，但两人都将于 6 月 2 日在新加坡参加一年一度的香格里拉对话安全论坛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据英国《金融时报》报道，北京本月早些时候表示，除非美国同意，否则不太可能举行高层防务会谈。准备取消对李的制裁，华盛顿后来表示此举并未“在谈判中”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2018 年以来，李一直因涉嫌参与 Su-35 战斗机的转让而受到美国制裁和 S-200 防空导弹系统从俄罗斯运往中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉特纳说，虽然美国“意识到”中国的期望，但这并不是中断对话的充分理由。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“无可争议的是，这些 [制裁] 对李将军能否在香格里拉会见奥斯汀部长没有任何法律或技术影响，”拉特纳说。 “所以这不是禁令，坦率地说，此时球在他们的球场上。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国国家主席习近平会见他的领导人后，人们希望 2023 年世界两个超级大国之间的关系会解冻。去年 11 月在巴厘岛举行的 G20 峰会期间，美国外长乔·拜登 (Joe Biden) 出席了会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，在 2 月中国间谍气球坠落事件后，这些希望很快破灭，这促使美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯 (Antony Blinken)推迟计划中的北京之行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据五角大楼的说法，在被击落时，李的前任魏凤和拒绝了从奥斯汀进行安全通话的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中美互斥“坦诚贸易谈判”，誓言应对日益加剧的紧张局势&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但已采取措施恢复部分沟通渠道。周四，美国和中国的高级贸易官员在华盛顿举行了首次面对面会谈，他们讨论了贸易政策并同意建立沟通渠道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次贸易会议在早些时候取得了又一次突破本月，中国最高外交官王毅在维也纳会见了美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥斯汀和魏此前曾在 11 月在柬埔寨举行的东盟国防部长扩大会议以及 2022 年的会议上会面据报道，他们在香格里拉对话会上讨论了有关台湾的安全问题以及保持畅通沟通渠道的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年是第 20 届香格里拉对话，超过 550 名国防军预计来自 40 多个司法管辖区的部长和安全部长以及其他政府官员将出席。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Billionaire’s solar deal revives Australia-Singapore undersea power cable dream]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3221976/billionaires-solar-deal-revives-australia-singapore-undersea-power-cable-dream?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/340a8c77-5d5d-4526-a2f4-2a378c21a115_ea8c299d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;亿万富翁 Mike Cannon-Brookes 将重振停滞不前的 300 亿澳元（200 亿美元）计划在收购失败的 Sun Cable 项目的资产后将太阳能从澳大利亚出口到新加坡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该交易使 Cannon-Brookes 和 Quinbrook Infrastructure Partners 控制了澳大利亚北部巨大的可再生能源开发项目，在 Atlassian Corp 联合创始人和亿万富翁 Andrew Forrest（两位主要投资者）发生纠纷后，该公司于 1 月进入自愿托管。两人对通过 4,200 公里（2,600 英里）海底电缆向亚洲输送电力的计划存在分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们一直相信 Sun Cable 在输出无限阳光方面的可能性，并且这对澳大利亚意味着什么，”支持出口计划的 Cannon-Brookes 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;科技大亨保持新加坡的太阳能梦想&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该项目被吹捧为可以帮助亚洲以化石燃料为主的经济体——尤其是空间受限的国家，如新加坡，几乎没有空间安装主要的可再生能源站点——转向低排放电力来源。开发商将 Sun Cable 设想为连接日本和印度的潜在超级电网的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cannon-Brookes 的 Grok Ventures 和正在美国和英国开发太阳能资产的 Quinbrook 旨在推进计划第一阶段项目将向达尔文提供 900 兆瓦的清洁电力，并向新加坡出口 1.8 吉瓦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的交易涵盖 Sun Cable 的知识产权、北领地的一个太阳能农场场地以及为到达尔文的传输线。尚未开始施工。买家和管理人 FTI Consulting Inc. 没有透露收购价格的细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据知情人士透露，Forrest 的 Squadron Energy 在出售过程的早些时候提出了一份提案。 Forrest 在周五的一份声明中表示，Squadron 没有提交最终出价，也没有因为向新加坡输出电力的优点而动摇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们仍然不相信澳亚电力链路的商业可行性，但如果其他人相信它可以实现，我们祝他们一切顺利，”铁矿石生产商 Fortescue Metals 的创始人 Forrest 说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Buddha’s Birthday: Hong Kong conservationists warn releasing animals destined for pots may still end in death]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3221977/buddhas-birthday-hong-kong-conservationists-warn-releasing-animals-destined-pots-may-still-end-death?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 20:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/efdc6d00-1094-44b8-a5c8-2b39c1ac98f3_fa65e415.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个保护组织在佛陀诞辰那天，这种习俗很普遍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五有人看到相信是佛教徒的人放生海洋生物，这些生物通常在公共码头出售以供食用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北角渡轮码头，包括鱼、章鱼和黄貂鱼在内的活体生物被释放到海中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;码头上还有海鲜摊位出售用于仪式的生物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“生物可能不适应水质或温度，或者有人钓鱼，或者周围有鸟儿吃它们，”香港爬虫学会委员会委员 Victor Wong Long-yin 说，两栖爬行动物的照顾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;放生是佛教徒为了拯救注定要被屠杀的动物或让它们重获自由的一种修行。信徒们认为这可以为他们带来善缘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“那些动物是否真的能活下来？我不这么认为，”Wong 说，并补充说这些生物在高速撞击水面时也可能被杀死，或者在被石油污染的水域无法生存。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说很多海龟，一些贝壳上用红漆写着经文，每年佛诞前后在水库放生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然他表示，由于气温低，这些乌龟很难在野外生存，食物不足或被鸟类捕食，即使存活下来，也可能威胁到当地的生物多样性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“红耳龟具有很强的适应性。如果它们在野外适应良好，它们可能会对当地的海龟构成威胁，”Wong 说。他指的是一种常用于放生仪式的物种。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，在野外，不同物种的海龟可能会战斗、受伤甚至死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong 补充说，并不是所有的鱼可能被释放到香港水域。例如，如果将当地餐馆常见的沙巴石斑鱼放回野外，它们会吃掉任何能放进嘴里的东西，破坏生物多样性，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;鸟类救援数量猛增 20 倍过去十年在香港保育中心&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该组织敦促政府立法规范香港的放生仪式。包括中国大陆、台湾、澳门和新加坡在内的周边地区也有类似的法律禁止或控制这种做法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府可以向特定组织发放终身释放许可证吗？许可意味着有监管，”Wong 说，并补充说政府还可以要求报告有多少动物被释放，种类和地点。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获得更多RSS： &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong police seize HK$650 million worth of cocaine, cannabis buds in biggest haul uncovered this year]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3221972/hong-kong-police-seize-hk650-million-worth-cocaine-cannabis-buds-biggest-haul-uncovered-year?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 19:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/390e2a53-b650-4e68-a22a-69f084056af1_bd7c17eb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港警方检获估计市值约650港元的可卡因和大麻万，这是今年最大的缉获量，其中一些毒品藏在冷冻鱼箱中以避免被发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周五结束的为期三天的行动中，该部队的缉毒局扣押了 592 公斤毒品怀疑可卡因及91.2公斤怀疑大麻芽，并拘捕四名涉嫌贩毒男子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次检获的大麻花芽，存放在冷冻鱼中，”总督察詹耀光告诉警方周五的新闻发布会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们认为贩毒集团使用了这种方法……试图用冷冻鱼的刺鼻气味掩盖大麻的气味。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高级督察罗启贤说，该局于周三在观塘巧明街和伟业街的两座工业大厦对毒品集团进行了伏击行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，侦探截获了一名 32 岁的男子男子刚离开巧明街的大楼，将他带回转租单位进行搜查。侦探在工业单位发现了 120 包可卡因，每包重 1 公斤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗补充说，这名姓苏的建筑工人随后因涉嫌贩毒被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方查获 1.8 亿港元的可卡因，是今年迄今最大的缉获量&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;侦探们还截获了两名姓陈，25 岁​​和 31 岁的男子，并发现了 160 包大麻花蕾，总计约体重91.2公斤，伟业街货仓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对建筑工人和厨房员工也因涉嫌贩毒被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该局人员突击搜查位于葵涌、红磡、荔枝角及土瓜湾的另外四个货仓，检获472包可卡因，每包重1公斤。罗说，据信控制这些仓库的是同一个贩毒集团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第四名男子，32 岁，姓张，失业，于周四下午在落马洲支线管制站试图离开时被捕香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四名嫌疑人中的一些涉嫌与黑社会集团有关。警方表示，他们不排除进一步逮捕的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这四人将于星期六在观塘裁判法院出庭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方正在调查这批赃物的来源，并分析检获的物品是否可卡因与两周前侦破的另一起案件有关，也涉及 227 公斤毒品。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;10 名涉嫌贩毒和其他罪行的嫌疑人在香港被捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该局高级警司陈光-明表示，由于可卡因原料古柯的收成不断增加，他们将加大打击毒品犯罪的力度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最近，南美国家的古柯叶生产持续进行增加，导致制造可卡因的成本相应降低，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“禁毒局已加强情报收集，以应对因价格下跌导致更多可卡因流入香港的风险”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但陈指出，香港整体吸毒情况“大致上受到控制”，预计本地不会有上升趋势。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s Tata looks to AI to help Asia tackle elderly care, climate change, skills training]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3221974/indias-tata-looks-ai-help-asia-tackle-elderly-care-climate-change-skills-training?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 19:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/206f398d-d58b-4d23-a11c-ab51a504ccbe_fa7f8d12.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度最大的 IT 服务提供商 Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) 旨在利用人工智能一位公司高管表示，人工智能 (AI) 可以通过提供老年人护理等便捷服务来帮助亚洲国家变得更具包容性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些计划类似于 India Stack，这是一个在印度全国运行的数字平台14 亿人通过政府支持的应用程序接口，第三方可以在其中提供一系列服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“TCS 已经与许多东南亚国家就实施印度的‘Stack-like’解决方案进行了对话， ” 该公司驻伦敦的人工智能负责人 Anantha Sekar 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东南亚的总人口超过 6.6 亿，其中有许多农村和偏远地区，包括许多岛屿。许多居民无法轻松获得公共服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但更发达的地方也可以从人工智能中受益。 Sekar 说，例如，在数字基础设施完善的城市国家新加坡，基于人工智能的服务可能有利于帮助公民进行新活动培训。 “我们正在与新加坡就许多事情进行合作。我们在那里设立了一个数字加速器，它在技能开发方面发挥了很大作用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sekar 补充说，AI 工作的重点是展示大量项目的可能性，并表示马来西亚和泰国也有兴趣使用新技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以最简单的形式，人工智能结合了计算机科学和强大的数据集来解决问题。它关注的是构建能够执行通常需要人类智能才能完成的任务的智能机器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，人工智能经历了许多炒作周期，但去年美国 OpenAI 的 ChatGPT 发布 – 一个自然而然的语言处理工具可以让你进行类似人类的对话——这似乎标志着一个转折点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sekar 说，总的来说，亚洲拥有多样化的地貌、人口众多和使用多种语言，因此拥有此类机会的时机已经成熟。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最早的用途之一可能是那些无法以传统方式访问计算机或在线服务的残障人士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果人们有视力障碍或有语言障碍Sekar 说，“该技术可以通过语音识别等工具进行翻译”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还可以用于帮助照顾一些老年人并远程监控他们的一些需求，而不是让他们处于低处持续的身体监督。例如，可以通过 AI 远程监控瞳孔的放大情况，这可能会突出眼睛受伤、头部受伤、肿瘤或中风。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自声纹的数据也可以被处理以检测某人何时可能遭受痛苦一个秋天，Sekar 补充道。 “基本上今天，家人或护理人员可以立即与老人联系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从印度到新加坡以及南亚和东南亚的其他国家，“你会发现，这些解决方案正在被采用整个业务都在老年护理和教育领域开展”，该技术通过在线课程帮助偏远地区的人们进行教学和培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但推出此类服务的稳健程度取决于每个国家/地区以及他们希望通过 AI 优先考虑哪些服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果政府明确其重点和战略（通常以国家战略的形式），那么很多 [AI] 的工作效果会更好。只有 45 到 50 个国家制定了这样的国家战略，”Sekar 补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，亚洲很可能会带头。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >; 该地区拥有全球一半的互联网用户和采用各种数字和移动技术的商业领袖。近三分之二的亚洲人口已经通过固定或移动网络上网。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们估计亚洲采用新技术的时间比西方早 8 到 12 年，这使它很像通往未来的时光机”，全球银行花旗周四发布的一份报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;智库布鲁金斯学会在花旗报告中援引世界数据实验室的预测称，到 2024 年该地区一半以上的人口将成为中产阶级或富人.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种富裕预计将进一步推动对商品和服务的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲还占全球“独角兽”的 40%——估值为 1 美元的科技初创企业十亿——据花旗称，全球 56% 的中小型企业和全球专利申请的 68%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲对技术的快速采用是由欠发达的基础设施推动的——在零售、报告称，银行、医疗保健和其他领域正在推动对数字解决方案的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sekar 说，在印度南部的安得拉邦，数字技术被用于帮助对厕所进行目视检查作为政府在全国范围内改善卫生和废物管理运动的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天，技术允许您 [远程] 拍照。并且您可以实施 AI 来检测哪里存在问题并进行干预以采取补救措施，”Sekar 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲拥有 11 亿 15-29 岁的人口，他们往往是最花旗表示，他们擅长使用移动和数字技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人工智能在亚洲的另一大用途可能是应对气候变化，包括进入难以到达的偏远地区。它可用于通过收集然后发送数据的摄像头帮助检查森林、交通状况和空气污染。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此类应用程序可以使用多种语言，可以减轻检查人员的负担并收集更多信息， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sekar 说，评估可以发布在互联网、内联网和手机等多种渠道上，这将提高公民的意识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们可以询问 ChatGPT 他们在哪里他说，国家在可持续发展目标方面，使他们更加了解，因此更有能力在政府层面“推动发生的事情”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他没有详细说明如何进行验证以使居民可以信任数据，但表示尽管该技术有可能改变社会，但最大的挑战之一将是确保制定政策和规则以确保以合乎道德的方式使用人工智能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然欧盟提议通过以下方式进行严格监管类似于通用数据保护条例的人工智能法案——被认为是最严格的隐私和安全法律之一——印度和英国等其他国家似乎倾向于更宽松的方式，有利于自我监管和审计。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sekar表示 AI 为服务带来高度个性化的能力可能意味着该技术的采用将比以前的颠覆性技术（例如智能手机和社交媒体）快得多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我会说较弱的如果做得好，社会各阶层将从人工智能带来的包容性和体验中受益匪浅，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China-South Korea ties are low and could go lower, Chinese envoy says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3221965/china-south-korea-ties-are-low-and-could-go-lower-chinese-envoy-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/d4cf0b5c-df39-4705-95c5-ffeed6d4b022_819e0a39.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国和韩国之间的关系处于低点并且可能会恶化，北京的最高点驻首尔特使周五表示，并补充说中国决心改善关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“坦率地说，目前中韩关系不好，存在进一步恶化的风险……我对此感到非常担心”邢海明大使告诉位于首尔的 MBC 广播公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邢海明说，“邻国和伙伴”最重要的是相互尊重，尤其是在至关重要的核心利益方面，提到台湾问题，北京和首尔之间外交争端的中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邢还排除了习近平主席与尹在近期举行会晤的可能性，称这样的访问需要有利的政治气氛，双方&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首尔首先需要表现出“对中国在台湾问题等领域的核心关切”的充分尊重，然后才能举行其他会谈，邢说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国和韩国就台湾问题的主张和反诉争论了数周。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为与大陆统一的分离省份。包括美国和韩国在内的大多数国家都不承认台湾是一个独立国家，并反对北京使用武力改变现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但最后一次去美国旅行之前月，韩国总统尹锡烈表示，台湾“不仅仅是中国和台湾之间的问题”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“就像朝鲜问题一样，这是一个全球性问题，”尹在接受采访时说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“毕竟，这些紧张局势的发生是因为企图以武力改变现状，我们和国际社会一起坚决反对这种改变。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该声明引发了中国的抗议，随后韩国就中国媒体发表的评论文章提出了抗议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yoon 的评论反映了该国外交政策自他一年前上台以来的转变，令韩国感动由于朝鲜的武器试验导致半岛局势紧张，因此与美国和日本的关系更加密切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周早些时候，中国外交部一名高级官员访问了首尔，“就中国的核心关切表明了严正立场”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;据中国外交部称，外交部亚洲司司长刘劲松周一在首尔会见他的副手崔勇俊时“就中国的核心关切阐明了严正立场” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首尔会议紧接在广岛七国集团峰会之后举行，领导人对东海和南海局势表示“严重关切”，并呼吁维护“和平台海两岸的稳定”。韩国不是该小组的成员，但 Yoon 被邀请作为观察员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为回应，中国外交部副部长孙卫东召见日本大使，抗议“围绕中国相关问题的炒作”峰会并指责东京与其他 G7 国家合作“在活动和联合声明中……抹黑和攻击中国，粗暴干涉中国内政”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;阵营对抗和冷战思维&#39;：中国猛烈抨击日本关于 G7 峰会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Xing 周五还表示，在上周的一次会议上，财政部长官 Choo Kyung-ho 表示希望尽快与负责经济的部长们进行会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在双方的会面重申了在中国对美国存储芯片制造商美光科技实施禁令后维护供应链安全稳定的原则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国是三星电子和 SK 海力士的所在地，这两家公司是全球最大的存储芯片制造商芯片供应商。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a >;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong commerce secretary tells trade meeting in US that WTO should repair dispute settlement system after Washington froze operations in retaliation for national security law]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3221966/hong-kong-commerce-secretary-tells-trade-meeting-us-wto-should-repair-dispute-settlement-system?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 19:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/79589f82-c6bd-4aa6-918b-4cc8d30965bf_480ab126.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;世界贸易组织 (WTO) 的争端解决系统应该“功能齐全”在裁定华盛顿将城市产品标记为“中国制造”违反国际贸易规则五个月后，香港商务部长在美国的一次高层会议上再次表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秘书商务和经济发展部部长 Algernon Yau Ying-wah 在周五于底特律举行的亚太经合组织贸易部长会议的讨论会上表示，成员经济体应与其他 WTO 国家“建设性地迅速合作”，到明年恢复“所有成员均可使用的全面且运作良好的争端解决系统”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“丘先生还强调了早日使 WTO 谈判结果生效的重要性，以证明 WTO 正在努力为了人民的利益，”市政府表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自即将卸任的美国总统唐纳德特朗普于 2020 年发布行政命令要求香港制造的商品带有“Made在中国”的标签而不是“香港制造”，作为对北京实施的国家安全法的报复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管 WTO 法官小组在 12 月做出裁决，但美国仍保留该命令去年，美国违反了贸易规则，并呼吁该国放弃标签要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国在 1 月份对 WTO 专家组的裁决提出上诉，并阻止了其上诉机构的所有新法官任命&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港在世贸组织会议后就“中国制造”的出口规则抨击美国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在日内瓦的世贸组织争端解决机构讨论了标签规则之后，市政府称华盛顿的呼吁是“虚伪和傲慢的行为”，审查机制因此瘫痪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港中小企业协会名誉主席刘达邦协会周五表示，无论上诉结果如何，标签变更对该市经济的影响微乎其微。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lau 解释说，一些制造商使用的标签上写着“Made in中国，在香港设计”以安抚担心产品质量的消费者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港反击美国针对香港在美国的贸易办事处的法案&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“一些最终用户担心标有‘中国制造’的产品质量，他们认为香港的产品质量更好，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一些制造商通过说他们是中国制造来回避问题&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘补充说，两年来消费者在购买香港生产的商品时看到“中国制造”的标签后，意识到质量没有下降。 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese artificial intelligence firm iFlytek blames chatbot-generated article for sudden share price swing on Shenzhen bourse]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3221953/chinese-artificial-intelligence-firm-iflytek-blames-chatbot-generated-article-sudden-share-price?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 18:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/cf8d7952-4402-4c99-8f49-d53dce6d7bf7_d8154072.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国人工智能 (AI) 公司科大讯飞，中国最早的大型科技公司之一该国推出 ChatGPT 替代方案，该公司将其在深圳上市的股票周三的突然下跌归咎于一篇由一位未具名的本地聊天机器人生成的在线文章，这一事件可能成为使用该技术的潜在风险的预兆。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;iFlyTek 的股价自今年年初以来上涨了 70% 以上，但在周三的午盘交易中下跌超过 9%，收盘时下跌 4.26% 至 56.57 元（8.02 美元）。周五，该公司股价收盘上涨 1.83% 至 56.63 元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周三通过科大讯飞投资者关系网站进行的两次独立查询中，散户投资者表示，意外的价格波动是由广泛的 -网上流传一篇关于该公司如何为人工智能研究非法收集用户信息的文章。他们说这篇文章后来被发现是人工智能生成的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司表示同意投资者的发现，但没有就使用哪个中文聊天机器人生成违规文章发表任何评论。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“使用大型语言模型 [LLM] 来生成虚假信息是违法的，这种行为将受到法律的惩罚，”科大讯飞的一位代表说。 “我们将对任何编造虚假信息抹黑我们公司的实体或个人采取法律行动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司周五没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An据美国科技公司 Nvidia 称，LLM 是一种深度学习算法，可以根据从海量数据集中获得的知识识别、总结、翻译、预测和生成文本和其他内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科大讯飞股价的突然波动凸显了 ChatGPT 和类似聊天机器人服务等生成式人工智能系统带来的潜在网络安全风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月，北京警方就 ChatGPT 产生的谣言发出了公开警告。它说，研究机构发现，当被问及与阴谋有关和误导性的问题时，人工智能聊天机器人会在没有引用消息来源的情况下迅速生成令人信服的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同月，浙江省东部省会杭州市的一名居民，使用该聊天机器人生成了一个类似于该市宣布将取消基于车牌的驾驶限制的公告，这是中国许多城市为减少交通拥堵而实施的一项措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科大讯飞代表​​周三告诉investors that the company&#39;s user privacy protections include a dedicated committee that oversees all privacy matters, which ensures the firm complies with national standards.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s internet watchdog warns of risks from generative AI, other advanced tech&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Based in Hefei, capital of eastern Anhui province, iFlyTek launched its own AI chatbot, called SparkDesk, earlier this month. It claimed that SparkDesk will exceed ChatGPT&#39;s Chinese data capacity and catch up on English-language resources by the end of October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That declaration made iFlytek, which has been on the US government&#39;s trade blacklist since October 2019, the first Chinese tech company to provide a clearly articulated timeline to challenge ChatGPT.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Baidu, meanwhile, announced last week that it has started to offer Ernie Bot, its own ChatGPT alternative, to a variety of clients in industries such as financial services, software and education.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 18:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘I thought the plane was going to explode’: passenger opens aircraft door mid-air]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3221959/south-korea-detains-passenger-after-asiana-plane-door-opened-mid-air?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 18:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/26/4b87d520-6ea4-457e-9dcf-f7ddcb0b9ee3_1ac10546.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;South Korean authorities detained a man on Friday after he opened a door of an Asiana Airlines plane minutes before it was due to land in the city of Daegu, causing panic among the passengers, officials said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Airbus A321-200 plane landed safely at around 12.40pm local time. It had set off from the holiday island of Jeju an hour earlier, the airport&#39;s flight schedule showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No one was hurt in the incident but nine people, all teenagers, were sent to hospital after suffering breathing issues, a Daegu fire department official said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I thought the plane was going to explode … It looked like passengers next to the open door were fainting,” an unidentified 44-year-old passenger told the Yonhap News Agency.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;YouTuber who staged US plane crash faces up to 20 years jail&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The passenger said the cabin crew had made an in-flight announcement asking if there were any doctors on board.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A video aired on television, reported to have been shot by a passenger, showed the moments before the landing, with a door open and wind rushing in as passengers sat nearby.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The transport ministry said in a statement police had taken into custody the man who had opened the door and authorities were investigating violations of aviation safety laws.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ministry did not say whey he had opened the door.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A transport ministry official told Reuters authorities were looking into whether Asiana Airlines had followed protocols to manage emergency exits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official said it was possible an emergency exit could be disarmed near the ground when pressure inside and outside the cabin were similar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plane was two or three minutes away from landing when the male passenger sitting next to an emergency exit opened a cover and pulled a lever so the door opened about 200 metres (656ft) above the ground, an Asiana spokesperson said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All on board were seated with seat belts fastened because the plane was about to land, the spokesperson said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 18:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ultraman bride: Chinese woman swaps wedding dress for Japanese superhero outfit to surprise her big fan man and millions online]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3221525/ultraman-bride-chinese-woman-swaps-wedding-dress-japanese-superhero-outfit-surprise-her-big-fan-man?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/24/317e4214-1778-4044-8c1a-43748f699269_3ecf36cd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Chinese bride sprung a wedding-day surprise by dressing up as Ultraman – her husband-to-be&#39;s favourite Japanese superhero.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a May 20 video filmed in central China&#39;s Henan province – which has attracted more than 5 million views on Douyin – the groom and his friends only find out about the costume caper when they open the door to the bride&#39;s room to pick her up on the big day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instead of being dressed in a traditional Chinese wedding dress and striking a demure pose on her bed like most brides, the woman had turned into the fictional superhero character, Ultraman, and was perched on one knee atop the bed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the groom entered the room, the nuptial Japanese superhero stood up and began flashing beams towards him using a magic stick.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The groom&#39;s initial shock turned to delight as he exclaimed to his friends: “I knew she would surprise me one way or another.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Douyin video the bride, surnamed Fan, said: “I&#39;m willing to take off my wedding dress and become his light.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a later Douyin video together with her husband, Fan said she had prepared the surprise for a year because her man was a huge fan of the Ultraman television series, which was first aired in 1966 and has been popular in China since the 1980s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The newlywed couple, who have known each other for nine years and been together for seven, said their parents supported their unconventional ideas because “marriage and happiness are all about us”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Traditionally, Chinese brides sit on a freshly made bed for the groom to pick her up before the official wedding ceremony. The pick-up ceremony usually involves games such as hiding the bridal shoes for the groom to find.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is believed that such a ceremony offers an auspicious blessing for the newlyweds to have a baby soon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Ultraman bride delighted mainland social media, with some men expressing envy towards the groom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is true that birds of a feather flock together,” one person said, complimenting the couple as “a perfect match”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You are not only his light, but also the light of most men,” another man commented.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is not the first time unconventional wedding events have captured the imagination of people in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This month, at a wedding in eastern China&#39;s Shandong province, the bride&#39;s younger brother played a prank on his brother-in-law by walking onto the stage in a white wedding dress on behalf of his sister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The groom, who kept his eyes closed as the “bride” walked towards him, jumped back the moment he saw who that actually was, amusing guests and online observers alike.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China, Russia hold security talks in Moscow amid tensions with the West]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3221956/china-russia-hold-security-talks-moscow-amid-tensions-west?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 18:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/26/73808384-e844-4c6a-b372-48a633ccf2ce_8253b9b1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s top security official Chen Wenqing met Russian spy chief Sergey Naryshkin on the sidelines of a multilateral security meeting in Moscow, as the two nations move closer on security amid tensions with the West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting, reported by Chinese state news agency Xinhua on Thursday, was their first since Chen was promoted to the top security job overseeing police and intelligence in October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As well as being secretary of the Central Political and Legal Affairs Commission, Chen was also elevated to the Politburo – the ruling Communist Party&#39;s top decision-making body – during the leadership reshuffle. He was previously the state security minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No details of the talks were released in the Xinhua report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen and Naryshkin both attended this week&#39;s International Meeting of High Representatives for Security Issues in Moscow – along with officials from more than 100 countries and six international organisations – and both took a hard line against Western hegemony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Individual states are trying to use the pretext of protesting [for] democracy to substitute the existing world order based on international law with an artificial rules-based order,” Chen was quoted as saying during the meeting in a Tass report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Naryshkin, meanwhile, accused the West of undermining global security and “blaming its mistakes in the Middle East on Russia”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the “Anglo-Saxons” should deal with their domestic civil conflicts, “or better yet, to go to hell, where they belong”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Xinhua, Chen also met representatives from the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation and the BRICS emerging economies – regional groupings whose members Beijing is trying to forge closer ties with as its relations with many Western countries deteriorate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the security meeting, Chen touted Beijing&#39;s proposed alternatives to the Western development model – the Global Development Initiative, Global Security Initiative and Global Civilisation Initiative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also met Nikolai Patrushev, the secretary of Russia&#39;s Security Council, with the two sides agreeing to deepen cooperation to safeguard their “security interests”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is willing to work with Russia to formulate cooperation measures, practise the vision of common, comprehensive, cooperative and sustainable security, jointly implement the Global Security Initiative and better safeguard the security interests of the two countries and the international community,” Chen was quoted as saying by Xinhua.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China-Russia trade has &#39;plateaued&#39; despite &#39;unprecedented high level&#39; relations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Patrushev said it was Russia&#39;s “unswerving policy” to deepen the Russia-China comprehensive strategic partnership of coordination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Comprehensively promoting law enforcement and security cooperation between the two countries under the guidance of the consensus of the heads of state will provide strong support for Russia and China to cope with security risks and challenges,” he said, according to Xinhua.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pair met under the China-Russia law enforcement and security cooperation mechanism, which was set up in 2014. Bilateral meetings are held annually to discuss issues such as national security and counterterrorism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During talks in Moscow in March, Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian leader Vladimir Putin agreed for the two nations to continue high-level dialogue based on “mutual trust” under this mechanism, to provide “firm support” on security issues and to strengthen security cooperation to prevent “colour revolution”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen&#39;s trip to Moscow coincided with Russian Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin&#39;s visit to Beijing this week, when Mishustin and Xi pledged to strengthen cooperation as Russia seeks more trade support from China to offset the impact of Western sanctions over its invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also came as Chinese special envoy for Eurasian affairs Li Hui is touring Europe to promote Beijing&#39;s peacemaking efforts for Ukraine. He is expected to meet Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov on Friday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>