<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong hospital says ‘not protocol’ to check valve involved in baby’s death, facility chief insists ‘we’re not finding an excuse’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3224312/hong-kong-hospital-says-not-protocol-check-valve-involved-babys-death-facility-chief-insists-were?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 15:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/623b0b4e-8160-408f-af4b-ba9c6a23480f_4a7f9c6e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港一家主要公立医院表示其护理规程不需要双重检查一个三通阀被阻塞，阻止了药物到达一名后来死亡的早产儿的身体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周早些时候，威尔士亲王医院披露了更多关于悲剧的细节，周五停止了表示此案涉及人为错误，但补充说它已经更新了指导方针以防止类似事件发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医院表示，这名早产两个多月的婴儿患有先天性心脏病，是一系列双胞胎周一分娩。涉案的两名护士和两名医生现已休假。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医院行政总裁钟建礼医生说：“我们不是在找借口。情况并没有想象中的那么简单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这么小的婴儿，管子很多，三通阀很多……条件很多，我担心真的有那么容易吗？”如果阀门调整正确。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chung 说已经成立了一个委员会来调查事件的原因，并补充说协议将是调查的方向之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;香港医学专家告诫不要将婴儿死亡标记为失误&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;医院也已致函涉事设备的承建商，要求检讨设计并加强安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医院据称，案件中的两名护士都有20多年的从业经验。调查报告预计将在八周内完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该案例的核心是一个关闭的供应阀门，该阀门阻碍了药物到达婴儿身体达 50 分钟，直到设备发出警报。这名婴儿于周二下午——事故发生后 12 小时死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名婴儿在医院的新生儿重症监护室接受治疗，医生确定这名儿童需要通气护理和正性肌力药——一种有助于控制心脏的药物宫缩。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s Cathay Pacific reveals changes to pilots’ pay in third gesture appearing to address staff concerns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3224304/hong-kongs-cathay-pacific-reveals-changes-pilots-pay-third-gesture-appearing-address-staff-concerns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 14:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/1fcc62c4-282a-4d6b-9281-7173619a56b4_fbbfc42a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港旗舰航空公司国泰航空周五透露了薪酬机制的变化飞行员采取的最新举措是提高员工士气，并解决因驾驶舱机组人员不高兴而导致飞机滑行缓慢的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司周五宣布，飞行员的生产率工资将按他们工作的小时数计算被列入名册，被称为他们的“公布的轮班时间”，或他们飞行的实际时间——以较高者为准。这一变化将于 10 月生效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;飞行运营总监克里斯·肯皮斯机长表示，这将为飞行员的薪酬带来更多确定性，并表明该航空公司正在倾听员工的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将继续审查我们飞行员薪酬和福利的竞争力，并在合适和可持续的情况下做出改变，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，该市最大的航空公司警告不要让飞机滑行缓慢，因为其飞行员据称他们这样做是为了加班并收取更多工资。当局指责他们助长了香港机场的拥堵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;飞行员告诉邮报，虽然额外的滑行时间并不多，但这反映了士气低落，部分原因是大幅削减作为削减成本措施的一部分，在大流行病期间降低了工资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020 年 10 月，国泰航空为所有机组人员和飞行员引入了更便宜的雇佣合同，后者的工资减少了约 40%，以及降低了退休金和住房福利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，现在高达 30% 的飞行员工资是可变的，并且与飞行小时数挂钩。此前这一比例仅为 10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国泰航空为初级飞行员提供通过 HK Express 晋升的机会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在给邮报的一份声明中，香港空勤人员协会代表国泰航空的飞行员表示，这些变化对驾驶舱机组人员的收入“影响很小”。它补充说，由于减薪和服务条件，士气处于“谷底”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工会呼吁国泰航空解决缺乏经验丰富的飞行员的原因，该航空公司雇用了大约一半的飞行员&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工会主席 Paul Weatherilt 表示，这些变化使该航空公司符合行业标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，排班航班的不可预测性影响了飞行员，合同意味着工资与生产力紧密挂钩，所以经常坐飞机的人会带回家更多的钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着航班数量的增加，香港国泰航空的新机组人员月薪最高可达 20,000 港元&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;“薪酬的真正波动来自于你将获得多少航班的不确定性——并且可以随着花名册的变化而被消除。这是一个更大的影响，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一变化是国泰航空本周第三次宣布，似乎是为了解决员工的担忧和士气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，国泰航空表示，从 7 月开始，由于与飞行小时数挂钩的生产力工资，空乘人员的月收入将增加 3% 至 8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，国泰航空的初级飞行员有机会申请在该航空公司的低成本子公司香港快运航空 (HK Express) 担任高级管理人员两年，成功的候选人随后能够以更高级别加入这家主要航空公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国泰航空将向政府支付 15 亿港元的股息到月底&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一月份，该航空公司将其基本月薪提高了 3.3%，并增加了某些级别的飞行员津贴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，国泰航空员工的士气受到了三名机组人员的打击成员因在飞往香港的航班上侮辱一些中国大陆乘客的英语能力而被解雇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时，空乘工会称士气“极低”，需要绝望&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由国泰航空及其预算部门香港快运航空组成的国泰集团已设定目标，到年底达到其运力的 70%，并在 2024 年 12 月达到 100%。&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[HK$22 million in endangered species items, from shark fins to live star tortoises, seized in operation against wildlife smuggling]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3224299/hk22-million-endangered-species-items-shark-fins-live-star-tortoises-seized-operation-against?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 14:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/816129d4-07cb-4485-b6ca-0606f867687e_47a964ee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港当局查获了价值 2200 万港元（280 万美元）的违禁品在为期一个月的打击濒危野生动物走私活动中，从干鱼翅到活星龟，范围广泛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，海关航空货运组助理总监张嘉中表示，当局破获了 24 起走私案件，涉及在 5 月的行动中，包括机场在内的各个控制点的濒危物种也导致 14 人被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在其中一起案件中，海关人员从机场查获了超过 5 吨干鱼翅。他说，怀疑是濒危物种，估计价值 2100 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheung 补充说，5 月 4 日从澳门运往香港的两个集装箱中发现了这些鱼鳍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;警方还在 5 月 25 日从马来西亚空运进港的包裹中查获四只受保护的星龟。活体动物估计价值 36,000 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2 名香港男子涉嫌走私濒危物种产品被捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;行动中检获的其他怀疑濒危物种包括人参、干海马和兰花。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关表示，是次行动是与渔农处人员联合展开的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，今年前5个月，海关共破获175起走私濒危物种案件，占291起走私案件的60%。 2022 年全年都有病例记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheung 说，由于空中、海上和陆地的急剧减少，病例数从 2019 年的 659 例下降到过去三年的平均每年约 300 例。在 Covid-19 大流行期间旅行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，随着 Covid-19 限制措施的放松恢复正常旅行，当局注意到今年走私濒危物种的趋势有所上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheung 警告说未经有效许可，公众不得携带濒危物种产品进出本市。他补充，前线人员会继续在管制站保持警惕，并加强情报搜集，以打击此类活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港海关拘捕5名男子，检获价值2亿港元的违禁品&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在香港，未经许可进口或出口濒危物种最高可被判入狱 10 年和罚款 1000 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据海关的规定，走私是严重的犯罪行为，被发现进出口的人未列舱单的货物将面临最高 7 年监禁和 200 万港元罚款。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How much prison time could Donald Trump face?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224301/how-much-prison-time-could-donald-trump-face?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 14:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/f4f12ddf-a40b-4c67-b044-64d3803f01dc_c85d7713.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;FBI 调查人员在 2016 年秋季搜查哈罗德·马丁在马里兰州的房产时发现了机密文件- 包括绝密级别的材料 - 散落在他的家、汽车和储藏棚里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与前总统唐纳德特朗普不同，这位前国家安全局承包商没有对这些指控提出异议，最终在 2019 年认罪并承认他的行为是“错误的、非法的和高度可疑的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他对一项故意保留国防信息的罪名的忏悔和认罪并没有使他免于九年的严厉惩罚年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该案件的解决方案隐约可见特朗普可能面临法律危险的不祥路标，因为他面临 37 项重罪指控——其中 31 项根据用于起诉 Martin 和其他被告据称非法保留机密文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使像 Martin 这样认罪并承担责任的许多人仍然被判处多年徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当他们决定追究故意处理不当的案件，就是要发出一个信息：我们非常重视这些案件，”辩护律师兼前司法部检察官迈克尔茨威巴克说。 “他们几乎总是在寻求入狱时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普的传讯耗时 45 分钟，但通往审判的道路可能需要几年时间&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这位前总统可能面临多少监禁时间定罪事件是不可能说的，这样的决定最终取决于初审法官——在本案中，特朗普任命的一位已经表现出愿意做出有利于他的裁决的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;也很难知道其他因素（包括监禁前总统的后勤和政治复杂性）可能在多大程度上发挥作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《间谍法》的罪行最高可判处 10 年监禁，但这种情况很少见初犯的联邦罪犯接近最高限额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但除了保留之外，检察官还发现了特朗普涉嫌行为的多个加重因素，指控他寻求招募其他人——包括律师和助手——向调查人员隐瞒记录并向来访者炫耀一些记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;起诉书中的其他一些罪名，包括共谋妨碍司法公正，最高可判处 20 年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;近年来，司法部检察官利用反间谍法条款对付各种被告，包括一名西弗吉尼亚州妇女，她保留了一份与外国政府军事和政治问题有关的美国国家安全局文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊丽莎白·乔·雪莉 (Elizabeth Jo Shirley) 恳求道2020 年因蓄意保留罪被判处八年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月，退休的美国空军情报官员罗伯特·伯彻姆 (Robert Birchum) 承认保密罪，被判处三年徒刑。他的家中、他的海外官员宿舍和车道上的一个储物柜中都有文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多被告已认罪，而不是接受审判，尽管并非所有人都进了监狱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普——他在纽约州法院也面临与支付封口费有关的指控——没有迹象表明他可能会达成认罪协议，他极力坚称自己是无辜的，并在出庭数小时后人身攻击司法部特别检察官杰克·史密斯。周二迈阿密联邦法院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管起诉书中有详细信息，但特朗普确实有一些途径试图对指控提出异议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一方面，他吸引了艾琳·坎农法官，后者站在一边去年与特朗普一起参与前总统任命一名特别主管对查获的机密文件进行独立审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;引用她所说的与联邦调查局搜查特朗普家有关的“耻辱”，她表示，基于本应归还给特朗普的物品的“未来起诉”“将导致明显不同数量级的声誉损害”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国上诉法院的三名法官合议庭第 11 巡回上诉法院一致推翻了她的裁决，该裁决被法律专家广泛批评为非同寻常且范围异常广泛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在接下来的几个月中，Cannon 将做出影响审判的决定，包括它将以多快的速度进行&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官还面临佛罗里达州的挑战——共和党人近年来在佛罗里达州取得了稳步进展——陪审团可能比案件更有利于特朗普&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普宣布“人人有饭吃”，不付钱就离开餐厅&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;不过，“我认为杰克·史密斯很可能欢迎一个乔治华盛顿大学法学院教授、前司法部官员史蒂芬·萨尔茨堡 (Stephen Saltzburg) 说：“佛罗里达州陪审团，因为如果有罪，就很难说‘好吧，那个陪审团在某种程度上是反特朗普的’”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;专家预计特朗普的律师会回应前总统的公开言论，试图通过辩称他有权获得这些文件并且是检察过度的受害者来驳回此案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普也可以尝试阻止检察官使用关键证据，例如他的律师详细说明与前总统谈话的笔记。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，如果此案进入审判阶段，特朗普的律师可能会尝试所谓的“陪审团无效”或试图说服陪审员，即使他们认为特朗普触犯了法律，他也应该被宣告无罪，因为违法行为还没有严重到足以引起指控并且他被单独挑出来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“辩护的主题可以充斥着不公平和选择性起诉的建议——基本上是试图说服陪审团，即使前总统按照政府所说的去做，这些都不应该以刑事起诉告终，”辩护律师罗伯特·明茨 (Robert Mintz) 说律师和前司法部检察官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿刑事辩护律师罗伯特·凯尔纳 (Robert Kelner) 表示，鉴于大量证据，完全无罪释放似乎不太可能，但如果特朗普的律师可以说服哪怕是一名陪审员，则存在审判不当的途径以总统享有解密信息的绝对权力为由宣告无罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该权力在特朗普离开总统职位后就结束了，但即便如此，“一些陪审员可能会发现很难合理化给他定罪的理由他以前拥有绝对的权力（去做），只是因为他没有提交正确的表格，也没有在正确的时间做这件事，”Kelner 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后，面对堆积如山的证据和前联邦检察官兼福特汉姆大学法学院刑事辩护诊所负责人谢丽尔·巴德 (Cheryl Bader) 表示，考虑到可能会被判入狱多年，特朗普最大的希望可能是他经常采用的策略：拖延、拖延、拖延。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “他最好的辩护方法可能是设法度过选举周期，当选为总统，并因此在案件开庭审理之前负责司法部，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan overhauls century-old sex crime laws, raises age of consent from 13 to 16]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3224302/japan-overhauls-century-old-sex-crime-laws-raises-age-consent-13-16?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 14:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/8aa2aa1e-1c63-4e73-a8ff-0bbbdd444c38_d3e47c05.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本的同意年龄从世界上最低的 13 岁提高到 16 岁上周五立法者通过了对性犯罪立法的重要改革。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;议会上议院一致通过了一项新法案，该法案还阐明了强奸起诉要求并将窥淫癖定为犯罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国的同意年龄为 16 岁，低于该年龄的性行为被视为法定强奸，法国为 15 岁，德国和中国为 14 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本的年龄自 1907 年以来一直没有改变，13 岁及以上的儿童被视为有同意能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在实践中，在美国许多地方，禁止对未成年人进行“猥亵”行为的区域法令有时被视为有效地将同意年龄提高到 18 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;约翰尼·北川 (Johnny Kitagawa) 的性虐待指控引发了对日本媒体同谋的质疑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据新法律，年龄相差不超过 5 岁的青少年夫妇如果双方都超过 13 岁，则免于起诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本上一次修订其关于性犯罪的刑法是在 2017 年，这是一个多世纪以来的第一次，但活动人士表示改革不够。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年，一系列强奸案被判无罪案件引发了全国性的集会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据以前的法律，检察官必须证明受害者因暴力和恐吓而丧失行为能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;批评者认为，这一要求实际上是在指责受害者没有足够的抵抗力。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;周五通过的法案列出了可以对强奸提起诉讼的例子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些例子包括受酒精或药物影响的受害者、受到惊吓的人以及实施强奸的人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;司法部一位官员今年早些时候表示，这些澄清并不是“为了让强奸定罪变得更容易或更难”，而是“有望使法庭判决更加一致”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据司法部的说法，该法案还包含一个新的“探视请求罪”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这意味着使用恐吓、引诱或金钱胁迫 16 岁以下儿童见面的人出于性目的将面临最高一年的监禁或 500,000 日元（3,500 美元）的罚款。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore becoming magnet for investment from Taiwan to hedge tensions with mainland China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3224303/singapore-becoming-magnet-investment-taiwan-hedge-tensions-mainland-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 14:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/635314a4-1497-4faa-895a-0593a8c9e0d1_6820a1ca.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;过去两年，台湾在新加坡的投资激增，因为这个城市国家已经成为根据官方数据和分析师的说法，这是对冲与中国大陆发生军事冲突风险的资金避难所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020 年，只有 36.9 亿新元（28 亿美元）的台湾资金流向了新加坡的企业， 2019 年只有 14.8 亿新元流入新加坡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但根据新加坡的数据，2021 年台湾流向新加坡的直接投资达到 72.1 亿新元（54 亿美元），去年达到 61 亿新元统计部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在台湾，鉴于与中国大陆的紧张关系，他们心里想的是很多不确定性，”台北专业服务公司 PwC Legal 的常务董事 Kent Chong 说， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们的资金存在焦虑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾的投资基金、公司和富人比其他国家更青睐新加坡Chong 补充说，因为他们认为它在政治上是“中立的”，如果需要的话，可以选择居住。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;转向新加坡可能是因为严格的冠状病毒控制“破坏了中国大陆的商业活动”，驻台外交事务分析师、乔治城大学入境外交硕士生王伟杰。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“永久的家”：为什么一波中国富人移居新加坡&lt;/h3>; p>;Wang 补充说，台湾商人传统上倾向于在中国大陆投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 1980 年代以来，台湾投资者将中国大陆视为为中国市场制造商品或再出口到其他国家的地方&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但封锁在 2020 年初和去年再次爆发，使工厂停滞不前，港口货物运输放缓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此外，美国和中国之间不断加剧的地缘政治紧张局势王说，[台湾海峡] 可能在这些投资者的计算背后发挥作用。近年来，两岸紧张局势不断升级，并在美国前众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台湾时的 8 月达到顶峰。这促使中国大陆在自治岛屿附近海域进行大规模军事演习，并对台湾出口产品实施贸易制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾的许多外国企业都有自己的应急计划，以防发生任何潜在冲突美国商会在 2 月份表示，这可能涉及转移资产和外籍员工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡对台湾来说意义重大，因为它的地理位置接近，在不断增长的供应链中发挥着重要作用经济学人智库分析师 Wen Wei Tan 表示，东南亚的优势及其法治声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;如果解放军继续演习，台湾将失去投资和供应链&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;CIMB Private Banking 驻新加坡的经济学家 Song Seng Wun 表示，一些离岸投资者到达新加坡是为了在邻国马来西亚或印度尼西亚购买工厂等固定资产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们他补充说，他们认为他们的钱在新加坡是“安全的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡贸易和工业部的一位女发言人表示，这个城市国家吸引外国资本是因为其“明确的政策和作为稳定和中立国家的声誉” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾家族投资公司 Mimesis Capital 的创始人兼首席执行官 Louis Liu 表示，由于东南亚的“需求”，他正在考虑在新加坡开设账户，同时他也看到了在新加坡开设账户的可能性数据显示，中国大陆在过去两年也增加了对新加坡的投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大陆个人和机构的对内直接投资达到2021 年为 87 亿新元（65 亿美元），去年为 92.8 亿新元，而 2020 年仅为 21.9 亿新元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港的投资者——分析师认为他们主要是中国大陆的银行账户持有人——去年在新加坡停放的资金略多于 100 亿新元，高于 2021 年的 34.5 亿新元和 2020 年的 16.8 亿新元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Covid-zero 政策和由此产生的封锁令许多成功、富有的商人及其家人受益香港大学金融学讲座教授陈志武说：“意识到中国的制度对他们的财富、业务和家庭嵌入了很多制度上的不确定性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;外国投资者纷纷撤资台湾外交事务分析师 Wang 补充说，中国投资者 5 月份的债券总额达到 72 亿美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国投资者希望增加其在亚洲的头寸，以避免病毒限制的影响，此前北京仅削减了Chen 补充说，去年 12 月实施封锁，并于 1 月取消了国际旅行限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但关注新加坡的中国投资者仍然担心中美之间发生冲突时会造成“人身伤害”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京对跨境资本流动实施严格控制，过度控制可能会破坏中央管理的人民币货币的稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这显然是每个人都应该尝试思考的问题，”他说。 “中国的货币管制现在比以前更严格了。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ron DeSantis dares Gavin Newsom to take on Joe Biden in 2024]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224298/desantis-dares-newsom-take-biden-2024?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 13:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/ceb0a49e-0079-48bf-bf45-fba715cbecbe_3fb45fbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;佛罗里达州共和党州长罗恩德桑蒂斯升级了他与加州州长加文纽瑟姆的不和，大胆西海岸民主党人将“停止故步自封”，并向美国总统乔·拜登发起初选挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月底宣布参加总统竞选的德桑蒂斯在佛罗里达州的新闻发布会上与纽森较量被问及纽森最近对福克斯新闻的评论，同意与肖恩·汉尼提 (Sean Hannity) 主持的与德桑蒂斯 (DeSantis) 的假设辩论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他在他的州有很大的问题——我的意思是，他的州有很大的问题，”德桑蒂斯周四说。 “尽管存在所有这些问题，但他对佛罗里达州有着真正认真的关注。我认为这很奇怪。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯随后转向民主党 2024 年的初选，其中 80 岁的拜登仅面临象征性的反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你知道吗？别故步自封了，”德桑蒂斯说。 “你打算投身赛场挑战乔吗？你要进去做吗？还是你只是坐在场边喋喋不休？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯的攻击来自于他回避与他在共和党白宫初选中的主要竞争对手、前总统唐纳德特朗普的对抗。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;罗恩·德桑蒂斯 (Ron DeSantis) 利用丘吉尔 1940 年标志性的演讲向“觉醒者”发起战争&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;民主党的后起之秀纽森一再表示，他没有兴趣竞选总统，并表示他完全支持拜登竞选连任。 4 月，总统宣布竞选连任后不久，纽森在华盛顿举行的一次筹款活动中为拜登筹集资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 55 岁的纽森继续提升他的全国知名度，引发了更多猜测他正在为 2024 年以后的总统竞选奠定基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2022 年再次当选州长后，纽森拿出竞选账户中剩余的数百万美元成立了一个新的政治行动委员会。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽森表示，他计划用这笔钱支持民主党人在阿肯色州、阿拉巴马州和密西西比州等共和党占主导地位的州竞选公职。上周，纽森表示，该委员会将推动美国宪法第 28 条修正案，以强化联邦枪支法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽森发言人没有直接回应德桑蒂斯的最新评论，但确实指出纽森参加了迪士尼乐园的活动本周骄傲之夜与公司首席执行官鲍勃·艾格 (Bob Iger) 一起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迪士尼已起诉德桑蒂斯，指控州长在公司反对佛罗里达州的一项被批评者称为“不要说同性恋”的法律后进行了“有针对性的政府报复运动” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽森高级顾问埃斯·史密斯在推特上回应德桑蒂斯的新攻击：“你的牢骚很不符合总统的要求！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长期以来，两国之间的紧张局势一直很严重- 人物，但在本月德桑蒂斯政府将移民从德克萨斯州迁移到纽森管辖的州首府萨克拉门托时达到了高潮。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯指责加州通过建立庇护城市鼓励非法移民，而纽森则称德桑蒂斯是一个“小而可怜的人”，并威胁要考虑绑架指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯对纽森的最新评论是专门针对周一播出的加利福尼亚州州长对汉尼提的采访做出的回应。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;小罗伯特·肯尼迪说采取“预防措施”以避免中情局暗杀&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在那次采访中，纽森坚称拜登的身体状况适合连任总统，但拒绝透露支持者是否敦促他与拜登竞选在 2024 年的选票上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及他是否相信拜登“认知能力强到足以成为总统”时，纽森说是的，并补充说他“一直”与总统交谈，并与他一起乘坐飞机旅行Force One。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你从来没有直接回答我的问题，”Hannity 回答道。 “你的电话一天响了多少次，人们说你需要参加这场比赛，因为他们同意我的看法，他不能胜任这份工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Newsom 在回答之前有些结结巴巴：“我”我不回答”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近的美国民意调查显示，对拜登再次竞选的支持不冷不热。拜登是美国历史上最年长的总统，第二个任期结束时他将年满 86 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普本周迎来 77 岁生日。 DeSantis 44 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Business Insider 的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Moral bankruptcy under the sun’: Chinese parents who praised schoolteacher fired for severe physical punishment of student slammed online]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/social-welfare/article/3224035/moral-bankruptcy-under-sun-chinese-parents-who-praised-schoolteacher-fired-severe-physical?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/28f8997d-a5d8-4f08-bc19-620f12cff826_b95bb5e8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一位教师因体罚学生而道歉并收到感谢的故事他们照顾的其他孩子的父母没有谴责，反而在大陆社交媒体上引发了愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名姓方的老师在调查后被解雇，当时他在义乌的一所小学工作，事件发生时，中国东南部的浙江省。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;性别不明的教育工作者在一名不服从的女学生魏某后对她进行了处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;图片有一个微信群里出现的视频显示，惩罚似乎过重，导致学生手臂严重瘀伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事件发生后，方某在群聊中道歉并表示：“我终于打到魏了。作为一名老师，我不应该有这样的行为。我真诚地向魏老师和她的父母道歉。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，其他家长没有谴责，而是对这位老师表扬、感谢和赞赏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位王姓妈妈说： “我们都见证了方舟子的付出。 You are such a diligent and caring teacher!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A father, surnamed Huang, said: “We&#39;ve had so many teachers over the past six years, but thankfully, Fang came in the last two years. We are truly grateful to you!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not surprisingly, Wei&#39;s parents took a different view: “If your child had suffered from the violence would you overlook it and even praise the teacher?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What kind of parent thinks that the teacher&#39;s behaviour is normal? Please come forward and talk to me. Let&#39;s see if I&#39;m overreacting. I&#39;m waiting online,” one of the parents of the victim said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The content of the WeChat group went viral on mainland social media, prompting an investigation by the school and local education authorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In less than a day the Education Bureau of Yiwu City confirmed that the teacher had used corporal punishment on students and the school has been ordered to terminate the teacher&#39;s employment contract.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dismissal has failed to quell online anger.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “Just termination? The parents should report this matter to the police.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some slammed the other parents: “The most despicable are these bootlicking parents who have ruined the school atmosphere. This is moral bankruptcy under the sun.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Traditional attitudes towards education and the role of teachers mean physical punishment is not uncommon in China&#39;s schools while many parents are afraid to voice concern when it arises.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, a female teacher at a middle school in southeastern China slapped a male student in the classroom to which the student responded by grabbing her hair and hitting her on the head.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also, two months ago, in eastern China, a male teacher was captured on a classroom surveillance camera yelling at students and slapping them for poor academic performance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under Chinese law, teachers who continue to impose corporal punishment on students after being warned not to can face administrative sanctions, dismissal, or, in the most serious cases, criminal prosecution.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can Li Qiang cement Europe’s ‘de-risk not decouple’ strategy on China?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224297/can-li-qiang-cement-europes-de-risk-not-decouple-strategy-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 14:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/9af12b48-9d99-424c-abf2-49e60fb9050b_63d0735c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang&#39;s first overseas trip as Chinese premier could cement the European Union&#39;s middle point strategy of “de-risking not decoupling” from China, according to analysts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li&#39;s visit to Berlin and Paris, which begins on Sunday, will be closely watched as he seeks to boost relations with two major European powers amid growing pressure from the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Germany&#39;s early pivot towards diversifying supply chains and cutting reliance on China, Chancellor Olaf Scholz openly clarified his stance against decoupling as “the wrong answer” in October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scholz made his statement months before the EU adopted a similar economic strategy of de-risking while progressing partnerships with Beijing in areas of common interest, such as climate change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Austin Strange, who teaches international relations at the University of Hong Kong, said the de-risking strategy would theoretically allow countries to more effectively identify and manage risks arising from international circumstances.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The strategy is intended to ensure stable supply chains as well as minimise opportunities for potentially adversarial economic coercion, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese premier to make first overseas trip to France and Germany&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Germany appears to want to retain China as a vital economic partner but pursue selective cooperation that minimises economic, political and security vulnerabilities.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To this end, Berlin is “actively tailoring engagement in hi-tech and infrastructure-heavy sectors, especially domestically and in Europe,” Strange said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scholz&#39; visit to China in November – the first by a G7 leader since the pandemic – was met with scepticism by some, who felt his openness to Beijing could undermine a united Western front.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Half a year later, Strange said Li&#39;s trip will be “an opportunity for outside observers to gauge their own options”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And, if it yields results, the visit will show that viable cooperative pathways exist beyond decoupling, and that the more confrontational approach of recent years is not the only way, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;EU&#39;s &#39;de-risking&#39; plan for China meets resistance from some members&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In an indication that Germany remains cautious about its engagement with China, Berlin labelled Beijing a “systemic rival” in its first national security strategy released on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zoon Ahmed Khan, a foreign-policy analyst and research fellow at Tsinghua University&#39;s Belt and Road Strategy Institute, said there were “diverging views” in Berlin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For example, foreign minister Annalena Baerbock holds a more suspicious view of China when compared to Chancellor Scholz, who takes a pro-pragmatism position,” Khan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s influence on Russia is key to EU relations, German minister says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Partnerships in some areas are more likely to be agreed upon than others by most of Berlin&#39;s decision makers, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Li&#39;s visit will serve as a platform for the two countries to advance three main agendas: trade and economic cooperation by promoting trade liberalisation, cooperation on global governance especially climate change, and global peace.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khan said both countries can benefit from collaborating in these areas, noting that China&#39;s high carbon emissions – 32 per cent of the global total in 2022, followed by the US at 14 per cent and India at 8 per cent – have raised concerns in the EU.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In terms of per capita emissions, China&#39;s load was around half that of the US, making it the 28th largest polluter, according to the most recent data from Climate Watch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But [China&#39;s] commitment to carbon neutrality by 2060, its investment in green technology and its cooperation with the rest of the world, including the global south, have simultaneously made Beijing emerge as a vital climate partner for the bloc.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zuo Xiying, international relations professor at Renmin University of China, said Beijing should continue its strategy of encouraging European countries to adopt relatively friendly policies, as a major approach to counteract US containment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[China] should deepen cooperation with Europe as much as possible to promote Europe to maintain its strategic autonomy,” he told a virtual forum last Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Berlin, Li will head to Paris to attend the summit for a new global financial pact, announced by French President Emmanuel Macron at the G20 in November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron attracted controversy in April, when he called for Europe to build its strategic autonomy and avoid becoming Washington&#39;s “vassal”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But a new report by the European Council on Foreign Relations shows nearly three-quarters of Europeans agree with Macron&#39;s view that the continent should cut its military dependence on the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 43 per cent see China as a “necessary partner”, compared to 35 per cent who regard Beijing as a “rival” or “adversary”, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Khan&#39;s view, public concerns in Europe about inflation and energy shortages trump fears of the “China threat”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Most Europeans would want to stay neutral in a US-China war over Taiwan: study&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Macron&#39;s position is intrinsically compatible with the EU&#39;s de-risking strategy [and] aligns with the need to boost its economy,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khan added that disengaging from Beijing would be more likely to result in Europe&#39;s isolation from the world, rather than China itself being shunned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Macron&#39;s own visit to Beijing shed light on the Global South&#39;s emergence and Beijing&#39;s role as a leader in global governance, which is growing more important in North-South and South-South cooperations,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;World expects China to take bigger role in regional issues: foreign minister&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The war in Ukraine – soon to enter its 16th month – will not be a priority during Li&#39;s visit to Berlin, although the two sides may broach the subject to assess each other&#39;s stances, according to Moscow-based international relations analyst Andrew Korybko.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is limited common ground between the two countries on the issue and Beijing would “at most” reiterate its commitment to promoting peace talks, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Ukrainian conflict affects the world in different ways, but it&#39;s not an impediment to the improvement of Sino-German relations, which are focused on trade ties.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine war: China, France agree to keep pushing for political settlement&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Korybko said any attempt by Berlin to problematise Beijing&#39;s position could be interpreted by China as the European state acting under Washington&#39;s influence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A week after Li&#39;s European trip, EU leaders will meet in Brussels and Korybko predicts that both internal and external discord will be on display.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Central and Eastern European (CEE) countries like Poland and the Baltic states are likely to be “suspicious” of the uptick in France and Germany&#39;s diplomacy with China, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The West has a narrative interest in presenting a united front on this issue, though there is also no denying that rifts are emerging between the US and CEE states on one hand, and on the other between the CEE and Western European states led by France and Germany.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latter are “flirting with a potential compromise” on the war, Korybko said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Orange Wang&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: US chip maker Micron to invest US$600 million on China plant despite Beijing’s partial ban on its products]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3224291/tech-war-us-chip-maker-micron-invest-us600-million-china-plant-despite-beijings-partial-ban-its?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 13:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/b149ba52-262d-4ba5-9545-e91ebe7df6c5_a02524e5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US memory chip giant Micron Technology said it plans to invest 4.3 billion yuan (US$602 million) to upgrade its chip packaging plant in Xian, a decision that comes just four weeks after Beijing imposed a partial ban on its products being sold in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a statement published on its official WeChat account on Friday, Micron said it would acquire the operations of its outsourcing partner Powertech Technology, and add new buildings to the site to “better meet Chinese customers&#39; demand”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Micron CEO Sanjay Mehrotra said in the statement, which was only in Chinese, that the plan shows the firm&#39;s commitment to its China operations and the local team. Betty Wu Mingxia, the recently appointed general manager of Micron China, said the deal would allow the US company to directly manage all chip packaging and testing operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China-South Korea tech trade slumps in May amid changes in chip supply chain&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Upon completion of the deal, which is expected to take a year and is subject to regulatory approval in China, Micron&#39;s total payroll in the country will increase to 4,500, by adding 1,200 workers from Powertech, Micron said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan-listed Powertech said the acquisition price would be based upon the book value of its operations, which ranges from US$50 million to US$60 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Micron&#39;s plan to expand its Xian plant comes after the China Administration of Cybersecurity (CAC) barred critical information infrastructure providers from buying Micron&#39;s products, citing national security risks. The CAC launched a probe into Micron&#39;s products in late March, a move seen as China&#39;s reprisal against US sanctions on its technology firms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s ban could see a hit to Micron&#39;s revenue in the single digits, the company&#39;s management has said, as China contributes about 11 per cent of Micron&#39;s global sales. After Beijing&#39;s ruling, China&#39;s top server makers, including Inspur Group and Lenovo Group, asked their suppliers to suspend shipments of modules containing chips made by the US company, the South China Morning Post reported earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s ban also has geopolitical implications, as Washington has reportedly asked Seoul to dissuade South Korean chip makers from filling any market gaps in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Micron&#39;s US$600 million spending in Xian pales in comparison with its plans in Japan, where the company said it would invest US$3.6 billion over the next few years in next-generation memory chip fabs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, packaging and testing are relatively low-end and low-margin operations compared with wafer fabrication. In 2014, Micron reached an outsourcing deal with Powertech for chip packaging and testing at the Xian plant, under which Micron owns the land and buildings while the Taiwan firm owned the equipment and provided the workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The outsourcing deal ended in April 2022, but both sides agreed to renew it on a quarterly basis, according to Powertech last year. Micron&#39;s acquisition will allow Powertech to cash out from the Xian operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Powertech chairman DK Tsai was quoted by Taiwanese media earlier this year as saying Taiwanese semiconductor companies are considering pulling out of mainland China due to geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[45 airguns seized from Hong Kong flat, man arrested over hoax call wasting police resources]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3224293/45-airguns-seized-hong-kong-flat-man-arrested-over-hoax-call-wasting-police-resources?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 13:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/18a8adbf-a937-4683-9c6d-910b95c576df_d417e5d4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong officers have seized 45 airguns from a New Territories flat and arrested a local man while investigating a case of “wasteful employment of police” linked to a hoax call.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The imitation firearms, containing about 30 air-powered rifles, were sent for tests to determine if they could produce more than two joules in kinetic energy – a mark that would classify the items as firearms in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Possession of an unlicensed firearm is punishable by up to 14 years in jail under the Firearms and Ammunition Ordinance. The case came to light after police late on Thursday night released details.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last Saturday, officers in bulletproof vests rushed to a shopping centre in Ngau Tau Kok after receiving a call claiming that several men were seen carrying what appeared to be handguns in the mall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the force, no suspicious individuals were found at the scene and the caller could not be reached. The case was classified as so-called wasteful deployment of police.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;HK$150,000 reward for leads on attack on Hong Kong subversion trial court&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;After gathering evidence, detectives raided a Yuen Long flat and arrested a 39-year-old man. Officers also found 45 suspected imitation firearms on the premises.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said an investigation suggested the suspect allegedly made a false report to the force due to personal grudges against a wargame venue. He is also believed to be linked to three similar reports made on June 4.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police seize 200 airguns, arrest 10 in raids ahead of election&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The man was charged with one count of the wasteful employment of police and brought before Kwun Tong court on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the Criminal Procedure Ordinance, the offence is punishable by up to six months in jail and a HK$2,000 (US$255) fine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On February 8, an airgun pellet, fired from a moving vehicle on the elevated West Kowloon Corridor, hit the West Kowloon Court building and grazed a glass panel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The airgun attack sparked the deployment of several police vehicles to guard the flyover near the court in Sham Shui Po. The court is the venue for the trial of 16 to 47 opposition politicians and activists charged with subversion of state power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police have offered a HK$150,000 reward for information leading to the arrest of anyone involved in the attack.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>