<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong national security law: ‘2 more ex-Demosisto members’ arrested over funds support for Nathan Law, total number of suspects at 7]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3229094/hong-kong-national-security-law-2-more-ex-demosisto-members-arrested-over-funds-support-nathan-law?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 14:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/b599c7b9-7b60-4fc2-b773-473a763eec34_cb862f3f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港国安警察周四又拘捕两名解散反对党众志成员据《华盛顿邮报》获悉，涉嫌为逃亡的前立法会议员罗冠中进行筹款活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上午的最新逮捕行动使该案中的前众志嫌疑人总数达到七人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;警方表示，他们逮捕了一名 29 岁的男子和一名女子，但没有透露嫌疑人的名字。他们涉嫌勾结外国或外部势力，危害国家安全并实施煽动性行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;香港警方突击搜查反对党众志前议员家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“经调查，两名被捕人士涉嫌与7月5日被捕的一批人有联系，”警方表示。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至周四下午，两人仍被拘留接受审讯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月5日，部队国家安全部门的官员逮捕了一名前香港众志领导人和三名成员。他们被指控参与为罗先生筹集资金，罗先生目前居住在英国，是根据国安法列入通缉名单的八人之一，每人悬赏 100 万港元以逮捕他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这四人早前被捕的人包括前众志领袖林朗贤及三名前众志成员廖伟廉、李启正及钟展九。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;翌日，警方拘捕另一位前香港众志成员朱彦浩 (Calvin Chu-Yan-ho) 与此案有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五名嫌疑人已被保释，等待进一步调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;4 名前香港众志成员香港众志因“黄圈”筹款被捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;法律于 2020 年 6 月 27 日离开香港，就在国家安全法颁布前几天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据警方称悬赏通知书《Law 30》据称呼吁外国在 2020 年 7 月至 2022 年 11 月期间对国家和香港实施制裁或从事敌对活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Law 是香港反对派和香港的主要声音。 2014 年占领抗议期间的学生领袖。 2016年，他与他人共同创立了地方党众志，并担任主席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;23岁时，他当选为立法会议员，成为香港历史上最年轻的立法会议员。当局对他首次出席立法会时所作的颇具争议的宣誓提出质疑，导致他于 2017 年 7 月被取消资格。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 14:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Coroner’s inquest into Hong Kong’s Lamma IV disaster must expose systemic issues, reveal ‘full story’ of ferry crash, victims’ families say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3229095/coroners-inquest-hong-kongs-lamma-iv-disaster-must-expose-systemic-issues-reveal-full-story-ferry?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 14:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/3032cdb3-b254-465a-b68d-33f397eb987d_1ef09b99.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;迟来的验尸官对香港最严重的海难之一的调查必须有助于揭露真相受害者家属在法院驳回了早些时候拒绝其调查请求的决定一天后表示，该事件造成了 39 人死亡，并揭露了造成 39 人死亡的渡轮碰撞事故背后的真相。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但前立法会议员涂谨申-一直在帮助这些家庭的孙周四表示，只有政府向公众发布两份未公开的调查报告，正义才能得到伸张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，上诉法院推翻了法官早先的裁决，该裁决要求进行调查没有必要对 2012 年 10 月 1 日两艘渡轮在南丫岛附近海域相撞造成的死亡事件进行调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在高等法院作出裁决后，涂先生表示，他预计将进行研讯以确定海事处是否未能确保相关船厂遵守安全规定，也未能解决警方和调查委员会两份报告之间的不一致问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Philip Chiu Ping-chuen 在悲剧中失去了妹妹，表示他希望调查能够解释为什么其中一艘船只沉没得这么快。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“应该有人承担责任，但完整的故事出来对我们来说是最重要的，”他在周四的一个电台节目。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2012 年南丫岛四号沉没的阴影终于能消除吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当局发布了一份由政府指定的独立机构进行的报告的执行摘要调查委员会于2014年进行了调查，但警方和运输及物流局编制的另外两份资料尚未向公众披露。当时他们只是在一次闭门会议上向立法者提出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chiu 表示，法院的裁决为受害者家属“打开了一扇门”，他们在十多年后仍在努力寻找答案。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该委员会报告的执行摘要称，这场灾难与“涉嫌犯罪”有关，17 名未透露姓名的官员被指控行为不当。委员会还发现，港灯旗下的南丫四号由于没有水密舱壁门，在 112 秒内沉没。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杜涛表示，他已阅读该委员会的完整报告，其中指出 Sea Smooth、撞上南丫岛四号的港九渡轮是由金属而非木材制成的。立法者表示，这可能是导致沉没如此之快的一个因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他表示，报告摘要中从未明确说明这一点，受害者家属对为什么会这样有很多疑问他们的亲属在碰撞后很快就去世了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港法院下令验尸官对 2012 年南丫岛渡轮事故进行调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;梁淑玲和徐志成的家人两名受害者表示，他们知道这些年来一些证据可能已经丢失，一些目击者可能已经去世。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“谜题可能不会完成，但调查肯定会揭示更多的证据梁告诉另一电台节目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;原讼法庭最初于 2020 年驳回了家属的调查请求，法官称上诉不符合公共利益。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;去年有媒体报道称警方曾在2015年调查期间建议进行研讯，因此去年向死因裁判法庭提出上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三运输及物流局和港灯表示将全力配合调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 14:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China tests ultra-thin flexible solar wing as it prepares satellite megaconstellation to rival Elon Musk’s Starlink]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3228943/china-tests-ultra-thin-flexible-solar-wing-it-prepares-satellite-megaconstellation-rival-elon-musks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 13:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/f2003e77-f68c-44c0-9493-dcb9405698b6_0de4829b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国发射首颗搭载超薄柔性太阳翼的通信卫星测试该国计划在近地轨道由 13,000 颗卫星组成的宽带巨型星座的技术，以与 SpaceX 的星链相媲美。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由北京初创企业银河航天开发的灵犀三号从太原卫星发射中心升空周日上午 10 点 50 分，在中国中部山西省的长征二号丁运载火箭顶部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;灵犀一号的可弯曲太阳能电池板厚度约为 1 毫米，类似于信用卡，仅为信用卡的 5%。据国家电视台中央电视台报道，传统太阳能电池板的厚度。当折叠在火箭内时，太阳能电池阵列厚 5 厘米（2 英寸），一旦在轨道上运行，它就会膨胀至 9 米长、2.5 米宽（29.5 英尺 x 8.2 英尺）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此前，中国据央视周日报道，该公司仅使用此类太阳能电池板为其天宫空间站供电。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些太阳能翼体积小、重量轻且易于存放。它们比传统太阳能电池板吸收更多的太阳能，特别适合大规模可堆叠卫星发射。”银河航天首席技术官朱正贤周二告诉《中国科学报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;灵犀03号是朱说，这也是我国第一颗具有一体化主体结构的卫星。他说，该卫星平台的灵感来自汽车底盘，得益于尖端的压铸技术，适合后续批量生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;灵犀三号搭载的数字有效载荷可处理数十个卫星总指挥胡钊告诉中央电视台，每秒传输千兆字节数据，并将验证下一代低轨宽带通信、主动热控制和可堆叠卫星释放等相关技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它综合了地面站的多种功能，可以分析大量用户信息。”胡说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国在快速卫星发射方面面临落后于中国的风险：报告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;灵犀- 03号采用开放式框架设计，这意味着所有仪器都直接附着在卫星外部，暴露在恶劣的太空环境中。胡说，这需要灵犀三号上的电子设备具有出色的辐射防护和温度控制能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;银河空间成立于 2018 年，是中国第一家致力于卫星互联网服务的公司。据报道，该公司在 9 月份筹集了资金，使其估值达到 15.8 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 3 月，GalaxySpace 向近地轨道发射了六颗通信卫星，用于一个绰号为“迷你蜘蛛星座”的实验网络，并进行了5G网络测试取得成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朱总表示，公司将加快星机直连相控阵天线等核心技术研究，与产业链合作伙伴合作，助力推进5G网络建设。据《SpaceNews》3 月份报道，今年晚些时候，中国将发射第一批“国网”卫星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，中国有超过 4,500 颗星链卫星天文学家乔纳森·麦克道尔（Jonathan McDowell）在其网站上跟踪发射情况，他表示：“中国科学家正在开发人工智能算法来躲避太空垃圾，”星链卫星的数量可能在 10 年内达到 42,000 颗。 。加上中国和其他西方公司提出的巨型星座计划，卫星总数可能轻松超过 60,000 颗，使近地轨道变得更加拥挤，并可能更加危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日的发射还包括三颗遥感卫星机载卫星：Skysight AS-01、AS-02 和 AS-03。这三台卫星均属于北京天视科技有限公司所有，是该公司在雷达、光学和红外波段观测地球的商业星座的一部分。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What are the odds? Hong Kong woman has iPhone 14 Pro stolen by taxi driver, encounters same car with new cabby days later]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3228766/what-are-odds-hong-kong-woman-has-iphone-14-pro-stolen-taxi-driver-encounters-same-car-new-cabby?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/25/7be60f4e-b978-4954-85f1-6887d018e229_e83d7084.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;尽管困难重重，一名幸运的香港女子在一周多时间里却遇到了同一辆出租车将价值 10,000 港元（1,300 美元）的 iPhone 14 Pro 留在里面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名名叫 Tung Tung 的女士在香港失物招领 Facebook 群组中发帖称，她将 iPhone 落在锦田的出租车里HK01新闻网站报道了7月7日在该市北部地区新界的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，她刚下车就发现手机还在车里，但她声称司机见她示意停车，加速开走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;童童称，五分钟后，她拨打她的电话时，手机已经关机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;童童在丢失手机的同一天发帖称，她给司机发信息，恳求他归还手机，里面有重要内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个多星期后，童童给了司机再次看到她的手机。 7 月 16 日，当她​​在确切位置叫了一辆出租车时，她找到了与她放置手机相同的车辆，但驾驶者是不同的司机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出租车司机说，之前和她一起离开的司机那天他的手机正在接班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他给童童的第一位司机打电话，发现他已经以 600 元（85 美元）的价格将她的手机卖给了中国大陆的一家商店，但提出愿意付款1,000港元（128美元）赔偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;童童表示，她录下了这段对话，并要求第一位司机归还手机，否则她会报警。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子惊慌失措，答应找回她的手机，并在下周归还给她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;童童说，不诚实的司机告诉她，他每次找到手机都把手机卖给同一家商店，他可以询问失主在取回手机之前不要卖掉她的手机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他本来可以向我索要 1,000 港元，但他却以 600 元的价格出售了它，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，很多读童童帖子的人都不相信司机按照他声称的价格卖掉了手机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然HK01报道她说第二位司机在她应该拿到手机的那天联系了她回来后称歹徒已将她的手机带回香港，她更新帖子称仍未收到手机，已向警方报案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“即使我无法找回我的手机电话，我不想看到另一个人成为他的受害者，”她在更新的帖子中写道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea backs Moscow’s ‘battle for justice’ as Kim Jong-un shows off banned missiles to Russian minister]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3229085/north-korea-backs-moscows-battle-justice-kim-jong-un-shows-banned-missiles-russian-minister?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 13:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/52266f73-17df-4e0d-838f-57f5d7a7ab2a_bd035350.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部长陪同朝鲜领导人金正恩参加国防展览，其中包括朝鲜官方媒体周四报道，平壤禁止弹道导弹，因为邻国承诺加强关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯部长谢尔盖·绍伊古和一个包括一名政治局成员在内的中国代表团本周抵达朝鲜，参加朝鲜核试验。朝鲜将朝鲜战争结束 70 周年庆祝为“胜利日”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据在俄罗斯和中国的支持下通过的联合国安理会决议，这些导弹被禁止，但本周它们为朝鲜的“胜利日”提供了引人注目的背景。这是三个国家因与美国竞争而联合起来的团结表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;绍伊古是自苏联解体以来俄罗斯国防部长首次访问朝鲜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;对于朝鲜来说，俄罗斯和中国代表团的到来标志着自冠状病毒大流行以来该国首次向世界开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国不会“鼓励”朝鲜，即使它着眼于在朝鲜半岛局势中加深联系。据朝鲜媒体报道，绍伊古向金正恩递交了俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京的信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金正恩感谢普京派出绍伊古率领的军事代表团，称此次访问加深了朝鲜与俄罗斯的关系。朝鲜和俄罗斯之间的“战略和传统”关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[金正恩]从最高层就维护两国主权、发展和利益的斗争中共同关心的问题发表了看法。朝鲜媒体称：“他多次表示相信，俄罗斯军队和人民将在建立一个独立国家的斗争中取得巨大成功。”朝鲜中央通讯社没有提及乌克兰战争，但据报道，朝鲜国防部长康顺南表示，朝鲜完全支持俄罗斯的“正义之战”，并希望保护其主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝中社称，金正恩带领绍伊古参观了新武器和军事装备展览。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方媒体照片显示金正恩和他的客人参观了一些新武器和军事装备的展览。朝鲜弹道导弹的多轴运输发射器。另一张图片显示了分析师所说的似乎是一架新型无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位分析师表示，绍伊古对朝鲜导弹访问的检查表明俄罗斯接受朝鲜的核计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们”美国卡内基国际和平基金会的安吉特·潘达 (Ankit Panda) 表示，与朝鲜在俄罗斯和中国的高级外国政要到访时避免展示其核能力相比，已经发生了很大变化。他称这次访问“非常了不起”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“绍伊古的个人访问——以及绍伊古愿意在访问过程中与金正恩合影——证明莫斯科对朝鲜正在进行的核现代化感到自满，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;朝鲜可能声称美国士兵“从帝国主义美国叛逃”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据朝鲜媒体报道，金正恩还会见了中国共产党政治局委员李鸿忠进行会谈，并收到了中国国家主席习近平的一封信&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜国家通讯社朝中社援引金正恩的话说，李克强代表团的访问表明了习近平“高度重视朝中友谊”的承诺。其正式名称为朝鲜民主主义人民共和国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士称，俄罗斯的访问增加了对朝鲜提供更公开支持的可能性，特别是在莫斯科因入侵乌克兰而被西方孤立的情况下。 p>;&lt;p>;“虽然俄罗斯与朝鲜的官方军事合作一直有限，但所谓后冷战秩序的任何真正破裂都可能导致俄罗斯更愿意公开违反制裁，特别是考虑到他们对朝鲜的制裁态度相对宽松。去年朝鲜核地位的转变，”中朝智库韩俄关系专家安东尼·林纳 (Anthony Rinna) 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，朝鲜制定了一项内容广泛的新核法，宣布其核武器国家的地位“不可逆转”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月，中国威胁要对美国展示武力进行核报复，称在朝鲜半岛附近部署战略军事资产可能符合标准白宫国家安全发言人约翰·柯比 (John Kirby) 表示，俄罗斯向朝鲜示好是在克里姆林宫努力采购武器之际。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这已经不是什么秘密了……先生普京正在向其他国家寻求帮助和支持，以支持他在乌克兰的战争。我们知道，这包括与朝鲜进行一些接触。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜在与乌克兰的战争中支持克里姆林宫，并运送了包括步兵火箭和导弹在内的武器来支持俄罗斯的战争，白宫已表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜和俄罗斯否认进行过武器交易。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pentagon chief says US to deploy coastguard ship to Papua New Guinea but no permanent military base amid China tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3229080/austin-says-us-deploy-coastguard-ship-papua-new-guinea-no-permanent-military-base-amid-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 12:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/7d8f6939-0660-40da-a0f0-e8ae2719c82e_1c35f904.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀周四宣布向巴布亚部署一艘美国海岸警卫队船只新几内亚，华盛顿在与中国争夺影响力的激烈竞争中寻求扩大在该地区的军事足迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国海岸警卫队快艇将于八月抵达这里，”奥斯汀在成为五角大楼首任负责人时说道访问巴布亚新几内亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举利用了两国最近签署的防务协定，该协定为美国提供了进入南太平洋战略重要地区的更大军事通道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;华盛顿热衷于向地区伙伴表明，地区合作伙伴可以从美国加强安全合作中受益，并减轻当地对巴布亚新几内亚正在被拖入美中争夺该地区影响力之战的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于台湾之间巴布亚新几内亚是美国的盟友澳大利亚，是美拉尼西亚面积最大、人口最多的国家，该地区对于决定第二次世界大战太平洋结果至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚可以成为“合理”的调解者缓解中美紧张局势：前部长&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;奥斯汀强调，部署海岸警卫队将有助于巴布亚新几内亚制止对其保护薄弱的海洋资源的掠夺，制止非法捕鱼和贩运等活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据今年早些时候签署的具有里程碑意义的美国-巴布亚新几内亚安全协议，华盛顿将能够在全国各地开发和运营设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据巴布亚新几内亚的协议，美国军方可以在六个主要港口和机场驻扎部队和船只，包括马努斯岛的隆布鲁姆海军基地和首都莫尔兹比港的设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿将“不受阻碍地进入”这些地点，“预置设备、物资”根据文本，Lombrum 曾被用作英国、德国的驻军。 、日本、澳大利亚和美国军队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二次世界大战期间，它是美国在太平洋最大的基地之一，停泊着 200 艘舰艇，其中包括用于收复失地的 6 艘战列舰和 20 艘航空母舰&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但奥斯汀试图减轻人们的担忧，即该协议将削弱这个南太平洋国家极力维护的独立性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴布亚新几内亚只是摆脱了英国数十年的直接统治， 1975 年的澳大利亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我只是想明确表示，我们并不寻求在巴布亚新几内亚建立永久基地，”奥斯汀告诉东道主。 “这是扩大长期关系的机会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理詹姆斯·马拉佩也阐述了该协议的理由，称这将有助于巴布亚新几内亚的基础设施现代化并加强其安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“他们从未篡改我们的主权、自治和独立，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不是他们进来的。我们邀请他们进来……是为了加强我们的防御保护我们自己的边界，包括阻止从我们的海域盗窃鱼类。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们这样做是为了改善我们的国家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;汤加的布林肯呼吁“掠夺性” ”中国的“有问题的行为”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;同样在周四，美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯在太平洋地区三个国家访问期间在新西兰停留了一天多，他提出了一种可能性惠灵顿和其他参加奥库斯防御协议的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新西兰和其他合作伙伴在他们认为适当的情况下进行参与的大门非常开放，”布林肯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;新西兰总理克里斯·希普金斯周三表示，新西兰愿意就奥库斯可能发挥的作用进行“对话”，只要它不涉及核动力潜艇的开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新西兰一直在自 20 世纪 80 年代中期以来，两国一直在无核化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，官员们似乎着眼于网络、人工智能和高超音速武器等国防技术方面的合作，这些技术属于奥库斯协议所谓的“第二支柱” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国强烈反对奥库斯协议，称该协议会破坏该地区的稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新西兰外交部长纳纳亚·马胡塔 (Nanaia Mahuta) 表示，关于奥库斯协议“尚未达成任何协议”，而且在达成任何协议之前，该国内阁必须考虑任何提案。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[4 injured in crash between light rail train and delivery van in Hong Kong’s Tin Shui Wai, marking second such incident in a week]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3229070/4-injured-crash-between-light-rail-train-and-delivery-van-hong-kongs-tin-shui-wai-marking-second?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 10:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/fcc2ab8c-2f5e-4306-8706-4ae01e80ee62_089a35af.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周四，一列轻轨列车与一辆送货车相撞，造成四人受伤香港新界，这是该市一周内发生的第二起此类事故。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新一起事故发生在上午 8 点 51 分，发生在天水围天水站附近。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;3香港轻铁线路在碰撞后恢复运营&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方发言人表示，货车上的三人和火车上的另一人受轻伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日晚上，两名轻铁司机614P 及 507 号线列车在屯门站相撞，因此停运。该事件中没有人员受伤的报告。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:20:21 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What Elon Musk’s X offered Gene X Hwang for prized @x Twitter handle he had since 2007]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229072/what-elon-musks-x-offered-gene-x-hwang-prized-x-twitter-handle-he-had-2007?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 10:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/ed2af7c7-59c7-4f6a-816c-4ab88a3c90b5_e5f94388.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在品牌重塑过程中，X（以前称为 Twitter）突然接管了其中之一周二晚上，其用户帐户的帐号为 @x。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该帐号的原始所有者 Gene X Hwang 告诉 Insider，他收到了一封有关帐号变更的电子邮件，并获得了更长的帐号 @x12345678998765。他自 2007 年起就拥有 @x 账号，并在该社交媒体网站上拥有了超过 53,000 名粉丝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hwang 是一位来自旧金山的摄影师，他表示他对交易 @x 的想法持开放态度。处理，但 X 最终没有向他提供任何经济补偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当这一切开始发生时，我想也许会产生一些很酷的东西，”黄说。 “在某种程度上，这有点像中了彩票的幻想。你买了彩票，希望也许你会赢得一些东西，但你也知道这可能不会发生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黄补充说，人们告诉他他可能会得到一辆特斯拉 Model X &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一些金钱或补偿对他们来说似乎并不是什么大不了的事，”他说。 “我肯定会接受一些东西，但我也没有试图勒索金钱或类似的东西。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马斯克的 Twitter 品牌重塑因色情、赌博而在印度尼西亚被屏蔽&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;由 Insider 查看的来自 X 的电子邮件称，该用户名“隶属于 X Corp”，因此 Hwang 获得了不同的用户名。他的帖子和关注者也已转移到新帐户。 《电讯报》率先报道了这一问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司告诉黄，他们将为他提供“X 商品，并独家访问 X 总部，与我们团队的成员会面”。不过，黄说他几年前就和一位朋友参观过该公司总部，并且对 Twitter 相关商品比 X 品牌材料更感兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家社交媒体公司的所有者埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 宣布成立该公司周末进行了品牌重塑，放弃了其标志性的蓝鸟徽标，改为简单的“X”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了不断改进其新徽标外，该公司还一直在更改其平台上官方帐户的名称。不过，该公司的主帐户花了更长的时间，因为 Hwang 已经注册了 @x。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社交媒体用户开始注意到当时的私人帐户 @x 正在将其简介更改为“！！！”本周早些时候，当 X 徽标开始在整个网站上出现时，人们发出“哦”的感叹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一条推文开玩笑说，“他一定是担心自己的生命安全。”这条推文获得了近 20 万个赞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“一切都好，结局好，”黄周二晚上在他的帐户被更改后发推文。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去，以前称为 Twitter 的网站上的用户可以以数千美元的价格出售他们的账号。在黑市上。这种做法违反了该公司的用户名抢注政策，该政策不允许用户在网站上买卖账号。据 Gizmodo 报道，另一个单字母帐户 @n 的所有者在 2014 年表示，在他们被黑客攻击并丢失帐户之前，有人向他们提供了 5 万美元的价格来购买该名称。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;解释：埃隆·马斯克给出了 Twitter 更名背后的原因&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hwang 在 2014 年面临类似的黑客攻击，但他在博客中写道，他能够重新获得对 @x 的控制权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个尚未更名的公司帐户是 @TwitterMovies，这可能与一些用户开玩笑说 X 这个名字听起来更像是一个色情网站这一事实有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更重要的是，接管 @x手柄似乎是社交媒体品牌重塑问题中最小的一个。该公司的竞争对手 Meta 还拥有“X”标志的商标权，这个问题可能会让马斯克的公司更加头疼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司正努力更换其 Twitter 标志周一晚上，旧金山警察局表示，他们对“可能未经许可的街道封锁”做出了回应，但其总部在周一晚上被警方挫败，但后来确定这不是警察的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;X 的发言人确实这样做了没有立即回应内部人士的置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:20:21 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why South Korea needs China even as it teams up with US on chips and more]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228899/why-south-korea-needs-china-even-it-teams-us-chips-and-more?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/25/295394a2-1c8c-484a-a142-9087b1a72fc5_10451c8a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国今年有望首次出现对华年度贸易逆差，标志着这是自两国 31 年前正式建交以来的历史性转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是因为北京对制造业自给自足的关注减少了从韩国的进口，越来越多的韩国企业将其供应链迁出中国，同时紧张局势也加剧了。中美竞争继续影响着东北亚的地缘政治动态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国毫不掩饰对日本和韩国日益向华盛顿倾斜的不满，并一再将两国关系急剧恶化归咎于美国的战略遏制。与两个主要贸易伙伴的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，贸易和投资联系 — — 被广泛认为是北京与美国这两个条约盟友和谐相处的基础 — — 早在近年来摩擦加剧之前就开始发生转变。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;分析人士表示，经济实力差距的扩大和国际产业格局的变化是这三个国家之间日益不和的“最大”催化剂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国关系可能会变得更加紧密。他们表示，当中国进一步提升全球价值链并挑战日本和韩国的地位时，这令人担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国迅速升级其高科技产业，日本和韩国产品的中国市场份额和利润南京大学国际关系学院执行院长朱锋表示，这是导致中国与两国关系进入“紧张新阶段”的主要因素之一。他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在（日本和韩国）商界再次转向美国，认为在美国的投资比在中国的投资更重要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外， the United States&#39; “full-scale suppression” of China had left no leeway for Tokyo and Seoul to balance economic and diplomatic ties with the two rival powers, Zhu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ironically, the economic rise of Japan, South Korea and China followed similar trajectories.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All three successively created their own growth miracles following the end of World War II, through similar state-led, industrial policy-driven and export-oriented paths.&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Each progressed from labour-intensive to innovation-intensive sectors, with some low-value-added industries, such as assembly and processing, moving first from Japan to South Korea and then on to China, highlighting the close linkages between the three economies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, that also led to a high degree of overlap in their industrial and export structures, sparking competition and strategic jockeying in the global value chain.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How better South Korea -Japan ties could weaken a China-centric supply chain&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;South Korea dethroned Japan as the world&#39;s largest display producer in 2004, just five years after taking over as the No 1 shipbuilder. In the 1990s and 2000s, led by tech giants Samsung and SK Hynix, South Korea beat Japan in the memory chip race and now holds over half of the global market share.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, a four-year trade dispute with Tokyo, which formally ended only last month, exposed South Korea&#39;s dependence on Japanese equipment and materials for advanced chip-making, and the challenges it faced in overtaking Japan in the value chain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Again, China unseated Japan as the world&#39;s No 2 economy in 2010, a feat widely viewed as having sparked a structural change in bilateral relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first quarter of 2023, China surpassed Japan as the world&#39;s top auto exporter on the back of rising demand for new energy vehicles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bilateral economic cooperation model had gone from “vertical” to “horizontal”, Chinese ambassador to Japan Wu Jianghao told business representatives in Tokyo last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was referring to a shift from an upstream-downstream hierarchy in the supply chain to a mode where countries with similar development levels trade similar goods.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Such tensions have recently become more evident in China-South Korea trade, with Beijing now the largest source of trade deficit for South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea recorded a surprise overall trade surplus in June, its first in 16 months, but it was still a ninth straight month of deficit with China, according to Korean official data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As recently as 2021, South Korea would record sizeable annual surpluses with China – its top trading partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Noticeable increases in imports from China have included fibres, machinery, computers, automotive batteries and even semiconductors, sectors where South Korea long held an advantage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Korean products also continue to lose ground globally to China-made alternatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kang Jun-young, professor of Chinese studies at Hankuk University of Foreign Studies in Seoul, said South Korean firms&#39; loss of technological competitiveness had led to difficulties in trade and business with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This makes long-term changes in the structure of the trade relationship “inevitable”, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There was declining demand for intermediate goods supplied by Korea as exports to China decreased in the aftermath of the global economic downturn and China&#39;s zero-Covid policy,” Kang said, referring to Beijing&#39;s strict anti-pandemic measures involving mass lockdowns and border controls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A more fundamental reason is that as China&#39;s technological prowess increased, some goods could now be substituted.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Cho Young-nam, professor of international area studies at Seoul National University, China and South Korea had shifted from being “complementary partners” to “competitive rivals” with regard to their economies, and this had contributed to the current “fragile” state of bilateral ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Over the past three decades], the gap in national power between South Korea and China has been widening,” Cho told the 11th World Peace Forum (WPF) in Beijing earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is the largest picture and the most important factor affecting the Korea-China relationship.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The nearly US$18 trillion Chinese economy last year, according to World Bank data, dwarfed South Korea&#39;s by more than tenfold – a far cry from a gulf of merely 20 per cent in 1992, when the two countries established formal relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The difference is stark in military spending as well. From being virtually identical three decades ago, Beijing&#39;s military expenditure had ballooned to more than six times that of Seoul last year, figures from the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Against such a backdrop, the &#39;China threat theory&#39; has spread in South Korea,” Cho said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Yoon Suk-yeol is leading a drive to diversify Korean trade away from China and build “supply chain alliances”, especially with regard to advanced semiconductor chips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a state visit to Washington in April, Yoon said Seoul would further strengthen economic alignment with the US under its Chips and Science Act and Inflation Reduction Act. South Korea and Japan are also members of the US-led Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All three initiatives aim to build supply chain resilience by reducing sourcing from China and contain its rising influence.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China, not self-sufficiency, is US target in chips initiative: Raimondo&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yang Bojiang, director of the Institute of Japanese Studies at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, also said the China-South Korea relationship was “more fragile than before” as Beijing overtakes South Korea as world leader in many industries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Addressing the same WPF panel as Cho, Yang said: “How to … strive to reconstruct structurally complementary relationships and find new bright spots for cooperation is … a fundamental yet extremely important issue.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korean companies operating in China saw sales shrink by about 13 per cent from 2016 to 2022 – but the figure rose to about 40 per cent if batteries and semiconductors were excluded, data from Korean business research firm CEO Score earlier this month showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2021, China ended Korea&#39;s 17-year reign as the world&#39;s largest display manufacturer. After overtaking it as the world&#39;s largest shipbuilder in 2010, China now has also begun to chase Korean players in high-added-value vessels like liquefied natural gas (LNG) carriers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, Seoul announced a 66 trillion won (US$51.7 billion) investment plan to recapture the No 1 spot in the global display market by 2027.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, in a wide range of key sectors apart from shipmaking and displays – such as petrochemicals, home appliances and memory chips – Korean exports are likely to face stiff competition from China in the second half of 2023, the Korea International Trade Association (KITA) said, citing Chinese technological advances, policy support and pricing edge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also, with growing demand for electric vehicles, Korean dependence on imports from China for rechargeable batteries and related raw materials will continue to increase, which is “structurally constraining” the trade balance with Beijing, the business group warned in a report late last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[It is] imperative to diversify the supply chain as soon as possible”, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Samsung pulled out of China&#39;s mobile phone market in 2019 and moved production to Vietnam, amid fierce competition with local rivals and rising labour costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Korean car brands, led by Hyundai and Kia, saw their market share in China shrink from nearly 10 per cent a decade ago to a mere 1.4 per cent in May, according to the China Association of Automobile Manufacturers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moon Chung-in, a professor of political science at Yonsei University in Seoul, said it was “very natural” for South Korean firms to reshore to other countries – given changes in competitive advantage and the need to reduce “excessive dependence” on the Chinese market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, he said South Korea was faced with a “dilemma” in trade with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s OK for us to reduce dependence on China and diversify, but the result of diversification should increase South Korea&#39;s trade volume, expert volume and trade surplus,” said Moon, a special adviser to former South Korean president Moon Jae-in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But the reverse is taking place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The China market is so critical to the South Korean economy. Having such a big market just next to our border could be a curse but also it is a blessing … if we take advantage of that geographic proximity in every possible way,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even though South Korea leaned towards the US on the economic and supply chain fronts, “there are always market constraints”, Moon said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, Seoul was reported to have asked Washington to review a proposal under its Chips Act that could significantly limit expansion plans for South Korean semiconductor makers in China, calling it “an unreasonable burden” on investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“South Korea cannot easily get away from the China market, even if it emphasises security and political reasons,” Moon said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Seong Hyeon Choi&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:20:21 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can the shadow of the Lamma IV disaster at last be lifted? The Post looks at the implications of a High Court ruling in favour of an inquest 11 years after the ferry sinking claimed 39 lives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3229047/can-shadow-lamma-iv-disaster-last-be-lifted-post-looks-implications-high-court-ruling-favour-inquest?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/26/51e4050f-2a39-4b5b-8608-a96fb12c77a7_3f20ba60.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;An order by Hong Kong&#39;s High Court on Wednesday to open a coroner&#39;s inquest into one of the city&#39;s worst maritime disasters is a breakthrough in an 11-year battle for justice by families of its victims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the plaintiffs, Alice Leung Suk-ling, who lost her brother in the tragedy, said outside the High Court that the ruling made her “very emotional”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is the only time I can smile in front of the camera after so many years,” she said. “I was very emotional inside the courtroom, this is the result of everyone&#39;s hard work over the past 10 years.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Here the Post explains why the shadow of the 2012 disaster still lingers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The accident happened on China&#39;s National Day in 2012, when the Lamma IV, with 124 passengers on board, was struck on the port side by the Hong Kong and Kowloon Ferry vessel Sea Smooth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The damaged Sea Smooth continued on to Yung Shue Wan, but the Lamma IV sank in minutes, partly because of design flaws.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The collision led to the deaths of 39 people, including eight children, and another 92 were injured on both ships.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the city&#39;s worst maritime disaster since 1971, when a ferry sank during a typhoon, killing 88 people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Owned by city power company HK Electric, the Lamma IV was taking the firm&#39;s staff and their families to see the National Day fireworks display in Central.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong court orders coroner&#39;s inquest into 2012 Lamma ferry crash&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;An independent Commission of Inquiry led by Mr Justice Michael Lunn released its report in April 2013. It found the absence of a watertight bulkhead door on the Lamma IV caused the ferry to sink faster.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report said other contributing factors were a failure to comply with life jacket regulations, which resulted in a lack of child-sized life jackets, and unsecured upper deck seating.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Marine Department was criticised for “serious systemic failings” and “a litany of errors committed at almost every stage by many different people”, including not enforcing the law, as well as a failure to document its decisions and a lack of proper inspections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A media report in December 2021 quoted court papers as saying that police had suggested in 2015 that an inquest be held.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 17 of the 22 Marine Department officers who gave statements did not testify before the commission.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two vessels&#39; captains, a ship inspector and a Marine Department assistant director were sentenced to prison terms ranging from 4½ months to eight years on a variety of charges related to the tragedy, including manslaughter, endangering the safety of others at sea, misconduct in public office and perjury.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Transport and Housing Bureau, a former government agency, found after an internal investigation in 2014 that 17 unidentified Marine Department officials responsible for safety were found guilty of misconduct and linked the tragedy to “suspected criminality”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the Department of Justice ruled there was insufficient evidence to charge them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government has since resisted the idea of releasing the report in full on the grounds it would risk prejudicing criminal proceedings and privacy concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We feel there is more truth that could be disclosed if there is an inquest,” Chiu Bing-chuen, who lost his sister, Chiu Siu-king in the disaster, said. “The details of the incident made known so far are not enough.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong court rejects coroner&#39;s inquest bid into 2012 Lamma ferry disaster&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Families of the victims and survivors argued that the Transport and Housing Bureau investigation had more information on the cause of the sinking than was made public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The executive summary of the report said the disaster was linked to “suspected criminality” and 17 unnamed officials were accused of misconduct.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the report was only partly disclosed to the families under a confidentiality agreement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relatives have since demanded that the report be released in full and that an inquest be held, but the Coroner&#39;s Court in 2020 said it would not investigate the tragedy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Campaigners&#39; efforts were renewed in 2021 after a media report revealed that police in 2015 suggested an inquest should be held. But authorities said they would not pursue the matter further.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest attempt was sparked by a 2022 application for an inquest to the Coroner&#39;s Court, which was originally rejected as not in the public interest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision by the court on Wednesday means that the quest for the truth may finally come to an end.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung told reporters after the High Court ruling that she believed in 2012 she would know the truth about the collision and the death of her brother within two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is regrettable that this was not the case, so I could only keep asking questions, search and find the answers,” she explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A statement by campaigners said the Coroner&#39;s Court was “only the beginning” and that there was a long way to go.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They said, apart from uncovering more information on the circumstances of the sinking, the most important result of the inquest would be recommendations on how to prevent similar disasters happening again.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have never understood why the Lamma IV sank so quickly, why the Sea Smooth was able to so easily strike through the Lamma IV, what is the real cause of the disaster, and what is the responsibility of those involved ?” the statement said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Transport and Logistics Bureau and HK Electric said they would give their full cooperation to the inquest.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:20:21 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Weaker yen, Osaka casino bet spark Singapore property investors’ rush to Japan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3229074/weaker-yen-osaka-casino-bet-spark-singapore-property-investors-rush-japan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 11:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/27/ba223c29-26ea-4792-95ce-8fab63d80e7c_0145a355.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Singapore investors are snapping up Japanese real estate, lured by a weaker yen and the prospect of tourism-driven growth in the second-largest metropolitan area Osaka.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;International property agent FM Investment said it&#39;s seen a fivefold increase in inquiries since Japan opened its borders in October, with Singapore making up about 70 per cent of 800 requests between April and June alone, followed by Hong Kong. Second-quarter sales are double the volume of the whole of last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The yen has fallen about 8 per cent against the Singapore and Hong Kong dollar this year, increasing the purchasing power of property investors seeking bargains outside two of the most-expensive markets in the Asia-Pacific region. Agents say buyers are particularly attracted to Osaka, where the next World Expo will be hosted in 2025 and a multibillion casino resort is expected to open in 2029.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The coming integrated resort is a real game changer,” said Jason Lam, co-founder and managing director of Japan Hana Real Estate, which has offices in Hong Kong, Tokyo and Osaka. He said sales have doubled since Japan reopened to tourists last October and inquiries from Singapore have tripled.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan&#39;s Osaka World Expo plagued with cost overruns, delays as clock ticks down&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The World Expo, an international event held every five years, and the casino resort are expected to boost tourism and are fuelling demand for residential units and tourist accommodation, Lam added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MGM Resorts International is partnering with Japanese financial services firm Orix Corp. on the project, which will feature hotels, entertainment and conference centres and compete with Asian neighbours such as Macau, South Korea and Singapore for customers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Osaka city authorities estimate it could attract 20 million visitors a year, helping Japan hit a long-term target of attracting 60 million annual foreign tourists by 2030, Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Angela Hanlee said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wendell Wong, who owns a Singapore-based fine wine business, bought a 14-storey bed and breakfast hotel at an “attractive price” in Shinsaibashi, a major shopping area in Osaka, in May. He said he plans to lease the building to another bed and breakfast operator at a rental yield of 10 per cent, compared with the 6 per cent he&#39;s getting under a contract drawn up during the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Tokyo property prices have been overrated and much more costly than Osaka” and operating bed and breakfast accommodation is less restrictive in the smaller city, added Wong. He said he plans to build on land he owns in Namba, a commercial and entertainment district in southern Osaka.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Based on stabilised trading for a managed asset in a prime location, hotel yields in Osaka average 4 per cent-4.5 per cent, compared with 3.5 per cent-4 per cent in Tokyo, and 4 per cent-5 per cent in New York, Hong Kong and London, according to Jones Lang LaSalle Inc.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan approves Osaka as site of country&#39;s first casino&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Aside from tourist accommodation, foreign investors are also buying residential property in Osaka, which has a high occupancy rate and stable rental income, said Koji Naito, a research director for Japan capital markets at Jones Lang LaSalle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inquiries about rental housing in Osaka from overseas buyers in the first half of this year are 3.5 times higher than the same period last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Foreign investors poured 268.7 billion yen (US$1.9 billion) into Japanese real estate in the first quarter of the year, more than double the same period in 2022, according to a Jones Lang LaSalle report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Osaka made up 18 per cent of total investment, including foreign and local, in the first quarter, up from 13 per cent a year earlier. The largest investment remained in Tokyo&#39;s central five wards at 36 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mark Phooi, a Singaporean entrepreneur in the design industry, recently bought two US$2.5 million buildings in Osaka as he looks for passive income from rental leasing. On top of that, he predicts more return on his investment if the yen strengthens by the time he plans to sell the properties in three to four years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it&#39;s not just about the returns, he said. “I also enjoy the culture and life in Japan,” said Phooi.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 11:20:21 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>