<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China’s tough stance in South China Sea ‘may be sign of its unhappiness over closer Philippine ties with US’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3230774/chinas-tough-stance-south-china-sea-may-be-sign-its-unhappiness-over-closer-philippine-ties-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/00e00b02-382a-44e0-9fcc-70d04ff8a625_06de0354.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国正试图表达对菲律宾的不满以及加强与美国的联盟据观察人士称，中国对南海有争议的浅滩采取了更强硬的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国海岸警卫队使用高压水枪破坏向菲律宾军队运送物资的任务后，敌对声索国之间的紧张关系正在加剧驻扎在一艘故意在仁爱礁搁浅的二战军舰上，以宣示马尼拉的主权主张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国也声称对南沙群岛的珊瑚礁拥有主权，自上周末的对峙以来，中国海岸警卫队已发表多项声明指责菲律宾“一再无视中方警告，试图运送建筑材料用于修复和加固”该船。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，菲律宾谴责菲律宾所谓的“危险举动”中方和小费迪南德·马科斯总统否认了中国关于菲律宾已承诺移除 BRP Sierra Madre 号船只的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾之前的补给任务也曾导致过对抗，包括 2 月份发生的一起事件：马尼拉指责中国海岸警卫队将军用级激光指向其一艘船只。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时北京否认了这一指控，中国外交部呼吁双方就海上争端进行沟通。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;随着中国紧张局势升级，菲律宾将向礁石派遣更多物资和船只&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;东南亚-尤索夫伊萨研究所智库高级研究员伊恩·斯托里 (Ian Storey) 表示，北京在最新事件可能反映出中国对马科斯领导下的马尼拉和华盛顿加强关系的愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国加大了在南海的赌注，以表达对马科斯政府在南海问题上采取更强硬立场的不满。” ” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当马尼拉四月份允许华盛顿进入另外四个军事基地时，北京感到不安。这些基地包括一个靠近中国位于南沙群岛美济礁和永暑礁的人工岛的基地，以及两个距离台湾约 500 公里（310 英里）的基地，台湾现在是一个主要的潜在爆发点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一项努力中为了重振与美国的联盟，菲律宾表示将恢复2016年被前总统罗德里戈·杜特尔特暂停的与美国在南海的联合巡逻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;副研究员丁铎中国南部海南省南海研究院的研究员表示：“美菲同盟的加强确实可能会产生一定的影响，特别是当菲律宾越来越愿意与美国战略结盟时，美国实际上已经&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但出发点更多还是出于中国维护领土主权的需要，中国试图在领土争端问题上划定底线。”&lt;/p>;&lt;据信，这是为了对抗美国的影响力，中国还提出与菲律宾举行联合军演，但菲律宾国家安全委员会助理总干事乔纳森·马拉亚表示，这种做法没有法律依据。此类演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日事件曝光后不久，北京表示，美国试图“鼓励和支持菲律宾修复和加固”BRP Sierra Madre。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;菲律宾谴责中国在其船只上“危险”使用水炮&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国外交部表示，美国还试图通过强调其与菲律宾的共同防御条约来威胁中国，该条约将迫使华盛顿来到马尼拉援助号是其在国际公认的菲律宾水域遭受攻击的船只之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然预计北京和马尼拉可能会试图阻止对抗进一步升级，但观察人士表示，最近的对抗将蒙上阴影周三，菲律宾军方表示，已准备好“在未来几年内执行另一次补给任务”。两周”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“（行为准则谈判）气氛并不理想，菲律宾可能会采取更强硬的立场或在谈判中提高讨价还价，”丁说。&lt;/p>;&lt;斯托里表示，最近发生的事件“只是凸显了南海问题[行为准则]的必要性”。然而，由于对协议的地理范围以及是否应具有法律约束力存在分歧，最终文件（有助于解决争端）可能仍需要数年时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不幸的是，最终协议不太可能达成今年甚至明年就达到了，”斯托里补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese short video giant Kuaishou pledges massive subsidies to fight Douyin, Meituan in local services race]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230829/chinese-short-video-giant-kuaishou-pledges-massive-subsidies-fight-douyin-meituan-local-services?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/b35a750d-9ecd-454c-80f4-e9ab8e63ef09_f50ca4b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国第二大短视频应用运营商快手科技正在加倍努力在中国经济复苏不平衡的情况下，该公司正在与其他科技巨头争夺一个难得的增长市场的份额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家总部位于北京的公司表示，它将向本地服务提供数千万人民币的补贴帮助有影响力的人提高平台上团购交易的销售额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划于周四在上海举行的一次企业活动上宣布，是快手飞鸟项目的一部分，该项目旨在提高当地产品的销售额&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他支持包括佣金激励、在线流量导流、培训课程以及升级的在线工具以帮助管理销售。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“我们希望通过一系列的投资，让网红更容易运营，并激励更多的短视频创作者加入成为网红。”快手本地服务业务高管石春晓表示。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;在中国，本地服务指的是利用在线平台向互联网用户提供线下消费服务，例如餐厅和酒店预订。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;快手在该领域的投资不断增加，这使得该公司对一些该行业最大的参与者，包括点播服务巨头美团、阿里巴巴集团支持的饿了么以及字节跳动旗下的短视频应用抖音。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抖音的本地服务业务于 2018 年推出据中国媒体《LatePost》最近报道，今年上半年，其平台上销售的商品价值超过 1000 亿元人民币（139 亿美元），几乎是美团同期销售额的一半。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;《南华早报》母公司阿里巴巴的本地服务收入同比飙升 30% 至 19 亿美元，部分原因是其外卖服务饿了么订单量强劲增长根据该公司最新的财报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;史在 2023 年前 6 个月的公司活动中表示，快手本地服务的交易用户数和商品总价值在 2023 年前六个月飙升了 498% 和 848%。星期四，没有详细说明具体数字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着腾讯的微信视频频道和上海的生活方式社交媒体应用程序小红书最近也进军该领域，本已竞争激烈的本地服务市场将变得更加拥挤。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师表示，由于中国科技公司的一些主要业务已经陷入停滞状态，本地服务为中国科技公司提供了新的增长来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市场咨询公司Dolphin创始人兼首席分析师李成东表示，快手和抖音的商业业务都已触及天花板，促使它们进军本地服务的增长市场，特别是在中国取消Covid-19限制之后。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;艾媒咨询发布的报告显示，2025年中国按需本地服务市场规模预计将达到2.5万亿元。报告称，随着越来越多的公司进入市场，未来本地服务行业将成为多平台竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;快手和抖音等短视频应用可能会挑战美团在该领域的主导地位，因为它们李说，“美团的优势在于一四线城市，而不是小县城，因为那里的外卖需求几乎不存在。” “但快手和抖音即使在那些县也很受欢迎。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hollywood blockbuster Barbie opens in Japan after atomic bomb controversy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3230823/hollywood-blockbuster-barbie-opens-japan-after-atomic-bomb-controversy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 18:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/0e346c5a-3142-4b1e-9dcd-e86bf4c26e01_7f824844.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;好莱坞大片《芭比娃娃》于周五在日本上映，其中“Barbenheimer”模因将以原子弹为主题的娃娃电影引起了轰动，发行商华纳兄弟在上映前道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由玛格特·罗比主演的《芭比娃娃》门票在日本卖得很快，粉丝们蜂拥而至。上映时间恰逢国定假日，标志着日本延长暑假周的第一天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“芭比娃娃的粉色世界绝对美丽”，29 岁的铃木美咲 (Misaki Suzuki) 说道美甲沙龙工作人员在东京一家电影院看完这部电影后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 7 月 21 日首映以来，《芭比娃娃》的全球票房已突破 10 亿美元，使编剧兼导演格蕾塔·葛韦格成为第一位超越这一基准的女性电影制片人作为独奏导演。与奥本海默的合作进一步推动了这部奇幻喜剧的成功，这部传记片记录了第二次世界大战期间原子弹的制造过程，该片于同一周末上映。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但“巴本海默”的组合引发了轰动。日本本月早些时候举行了纪念 78 年前美国广岛和长崎原子弹爆炸的活动，这在日本引起了强烈反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国特使的芭比娃娃帖子在日本火上浇油，人们对表情包的愤怒日益高涨&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;在 X 平台（以前称为 Twitter）上现已删除的帖子中，华纳兄弟的芭比娃娃营销帐户锁定了粉丝制作的表情包，其中描绘了罗比与奥本海默演员希里安·墨菲以及核爆炸的图像。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;8 月 1 日，Change.org 发起请愿书，要求华纳兄弟和奥本海默背后的工作室环球影业停止在社交媒体上使用 #Barbenheimer 标签。迄今为止，它已经收集了大约 22,600 个签名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时，#NoBarbenheimer 标签在日本流行，促使华纳的日本部门罕见地公开批评其美国母公司，并随后道歉周。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在日语版本中为芭比娃娃配音的高畑光希 (Mitsuki Takahata) 在 8 月 2 日的 Instagram 帖子中表示，她在得知这些表情包后感到沮丧。她发帖称：“这起事件真的非常令人失望。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，这部将美泰标志性玩偶带入现实生活的电影的日本粉丝表示，争议并没有阻止他们去电影院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“这很残酷”，24 岁的大学生 Rie Takeda 在评论粉丝制作的#Barbenheimer memes 时说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但这部电影光芒四射，超出了我的想象。她说：“观看这部电影很有趣”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《奥本海默》尚未公布在日本的上映日期，该片因在很大程度上忽视了 1945 年原子弹摧毁日本两个主要城市、导致超过 20 万人死亡而受到批评。 .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Subway sandwich chain in India takes away free cheese slice, offers sauce as inflation bites]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3230813/subway-sandwich-chain-india-takes-away-free-cheese-slice-offers-sauce-inflation-bites?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 17:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/928fa12c-4941-4a4f-a690-3d65bcb2e4c1_caf12c95.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度的 Subway 三明治将不再提供免费奶酪片的选项分析人士认为，菜单的修改更多的是为了削减成本，而不仅仅是口味问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国连锁店赛百味是印度最大的餐厅特许经营商之一，拥有约 800 家门店。现在，他们对大多数三明治中的奶酪片额外收取 30 卢比（0.40 美元）费用，但改为提供免费的“奶酪”酱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括乳制品在内的原料价格上涨，导致全球快餐业陷入困境。印度的连锁店面临着削减成本同时保持顾客满意的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达美乐最便宜的披萨在印度的促销价仅为 60 美分，其特许经营商已公开表达了对印度披萨价格上涨 40% 的担忧。 3 月份结束的财政年度中奶酪的价格上涨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近几周，印度的许多赛百味和麦当劳门店也从菜单中删除了西红柿，理由是西红柿价格飙升 450% 左右，创历史新高后存在质量问题。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度不得不从尼泊尔进口西红柿来缓解短缺问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度菜世界排名第五，让印度人的口味不好&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; Everstone Group 的 Culinary Brands 表示，现在 Subway India 免费提供的奶酪酱“仅出于质量原因而开发”。Everstone Group 的 Culinary Brands 管理着所有 800 家门店的供应链，并且是大约 200 家门店的主要特许经营商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;质变显然并不符合所有人的口味。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赛百味“用液体奶酪混合物取代了奶酪片……你只是失去了一位忠实的顾客”，一位不为所动的顾客苏米特·阿罗拉 (Sumit Arora) 在社交媒体 X 上写道。媒体平台，以前称为 Twitter。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新德里的一家 Subway 商店经理表示，新的奶酪酱每公斤售价 400 卢比（5 美元）。市场价格显示，奶酪片的价格通常约为每公斤 700 卢比（8.50 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Culinary Brands 营销主管 Mayur Hola 表示，“可以以较低的成本添加奶酪片”。 “我们不会评论原料成本……这只是为了让我们的潜艇变得更好而进行的升级。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及赛百味的举动时，印度 Elara Capital 的非必需消费品分析师卡兰·陶拉尼 (Karan Taurani) 表示，奶酪的升级粮食和蔬菜价格上涨促使餐馆提出“创新”策略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是向顾客施加通胀压力的一种方式，而不是全面涨价，”他说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在印度，一个 Subway 三明治的售价约为 200-300 卢比（2.40 美元至 3.60 美元），如果顾客添加曾经免费的奶酪片，现在的价格将上涨 15%。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;赛百味发言人没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度央行本周将本财年的通胀预期上调至 5.4%，理由是食品价格带来的压力.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesia cheers Dutch return of artefacts, but fears of heists, preservation persist amid lax museum security]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/lifestyle-culture/article/3230767/indonesia-cheers-dutch-return-artefacts-fears-heists-preservation-persist-amid-lax-museum-security?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 17:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/9fe4ad10-c457-47aa-b026-f5716a6ff21f_e7700628.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;从印度尼西亚掠夺的雕像、宝石和珠宝在前殖民统治者手中保存了一个多世纪荷兰已抵达雅加达，并正在该市的国家博物馆进行编目，专家们对这个东南亚国家如何处理大量文物表示担忧，因为该国博物馆基础设施有限且有盗窃历史。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;殖民时代的战利品包括龙目岛宝藏、一批精美的 335 件宝石和珠宝、132 件巴厘岛 Pita Maha 藏品，以及以前安装在东爪哇玛琅印度教 Singasari 寺庙中的四尊火山石雕像。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些文物根据印度尼西亚独立 78 周年纪念日达成的协议归还，将保存在雅加达国家博物馆，尽管它们的原产地正在游说归还。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有不同等级的文物荷兰皇家东南亚和加勒比研究所 (KITLV) 和 NIOD 战争、大屠杀和种族灭绝研究所的印度尼西亚研究员阿德里安·佩尔卡萨 (Adrian Perkasa) 表示： /p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚的博物馆，尤其是各省的博物馆，没有足够的能力来处理来自荷兰的文物，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在印度尼西亚的 430 家博物馆中，只有 30% 的博物馆被评为“A” ”并配备了安全系统和设施来容纳国际标准的展品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我怀疑国家博物馆是否有足够的空间来容纳所有返回的藏品，所以这一刻必须成为升级我们博物馆基础设施的催化剂在这些地区，”佩尔卡萨说。 “这些文物可以成为团结和民族治愈的推动者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，博物馆基础设施的差异可能会导致归还的藏品只有首都的人才能欣赏到，至少对于当地人来说是这样。可预见的未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么印度尼西亚人说荷兰承认 1945 年独立是“巨大的侮辱”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;从 1800 年起，印度尼西亚在近 150 年的时间里一直是荷兰直辖殖民地，并被称为荷兰东部独立国家。它因其丰富的自然资源而被殖民统治者剥削，并成为全球香料贸易的枢纽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;荷兰人长期以来一直认为印度尼西亚是在通过武装斗争推翻殖民政府后于 1949 年赢得独立的，而不是四年前的 8 月 17 日，雅加达庆祝活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西方国家最近面临着归还殖民统治战利品的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印尼传家宝的归还也正如预期的那样进行。到 2030 年，印度尼西亚将成为世界第四大和第七大经济体，其庞大的消费者市场将远远超过荷兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们庆祝独立之际，这对印度尼西亚来说是一个特殊的福音，”Hilmar Farid 说道，文化、教育和研究部总干事于去年 7 月与荷兰政府签署了文物归还协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Farid 表示，他的部门完全有意允许这些地区归还文物。在雅加达国家博物馆收到所有物品并对其进行编目后，这些物品最初是从回收中受益的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“向地区博物馆，特别是这些物品的来源地，提供贷款是非常有可能的，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但专家们质疑地区博物馆是否准备好处理这些珍贵物品，并确保它们抵达后的安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“以 Singasari 为例一个多世纪前，雕像被运往荷兰。”佩尔卡萨说。 “玛琅的人们希望在寺庙里见到他们。但是，寺庙在接收雕像的基础设施方面是否处于有利位置，或者将它们放置在原地是否会危及雕像？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚也有悠久的博物馆盗窃历史。自 1961 年以来，印度尼西亚已记录了 23 起博物馆失窃事件，其中包括 1961 年和 1979 年国家博物馆发生的两起盗窃事件，导致 11 件历史钻石、古钱币和中国陶器丢失。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度尼西亚的“科科西奇的文化大使旨在保护中国遗产&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2007年，梭罗拉迪亚普斯塔卡博物馆的高层工作人员密谋通过用赝品交换来窃取六尊古代雕像，并将原件卖给一位大亨，这位大亨后来声称他不知道自己为不义之财付了钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后一次已知的博物馆抢劫案发生在 2022 年，发生在南苏拉威西岛拉帕瓦沃伊博物馆，博物馆 95% 的藏品都丢失了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“作为一名艺术爱好者，我去过国内外的博物馆，”PSI 党立法候选人玛莎·西亚吉安 (Marsha Siagian) 说道，她补充说，她的政党对遣返文物的未来深感担忧.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“恐怕我不得不说我们的安全标准还没有达到。我不愿意看到它们中的任何一个最终成为只有少数人喜欢的私人收藏的一部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;居住在阿姆斯特丹的印度尼西亚历史学家乔斯·维比索诺 (Joss Wibisono) 表示，荷兰媒体的一些部分也提出了质疑”关于将不可替代的文物归还印度尼西亚的明智之举。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“总体情绪良好，但一些人不相信印度尼西亚能够妥善保管它们，”他说，并补充说荷兰媒体报道Klungkung 的世袭国王声称他对祖先的短剑（一把精心制作的礼仪匕首）即将回归一无所知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这暗示着雅加达的精英未能与起源的核心政党进行协调Wibisono 补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚政府誓言，在这些来之不易的国家传家宝归还后，将尽最大努力保护和保存它们，以便子孙后代能够从中受益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“我们已经与这些物品之前所在的荷兰博物馆启动了合作计划，以增强我们在保护这些物品方面的专业知识，”法里德说。 “这始终是计划的一部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange “ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Former Hong Kong policeman facing HK$450,000 claim over occupying government flat for 2½ years after retirement]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/article/3230815/former-hong-kong-policeman-facing-hk450000-claim-over-occupying-government-flat-2-1/2-years-after?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 17:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/6d6f1661-8289-4470-82f9-d4723cc3e853_52d279ef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港政府已向一名前任官员提出 450,000 港元（57,560 美元）的索赔一名警察涉嫌在退休后 2.5 年内非法占用警官住宅区的一套公寓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;律政司指控庞展清尽管有最后期限，却拒绝移交该处所的管有权。根据《邮报》周五看到的一份区域法院令状，庞先生及其家人于 2001 年 6 月搬进观塘顺利纪律部队宿舍，该文件显示，他的搬出时间被推迟了 13 个月。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;前香港警官考虑对贪污、不当行为案件认罪&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;前警官只需支付相当于其工资7.5%的月租，并根据公务员协议免除管理费、差饷和停车场租金等附加费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pong 在 2017 年 10 月开始退休前休假时最初不得不离开公寓，但搬迁被推迟，等待他根据政府配额计划申请公营房屋，该计划优先考虑初级公务员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;房屋署于2018年6月驳回他的申请后，按照协议要求他腾出该处所两个月内。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;性侵孕妇的香港警官称自己将面临牢狱之灾&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警务处处长给予庞再三个月的宽限期，直至 2018 年 11 月，以便他找到令状称，但该官员“未能和/或拒绝将空置的房产交给专员”，也未能按市场价格支付租金。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;一家人于2021年5月搬出，庞只能支付港币91,494元，以支付总价值港币541,325元的未付租金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;庞的家人现居住在西贡的一间村屋，律政司表示，该公司未能缴付余款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府物业管理人员估计，自2018年9月起，观塘警察宿舍的公开市场租金每月介乎15,900港元至16,400港元之间到 2022 年同月。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Emotional garbage bins’: Chinese parents who use ‘guilt-inflicting’ mental tricks to induce hard study urged to stop]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3230521/emotional-garbage-bins-chinese-parents-who-use-guilt-inflicting-mental-tricks-induce-hard-study?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/0d2bbf99-71fb-450f-b520-c625431cb84f_976b3898.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国父母“鼓励”孩子努力学习或成为一个新趋势专家表示，通过让孩子感到内疚来服从可能会导致青少年出现长期的心理问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所谓的“内疚教育”及其可能造成的损害，让大陆社交媒体上的一些观察人士认为，呼吁家长不要把孩子当作“情感垃圾桶”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月，一位来自中国东部浙江省的母亲在网上发布了一段视频，视频中，家里的父亲光着膀子坐着，手里拿着香烟据自媒体平台报道，母亲说，父亲告诉孩子：“爸爸两天只睡了四个小时，每天只吃一次。当我开车去工厂的时候，我连休息的空调都不用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;父亲接着一一列举了他日常生活中遇到的问题和困难以及挣扎的过程。他必须供养她，试图让女儿感到内疚，从而更加努力地学习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频中，明显心疼的女孩坐在桌旁听父亲说话。&lt;/p>;&lt;她的母亲谈到视频时说：“他不善于表达自己，很少和孩子说话。他不介意受苦，但他不想让孩子和他一样受苦。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然这位父亲的初衷可能值得称赞，但他的行为却引发了网上的愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;一位网友说：“内疚教育是自卑感从童年开始的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位网友补充道：“你的痛苦不是你女儿造成的，她的痛苦源于你。 .”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“控制你自己。把烟从嘴里拿出来。穿上衬衫，以尊重和平等的态度与您的孩子沟通。不要把孩子当作情感垃圾桶。”第三位人士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国传统文化强调孝顺的美德。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而不是把孩子视为独立的个体，并认为对他们的无私奉献是自然的，期望以服从和努力工作的形式得到回报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种观点常常涉及通过情绪操纵让孩子感到内疚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种文化观点甚至延伸到了媒体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，在中国电视节目《别小看我》中，一个四岁的女儿在做作业时遇到困难，遭到她的责骂。母亲坚持要求她必须在睡觉前记住它。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最终，凌晨 1 点，这位歇斯底里的母亲用掌掴自己的方式警告女儿，每次女儿没能记住，她就会继续这样做。满足她的期望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然电视案例可能很极端，但其他形式的内疚感则更为微妙，可能包括情感勒索，例如将父母之间的关系问题归咎于孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;香港大学社会工作及社会行政学系临床心理学家、副教授黄伟正博士表示，很难将此类行为定义为虐待儿童或家庭暴力。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“言语虐待的定义很难定义，而且在不同的文化中也有所不同，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong 说，西方文化倾向于使用赞扬作为激励因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“传统的儒家教育方式不是赞扬你的孩子，这与西方的教育方式不同。有时我们会激起孩子的内疚感，希望他们能更加努力，在学业上取得更好的成绩。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这意味着他们可以拥有更好的社会流动性、地位和权力。长期以来都是这种情况，尤其是在韩国、日本和中国等具有儒家传统的国家。”黄补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国父母尝试过西方通过表扬孩子来激励孩子的方法，但失败了黄说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这导致了引发负罪感的教育的复兴，黄说，这会产生后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据黄说，一个潜在的长期结果学术上的说法是，孩子在成长过程中接触到内疚感的方式长大后，就无法与年迈的父母相处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这也很可能让人焦虑，极度焦虑，让他们担心自己会做错事。”错误使他们想成为一个完美的孩子。他们不想冒险，也不知道如何冒险，并且永远保持谦虚，永远低着头。”Wong 补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US wants China’s chip industry 5 generations behind cutting edge, head of equipment maker AMEC says at Wuxi conference]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230803/us-wants-chinas-chip-industry-5-generations-behind-cutting-edge-head-equipment-maker-amec-says-wuxi?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/cfbaa8f2-0dda-471a-b293-e8b7167cde44_689dae26.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国领先的半导体设备制造商之一的负责人认为华盛顿不断升级的出口和投资限制背叛了美国的真正目的：让中国的芯片制造技术落后至少五代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国中微微加工设备公司（AMEC）董事长兼首席执行官尹志耀发表评论周四在中国东部靠近上海的城市无锡举行的中国半导体设备年会。他提到美国去年 10 月实施的出口限制，本周拜登政府公布了限制半导体等敏感领域对中国投资的计划，出口限制进一步升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“10 月的规定确实暴露了美国的真实意图是要将中国的芯片制造固定在28纳米上，比3纳米到14纳米的全球领先优势至少落后5代。”尹在会议上发表讲话时说道。 “我们不能接受[这一点]，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尹称，美国针对所有中国代工厂更新的技术出口管制是自美国开始实施相关制裁以来最“致命”的禁令尹称，最新的行政命令是针对美国对中国半导体、人工智能和量子计算行业的投资，这是华盛顿自此以来针对中国的“第16次举措”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; The rules imposed last October aim to cap China&#39;s logic chip-making capabilities at the 14-nm level, DRAM chips at 18-nm and 3D NAND memory at 128 layers. The US cited national security risks and the potential military applications of advanced chips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yin, a 20-year veteran of the US chip equipment industry including time at Applied Materials, said locally-procured semiconductor equipment in China&#39;s foundries accounted for just 15 per cent of the total. The other 85 per cent of machines come from the US, Netherlands and Japan, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That&#39;s why the US needed Japan and Netherlands on board to curb our development,” he told a room packed with semiconductor professionals and investors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese semiconductor equipment firms still lag global peers in both market share and technological sophistication, according to industry professionals attending the conference. China&#39;s tool makers have virtually no global presence in some segments such as lithography. Catching up in these areas is an uphill battle for Chinese firms in a worsening geopolitical environment that is squeezing out foreign money and technological cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Jinxiang, deputy secretary general of China Electronic Production Equipment Industry, said some China-made equipment fails to meet the efficiency needs of foundries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s a huge waste that a 1 billion yuan [US$138.7 million] ASML-made lithography machine has to wait for a domestically-made wafer coating and developing machine to catch up in speed,” Li said, referring to the Dutch chip equipment firm that has a virtual monopoly on the most advanced lithography machines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An ASML lithography machine is capable of processing 350 12-inch wafers per hour, Li explained, while China-made wafer coating and developing machines cannot match that output.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A wafer coating and developing machine is crucial in assisting the lithography process. It applies the light-sensitive photoresist material to the wafer, which is then put into lithography systems for exposure. The machine then takes the exposed wafer to develop the pattern.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Yin said he has confidence that China can develop a globally competitive equipment industry within years, as many US-trained Chinese experts have returned home. Using chip-making equipment to curb China&#39;s progress will yield no good results, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yin also called AMEC&#39;s brief inclusion in 2021 on a US defence department list of companies allegedly supporting the Chinese military “sheer nonsense”. It was the first time Yin publicly commented on the US sanctions against AMEC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the US “reluctantly” removed AMEC from the list after “four months of intense negations”.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese military scientists claim to have achieved a ‘huge breakthrough’ on laser weapon technology]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3230589/chinese-military-scientists-claim-have-achieved-huge-breakthrough-laser-weapon-technology?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 17:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/10/88b9c4c2-65b6-4064-970d-7863452fc822_5fd869c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese military scientists have announced a major breakthrough in laser weapon technology, claiming they have developed a new cooling system that allows high-energy lasers to operate “infinitely” without any build-up of waste heat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to scientists at the National University of Defence Technology, in Changsha, Hunan province, the new cooling system completely eliminates the harmful heat that is generated during the operation of high-energy lasers. The issue has been a major technical challenge for laser weapon development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the new technology, weapons can now generate laser beams for as long as they want, without any interruption or degradation in performance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is a huge breakthrough in improving the performance of high-energy laser systems,” said the team led by laser weapon scientist Yuan Shengfu in a paper published on August 4 in Acta Optica Sinica, a Chinese-language peer-reviewed journal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“High-quality beams can be produced not only in the first second, but also maintained indefinitely,” they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new cooling system uses advanced structures and optimised gas flow to remove heat from inside the laser weapon, while minimising turbulence and vibration and improving mirror cleanliness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has the potential to significantly change the face of battle by extending engagement times, increasing range and damage, and reducing logistics and costs, according to the researchers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since the invention of the first ruby laser in 1960, people have been enthusiastic about transitioning from kinetic energy to laser energy for the rapid projection of energy at the speed of light, dreaming of laser beams to become &#39;death rays&#39; that can instantly kill targets,” Yuan and his colleagues said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Unfortunately, 60 years have passed and while various types of lasers have been developed, the application of high-energy laser systems has not been successful.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the United States, some of the most famous projects throughout the years include the Navy Advanced Chemical Laser (NACL) that used deuterium fluoride as a laser source, the Middle Infrared Advanced Chemical Laser (MIRACL) that used advanced mid-infrared chemical lasers, the Tactical High Energy Laser (THEL), the Space-Based Laser (SBL) that used hydrogen fluoride as a laser source, and the Airborne Laser (ABL) that used chemical oxygen iodine lasers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These have all been demonstrated in test fields, with MIRACL having shot down supersonic missiles, THEL having shot down 48 flying targets and ABL having successfully intercepted liquid fuel missiles, according to Yuan&#39;s team.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the projects were all cancelled, with the reason given to the public being the large size and weight of the lasers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The true reason for the cancellation of these projects was that their destructive power did not meet expectations,” the scientists said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The maximum effective range of these weapons was only a few kilometres. Yuan&#39;s team said to improve the destructive power of a beam, “longer continuous operation times are needed”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inside the laser weapon, a high-energy beam is generated through a process called stimulated emission. This involves exciting atoms or molecules in a gain medium, such as a crystal or gas, to a higher energy state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When these excited atoms or molecules return to their ground state, they emit photons, which are then amplified through a process of optical feedback to create a high-energy laser beam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The beam control system is responsible for directing and controlling the laser beam, typically through the use of mirrors and lenses. This system must be highly precise and stable, as even small deviations or vibrations can cause the beam to miss its designated course.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But as the laser beam passes through the air, it heats up the gas in its path, causing it to expand and create a turbulent flow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This turbulence can cause the beam to scatter and distort, reducing its effectiveness and accuracy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additionally, the heated gas can cause the mirrors and lenses in the system to become contaminated, leading to a decline in performance and a shortened lifespan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In some cases, larger pollutant particles burning on the mirrors can even result in them being cracked or damaged, greatly reducing the practicability and reliability of the high-energy laser weapons, according to the researchers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuan&#39;s team has developed an internal beam path conditioner – a system that blows gas through the weapon to remove waste heat and improve gas cleanliness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is designed to be compact and efficient, with a focus on optimising gas flow and minimising size and weight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has several key components, including an air source, a heat exchanger, a gas flow control system and a gas injection/suction system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The air source provides a supply of clean, dry air to the system, which is then passed through the heat exchanger to cool it down to the desired temperature.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gas flow control system regulates the flow of gas, ensuring it is delivered at the correct temperature and dwell time to achieve quasi-static small aberrations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gas injection/suction system is responsible for injecting the gas into the internal beam path of the laser system and removing it after it has passed through.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuan&#39;s team had to pay careful attention to a number of technical and practical points when building and operating the internal beam path conditioner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the main challenges was ensuring the gas flow achieved the desired cooling and cleaning effects. This required careful design and testing of the gas flow control system, as well as the injection/suction system that delivers the gas to the internal beam path.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another challenge was making it compact and efficient enough to be practical for use in real-world applications. Innovative designs were needed such as advanced pneumatic structures, flow optimisation of each path, integration of the injector/suction with the beam section and simplified pipelines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cooling system can introduce new problems such as turbulence and vibration that can affect beam quality if not properly built, according to the researchers. For example, the blowing of gas through the internal beam path can create turbulence and vibration which can affect the stability and quality of the laser beam.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russian hypersonic missile scientists face treason accusations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yuan&#39;s team conducted extensive testing of the technology to ensure that it met the performance specifications required by the military. The device has already been used in a number of laser weapons under development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So far, many advanced designs and research progress on dynamic air blowing thermal management in China have not been reported. This is the first time that some of the designs and test results [have gone] to the public,” the scientists said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has been developing high-energy laser weapons to destroy or disable targets such as drones, missiles and aircraft. These weapons have the advantage of being able to engage targets at the speed of light, making them highly effective against fast-moving targets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They also have the potential to be more cost-effective than traditional missile-based systems as they do not require expensive munitions and can be recharged quickly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China also plans to use laser weapons against satellites such as SpaceX&#39;s Starlink, according to some military scientists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These weapons can disrupt enemy communications, navigation and surveillance capabilities, and could be used to gain a strategic advantage in space-based conflicts.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong medical student, 2 teenagers among sex workers found in police raid on brothel]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3230768/hong-kong-medical-student-2-teenagers-among-sex-workers-found-police-raid-brothel?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 16:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/11/0caa76a6-7f5c-4336-8c08-99d3b748f423_44c7bd71.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Hong Kong medical student and two 16-year-old girls were among six sex workers found by police during a raid on a brothel in a popular entertainment district, the Post learned on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officers also arrested a 20-year-old woman accused of operating a seven-room brothel on Tsim Sha Tsui&#39;s Kimberley Road during the police raid on Thursday evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A source familiar with the case said a preliminary investigation suggested the student, who is in her 20s, had worked as a part-time prostitute for several months to make extra money.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Detectives from the Kowloon West regional crime unit launched an investigation into the brothel after receiving a tip-off.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police arrest 4 women in crackdown on vice syndicate running 3 brothels&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to the source, the sex workers&#39; services were advertised on a Telegram chat group that also featured photos of them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Young girls and students are the gimmick this brothel used in the advertisement to attract customers,” he said. “Intelligence indicated that each client was charged between HK$1,500 and HK$2,000 [US$191 and US$255] for sex services and the operator took half of the money.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source said the investigation suggested the brothel had been running for several months and may have made hundreds of thousands of Hong Kong dollars per month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The clients were believed to have included bankers and insurance agents, as well as male flight attendants, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Undercover officers posing as clients were deployed to gather evidence before police raided the brothel at about 7pm on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;16 women in Hong Kong detained in crackdown on sex ring at Tsim Sha Tsui hotel&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Inside the premises, police found the six sex workers, aged 16 to 27, and arrested the brothel&#39;s alleged proprietor – the 20-year-old woman.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officers also seized more than HK$6,000 worth of suspected crime proceeds and condoms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another source said some of the sex workers knew each other, and had joined the trade after being referred by friends.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;None of the six women had been arrested.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was not illegal for those above the age of 15 to work as prostitutes, he explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source added that the two 16-year-olds were taken to a Kowloon City police station and one of them was later picked up by her parents.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police arrest 2 teen sisters from mainland in prostitution crackdown&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Police on Friday morning applied for a care and protection order in court for the authorities to get custody of the other 16-year-old girl, since her father was dead and her mother was in jail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The teenager was still at the police station as of the afternoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the force, officers are still tracking the ringleader of the prostitution ring behind the brothel, as well as other suspects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The suspect arrested during the raid was still being held for questioning as of Friday afternoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Hong Kong, maintaining a vice establishment is punishable by up to 10 years in jail under the Crimes Ordinance.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Growth returns to Huawei’s consumer business as smartphone sales rise again despite US sanctions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230769/growth-returns-huaweis-consumer-business-smartphone-sales-rise-again-despite-us-sanctions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 16:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/11/1e8d3c9e-f193-41de-b5e6-b10e565054bc_225fbc57.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Huawei Technologies&#39; consumer business returned to growth after substantial decline in its smartphone sales in the past two years, as the Chinese telecoms equipment giant defies the impact of US sanctions to revive its once-lucrative handset segment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company said its total revenue grew 3.1 per cent in the first half of 2023, reaching 310.9 billion yuan (US$43.1 billion) and higher than the 0.8 per cent revenue growth seen in the first quarter and the 0.9 per cent growth for the full year of 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sales from the consumer business group, which includes smartphones and electric cars under the Aito brand, rose 2.2 per cent to 103.5 billion yuan, the company reported on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huawei said its first-half performance was in line with forecast. While the Shenzhen-based company is privately held, it voluntarily discloses key financial data on a regular basis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The improved results followed Huawei&#39;s efforts to survive US sanctions by resuscitating its handset business and diversifying into new industries, including cloud computing and electric cars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Richard Yu Chengdong, chief executive of the company&#39;s consumer business group and its car unit, last week announced that Huawei&#39;s flagship smartphones are “making a comeback” as he unveiled the latest update of its own Harmony operating system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the second quarter, Huawei resurfaced as a top-five smartphone vendor in mainland China, according to data from research firm IDC, following the launch of high-end handsets including its P60 series and foldable Mate X3 model.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huawei shipped a total of 14.3 million smartphones in China in the first half of 2023, up nearly 40 per cent compared to the same period last year, IDC data showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before Huawei was banned by the US government in 2019 from buying software, chips and other technologies from American suppliers, the company had briefly surpassed Samsung Electronics to become the world&#39;s biggest smartphone vendor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huawei is expected to resume its release of 5G smartphones by the end of this year, as it gets a fresh supply of chips from local suppliers, according to a Reuters report last month that cited three unnamed research firms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Revenue from intelligent automotive solutions, another segment that Huawei has been banking on to diversify its business, reached 1 billion yuan in the first half of 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cloud computing and digital power generated 24.1 billion yuan and 24.2 billion yuan in sales, respectively, posting “strong growth” according to Meng Wanzhou, daughter of Huawei founder Ren Zhengfei, who took up the rotating chairwoman role for the first time in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company has also been stepping up efforts to serve enterprise clients hoping to upgrade their operations in traditional businesses. Last month, Huawei joined the heated artificial intelligence race with the third generation of its Pangu model that focuses on industrial uses in sectors like coal mining, finance and government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Huawei has been investing heavily in foundational technologies to harness trends in digitalisation, intelligence and decarbonisation, focusing on creating value for our customers and partners,” Meng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From January to June, revenue from Huawei&#39;s information and communications technology business – its key segment that includes 5G network gear – reached 167.2 billion yuan, the company said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 11 Aug 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>