<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Sequoia China goes solo under HongShan brand, a sign that the bromance between US funds and China tech start-ups is over]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3223548/sequoia-china-goes-solo-under-hongshan-brand-sign-bromance-between-us-funds-and-china-tech-start-ups?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/d7ae7e08-65e7-4648-94ec-d92b44eda3ea_f52d5356.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;红杉中国分拆，美中金融关系的典范业内人士表示，过去18年，中国脱离美国母公司是中国创投行业的分水岭，美国资本家与中国企业家分道扬镳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很少有机构发挥过如此重要的作用正如耶鲁大学毕业的尼尔·沉南鹏创立的红杉中国，旨在将美国资金与中国的科技初创企业联系起来，但北京和华盛顿之间日益激烈的争执使得红杉中国等中介机构难以在太平洋地区协调利益。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国分拆是红杉资本全球重组的一部分，红杉资本是总部位于加利福尼亚州门洛帕克的美国风险投资巨头。中国业务已更名为红杉，而红杉资本在印度和东南亚的业务将以 Peak XV Partners 的名义独立。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在地缘政治紧张局势加剧的情况下，红杉资本拆分为 3 家公司&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;尽管红杉资本在解释此举时并未提及地缘政治考虑，但将红杉中国作为一个独立实体的决定是世界上最大的两个经济体之间脱钩的新迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;风险合伙人 Levy Cao总部位于上海的投资公司 Capital O 表示，红杉中国分拆标志着结束的开始。 “中国风险投资界可能需要记住这一时刻，因为这表明（在中国的）美元基金准备告别过去的美好时光，在中国寻找新的定位和方向，”他说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;红杉中国成立于 2005 年，当时中国新兴的互联网行业急需风险投资。该公司迅速成为中国第一大风险投资公司，投资于中国顶级互联网公司，包括电子商务巨头阿里巴巴集团、顶级食品配送平台美团和世界领先的无人机制造商大疆，为投资者带来了可观的回报。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴拥有南华早报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一个著名的案例中，红杉中国是美团点评 2010 年 A 轮融资的唯一投资者，向创始人王提供了 2o 万美元Xing，并帮助该平台赢得了残酷的团购价格战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它的成功使红杉（红杉）在中国初创企业和美国投资者中获得了主要品牌认可，使 Shen 成为谈到美中交易时，“去”这个词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国，沉是亚洲协会（一家有影响力的非营利组织）的受托人，并被任命为耶鲁大学商学院主席2021 年管理委员会顾问。在中国，他是中国人民政治协商会议任命的风险投资行业唯一代表，在 2018 年至 2022 年期间担任中国政府最高政治咨询机构。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;然而，随着北京和华盛顿之间的竞争加剧，沉能够两全其美的优势变成了不利条件。拜登政府正在考虑限制美国对中国高科技领域的投资，从半导体到人工智能，而北京方面越来越怀疑美国资金进入敏感领域及其数字基础设施。例如，在微芯片领域，中国政府将某些项目的投资和研究视为国家安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多获得红杉中国投资的中国科技公司现在都在华盛顿的关注范围内。总部位于北京的 ByteDance 正在努力说服美国立法者，其 TikTok 短视频平台独立于中国共产党的影响，无人机制造商 DJI 去年因涉嫌与中国军方有联系而被列入美国制裁名单。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;北京将重点转移到数据和国家安全问题上，这对红杉中国来说也是一个挑战。中国打车巨头滴滴出行是红杉资本的另一笔高调投资并获得回报，滴滴出行在 2021 年以 44 亿美元在纽约公开上市后几天就受到了网络安全调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在公开场合红杉中国管理团队在致中国企业家的信中表示，集中的后台运营已经成为一种负担而不是优势，因此分拆成为必要。它没有详细说明在利润分享或资金来源方面会发生哪些变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;红杉资本以 100 万美元的资金吸引中国初创企业，ChatGPT 洞察&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该公司，在中国投资了近1000个项目，已经培养了本土团队。红杉中国网站上列出的 42 位董事总经理、合伙人和高级管理人员都是中国人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究公司 PitchBook Data 的分析师高凯迪表示，美国对中国初创企业的风险投资资金正在枯竭，因为由于地缘政治紧张局势，一些最大的有限合伙人（例如养老基金）缩减了在中国的风险敞口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年，大中华区风险投资基金筹集的资金总额降至 368 亿美元，而相比之下根据投资数据公司 Preqin 的一份报告，2019 年至 2021 年期间的年均融资额为 1489 亿美元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[4 children lost for weeks in Colombian jungle after plane crash found alive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3223627/4-children-lost-weeks-colombian-jungle-after-plane-crash-found-alive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 09:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/4275a8a3-0fa0-4d35-aff1-0aa03b6ed209_64416b35.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周五在该国南部发现了来自哥伦比亚土著社区的四名儿童哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗 (Gustavo Petro) 说，他们乘坐的飞机在茂密的丛林中坠毁五个多星期后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;军方在哥伦比亚卡克塔省和瓜维亚雷省之间的边界附近解救了这些孩子，靠近小型飞机坠毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这架塞斯纳 206 飞机在亚马逊省阿拉拉库阿拉和瓜维亚雷省圣何塞瓜维亚雷市之间的航线上载有七人，当时它发布了求救信号由于 5 月 1 日凌晨发动机故障而发出警报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括飞行员在内的三名成年人因坠机而死亡，他们的尸体在飞机内被发现。这四名年龄分别为 13 岁、9 岁和 4 岁的儿童以及一名现在 12 个月大的婴儿在撞击中幸存下来。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;哥伦比亚总统撤回了飞机失事后发现儿童还活着的说法&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;哥伦比亚军方分享的照片显示，一群士兵带着四个孩子在丛林中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“整个国家都高兴！在哥伦比亚丛林中迷路的四个孩子……似乎还活着，”Petro 在 Twitter 上的一条消息中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Petro 最初报告说，这些最初来自 Uitoto 土著群体的孩子于 5 月 17 日被发现在 Twitter 上的一条消息中，但后来删除了该帖子，称该信息未经证实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从那以后，160 名士兵和 70 名熟悉丛林的原住民一直在进行大规模搜索，寻找这些年轻人，引起了全球关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该地区是美洲虎、蛇和其他食肉动物以及武装毒品走私集团的家园，但持续不断的线索——脚印、尿布、吃了一半的水果——让当局相信他们&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;担心孩子们会继续四处游荡并变得越来越难以找到，空军将 10,000 名传单扔进了森林，并用西班牙语和孩子们自己的土著语言进行了指导，告诉他们留在原地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;传单还包括求生技巧，军方还投放了食品包和瓶装水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;救援人员还播放了孩子们祖母录制的信息，敦促他们&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Uitoto 的孩子们学习打猎、钓鱼和采集，孩子们的祖父 Fidencio Valencia 说孩子们对丛林很熟悉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天我们有佩特罗在从古巴回来后告诉媒体，他在古巴与哥伦比亚最后一个活跃的游击队 ELN 签署了为期六个月的休战协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在协议中越来越接近并实现和平ELN 正在向前推进……现在我回来了，第一个消息是，确实是参与搜索的土著社区和军队在 40 天后找到了这些孩子，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们在一起，他们很虚弱，让医生评估一下吧。他们找到了他们，这让我很高兴，”Petro 补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Asia’s Russia-West balancing act on show with push for peace in Ukraine from Indonesia’s Prabowo]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3223563/asias-russia-west-balancing-act-show-push-peace-ukraine-indonesias-prabowo?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/dd87e6e2-f42b-4658-8c32-2ce21afe59eb_c87bc055.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚国防部长Prabowo Subianto 在 6 月 3 日于新加坡举行的香格里拉对话防务峰会上引起了轰动，他在激动人心的演讲中提出了一项有争议的乌克兰战争和平计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prabowo 提议两国停火俄罗斯和乌克兰，创建一个由观察员和全球维和部队提供保障的非军事区。他还建议最终由联合国组织“在争议地区举行公投”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不要责怪任何一方，任何冲突总是有两个版本，”他说，并强调停止敌对行动是必不可少的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反击是立即而猛烈的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰国防部长 Oleksii Reznikov 认为这个想法听起来“像俄罗斯的计划，而不是印度尼西亚的计划”，而强调不存在可举行公投的“有争议”领土。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不需要这个调解人来找我们[带着]这个奇怪的计划，”雷兹尼科夫说，而欧盟外交政策负责人Josep Borrell 呼吁国际社会为乌克兰带来“公正的和平”，而不是“投降的和平”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普拉博沃的计划在国内遭到批评，议会国防和外交事务主席 Meutya Hafid 也受到批评委员会称，国防部长在表达意见时应谨慎。印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多还表示，他将传唤普拉博沃进行解释。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为明年总统大选的有抱负的候选人之一，普拉博沃很可能是在向对西方帝国主义保持警惕并厌倦了粮食和石油价格战。然而，观察家将普拉博沃的讲话视为另一个迹象，表明由发展中国家组成的全球南方并不认同西方将俄罗斯定性为战争中彻头彻尾的坏蛋的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; “管理不善正在伤害所有人”：中国前美国特使猛烈抨击欧洲&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;平台的选择——香格里拉对话，一个由国防部长、专家和分析家组成的关于全球安全的秘密会议——让普拉博沃更加大胆&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prabowo 的演讲“具有挑战只有一种道德正确的乌克兰战争观点的价值，即华盛顿及其亲密盟友的观点”，Sarang Shidore 说，美国智库昆西责任治国研究所研究和高级研究员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在该智库网站上发表的一篇文章中，Shidore 表示，除了普遍接受的认为入侵是违反主权和领土完整，“对于如何在结束这场战争时牺牲和平与正义，还没有达成共识”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;代价高昂，最终可能既不会带来和平，也不会带来正义，”Shidore 写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚、巴西和印度等中等强国明确表示，全球南方与世界秩序息息相关，并且“将他补充说，并不羞于表达自己的意见以参与和塑造对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作为东南亚国家联盟现任主席国，印度尼西亚传统上保持着良好的关系与俄罗斯和乌克兰。尽管投票赞成一项谴责入侵的联合国决议，但它并未对莫斯科实施经济制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;维多多去年甚至访问了乌克兰和俄罗斯，并提出在交战国家之间进行调解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;战略咨询公司 Global Counsel 的首席印度尼西亚分析师 Dedi Dinarto 表示，Prabowo 的关键信息是冲突正在给全球南方国家带来经济不确定性，例如食品和燃料出口中断。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;安排乌克兰-印度尼西亚表示，俄罗斯和谈过于“艰难”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;严重依赖外国投资来推动经济增长的印度尼西亚越来越担心对莫斯科的制裁可能会导致炼油厂合资企业停工Dinarto 说：“因此，印度尼西亚希望俄罗斯和乌克兰之间的停火能够恢复战前局势，从而消除对[莫斯科]的严厉制裁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;Jenderal Achmad Yani 大学国际关系副教授 Yohanes Sulaiman 表示，印度尼西亚还希望在从俄罗斯采购武器方面保持“开放的选择”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;战略研究名誉教授 Brahma Chellaney 表示，国家考虑同样推动其他全球南方国家，其中大多数国家在被视为“俄罗斯与西方之间的代理人战争，乌克兰是后者的代理人”的冲突中采取中立立场在新德里政策研究中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;切拉尼举了印度的例子，其“战略矛盾心理”的姿态意味着它继续与俄罗斯和西方保持联系，抵制美国的直接推动反对莫斯科——它最大的武器供应商和最大的石油供应商之一。印度还寻求成为两个交战方之间的桥梁建设者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“战争持续的时间越长，非西方世界就越拒绝站队，”切拉尼说，并补充说很少有人接受西方的说法，认为这场战争是民主国家和专制国家之间的战争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰领导人沃洛德米尔·泽伦斯基“绝不是民主人士”，此前曾迫使批评者保持沉默，并试图控制媒体并试图以叛国罪逮捕前总统和反对派政治家佩特罗·O·波罗申科。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊斯兰堡战略研究所研究员穆罕默德·阿里·贝格说，发展中国家没有选择任何一方的奢侈因此可以“轻易缩小”他们进一步行动的范围，因此选择中立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，巴基斯坦就是这样一个“理性的行为者”，并指出该国不愿批评俄罗斯的行动，购买了石油来自莫斯科的产品。伊斯兰堡还否认了有关其向基辅出售武器的报道，此前还表示支持乌克兰的主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“巴基斯坦的经济正在萎缩，其对长期合作伙伴美国的依赖正在减弱， ”他说，并补充说这是由于华盛顿无力帮助巴基斯坦解决其经济困境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，巴基斯坦财政部长伊沙克达尔敦促华盛顿利用其外交影响力来说服国际货币基金组织放宽对伊斯兰堡的苛刻条件——例如修改其人为汇率——以恢复援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;能源匮乏的南亚在俄罗斯、中国和美国之间走在微妙的界限上&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;孟加拉国最初对一项呼吁俄罗斯从乌克兰撤军的联合国决议投了弃权票，理由是俄罗斯在 1971 年孟加拉国争取独立期间作为苏联提供了支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在 4 月，达卡改变了立场，宣布乌克兰战争违反了国际法和联合国宪章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈佛大学艺术与科学学院研究员 Anu Anwar 表示，鉴于孟加拉国在三个核武器国家的十字路口的地缘战略位置地区 – 印度、巴基斯坦和中国 – 达卡本可以在主权和领土完整问题上采取更大胆的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;注意到孟加拉国的初步反应与大多数南亚国家的反应一致，安瓦尔说达卡改变了心脏可能旨在安抚西方，因为对抗它是该国“最不需要的东西”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔指出美国国家安全委员会战略沟通协调员约翰柯比最近发表的评论敦促孟加拉国保持“自由和公正的选举”，定于明年 1 月举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“西方已经加大了压力……[因此]孟加拉国在全国大选之前对乌克兰战争的立场将主要由国内政治决定，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然主权和领土完整是亚洲发展中国家的主要考虑因素，但安瓦尔指出，乌克兰战争对他们来说“太遥远”了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们也不他补充说，他们看到他们有很大兴趣公开支持俄罗斯对抗西方”，并转向以符合其国家利益的方式“全方位平衡”西方和俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯里兰卡在近年来最严重的经济危机，是另一个没有谴责俄罗斯的亚洲国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北卡罗来纳州维克森林大学政治与国际事务教授尼尔·德沃塔说，这个南亚岛国俄罗斯在国际论坛上的支持必将获益，尤其是当涉及到对泰米尔人犯下战争罪的指控时，这个国家曾因数十年的内战而四分五裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯终于支持了斯里兰卡年的联合国人权理事会表示，科伦坡镇压要求该岛领导人辞职的抗议者是正当的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“像斯里兰卡这样的小国也更容易采取中立立场当像印度这样的大国拒绝谴责俄罗斯时，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DeVotta 表示，大多数全球南方国家都基于自身利益采取了中立立场，因为“从安全角度来看”，战争并未影响到它们。更重要的是，他们越来越认识到“正在重新排序权力分配的新兴多边体系”，这可能会导致去全球化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最初将战争定性为民主与专制之间的较量力量也可能促成了这种中立立场，”DeVotta 说，因为大多数南半球国家都是非民主或非自由民主国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最初信奉中立的泰国后来支持联合国决议，呼吁结束&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在叙事战争中，东南亚在乌克兰-俄罗斯冲突中的立场如何？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在去年的联合国投票中，泰国弃权谴责俄罗斯吞并四个乌克兰地区，称“国际原则的政治化加剧”已经“适得其反”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;密歇根大学政治学博士生 Ken Mathis Lohatepanont 表示，这反映了外交政策试图走中间道路，曼谷希望与所有大国保持友好关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“泰国长期以来一直奉行一种被称为‘风中竹子’的战略，” Lohatepanont 说，拒绝过于坚定地站在一个或另一个大国一边。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，迄今为止，泰国政府一直对支持俄罗斯或西方领导的联盟持矛盾态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最近几个月，尤其是在日本举行的 G7 峰会上，美国及其盟友呼吁全球南方国家支持乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但许多国家的支持力度不大英国布拉德福德大学名誉教授保罗罗杰斯说，随着包括印度尼西亚在内的伊斯兰国家对西方联盟在阿富汗、伊拉克和利比亚的行动有“更强烈的记忆”，亚洲国家出现了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据布朗大学的估计Costs of War Project，全球至少有 897,000 人死于这场可归类为反恐战争一部分的暴力事件，其中包括许多穆斯林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;战争的任何一方都不太可能，持久战让双方都筋疲力尽的可能性更大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佐治亚理工学院萨姆纳恩国际事务学院的杰出教授 Philip Breedlove 表示，这场战争“将结束西方希望它结束​​的方式”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“事实是，当西方向乌克兰提供它需要的东西时，它就赢了，”前美国欧洲司令部指挥官布里德洛夫说.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国“尽力”调解乌克兰战争：英国的本·华莱士&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但由于全球南方国家对战争存在分歧，罗杰斯表示，结局很可能会涉及其他国家，最引人注目的是中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近几周，中国派出了特使李辉，他在对欧洲进行了 12 天的访问后表示，要让各方坐下来讨论“相当困难”谈判桌上，但保证和平解决乌克兰冲突仍然是可能的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然全球南方可能不会在战争的结果中发挥决定性作用，看起来可能会拖延，但西方大国可以期待中等大国的更多和平计划继续出现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果俄罗斯使用核武器，人们可能会看到全球南方放弃中立立场，[但]除此之外，这些国家必须维克森林大学的 DeVotta 说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Dismissal dress’: silky pink frock worn by woman holding hands with sacked Chinese oil company executive in ‘mistress’ scandal sells out online]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3223516/dismissal-dress-silky-pink-frock-worn-woman-holding-hands-sacked-chinese-oil-company-executive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/999adaa7-0dc4-4bfc-958f-84dcebc37058_1e6053b4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;关于中国一位已婚石油公司高管的故事出现了一个不太可能的赢家在被摄像机拍到与一名不是他妻子的女人牵手后被解雇了——这名女子穿着的是飘逸的丝绸连衣裙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频片段拍摄于中国西南部四川省成都市一个繁忙的购物区省份，一名身穿粉色 Polo 衫的男子手牵着一名身穿同色连衣裙的女子，后者优雅地对着镜头挥手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在拍摄者的抖音账号上发布该片段后，据透露，画面中的男子是一家石油公司旗下北京公司的总经理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与他同属一家公司的女性不是他的妻子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月7日，该公司宣布，该男子已被免职并接受纪律审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国媒体第二天报道称，该女子也已被停职并接受调查。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;公告没有解释两人违反了哪些公司规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着这件事成为网上最热门的话题，摄影师小米也将他的账户设为私人账户。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;他告诉大河日报，两人并没有试图阻止自己和其他摄影师拍摄他们。后来，他在收到“有涉案人员”的消息后删除了这段视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，这起丑闻却产生了意想不到的赢家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频在网上疯传后，女在由南华早报的所有者阿里巴巴运营的电子商务平台淘宝上，佩戴该夹子的商品在搜索列表中名列前茅&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;超过 1200 万人查看了该商品，该商品被称为“解雇”或“牵手”礼服。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于服装的流量甚至使与幸运符相关的点心相形见绌，父母为他们正在参加全国高考的孩子购买了这些点心全国近 1300 万学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至撰写本文时，这件裙子的月销量也从十几件增加到 4000 多件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 6 月 8 日的直播中，这家商店出售这件衣服宣布已经售罄，新顾客需要等待数周才能拿到产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，人们不应该担心别人的意见，享受“穿衣自由”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;这一立场在店主小红书账号下的评论中得到了认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人说：“不要因为和视频中的女人穿同样的衣服而感到尴尬。”我看不到任何男人会因为穿粉色 Polo 衫而感到尴尬。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拍摄这对情侣的购物区是街头时尚摄影师经常光顾的地方，他们为时尚人士拍照和拍摄视频并将其发布到网上.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong proposal to build housing on luxury golf course heads to public debate next week. Here’s what backers and opponents plan to say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3223613/hong-kong-proposal-build-housing-luxury-golf-course-heads-public-debate-next-week-heres-what-backers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/d0b74554-213d-4f9f-9543-ee5aa846275e_3bbb9699.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港商界重量级人物将于周一开始面对前官员和关注团体成员就一个专属高尔夫球场的一部分辩论一项有争议的住房计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一方坚决反对在拥有一百多年历史的粉岭高尔夫球场兴建公共单位。拟议的 32 公顷（79 英亩）场地是香港高尔夫球会从政府租用的 172 公顷土地的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一方是支持该提案的人，该提案最初概述了一项计划到 2029 年，在 9 公顷土地上建造 12,000 套房屋，其余的保留用于娱乐和保护用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城市规划委员会至少安排了五次会议举行公开听证会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;委员会是评估土地申请的法定机构，去年收到了 6,788 份公众回应，其中压倒性的 99.6% 反对住房提案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在公开听证会前一周，政府更改了分区将拟议住宅用地的一部分更改为“未确定”，以便有更多时间按照环保部门的要求修改住房计划并降低密度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;夜生活大亨艾伦泽曼猛烈抨击住房计划“绝对错误” .他说，虽然他不是俱乐部会员，但他反对这项提议，因为他关心这个拥有 112 年历史的球场的遗产价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在香港高尔夫球场建造房屋的有争议计划的下一步是什么?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他认为，这不仅仅是“一个普通的高尔夫球场”，在经济仍在从 Covid-19 大流行中恢复期间，失去部分球场无助于修复城市形象。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;消息人士称，前港铁主席马时亨也将出席下周三的听证会，预计他将强调该提案的一些潜在问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对建屋计划的人士包括预计出席听证会的是资深测量师刘秉祥，他已宣布自己是高尔夫球会的成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管他是现已解散的长期房屋策略督导委员会成员，该委员会向时任行政长官提出建议措施十年前的梁振英，刘说这块地应该保留为由专业人士管理的公共高尔夫球场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他承认政府拥有这块土地并可以收回，但他说：“它鉴于有更多的土地选择，没有必要在此地建造房屋。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;开发香港农田“无法替代”在高尔夫球场上建造房屋&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lau pointed将新界 30,000 公顷的土地变成可容纳 250 万人的住房的经济强国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位在听证会前拒绝透露姓名的前官员，表示在高尔夫球场场地上建房会导致该地区严重的交通拥堵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有 16 名受访者告诉董事会他们支持住房计划，包括前规划总监林家根，他预计“这将对未来十年的住房供应造成重大打击”，他警告说，并补充说，鉴于土地供应紧张，寻找替代地点是不可能的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;住房顾问 Johnnie Casire Chan Chi-kau 说，他将代表香港物业管理公司协会出席公开听证会，支持该提案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一直很难找到建房用地，政府应该推进这个项目，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;建在香港最古老的球场上会伤害高尔夫的未来：运动机构&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;至于要建造的公寓数量，政府应该尊重环境的投入陈建议当局并调整计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在支持该建议并将出席公开听证会的关注团体中，有为穷人和弱势群体服务的社区组织协会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;敦促政府加快建设新房，因为公租房的平均轮候时间为 5.3 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港高尔夫球会住房计划罕见削减生态投票&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;当局强调了他们继续实施该计划的决心，但表示新公寓现在预计将在 2031 年完工，比最初的目标晚了两年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;使用部分高尔夫球场是在十年内为住房提供土地的短期至中期建议中。在就解决住房用地短缺的方法进行了数月的公开辩论后，现已解散的土地供应工作组于 2018 年推荐了它。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港农村机构提议在有争议的高尔夫俱乐部用地附近建立住房计划&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;公屋联会执行理事赵国伟表示，理解原计划因环保需要而作出修改，但希望规模不要大幅缩减。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我不希望看到建造房屋的目标发生变化，”他说。 “毕竟，政府已经接受了土地辩论的建议。 It will be a great pity to throw out the proposal.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Town Planning Board is expected to decide by November at the latest whether to approve the zoning of the golf land for housing and related purposes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it will need final endorsement by the chief executive and his advisers. If the proposal is approved, the government will amend the housing proposal and submit a new plan to the environmental authorities by the end of next year.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Is this metal-coated paper the start of the future for wearable devices?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3223569/metal-coated-paper-start-future-wearable-devices?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/f2e755dd-217f-4fd3-8f52-3f8e883da557_4b2743b7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Scientists in China have developed a way to turn origami into wearable devices and soft robotics by coating it with liquid metal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The metal-coated paper can be folded as usual, but is enhanced by the added properties of metal, such as tunable stiffness as well as the ability to conduct heat and electricity. It allows a 3D paper structure to be controlled by electricity, temperature changes or magnets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This facile approach provides a new material option for the wearable testing platform and flexible devices as well as soft robotics,” the team from Tsinghua University, Beihang University and the Chinese Academy of Sciences wrote in an article published in the peer-reviewed journal Cell Reports Physical Science on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A common example of liquid metal is mercury, a toxic silvery-white metal that is liquid at room temperature. It freezes into a soft solid around -39C (-38F).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this study, the team made use of two non-toxic liquid metal alloys eGaIn, which melts at 15.5C, and BiInS, with a melting point of 62C.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scientists have found sticking liquid metal to surfaces such as paper, plastic, cloth and even human skin difficult because of its extremely high surface tension and some have experimented with using an adhesive. But adding a third material may weaken the product&#39;s electrical, thermal or mechanical performance, the researchers say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese team made it possible by first applying liquid metal to silicone stamps, then rubbing the stamps with force on to paper so the metal droplets could effectively bind to the paper.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s the future of computing&#39;: we try Apple&#39;s US$3,499 Vision Pro headset&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The scientists showed that the metal-coated paper could still be folded into different shapes – such as a crane and a collapsible box – as with uncoated paper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They also folded the treated paper into a springlike shape. Thanks to the self-glueing ability of liquid-metal enhancers, the spring remained at its most compressed status and could be stretched to the required length or height when needed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The metal can be solidified by cooling and returns to its original state after reheating. The scientists had it carry a 50-gram (1.8 oz) weight in the study, showing its potential as a multifunctional smart material.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lead author Yuan Bo, a postdoctoral fellow in the department of biomedical engineering at Tsinghua University in Beijing, said liquid metal coating could turn commonly available materials into durable smart electronic devices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Devices like robotic grippers are conventionally powered by compressed air or heat and built with customised materials,” Yuan said. “Now we can use paper to make them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When we power the metal paper gripper with electricity, it expands. Without electricity, it tightens to pick up an item. After the item is moved to its destination, the gripper is powered again to release the object.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We can also create electric circuits on the skin to monitor finger movements, the heart&#39;s activity and body temperature,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese nanoplatform &#39;aircraft carrier&#39; delivers drugs to cancer patients&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;She said the coating was affordable, required only a thin layer of metal and could be recycled by solidifying and peeling it from the surface it coated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuan added that the team would work on protecting the liquid metal coating from melting by touch, as well as expanding its applications to more surfaces, such as other metals and ceramics.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia-Vietnam ties crucial ‘on own terms’, not just in relation to US, China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3223574/australia-vietnam-ties-crucial-own-terms-not-just-relation-us-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/2b877fb8-cc44-4479-971a-5f4a0ab52a08_5a98f6be.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Prime Minister Anthony Albanese&#39;s recent trip to Vietnam is recognition that Australia&#39;s relationship with the Southeast Asian nation is important on its own terms – not just in how it relates Australia&#39;s broader relationships with the United States and China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As such, it was surprising to see that a nicely executed state visit to a mid-power in the region, which resulted in the mooted upgrading of a “strategic partnership” to a “comprehensive strategic partnership”, had failed to generate substantive headlines, or capture the public imagination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australians need to see the enhancement of regional partnerships such as the one with Vietnam as having significant interest, with implications for Australia&#39;s future.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia and Vietnam linked by banh mi, beer and shared concerns over China&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;This is not the first bilateral visit of an Australian prime minister to Vietnam. The most recent was Scott Morrison&#39;s visit in 2019. But there was a particular resonance to this occasion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year marks the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between Australia and Vietnam. This was, of course, a particularly potent moment due to Australia&#39;s involvement in the war in Vietnam (known there as the “American War”).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the course of the war, more than 60,000 Australians were deployed to the country and 523 died. The war and the means of its prosecution – particularly conscription – became heated points of polarisation domestically in Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cost of the war to Vietnam itself was incalculable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australian commitment to the war began to wind down from late 1970, with the last Australian troops returning home in December 1972, soon after the election of the Whitlam government. Australia&#39;s involvement formally ended a month later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decades following the war were devastatingly difficult for Vietnam as it rebuilt itself amid international isolation, especially from the United States. A large number of refugees fled the authoritarianism of the new Communist regime, with many establishing strong and vibrant communities in Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1986, the Vietnamese Communist Party announced its Đổi Mới reforms to transition the country from a highly centralised economy based on state ownership to a form of market socialism. This began a process of opening Vietnam up economically and politically to the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In subsequent years, there has been a bipartisan effort in Australia to consolidate the relationship with Vietnam in both economic and defence agreements.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;An American option emerges in Vietnam&#39;s search for non-Russian arms&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;During the visit of Vietnamese Communist Party General Secretary Nong Duc Manh to Australia in 2009, the countries upgraded their relationship to one of “comprehensive partnership”. In 2018, to mark the 45th anniversary of diplomatic relations, this was upgraded further to a “strategic partnership”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are obvious economic and diplomatic benefits to enhancing the connections between the countries. According to the Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade, trade between the countries has grown on average by 8.6 per cent per year over the past two decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the attitude of the Morrison government to Vietnam was overtly inflected by its hardening hostility towards China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Morrison trumpeted the growth in trade during his visit, but within the framework of his government&#39;s foreign policy it was clear that such relationships were, relatively speaking, a sideshow to the main game: Australia&#39;s future was bound to the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Since its election, the Albanese government has showed its determination to rebuild and repair regional relationships. While this has included taking the heat out of the recent tensions with China, it also included enhancing collaborations with countries such as Vietnam, Malaysia, Indonesia and others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government&#39;s approach has not been a repudiation of Australia&#39;s ongoing defence and political ties with the United States, and is far from a passive stance towards China&#39;s positioning in the region. The staunch commitment of the Albanese government to Aukus makes this abundantly clear.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it was a recognition that the overwhelming emphasis of Australian foreign policy in recent years had diminished the significance of Australia&#39;s relationships with these mid-sized regional countries that were similarly seeking to adapt to the changing relationships and balance of power in the Asia-Pacific region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a recent prime ministerial statement outlined, stepping up Australia&#39;s relations with Vietnam is an important part of the government&#39;s determination to rebuild Australia&#39;s links with the countries of Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vietnam has experienced its own economic woes of late. It has a notable reliance on Australian coal for its power generation, and this is likely to remain the case in the short term. Its government is authoritarian. This should not be obscured in discussions of the two country&#39;s relationship.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Vietnam is a dynamic country with an economy that has been on the upswing. It also has a young population that is increasingly skilled and has showed itself to be globally connected.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Southeast Asia shows Australia the way to balance waning US and rising China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Australia is a country increasingly integrating itself into the region and exploring new economic opportunities in renewable energy. Among the agreements Albanese signed in Hanoi was a US$105 million package to help Vietnam decarbonise its economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia also has a large population of citizens with Vietnamese heritage with enduring ties – both familial and economic – to Vietnam. Current exchanges in trade and education are mutually beneficial, and growing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And all this is happening between two countries who, within living memory, were at war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The experience of the Vietnam War should remind all Australians of the dangers of following the US in pursuing its foreign policy ambitions without regard for its own. And the current relationship with Vietnam shows how Australia can do it its own way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liam Byrne is an Honorary Fellow of the School of Historical and Philosophical Studies at The University of Melbourne. This article was first published on .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Meet Walt Nauta, Donald Trump’s ‘Diet Coke valet’ who’s been indicted with his boss]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223626/meet-walt-nauta-donald-trumps-diet-coke-valet-whos-been-indicted-his-boss?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 07:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/10/4fe2f011-9320-4984-a7ae-c8031eb22ea5_bcb5ac74.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Former US president Donald Trump has been indicted on federal charges in connection to the Justice Department&#39;s investigation into his handling of classified documents, and an unsealed indictment reveals he has a co-defendant in the case – his aide, Walt Nauta.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nauta has been charged with six counts, including conspiracy to obstruct justice, a document or record, and false statements and representations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prosecutors allege that Trump directed Nauta “to move boxes of documents to conceal them from Trump&#39;s attorney, the FBI and the grand jury”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They allege that Trump and Nauta “hid, concealed, and covered up from the FBI Trump&#39;s continued possession of documents with classification margins at the Mar-a-Lago Club”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nauta is a long-time personal aide of Trump&#39;s and worked as a White House valet, a role that includes being a personal assistant, messenger, and errand runner for the president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New York Magazine&#39;s Intelligencer reported that Nauta was Trump&#39;s “Diet Coke valet”, the person who brought Trump a soda whenever he needed one in the White House&#39;s Oval Office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to The Washington Post, Nauta would also bring Trump anything else he needed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nauta was one of six siblings and grew up in Guam, a US island territory in the Western Pacific, before enlisting in the Navy in 2001, The Washington Post reported. He worked in the White House mess hall before becoming a valet.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;A breakdown of what&#39;s in Donald Trump&#39;s new office. Is he hiding his Diet Coke?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Washington Post reported that Nauta regularly travelled with Trump between his Bedminster, New Jersey home, Mar-a-Lago in Florida, and the White House. Nauta stayed on as one of Trump&#39;s aides after he left the presidency and has even been photographed on Trump&#39;s 2024 presidential campaign trail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The New York Times reported last year that Nauta was caught on security camera moving boxes from storage rooms at Mar-a-Lago before and after the Justice Department subpoenaed Trump.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the time, The Times cited three people familiar with the matter who said Nauta was seen moving boxes on security cameras. One source told The Times that the FBI also interviewed Nauta before its warrant-authorised search of Mar-a-Lago in August 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nauta&#39;s lawyer did not immediately respond to Insider&#39;s request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[For heat warnings to work, Hong Kong must have one clear, integrated system]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3223165/heat-warnings-work-hong-kong-must-have-one-clear-integrated-system?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/08/72ea3342-45ab-4abb-9903-3a3b80573308_a1477bb3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s new heating stress warning system for workers, introduced by the Labour Department last month, is a good start to the city&#39;s management of health emergencies and disaster risks from climate change. This comes as research shows strong associations among temperature, morbidity and mortality in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The warning system uses as the benchmark the Hong Kong Heat Index, which takes into account temperature, humidity, wind speed and sun radiation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But what should be tackled is how to integrate this new system with the Hong Kong Observatory&#39;s existing hot-weather warnings to simplify the city&#39;s health disaster warning system for heat risks. There have been successful examples in the use of typhoon and rainstorm warning systems for workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the article contributors, Emily Chan, collaborated with the Observatory to research and develop its heat index in 2014, using hospitalisation and heat stress data from 2007 to 2011 to assess the health impact of high temperatures, high humidity, slow winds and strong sun radiation. That same year, the Observatory introduced the two-tier hot weather warning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tier 1 is triggered by a heat index of 29.5 with Tier 2 warnings in place when the heat index hits 30.5. These thresholds are scientifically based – at 29.5, the excess hospitalisation ratio starts to pick up, increasing more rapidly after 30 and, by 30.5, reaches an alarming level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The earlier warning gives the public a reasonable lead time to protect themselves from the increased health risks of heat stress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In contrast, the new three-tier Heat Stress at Work Warning has thresholds for amber, red and black set at heat index readings of 30, 32 and 34 – which look too conservative. This is particularly because outdoor workers are much more exposed to weather than the general population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 22, when the Observatory issued its Tier 2 “very hot weather” warning to the public, the Labour Department did not put up even the lowest amber warning for heat stress at work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 30, the hottest day of the year, the amber alert was issued almost 30 hours after the “very hot weather” warning was in force, and 45 minutes after the Observatory issued for the first time an alert under its newly introduced “special weather tips” for when temperatures reach 35 degrees Celsius.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Greater transparency on the scientific basis of the new warning system for heat stress at work could improve people&#39;s understanding of the alerts and their efficiency. Moreover, having two such similar warning systems can confuse the public. Given that simplicity and clarity are important in risk communication, the integration of these two systems should be explored.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moreover, unlike the straightforward work guidelines under typhoon and rainstorm warnings, such guidelines under the new warning system are very complicated. The frontline challenges in policy implementation and the difficulties in effectively communicating the health risks of heat stress to the community should not be underestimated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Besides having the right policies, supportive work contexts and employers, raising public awareness of the health risks of heat, the responses they can take to extreme temperature warnings, and empowering people to take care of themselves via community education are equally important.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It takes coordination and planning for a warning system to work, and concerted efforts are crucial to ensure health protection objectives are met.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;End confusion over Hong Kong workers&#39; heat alerts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In addition to protecting outdoor workers, we should also be concerned about schoolchildren having physical education outdoors in the hot summer, pregnant women, older people and those living in suboptimal conditions, like subdivided units, who might be overexposed to extreme temperatures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compared to adults, children are more efficient at heat production and less efficient at sweating, and so adapt to changes in temperature more slowly. Importantly, children are more likely to become dehydrated as they can lose fluids quickly and don&#39;t have the awareness to adequately hydrate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The elderly are also vulnerable to extreme temperatures as ageing affects the body&#39;s ability to regulate temperature, leading to a decrease in the dissipation of heat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Research has shown that the very old and those with non-communicable diseases are at a higher risk of adverse health outcomes, including cardiovascular and respiratory diseases and accidental injuries. In the hot season in Hong Kong, every 1 degree Celsius increase above 29 degrees (the daily mean temperature) was associated with a 4.5 per cent jump in all hospital admissions and a 1.9 per cent increase in admissions for unintentional injuries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of respiratory admissions among children (for example, those with asthma) and infection disease admissions for the elderly (eg for pneumonia) started increasing when the temperature rose above the same threshold.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The risk of heart-attack admissions among patients with type 2 diabetes also increased when temperature rose over 28.8 degrees, highlighting the vulnerability of those with pre-existing conditions. These health effects will worsen with more frequent and severe extreme temperature hazards as a result of climate change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Hong Kong works to mitigate the impact of climate change, whether extreme temperatures, rising sea levels or more frequent and stronger typhoon and storm surges, government policies should not deviate from science and rationality, or ignore disaster risk reduction for the sake of economic activity, when Beijing emphasises high-quality development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Have China’s central and eastern European trade ambitions reached end of the line, and will bilateral deals fill gap?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3223555/have-chinas-central-and-eastern-european-trade-ambitions-reached-end-line-and-will-bilateral-deals?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/6a824941-65e7-40df-a9ca-99ba37209812_e55e90d9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A big Polish chicken producer has been knocking on China&#39;s door for eight years without selling a single drumstick, but hope springs eternal according to one of its representatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wipasz deputy sales director Rafat Koztowski attended the China-CEEC Expo &amp; International Consumer Goods Fair in Ningbo, Zhejiang province, last month on his second visit to China since the company applied for an import licence in 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has yet to surmount China&#39;s strict import rules for meat and poultry and its tortuous application processes for agricultural imports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They gave optimism, they gave hope, but not a timeline,” Koztowski said after his latest meeting with Chinese counterparts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are not giving up, we still need to try. China is a very big market.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Central and Eastern European Countries (CEEC), also known as the CEE, includes the likes of Bulgaria, Croatia, the Czech Republic, Poland and Romania, as well as Albania, Bosnia and Herzegovina and Serbia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Polish government said it had pushed for “a change in China&#39;s approach” on meat and poultry, according to a statement issued after a meeting with Chinese officials in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has yet to resume poultry imports from multiple countries where bird flu cases were once found, despite lifting official bans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wipasz was one of the more than 400 central and eastern European exhibitors at the Ningbo expo, which ran from May 16 to 20.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese officials said it was 30 per cent bigger than the previous expo, held in 2021, but only a few countries – including Poland, Hungary and Slovakia – sent official trade delegations or set up national booths.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lack of enthusiasm shown by other governments reflected their low expectations of gaining a foothold in one of the world&#39;s largest consumer markets, which is now contracting despite efforts to spark an economic recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Total Chinese imports fell by 7.9 per cent, year on year, in April to US$205.21 billion, following a 1.4 per cent fall in March, amid weak demand and lower commodity prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Central and eastern Europe&#39;s trade deficit with China has also been widening, with the value of exports to China down 4.9 per cent last year and the value of imports from China up about 13.8 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest quarterly trade data showed signs of improvement, with China&#39;s first-quarter exports to central and eastern Europe up 10.3 per cent year on year, and its imports from the two regions up 7.3 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the value of imports dropped by 12.2 per cent in April with the only growth recorded by Bulgaria, the Czech Republic, Poland, Romania and Montenegro.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Increasingly clear&#39; weak demand cools China exports, slowdown until late 2023&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Poland, the Czech Republic and Hungary were China&#39;s top central and eastern European trade partners last year, accounting for 59.6 per cent of imports from the two regions by value.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Beijing proposed setting up a cooperation mechanism with central and eastern European countries in 2012, one of the aims was to address a trade imbalance by importing more goods from the two regions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has called the mechanism a success because trade between the two regions and China has grown by an average of 8.1 per cent a year since it was established, and imports from the region have grown by an average of 9.2 per cent a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the diversity of traded items has remained limited. Machinery imports accounted for 72.5 per cent of the value of China&#39;s imports from central and eastern Europe last year, with agricultural products contributing just 2.2 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an online meeting with central and eastern European counterparts in February 2021, President Xi Jinping pledged to further boost the value and variety of imports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China intends to import more than US$170 billion of goods from CEE countries in the coming five years,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We need to speed up the entry of agricultural products from CEE countries into China and double CEE countries&#39; agricultural exports to China over the next five years.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the cooperation mechanism started to fall apart soon after – with Lithuania withdrawing after complaining there was little economic benefit from participation. Estonia and Latvia followed suit last year, leaving 14 European countries in the mechanism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Yu, China&#39;s special representative for China-CEEC cooperation, said at an academic conference held alongside the trade expo in Ningbo on May 17 that ties had entered a “key development era”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The cooperation is currently at a key development era where we have to continue with what we started and develop it farther into the future,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have to get used to what comes up in the relationship and continue to explore new mechanisms for cooperation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine last year changed Europe&#39;s security concerns and priorities. But while many central and eastern European countries grew more skeptical of China&#39;s close relationship with Russia, Budapest and Beijing have basked in warmer ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hungary was the “sole guest of honour” at the Ningbo expo, according to official Chinese statements. It was also the only country that had a national booth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hungarian Foreign Affairs and Trade Minister Peter Szijjarto, who led a delegation to Ningbo, said in his speech at the expo that it would be a mistake for the European Union to engage in rivalry with China, considering the benefits of cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We Hungarians do not consider China as if it was either a risk or a threat, but we do consider China as a country where cooperation brings a lot of profit and benefit,” he said, addressing a heated debate in Europe over China strategy and the degree of alignment with the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Budapest has said the European Union was partly to blame for the war in Ukraine, and has faced criticism from the bloc for tightening control of civil society over the past decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a visit to Budapest in February, China&#39;s top diplomat, Wang Yi, said Hungary was a “good friend in Europe”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang added that Hungary&#39;s “friendly approach” towards China would not only benefit Hungary&#39;s people but was also in accordance with the mutual interests of China and Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a visit to Beijing before the expo, Szijjarto announced that Hungary was expecting €3 billion (US$3.2 billion) of Chinese investment in its automotive sector, and foreign minister Qin Gang told him “bilateral relations have entered the best period in history”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hungary received US$7.6 billion in investment related to China&#39;s Belt and Road Initiative last year – more than any other country – even as Chinese investment in Europe fell 22 per cent, continuing a multi-year downward trend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Shanghai-based academic who studies Europe said Beijing was likely to deal with countries in the region differently after some dropped out from the mechanism and geopolitical tensions arose from the war in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The obvious change is that China&#39;s foreign policy has returned to become more country-based and issue-based,” she said, requesting anonymity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s not that the mechanism would be cancelled, but nothing really meaningful would be done through it, and it would only remain as a symbol that underpins China&#39;s eagerness to build relations with these regions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think Beijing finally came to realise that it is not really possible or not really meaningful to try to deal with so many countries that are so different all at once. The differences in their geopolitical importance, their geographical locations and their trade volume with China are too diverse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some people may say this is going back to the start, before the mechanism was set up, but at least now we have found out we should not lay our hopes on this path going forward.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Boris Johnson quits as UK lawmaker as he faces Partygate sanctions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3223623/boris-johnson-quits-uk-lawmaker-he-faces-partygate-sanctions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 03:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_coronavirus_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/10/8b2bdaa1-6cc6-4ba4-8f72-adeff67b3469_820d93e1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Former UK Prime Minister Boris Johnson shocked Britain on Friday by quitting as a lawmaker after being told he will be sanctioned for misleading parliament.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Johnson quit after receiving the results of an investigation by lawmakers over misleading statements he made to parliament about “Partygate”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a statement, he accused opponents of trying to drive him out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said he had “received a letter from the Privileges Committee making it clear – much to my amazement – that they are determined to use the proceedings against me to drive me out of parliament”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He called the committee a “kangaroo court”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The resignation will trigger a special election to replace Johnson as a lawmaker for a suburban London seat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Johnson, whose career has been a roller coaster of scandals and comebacks, led the Conservatives to a landslide victory in 2019 but was forced out by his own party less than three years later.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Boris Johnson admits he misled British MPs over lockdown parties&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He had been awaiting the outcome of an investigation by a House of Commons standards committee over misleading statements he made to parliament about a slew of gatherings in government buildings in 2020 and 2021 that breached pandemic lockdown rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police eventually issued 126 fines over the late-night soirées, boozy parties and “wine time Fridays”, including one to Johnson, and the scandal helped hasten the end of his premiership.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The committee is expected to publish its report in the next few weeks.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>