<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Flailing DeSantis would do better focusing on climate change than targeting Trump]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227971/flailing-desantis-would-do-better-focusing-climate-change-targeting-trump?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.18 01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/efa86cfa-32cb-4d16-ae3a-7c3ab1fea42d_45c3d363.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;上周美国政治最重大的事态发展之一引起了人们的关注有关环境和商业方面的新闻，这些因素的综合作用对共和党的两位主要总统候选人来说变得越来越不方便。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们都集中在佛罗里达州或包括佛罗里达州这一事实是考虑到它是最容易受到与气候变化相关的极端天气影响的国家之一，这也不是偶然的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这三项进展中的第一个进展是前总统唐纳德·特朗普最亲近的人的支持率明显下滑明年白宫选举的竞争对手是佛罗里达州州长罗恩·德桑蒂斯。对德桑蒂斯输给领先特朗普的解释包括，他回避那些不崇拜他的媒体，以及他的形象与俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京一样热情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有一个共和党温和派人士对德桑蒂斯竞选团队最近投放的一则极其奇怪的广告表示强烈反对。它的主角是肌肉发达、方下巴有男子气概的男人 - 具有讽刺意味的是，他的目的是为了提升他作为最反 LGBTQ 候选人的信誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一集揭示了州长无法从与迪士尼的持续战争中吸取教训 - 这使得他成为最反 LGBTQ 候选人的候选人。是佛罗里达州最大的雇主之一 - 反对该州的“不要说同性恋”法。它在温和派中也没有得到很好的支持，他们想知道为什么德桑蒂斯没有看到他有更大的鱼要煎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;煎鱼的主题给我们带来了第二个发展。德桑蒂斯州周围海洋珊瑚礁的水温达到了现代测量中未见的水平，国家海洋和大气管理局监测到某些地区的水温高达 97 华氏度（36.1 摄氏度）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该事件与此同时，佛罗里达州最大的奥基乔比湖正在酝酿一场有毒藻类大量繁殖的灾难。由于降雨量高于平均水平，该湖有可能溢出到居民区，而降雨量本身就是气候变化的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有第三个因素。随着湖泊水位上涨和飓风季节临近，许多佛罗里达人会发现抵御气候变化带来的灾难的选择越来越少。这是因为 Farmers Insurance 宣布将停止在佛罗里达州销售其自有品牌的房屋保险、汽车保险和雨伞保险，这些保险占其在该州销售的保单的近三分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DeSantis 和他的选民基础 –与共和党的很大一部分人一起——可能被右翼错误信息所蒙蔽，认为气候变化是一个骗局，因此能够忽视科学家几十年来一直警告我们的所有证据。然而，保险业并不是进步激进主义的堡垒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果保险精算专家没有警告说，最近佛罗里达州和美国其他地区的一系列恶劣天气，保险公司就不会放弃业务。美国是我们未来的常态。正如 State Farm 通过将其业务撤出加州向我们展示的那样，这种撤出正在成为整个行业的趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然德桑蒂斯基地中的许多人可能无法忽视年轻人要求立即采取行动削减开支的愤怒由于化石燃料的燃烧，他们中很少有人愿意在下一次飓风将屋顶掀翻时面临支付更高保险费或零赔偿的更大风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而特朗普 — — 他对通过在 2017 年让美国退出巴黎气候协议，他可能会在明年获得共和党提名，但他将面临一系列由火灾、洪水、干旱和极端高温造成的类似情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;德桑蒂斯在共和党总统提名竞选中无法与特朗普匹敌&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在美国大部分地区，尤其是南方，夏季正在成为室内季节。试着把这归咎于美国总统乔·拜登，他把应对气候变化作为首要任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论是特朗普在初选中获胜，还是德桑蒂斯在去年大选中取得决定性胜利后，都成功恢复了势头在中期选举中，他们将不得不努力转移选民的注意力，让他们忽视这样一个不可避免的结论：气候变化使野火变得更加猛烈、更加普遍、规模更大、损失更大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;面对这些因素，也许德桑蒂斯可以为他和他的州周围的汹涌大海提出自己的解决方案，而不是在他的竞选广告中与螺柱嬉戏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 18 Jul 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Crimea bridge attack: Russia tells stranded tourists to drive home via occupied Ukraine]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3228039/crimea-bridge-attack-russia-tells-stranded-tourists-drive-home-occupied-ukraine?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.18 01:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/18/fedf020b-c213-4cd5-a003-9bc69b5ede54_54ad269c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯官员周一鼓励滞留在克里米亚的度假者在被占领的乌克兰开车回家乌克兰袭击导致连接半岛与俄罗斯的桥梁上的汽车交通中断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袭击造成两人死亡，他们的女儿受伤，总统弗拉基米尔·普京命令当局修复道路并帮助滞留在克里米亚的游客。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰发动攻势后，飞往莫斯科吞并的克里米亚的商业航班已暂停，大多数俄罗斯游客通常开车通过大桥前往克里米亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着交通拥堵，官员建议游客开车 400 公里（250 英里）穿过俄罗斯军队控制的领土，其中一些地区受到战斗的严重影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我要求半岛居民和客人不要在克里米亚大桥上旅行克里米亚驻莫斯科领导人谢尔盖·阿克肖诺夫 (Sergei Aksyonov) 表示：“出于安全考虑，请选择一条穿越新地区的替代陆路路线。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国家电视台播出了该路线的地图，该路线穿过被占领的地区梅利托波尔到马里乌波尔港，终点是俄罗斯南部城市罗斯托夫。它提醒人们随身携带护照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被占领的乌克兰官员表示，他们将缩短宵禁时间，让游客通过，俄罗斯军队将加强安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“安全就是安全俄罗斯任命的乌克兰南部赫尔松地区（由莫斯科控制）地区负责人弗拉基米尔·萨尔多（Vladimir Saldo）表示：“在俄罗斯军队的保证下，这一力量将会得到加强。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;普京表示，俄罗斯拥有“足够的库存”集束炸弹，并在必要时使用它们&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他表示，他已“最小化”宵禁以“让过境运输通过”。萨尔多警告说，将设立检查站以避免“破坏”，但手续将“减少”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄新社报道称，约有 5 万名游客在克里米亚度假，其中大多数游客是开车来的。该广播公司发布了一段视频，显示汽车从克里米亚排队到被占领的赫尔松地区，长达数公里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在邻近的东南部扎波罗热地区，该地区是基辅反攻的重点目标，莫斯科任命的州长叶夫根尼·巴利茨基巴利茨基表示，官员将确保路线“安全”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“道路交通将在新地区为我们的公民提供最大的便利，”巴利茨基说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里米亚官员向司机保证这条路线是可靠的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一条著名的路线。非常好的一个，沿着亚速海，风景优美，”克里米亚议会主席弗拉基米尔·康斯坦丁诺夫说道。 “我们没有看到任何令人担忧的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯电视台播放了一些排队的镜头，一些驾车者决心无论如何都要回家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们告诉我们：去！一切都会好起来的，上帝保佑，”一名男子告诉国家电视台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但其他人似乎更加犹豫。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯游客因在圣树上拍裸照而被巴厘岛驱逐出境&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;“我们正在考虑该怎么做，”一位女士告诉同一家国家电视台。 “回去度假还是去梅利托波尔？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅利托波尔在去年俄罗斯军队的攻势初期落入俄罗斯军队手中，并经常成为袭击目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里米亚交通部发布了一份报告游客在出发前应注意的事项清单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中一条说明中写道，“给军车和纵队让路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还建议游客携带现金他们并警告沿途有警察和军事检查站。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 18 Jul 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[From GDP to youth unemployment, 6 takeaways from China’s economic data in June]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3228016/gdp-youth-unemployment-6-takeaways-chinas-economic-data-june?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.18 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/a45f2973-47db-40ef-8f6b-6f18d3f88433_160535ee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;第二季度中国经济增长6.3% 2023 年季度同比增速高于第一季度的 4.5%，但低于中国数据提供商 Wind 预测的 6.8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但环比来看，中国国内生产总值GDP仅增长0.8%，增速较一季度2.2%有所放缓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上半年，中国GDP同比增长5.5%去年，高于北京2023年全年增长目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国第二季度GDP增速意外下滑。显然，未来几天我们可能不得不接受新一波的增长前景下调。不过，5%的增长目标看起来是非常可以实现的。”国泰君安国际首席经济学家周浩表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;穆迪分析公司经济学家哈里·墨菲·克鲁斯表示，季度环比增长率“对于一个正在努力获得动力的经济来说，这是一个令人担忧的结果”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国的复苏正在每况愈下。 6 月季度同比增长 6.3% 低于预期，并因去年遭受封锁蹂躏的参考期而感到受宠若惊。在 2023 年初的几个月里，大流行的后遗症正在困扰着中国的复苏。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;16-24 岁年龄段的失业率创下新高6月失业率高达21.3%，高于5月的20.8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上月城镇调查失业率保持在5.2%不变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;青年失业率创历史新高穆迪分析公司的克鲁斯补充道，“只会增加人们的担忧”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管背后存在结构性因素，但青年失业率的上升凸显出需要更多的政策支持来扩大内需并带动经济复苏。”汇丰银行经济学家表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;6 月份零售额同比增长 3.1%，低于 5 月份 12.7% 的增幅。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;分析师表示，下降的主要原因是对冠状病毒敏感的餐厅销售以及汽车销售增长放缓，原因是上海于 2022 年 6 月解除封锁后被压抑的需求释放，导致基数较高。高盛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“家庭对支出持谨慎态度。消费者仍然对经济复苏持怀疑态度，对就业和收入增长的预期已转为负面。”穆迪分析公司的克鲁斯补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;工业生产，衡量制造业活动的指标采矿和公用事业行业上月同比增长 4.4%，高于 5 月份的 3.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管汽车产量增速因高盛分析师表示，基数较高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;按行业细分，制造业同比增长 4.8%，公用事业增长 4.9%，采矿业增长 1.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国关注东盟贸易关系，但成员国担心陷入“地缘政治陷阱”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但牛津经济研究院高级经济学家劳埃德·陈 (Lloyd Chan) 表示，由于外部挑战严峻，近期工业生产的上升只是暂时的6月份中国出口同比下降12.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们对未来几个月的工业生产和出口保持谨慎展望，因为去库存压力将继续加大。此外，与美国的贸易摩擦也在加剧。”他表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;固定资产投资——北京拉动经济增长的传统工具——2019年增长了3.8% 2023 年前 6 个月同比增幅低于今年前 5 个月的 4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;牛津经济研究院 (Oxford Economics) 的 Chan 表示，这种改善主要是国家主导的，抵消了 1-6 月民间投资同比下降 0.2% 的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通常占总投资三分之一的房地产投资也下降了 7.9%陈先生表示：“显然，房地产投资兴趣仍然严重不足，新屋开工率持续两位数下降，对该行业来说是不利的。”&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;高盛分析师预计未来几个月将采取更有针对性的宽松措施，以应对持续的增长阻力，包括房地产放缓和市场信心低迷，尽管他们补充说刺激幅度应该较小与之前的宽松周期相比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着脆弱的复苏减弱，刺激措施正在注入。中国人民银行降低了一些主要贷款利率，同时延长了电动汽车销售的减税政策。但迫切需要更多，”穆迪分析公司的克鲁斯补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们预计未来几个月货币政策将会放松，并向包括房地产和建筑业在内的关键行业提供有针对性的财政支持。但额外的支持并不是灵丹妙药。 2023 年对中国来说越来越像是令人遗忘的一年。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，中国人民银行 (PBOC) 维持向继上个月从 2.75% 下调之后，金融机构利率降至 2.65%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鉴于中国经济的现状，中国人民银行的降息周期将继续下去。我们预计政策利率将在未来一两个月内再次下调 10 个基点。”麦格理集团首席中国经济学家胡拉里 (Larry Hu) 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡还预计很快会下调存款准备金率，“以便鼓励银行向实体经济提供更多信贷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰君安国际首席经济学家周浩确实指出，6 月份的活动数据显示出更多积极消息，工业生产增速远高于市场预期，而固定资产投资增幅也超预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然，这是消费拉动的放缓，需要需求侧的政策支持。”我们认为进一步降息或多或少是有必要的，并且预计 MLF 利率最快将在第三季度再降低 10 个基点。”他表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“降息将转化为还房贷，不仅有利于购房者，也有利于消费者提高消费能力。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Women, girls tell of horrific, traumatic rape, sexual assault in Sudan as conflict rages]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3228038/women-girls-tell-horrific-traumatic-rape-sexual-assault-sudan-conflict-rages?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 23:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/75ed3e3d-22f4-4110-a91d-37256ff1ad48_e73327db.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;5 月 9 日，也就是她 12 岁生日后不久，Muna 离开了喀土穆的家，步行到当地的商店。她经常独自跑腿，很快就会回到母亲身边。但这次不是。两名买烟的士兵注意到穆娜正在挑选面包，其中一人抓住了她的手臂，另一人则举起了步枪，威胁店主与其保持距离。他们将她拖到附近的一个建筑工地并强奸了她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些士兵是快速支援部队的成员，这是一个准军事组织，在过去三个月里一直与苏丹军队作战，争夺首都的控制权。两人都享有可怕的名声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;穆纳被扔在路边，流着血，痛苦不堪，但在家族朋友店主的帮助下，穆纳回到了家。她的父母向司法当局提出投诉，司法当局将他们转介给一位心理学家，而心理学家则建议他们避开最近的医院，因为该医院由无国界医生组织控制。相反，他们在一家私人诊所检查了穆纳是否患有性传播感染，并向一家药房索要卫生巾和止痛药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几天后，一家人逃离了这座城市。在消失之前，穆娜的父母允许分享她的故事，但为了她的安全，她的真实姓名没有被使用。她的强奸行为——政府文件披露并得到两名援助人员证实——是苏丹冲突中士兵实施性暴力的更广泛模式的一部分。活动人士表示，在一个外国记者基本上被政府禁止的国家，许多案件都没有得到报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;联合国报告乱葬坑后，国际刑事法院正在调查苏丹达尔富尔地区的杀戮&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;四月，自十月政变以来一直统治苏丹的两位将军开始就一项国际支持的民主过渡计划争论不休。随着冲突不再成为媒体关注的焦点，邻国——乍得、中非共和国、埃及、厄立特里亚、埃塞俄比亚、利比亚和南苏丹——以及美国和沙特阿拉伯正在努力斡旋和平，以避免全面内战。战争跨越国界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自冲突开始以来，已有超过 290 万人离开家园，其中近 70 万人在该地区寻求庇护。根据美国研究组织武装冲突地点和事件数据项目的数据，约有 3,000 人被杀。无国界医生组织和苏丹军队都被指控犯有虐待行为，包括针对像穆纳这样的妇女和女孩的性暴力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国驻苏丹人权高专办表示，已收到关于 21 起与冲突有关的性暴力事件的可靠报告。至少有 57 名妇女和女童遭受暴力侵害。社会发展部下属政府打击暴力侵害妇女行为处处长苏利玛·伊沙克 (Sulima Ishaq) 表示，她的团队已记录了 88 起事件，其中 42 起发生在喀土穆，其余发生在达尔富尔地区，这是出于种族动机的袭击事件。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;根据记录了穆纳袭击事件的伊沙克的说法，这些案件只占总数的一小部分。 “这些数字并不代表真正发生的事情”，她说。在这个大多数权力职位都由男性担任的保守国家，“性暴力存在很多耻辱，而且这一切都没有得到充分报道”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;至少 22 名平民在附近的空袭中丧生。苏丹喀土穆&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;卫生工作者和活动人士表示，绝大多数提出虐待指控的女孩和妇女都将矛头指向无国界医生组织。该准军事组织的发言人否认了所谓的毫无根据的指控，并补充说“无国界医生组织强烈谴责一切形式的不道德行为，并断然拒绝对我们部队的指控。”苏丹军队发言人没有回答问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冲突中迄今为止记录最严重的案件之一发生在 5 月 1 日，当时无国界医生部队士兵绑架了 25 名来自苏丹的妇女（年龄在 14 岁至 56 岁之间）。达尔富尔地区的尼亚拉，前往境内流离失所者营地。根据伊沙克所在单位撰写的一份事件报告，他们被带到一家酒店，在那里多次遭到强奸。伊沙克表示，七人拒绝医疗帮助，要么是因为他们害怕受到侮辱，要么是因为他们所遭受的创伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;战争期间的强奸和性侵犯旨在羞辱社区和个人，让他们完全屈服。 ，两者都被视为战争罪和违反国际人道主义法的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在苏丹，武装分子也犯下此类行为，试图迫使平民离开家园，他们占领了家园并将其用作避难所。为苏丹各地性侵犯受害者提供帮助的女权活动家埃纳斯·穆扎米尔 (Enas Muzamil) 表示，他们会在避难所或安置狙击手。她说：“除了抢劫、占领房屋和驱逐居民外，民兵成员还在喀土穆和达尔富尔犯下这些罪行。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在和平时期，医生和卫生工作者会帮助性暴力受害者，但他们的数量正在减少。据记录遇难医务人员的协会苏丹医生初步委员会称，自战斗开始以来，至少有 27 人死于枪击或炮击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一时期至少有 3 名医生被绑架。苏丹中央医生委员会高级成员阿卜杜勒·穆内姆表示，他们与亲民主抵抗组织有联系，或者照顾受伤的战斗人员。他说，由于大多数医疗用品都是通过卫生部分发给平民的，无国界医生组织也在抢劫和征用医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;苏丹战争导致达尔富尔地区战事激烈，导致超过 200 万人流离失所&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;剩下的选择就很少了。苏丹档案组织负责人马哈辛·达哈卜 (Mahasin Dahab) 表示，无数妇女和女孩正在转向社交媒体，该组织利用开源情报来记录侵犯人权的情况。她说，网上活动人士已将一些性侵犯案件提交给当地的非政府组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达哈布表示，无国界医生组织和军队的性侵犯都是历史上有罪不罚的结果。她说，“法律不支持我们关于性别暴力的主张”，并补充说，战前警察侵犯妇女的身体，但现在，“无国界医生组织将性别暴力用作战争武器”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Record 16 PLA warships sailed close to Taiwan in single day, island’s defence ministry says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3228029/record-16-pla-warships-sailed-close-taiwan-single-day-islands-defence-ministry-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/d1840cec-fbd3-41b6-90b0-01c7777e853c_e0bda82a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京上周单日派遣军舰数量创纪录，超过了去年美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台北期间创下的最高纪录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾国防部表示，周六凌晨 6 点之前的 24 小时内，解放军军舰在台湾附近航行了 16 次没有宣布附近有任何大型演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是向台湾派出的 14 艘军舰中数量最多的，因为北京认为台湾是一个分裂的省份，8 月份对佩洛西的访问做出了反应，在周围进行了数天史无前例的实弹演习&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，台湾总统蔡英文在加州会见佩洛西的继任者凯文·麦卡锡后，台湾在一天内派出了多达 12 艘军舰，作为另一场大规模演习的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;随着解放军活动的增加，美国海军巡逻机飞越台湾海峡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;近年来，北京几乎每天都派战斗机和军舰前往台湾自行宣布的防空识别区（ADIZ），因为中美关系在蔡英文的倾向独立的民进党 (DPP) 领导下，这种情况更加恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些访问在佩洛西访问后只会加剧，解放军喷气式飞机更愿意飞越台湾海峡中线，这是双方默认的边界几十年来，直到 2019 年，北京不再承认这条线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着台湾准备 1 月份的总统选举，届时蔡英文将达到其规定的两届任期限制，军事压力也随之增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;最新民意调查显示，民进党候选人赖清德领先，亲北京的国民党（台湾主要反对党）的侯裕义位居第三，落后于相对较新的柯文哲。台湾人民党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据台北国防部称，上周解放军在台湾周边的行动有所增加，每天派出数十架飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;解放军飞机包括轰炸机周三凌晨6点前的24小时内，无人机以及先进的Su-30和J-16战斗机进行了32次飞行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中一些从台湾西南部飞往南部，另一些则越过台湾海峡中线。随后，周四和周五分别有 33 架和 30 架航班沿类似航线飞行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中华民国武装部队已监测局势，并派出[战斗空中巡逻]飞机、海军舰艇和陆基导弹系统，台湾国防部在一份宣布入侵的每日声明中表示，该声明使用了台湾官方名称中华民国的首字母缩写。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六的航班数量降至 15 架，2019 年 10 架。周日和周一 11 点。国防部表示，自周日以来，没有解放军飞机越过中线或进入台湾防空识别区西南段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京国防部和解放军都没有宣布在台湾附近加强军事活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;前解放军教官宋忠平表示，这些航班和军舰的通过反映了解放军计划使台湾周边的演习正常化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此类行为被认为具有政治挑衅性，是北京抗议中美更密切接触的形式。台北和其他政府，特别是华盛顿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京反对台北与其他政府进行官方交往，并认为这种互动是对其主权的挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然美国是台湾的作为最大的非正式盟友，它与大多数国家一样，并不认为这个自治岛屿是独立的。然而，它反对任何强行改变现状的可能性，北京方面也不排除这种可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宋说，加强演习的原因之一可能是美国领导的西方国家最近的行动，包括周三北约公报称中国具有胁迫性，并对防务联盟的利益、安全和价值观构成挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“宣布军事演习并不总是必要的，”宋说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宋尽管财政部长珍妮特·耶伦最近的访问引发了美中经济对话复苏的希望，但美国最新对台军售以及更紧密的美日韩联盟是造成紧张局势的原因。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;总统蔡英文表示，美国的国防法案对台湾安全“至关重要”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新加坡拉惹勒南国际研究学院高级研究员科林·科林 (Collin Koh) 表示，解放军的活动可能与华盛顿的《2024 年国防授权法案》有关，该法案于周五在美国众议院获得通过，其中条款呼吁与台湾进行军事合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在台湾附近部署更多船只而不是在台湾附近投射力量。高说，飞机使解放军能够集中精力过度扩张该岛海军的资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“解放军一直……利用频繁的飞越来逐渐削弱中华民国空军的能力。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来发生的致命军用飞机失事事件揭示了台湾空军的捉襟见肘，他补充说，由于解放军的活动，台湾还不得不将更多的国防预算用于管理费用和维护。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果你是解放军的规划者，那么对台湾军队施加压力的下一个前沿是海军，这不是很合乎逻辑吗？”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[President Macron to push French ‘alternative’ on Pacific trip amid rising China-US tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3228036/president-macron-push-french-alternative-pacific-trip-amid-rising-china-us-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/5ebb8a38-876b-4fbd-bfa1-6ca186253c8e_e4bb044e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;总统伊曼纽尔·马克龙下周将前往西南太平洋，提供“法国替代方案”他的办公室周一表示，该地区中美紧张局势不断升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙之行从新喀里多尼亚开始，新喀里多尼亚是法国的海外领土，在连续三次公投拒绝从法国独立后，该地区陷入严重分裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙的行程从新喀里多尼亚开始。 >;&lt;p>;一位官员表示，他随后将前往瓦努阿图和巴布亚新几内亚，这是此次旅程的“历史性”部分，因为没有一位法国总统曾访问过该地区的非法国岛屿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这位官员表示，马克龙将利用这两站来概述他的印度-太平洋战略，旨在让法国“重新承诺”该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙去年在因取消与澳大利亚的潜艇合同而发生的激烈争吵，使法国成为中美争斗主导地区的制衡大国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不相信霸权，我们不相信霸权。”马克龙在 11 月亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会间隙表示：“我们相信对抗，我们相信稳定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度莫迪被法国马克龙授予最高荣誉&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;2021 年，澳大利亚时任总理斯科特·莫里森 (Scott Morrison) 取消了法国向堪培拉提供潜艇的合同，转而宣布购买美国或英国核动力潜艇的协议，之后法国就开始积极参与该地区事务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位爱丽舍宫官员表示，在中美对峙中，“我们提供的是另一种选择”。这将涉及增加法国的参与，特别是在发展援助和帮助应对自然灾害方面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙对新喀里多尼亚的访问是在他上次访问新喀里多尼亚五年后，也是在新喀里多尼亚拒绝了 19 个月后根据有关该岛群未来的所谓努美阿协议，在第三次也是最后一次公投中宣布独立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙当时对投票结果表示欢迎，称“法国更美丽”，包括太平洋岛屿。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;但他也打开了“过渡时期”的大门。他说，该岛国和巴黎政府现在必须建立“一个共同项目”，“摆脱‘是’或‘否’的二元选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;支持独立的活动人士抵制了投票结果要求推迟，因为在冠状病毒感染人数众多的情况下，“公平的竞选”是不可能的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;投票结果加剧了种族紧张关系，较贫穷的土著卡纳克社区普遍支持独立，而不是较富裕的白人社区。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此时此刻，总统邀请新喀里多尼亚的所有政治代表与他讨论新喀里多尼亚的未来地位以及正在进行的谈判非常重要，”爱丽舍宫官员说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙还将前往新喀里多尼亚东海岸，提请人们注意那里的海岸侵蚀。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US climate envoy John Kerry and China’s Xie Zhenhua hold talks as rival powers seek to contain tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228035/us-climate-envoy-john-kerry-and-chinas-xie-zhenhua-hold-talks-rival-powers-seek-contain-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/1c0ac30e-acf2-479a-836f-40616e62dcb5_a7d2bc9a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;American climate envoy John Kerry and his Chinese counterpart Xie Zhenhua held talks which lasted for several hours on Monday, as the rival powers push to reopen channels of communication amid heightened tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting at the Beijing Hotel came as the two sides tried to get relations back on track following an alleged Chinese spy balloon incident in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s state broadcaster CCTV said a morning session had lasted over four hours and Kerry tweeted in the evening that the talks had just finished for the day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;ve just finished the first day of conversations in Beijing as the entire world is living the reality of daily record-breaking heat,” he wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The climate crisis demands that the world&#39;s two largest economies work together to limit the Earth&#39;s warming. We must take urgent action on a number of fronts, especially the challenges of coal and methane pollution.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neither side had issued an official statement by Monday night, Hong Kong time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xie, China&#39;s chief climate negotiator, said in his opening remarks that Beijing was seeking “substantial dialogue” this week, and that the two envoys could contribute to improving US-China relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kerry, special presidential envoy for climate, said earlier it was “imperative” that the US and China “make real progress” in the months leading up to the COP28 climate talks set for later this year in Dubai, while urging Beijing to cut methane emissions and reduce the impact of coal-fired power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the next three days, we hope we can begin taking some big steps that will send a signal to the world about the serious purpose of China and the United States to address a common risk, threat, challenge to all of humanity created by humans themselves,” Kerry was quoted as saying by Reuters.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can climate envoy John Kerry lower the heat in US-China relations?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Chinese foreign ministry was tight-lipped about the discussions saying information would be released “in due course”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese side will act in the spirit of the meeting between the two heads of state in Bali, have in-depth exchange of views with the US side on issues related to climate change and work with the US to meet challenges,” foreign ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning said, referring to the meeting between Presidents Xi Jinping and Joe Biden last November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kerry is the third senior US official to visit China in recent weeks as the rival powers seek to engage on mutual ground to contain a historic spike in tensions, over issues including trade and access to advanced technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Secretary of State Antony Blinken visited last month, followed less than three weeks later by Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken&#39;s visit, which had been postponed in the wake of the spy balloon row, was marked by meetings with top Chinese officials including President Xi Jinping, Foreign Minister Qin Gang and foreign policy chief Wang Yi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi told Blinken then that the world needed a stable US-China relationship and that the interests of both countries should be valued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And Yellen said she had had “direct, substantive and productive” discussions with China&#39;s new economic team, as she wrapped up her visit earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;El Nino and climate change combining to bake world in heatwaves: scientists&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Earlier, the US State Department said Kerry&#39;s four-day visit to China – which began on Sunday – was aimed at engaging Beijing on “addressing the climate crisis including … increasing implementation and ambition and promoting a successful COP28”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Climate talks between the world&#39;s top two economies and greenhouse gas emitters were among a range of exchanges suspended last year, as Beijing reacted with fury to then House speaker Nancy Pelosi&#39;s visit to Taiwan in August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But there has been a gradual resumption in climate exchanges since then, with Kerry and Xie last meeting at a global forum in Berlin in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kerry, who was US secretary of state from 2013 to 2017, said in Berlin that China had invited him to visit to “find the pathway forward to be able to cooperate in ways that are beneficial to the world”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Global warming and climate issues are among the top priorities of the Chinese government, with Xi earlier stressing the need for cooperation among countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February, Xi told the Communist Party&#39;s central leadership that China “should expand and deepen … joint scientific research on global issues such as climate change, energy security, biosecurity and outer space utilisation”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Food delivery giant Meituan adds more video features to app as Douyin marches into its market with Starbucks and Haidilao]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3228022/food-delivery-giant-meituan-adds-more-video-features-app-douyin-marches-its-market-starbucks-and?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/3102484f-496d-4ad9-a01f-cd8e1e33eb65_f6531a26.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Meituan is adding video features to its app as China&#39;s food delivery services giant braces for competition from Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok, in the online local services sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As ByteDance&#39;s Douyin pushes into the local delivery market, dominant player Meituan has taken a page from Douyin&#39;s playbook by using a mix of video content from live streaming to short videos on its platform to facilitate transactions. Analysts say the move could help Meituan to stay popular among younger consumers who are glued to mobile video content.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Meituan made the move [to launch video content] to cater to [Chinese] consumers&#39; changing preference for viewing and receiving [online] information,” said Zhang Yi, founder and chief analyst at Guangzhou-based market researcher iiMedia. “The younger Chinese have acclimated to … live-streaming and short video content.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brands such as US coffee giant Starbucks and local hotpot chain Haidilao have been quick to utilise Meituan&#39;s live-streaming capabilities, contributing to their increased online sales, according to a statement from Meituan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Starbucks experimented with selling its frappuccino drinks through Meituan live-streaming last month, and increased national sales by 370 per cent year-on-year in the week it held promotions on the app. Haidilao also saw its weekly sales up by 51 per cent over the same period, according to data provided by Meituan.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese premier endorses Big Tech firms in meeting with Alibaba, Meituan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meituan&#39;s dominance in local delivery is being challenged by Douyin, which has over 600 million daily active users. Since last year, ByteDance has been adding links to videos to take advantage of on-demand local services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Douyin last year struck partnership deals with on-demand courier services including JD.com&#39;s Dada Nexus and SFTC from SF Express. It also joined hands with Meituan&#39;s arch-rival Ele.me, which is backed by the Post&#39;s owner Alibaba.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The collaborations are expected to give it access to millions of couriers across the country to fulfil food-delivery orders placed on the short video app, helping it to square up to Meituan&#39;s core market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meituan&#39;s move to experiment with live-streaming follows similar efforts by online retailers, travel agencies, and even fintech companies to attract online Chinese consumers looking for money-saving deals or just entertainment, according to Chen Liteng, an analyst with consulting firm 100ec.cn.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meituan has piloted promotional events dubbed Shen Qiang Shou in Beijing and Shenzhen, mixing the use of “live-streaming, short-form videos, and other formats” to sell flash deals, Wang Xing, co-founder and CEO at the Beijing-based firm, told analysts in its first quarter earnings call. He added that the company would be looking to roll out the services in more regions and “further focus on live-streaming” to stimulate consumer demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, despite the promising initial results, analysts said that Meituan&#39;s relative inexperience in video and the lack of covent variety might be a hurdle for the company in the long run.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Compared to Douyin, Meituan is a green when it comes to video content production, in terms of creativity and copyright,” said iiMedia&#39;s Zhang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meituan needs more variety in its video content to attract more users to its platform, said Zhuang Shuai, founder and chief analyst at e-commerce consultancy Bailian.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Live-streaming content on Meituan is currently hard-wired into selling coupons and deals, he said, and more variety is needed to have a wider impact on the platform.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Does Taiwan risk being Russian ‘revenge target’ if retired missiles are sent to Ukraine?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3228027/does-taiwan-risk-being-russian-revenge-target-if-retired-missiles-are-sent-ukraine?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/08a3223d-d68e-4710-b8da-980740de4aee_3ac79af5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A reported plan by the United States to repurchase hundreds of Hawk air defence missiles from Taiwan so they could be sent to Ukraine&#39;s military has raised concerns over whether such a move would result in Russian retaliation against the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s military officially retired the medium-range anti-aircraft MIM-23 Phase III Hawk missiles made by US arms builder Raytheon Technologies on June 29.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the weekend, Taiwan news reports said the US was interested in buying back the weapons, which first went into service on the island in 1960. Between 1965 and 2017, Hawk missiles had been deployed in 41 combat exercises by the island&#39;s air force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There have been reports that the United States has intended to repurchase the Hawk missiles decommissioned in Taiwan last month and provide them to Ukraine,” as part of the American military aid package, the semi-official Central News Agency said on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US plans US$440 million in arms sale and military vehicle support for Taiwan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The government-funded Public Television Service in Taipei said if the repurchase plan was confirmed, and the appropriate launch systems were acquired, Ukraine would be able to use the weapons, assuming they were still in good condition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Citing an unnamed Taiwanese military source, the island&#39;s China Times newspaper reported that Taipei and Washington had discussed the idea during a recent security meeting about what to do with the hundreds of missiles after they were decommissioned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US agreed to repurchase most of the systems and send them to Ukraine to reinforce its air defence,” the source told China Times following the meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, the island&#39;s defence ministry declined to confirm or deny such a plan, but said “all weapons which are decommissioned and disposed of by the military must comply with relevant regulations”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reported plan to send the missiles to Ukraine to help deter attacks from Moscow has led to concerns that Taiwan might then become a Russian target.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hawk missiles are able to hit warplanes at altitudes up to 20km (12.4 miles) and if they strike something that Russia cares about, Taiwan could become one of its revenge targets,” warned political commentator and former lawmaker Julian Guo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the US has been purchasing older, outdated conventional weapons from other allies, and it would not be surprising to see similar offers made to Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan says it spots two Russian warships off its east coast&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wang Hung-wei, a lawmaker of the main opposition Kuomintang party, said that since the US is Taiwan&#39;s biggest unofficial ally, it is unlikely Taiwan would be able to say no if Washington asked to repurchase the missiles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To prevent us from becoming a target, we should make sure that the repurchased weapons are provided by the United States to Ukraine instead of Taiwan and they should not be considered as our military aid to Ukraine,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chang Yen-ting, a retired air force lieutenant general, said that even though the missiles had been in service in Taiwan for 63 years, they still had a target accuracy rate of 90.4 per cent, which would be an effective boost for Ukraine&#39;s resistance against Russian forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Because the missiles have not only been well maintained but have also remained in good condition, the US can swiftly deliver them to Ukraine without needing to spend time overhauling them,” Chang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chang said that since Taiwan had already retired the Hawk missiles, the US could repurchase them at “extremely low cost,” while the island would “not need to spend time and money on proper disposal of the weapons.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to an April legislative report from the island&#39;s defence ministry, the military originally planned to prepare a budget to have the National Chung-Shan Institute of Science and Technology destroy some 250 Hawk missiles by the end of this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Designed to counteract threats posed by advanced 1950s Soviet-built aircraft, the first Hawk missile went into service in 1959.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US retired its Hawk systems after the Cold War as air defence priorities shifted from aircraft to ballistic missile defence. However the updated Hawk MIM-23 Phase III is still in service in many countries, including Japan and Singapore.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong should allow imported workers on smaller construction projects, as most firms benefit little in new scheme, contractor group says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3228034/hong-kong-should-allow-imported-workers-smaller-construction-projects-most-firms-benefit-little-new?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/3ed8c785-b648-4568-aa5c-d05ccdcd67e4_edeb5787.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A group of Hong Kong contractors has appealed to the government to allow non-local construction workers to join small and medium private projects, arguing most companies in the sector benefited little from a new labour import scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong General Building Contractors Association made the comments on Monday, as the first round of applications for the scheme opened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is room for improvement in the scheme as most the contractors do not benefit in the first round,” association president Terence Ng Choi-wah said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s leader defends plan to import labour after union members stage walkout&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A spokesman from the Development Bureau said it had not received any applications on the launch day, without elaborating whether the lack of interest was linked to most companies being closed because of a No 8 typhoon warning signal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scheme aims to bring in 12,000 construction workers – mainly from mainland China – to the city in the fourth quarter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Principal contractors can submit applications for their own firm, or on behalf of subcontractors, to import workers for 29 types of jobs for skilled labourers and 18 for technicians. The scheme only applies to the construction sector, which faces a serious shortage of workers for projects of all sizes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But authorities earlier said that the first round of imported labour would mainly be allocated to public work projects with a contract value of no less than HK$1 billion (US$128 million).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng, from the association representing more than 200 member companies, said contractors had been struggling to hire workers even after raising salaries significantly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He expected the government to roll out another round of applications for bringing in non-local workers, with no priority given to public works. “Otherwise the scheme will only favour the big construction companies, but leave small and medium businesses like ours helpless,” Ng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Construction Industry Council&#39;s manpower forecast report in February this year, the skilled labour shortage will worsen by 2027, as vacancies will rise from 15,000 to 40,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Importing labour to Hong Kong will ensure &#39;more flights, help bring down airfares&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The industry will face a shortage of more than 25 per cent for jobs such as welders, scaffolders and civil engineers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These jobs were added to the list for the imported labour scheme that includes bar benders and fixers, metal-steel workers, blasting workers, as well as technicians in fire services and site supervision.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bureau said earlier that bringing in workers was “necessary” to “fill in the temporary manpower gap” and avoid any bottleneck caused by a manpower shortage in economic and infrastructure development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong Ping, chairman of the Hong Kong Construction Industry Employees General Union, said hiring new workers had been “extremely difficult”. He noted this meant workers would not object to the new scheme as long as the newcomers were experienced and well equipped with safety training.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will importing 20,000 workers fix Hong Kong&#39;s labour woes?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wong said concerns were not raised by workers about the new arrivals competing with locals, as long as the imported labourers were not hired at salaries lower than the median wage for the position.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under these conditions, bar benders should receive an average of HK$37,800 per month and scaffolders about HK$27,300, according to the Development Bureau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Contractors who apply for the scheme should first try to recruit workers locally and confirm their needs cannot be met before submitting the application.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Development Bernadette Linn Hon-ho last week said it would take around two months to process the applications.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Labour imports for Hong Kong &#39;will not improve local wages, welfare&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ng, as a contractor himself, said he might file an application once the government relaxed the scheme to allow more workers to join smaller projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He explained the arrival of labour from the mainland could potentially solve the city&#39;s manpower shortage, following observations made during his visits to many construction sites over the border that workers there were qualified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have been waiting for quite some years, it&#39;s not an issue to wait another six months to see if the government will give us a quota,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s working population declined by 6 per cent to 3.46 million in 2022 from 3.68 million in 2018. The number of low-skilled workers also fell by 160,000 over the same period. The figures exclude foreign domestic helpers.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwanese presidential contender William Lai’s planned visit to US leads Beijing to lodge formal protest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228025/chinese-foreign-ministry-lodges-formal-protest-us-over-planned-visit-taiwanese-presidential?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 20:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/057c5a26-8431-4b17-9ae8-e5777c42812a_c9082991.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing has lodged a formal protest with Washington over a planned visit to the United States next month by Taiwanese presidential hopeful and vice-president William Lai Ching-te, vowing “strong and resolute” action in response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When asked on Monday about the planned stopover by Lai, the candidate of the independence-leaning Democratic Progressive Party, Chinese foreign ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning said Beijing has made “solemn representations” to the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China firmly opposes any form of official US-Taiwan interactions, firmly opposes Taiwan independence separatists visiting the US under any name or reason and firmly opposes the US indulging and supporting Taiwan independence separatists and their separatist actions in any form,” she told a press conference in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China will closely monitor the situation and take strong and resolute measures to defend national sovereignty and territorial integrity.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taipei has confirmed that Lai will pass through the US in mid-August en route to Paraguay for the inauguration of the new president Santiago Pena.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan defends new biolab, denies claims that US asked it to build bioweapons&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Taiwanese foreign vice-minister Alexander Yui Tah-ray said it was the norm for Taiwanese leaders to stop over in the US when visiting South and Central America.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ll follow the previous usual practice this time and handle vice-president Lai&#39;s transit with the principles of comfort, convenience, safety and dignity,” he told a press conference on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai&#39;s anticipated stopover to the US will come just five months before the 2024 Taiwanese presidential election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He will be the second presidential candidate to visit the US after Ko Wen-je of the Taiwan People&#39;s Party, who spent three weeks there in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai has consistently been leading the polls in the run-up to the election, leaving Ko and Hou Yu-ih, the candidate of the mainland-friendly Kuomintang, vying for second place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan is a long-standing source of friction in the relationship between Beijing and Washington, but in recent years it has emerged as one of the main sources of acrimony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The situation has also caused increasing alarm among US allies in the region, and on Monday New Zealand&#39;s Prime Minister Chris Hipkins became the latest leader to express concern about “rising tensions” in the Taiwan Strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Responding to Hipkins&#39;s comments, Mao said that “the Taiwan question is China&#39;s internal affair, and the most important and crucial thing to maintain peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait is to adhere to the one-China principle.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen visited New York and California, meeting House Speaker Kevin McCarthy on the latter leg of her journey, as part of a tour that also included visits to Guatemala and Belize.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsai&#39;s meeting with McCarthy prompted an angry response from Beijing – which regards any meetings between US government officials and Taiwanese officials as a breach of its sovereignty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It responded with a series of extensive military drills similar to those carried out last August when McCarthy&#39;s predecessor Nancy Pelosi visited the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing regards Taiwan as a breakaway province and has not ruled out the use of force to bring it under mainland control. Most countries, including the US, do not formally recognise the island as a sovereign state but oppose any forcible change to the status quo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pena visited Taipei last week and met both Lai and Tsai, while Beijing sent navy ships and a large group of warplanes including fighter jets and bombers toward the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US Navy patrol plane flies over Taiwan Strait amid increased PLA activity&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;When asked whether Taipei was worried about more military exercises due to Lai&#39;s trip, Yui played down the threat saying Taiwanese vice-presidents have made 10 such visits to the United States before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no reason or cause [for Beijing] to create unnecessary harassment,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 21:20:08 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>