<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘What’s to celebrate?’: muted Pride Month for Asia’s LGBTQ folk in Muslim countries]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3225160/whats-celebrate-muted-pride-month-asias-lgbtq-folk-muslim-countries?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/fe96290c-ce1f-4221-b42a-365f912c213f_323f0b4d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿比尔一边喝着拿铁一边扫视咖啡馆，他说谨慎是每个人的座右铭孟加拉国的男同性恋者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们因为谈论同性恋而被杀，”他告诉《亚洲周刊》，为了安全起见，他使用了化名。 “我想我总是偏执。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿比尔是一名 30 多岁的医生，无论从哪方面来看都是成功的，而且是坚定的中上层阶级，但他仍然无法出柜，担心与自己的关系破裂。家人、朋友、同事和他热爱的工作中的病人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我担心我的母亲无法应付，”他说。 “这不是她的错；这是她的错。”社会和她的亲戚塑造了她的观点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孟加拉国是一个穆斯林占多数的国家，同性关系仍然被定为犯罪，尽管该国带有世俗标签，但保守的宗教价值观仍在流行。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;这意味着 6 月份在全球范围内举行的骄傲月将在不公开的情况下过去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，就像从马来西亚到印度尼西亚、巴基斯坦和马尔代夫等其他穆斯林占多数的国家一样，在印度也有私人聚会。家庭、大使馆、民间社会举办安全空间或在线聚会——这是更广泛的全球 LGBTQ 社区的生命线，促进多样性和接受性对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孟加拉国最新的人口普查记录了 12,629 名跨性别者，但准确的数字是鉴于同性关系被定为刑事犯罪以及相关的社会耻辱，该国 LGBTQ 人群的数量尚不清楚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对他们生命的威胁也是非常真实的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在孟加拉国，LGBTQ 人群人们害怕极端分子和英国时代的法律&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2016 年 4 月，孟加拉国第一本以 LGBTQ 为主题的杂志的联合创始人 Xulhaz Mannan 和活动人士 Mahbub Tonoy 在达卡的一间公寓里被患有以下疾病的男子谋杀：属于基地组织附属机构 Ansar al-Islam 的砍刀和枪支。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Xulhaz 和 Tonoy 奉献了他们所拥有的每一分力量和影响力来改善和保护孟加拉国 LGBTQ 群体，”阿比尔说。 “当我听到这个消息时，我感觉一层保护毯慢慢消失了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;像孟加拉国1.7亿人口中的大多数人一样，阿比尔是一名虔诚的穆斯林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说在两个曲折的几十年里，他成功地打破了所谓的戒律——被强硬派神职人员所推广，他们认为同性恋是一种罪孽并谴责同性关系——同性恋和穆斯林在某种程度上是不相容的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通常在周五祈祷时，我不得不忍受伊玛目在清真寺里发表的仇视同性恋的演讲，”阿比尔说。 “但我也了解到真主是慈悲的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，他不再觉得自己的性取向和宗教信仰是矛盾的，并认为他与神的关系是神圣的。 “我自己寻求服从我的安拉，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但英国殖民时代的一项法律（第 377 条）也规定了对同性关系的态度，该法律将鸡奸定为犯罪行为“违背自然规律”。印度于 2018 年废除了该法律。新加坡去年也废除了该法律。孟加拉国尚未采取行动效仿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“生活在亚洲穆斯林占多数国家的 LGBTQ 人群不断面临政府官员和宗教强硬派的歧视、逮捕和暴力挑战亚洲人权观察组织副主任菲尔·罗伯逊 (Phil Robertson) 表示：“我们决心消除任何与他们先入为主的伊斯兰礼仪观念相矛盾的性取向和性别认同的表达方式。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“面对这种不宽容的针对和虐待行为，LGBTQ 活动人士克服一切困难继续争取自己的权利，这既令人惊奇又值得赞扬。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在亚洲的穆斯林国家，骄傲月一直保持沉默，LGBTQ 活动很容易宗教强硬派和机会主义政客的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;骄傲月前几天，马来西亚当局突袭了瑞士制表商斯沃琪在全国各地的门店，没收了一系列特殊的彩虹色手表，他们声称这些手表正在传播 LGBTQ 信息。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;尽管气氛沉重，马来西亚的酷儿社区一直在举办谨慎的聚会，以避免公众和国家的监督。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这一切都是在地下进行的，因为每个人都害怕被卷入其中。来自吉隆坡的 37 岁纳伊姆 (Naim) 自称是同性恋。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;政治家在万圣节突袭中保持沉默，马来西亚 LGBTQ 群体感到沮丧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这些突袭已具有政治优势，很多人说。去年 10 月，警方突击搜查了一个为吉隆坡 LGBTQ 群体组织的私人万圣节派对，此举被视为在 11 月大选前对保守派的让步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有太多无论如何，庆祝的心情......既然我们总是政客的出气筒，那么在马来西亚有什么值得庆祝的呢？” Naim 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，并非马来西亚 LGBTQ 群体的每个人都对骄傲节表示欢迎。 40 多岁的同性恋男子杰伊 (Jay) 表示，这一事件给社区带来了太多关注，最好“生活在雷达下”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在印度尼西亚马六甲海峡对面，同性恋是一个很普遍的现象。不被视为非法，但亚齐除外，亚齐是唯一执行伊斯兰教法或伊斯兰法的省份。那里的同性关系最高可被鞭打 100 下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在印度尼西亚的其他地方，活动人士表示 LGBTQ 的权利和自由正在被地方权力倒退。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;性取向转变治疗仍然是一种常见的做法这种做法通常是由伊斯兰神职人员在附近的清真寺进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“市长、地区负责人、州长和一些议会议员发表了很多仇恨言论，”长期从事伊斯兰教活动的德德·奥托莫 (Dede Oetomo) 说。印度尼西亚 LGBTQ 权利的时代活动家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与此同时，中央政府也没有为社区提供任何保护，”他说。 “不幸的是，我认为隧道尽头几乎没有光明。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;驱魔、“矫正”强奸：印度尼西亚 LGBT“转变”疗法的内部&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年 12 月印度尼西亚通过了一项有争议的禁止婚外性行为的法律，引起了一些团体的谴责，他们称该法律中的道德条款可能会被用来针对 LGBTQ 群体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚乌里玛委员会，该国伊斯兰教的最高机构去年，学者们敦促雅加达不要效仿亚洲邻国越南和新加坡的做法，这些国家放松了对同性关系的一些严厉法律。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，这个保守派机构进一步呼吁音乐会组织者要求酷玩乐队不要在这支英国摇滚乐队 11 月在雅加达举行的演出中宣传 LGBTQ 主题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《亚洲周刊》在 6 月 4 日曼谷的骄傲活动上采访了印度尼西亚和马来西亚 LGBTQ 人士，因为泰国城市已相对宽容的态度和开放的声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，回到孟加拉国，许多人担心文化战争正在失去进步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两本学校教科书在二月份被下架旨在承认跨性别身份、同性关系和世俗科学的课程改革激怒了伊斯兰团体的抗议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;45 岁的非盈利跨性别权利组织 SadaKalo 的负责人 Anonnya Banik 出生一个男孩，但自认为是希吉拉人 (Hijra)，这是南亚用于指代包括跨性别者和双性人的社区的名称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我和我的丈夫正在努力打破人们对希吉拉人的刻板印象，即他们只是乞丐只属于街头。我们正在帮助他们找到工作、成为企业家并掌握自己的命运，”阿农尼亚说。 “[但是]很多人不喜欢这种进步。他们不想让我们活下去。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“你很有价值”：巴基斯坦变性人学校帮助消除偏见&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;厌倦了蜗牛般的进步Ushan，一个同性恋一名来自达卡的男子去年移居欧洲，为保护身份而化名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管在孟加拉国过着相对无忧无虑的生活，但他表示，抵达欧洲后他感到深深的宽慰。 ”接受，”他说。 “对于像孟加拉国这样的同质社会……指望他们对这样的话题非常乐意是不切实际的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href= &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; 样式=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australian PM Anthony Albanese’s visit to China to be locked in at ‘appropriate time’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3225290/australian-pm-anthony-albaneses-visit-china-be-locked-appropriate-time?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 11:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/3941931b-f66f-4c97-9769-bbfe26e1be36_3ea3f70a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内斯周日表示，他将确定与中国的会晤日期他在“适当的时间”访问，因为他强调了双边贸易的重要性，并对一名在北京被拘留的澳大利亚记者表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于澳大利亚中左翼工党阿尔巴尼斯访问中国的谈判正在进行中政府推动在外交关系低谷期间于 2020 年结束中国对部分澳大利亚产品的非正式禁令和关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及何时进行访问时，阿尔巴尼斯表示“我们将在晚些时候确定日期”合适的时间”，并补充说他的下一次海外访问将于 7 月参加在立陶宛首都维尔纽斯举行的北约峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Albanese 拒绝透露在访问前是否会释放被中国拘留的澳大利亚人，但再次呼吁释放自 2020 年 9 月被捕以来一直被拘留在北京的澳大利亚记者成雷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“成雷……应该被释放，并应该被允许返回澳大利亚，”他说据官方文字记录，天空新闻电视台播出了这一内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿尔巴尼斯补充道，澳大利亚继续主张消除“两个伟大国家”之间的任何贸易障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么中国结束煤炭禁令不太可能提振澳大利亚出口&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“事实是，向中国出口符合澳大利亚的利益，但接受这些出口也符合中国的利益，”他说。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;中国五月份表示，在贸易部长唐·法雷尔 (Don Farrell) 从北京返回几天后，将恢复进口澳大利亚木材。外交部长黄英贤于 12 月访问，几周后煤炭运输恢复。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Argentine dictatorship’s ‘death flight’ plane returned home for a historical reckoning]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3225287/argentine-dictatorships-death-flight-plane-returned-home-historical-reckoning?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 09:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/7aa6b704-e908-4432-8b59-745946f4c8ad_965c55f8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;从佛罗里达州飞往布宜诺斯艾利斯通常需要大约 10 个小时，但涡轮螺旋桨飞机降落在周六的阿根廷飞机并不是普通的飞机。它已经在途中 20 天了，许多阿根廷人急切地更新了飞行跟踪软件，以密切关注其进度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Short SC.7 Skyvan 既没有运载重要的货物，也没有运载 VIP 乘客。相反，这架飞机将成为阿根廷人正视该国 1976 年至 1983 年军事独裁的残酷历史的另一种方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这架飞机在美国发现，是第一架在美国发现的飞机。阿根廷军政府利用法庭将政治犯从天上扔下打死，这是该时期最冷血的暴行之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿根廷政府将把这架飞机添加到记忆博物馆，这是在军政府最臭名昭著的秘密拘留中心。它被称为 ESMA，收容了许多后来从“死亡航班”中被活活扔进海洋或河流的被拘留者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与返航飞机有关的受害者之一是阿苏塞纳·维拉弗洛 (Azucena Villaflor)，他的儿子内斯托尔失踪了，很可能是在独裁统治初期被谋杀的。在他失踪后，她成立了“五月广场母亲”组织，要求提供有关失踪儿童的信息，然后自己被拘留并被杀害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于我们作为家庭成员来说，飞机的安全非常重要比利亚弗洛尔的女儿塞西莉亚·德·文森蒂 (Cecilia De Vincenti) 说：“这将成为历史的一部分，因为尸体和飞机都准确地讲述了发生的事情。” “死亡飞行”飞机。这架飞机后来在佛罗里达州投递过邮件，最近又在亚利桑那州运送跳伞员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塞拉乌多说，在他的整个搜寻过程中，无数人不明白为什么他仍然坚定地专注于寻找军政府的飞机，特别是因为尸体许多独裁政权的受害者仍未被发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些飞机必须被找回，因为它们是一个重要的部分，就像[纳粹]毒气室一样，是一个可怕的工具，”塞拉乌多说。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;阿根廷军政府被广泛认为是 20 世纪 70 年代和 1980 年代统治拉丁美洲大部分地区的最致命的军事独裁政权。它拘留、折磨和杀害涉嫌反对政权的人。人权组织估计有 3 万人被杀，其中许多人失踪得无影无踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中一些人在“死亡航班”上消失了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2012-2017 年的一次广泛审判中，幸存者证实这些航班至少每周进行一次。据目击者称，囚犯经常被告知他们将被释放，有时还被迫随着响亮的音乐跳舞以示庆祝。然后他们接受了所谓的疫苗接种，实际上是一种强效镇静剂。药物生效后，他们被蒙上头罩，捆绑起来，然后登上飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次审判，29名前官员被判处无期徒刑，证明独裁政权将死亡飞行作为一种系统性模式的灭绝。它具体指出，刚刚返回布宜诺斯艾利斯的 Skyvan 被用来杀害 Villaflor 和其他 11 名被拘留者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官表示，不可能知道总共有多少被拘留者被从飞机上扔下来。但据非政府组织阿根廷法医人类学小组称，至少有 71 具疑似死亡飞行受害者的尸体被冲上海岸，其中 44 具在阿根廷，27 具在邻国乌拉圭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1977 年 12 月至1978 年 2 月，五名妇女的尸体被冲上岸，其中包括维拉弗洛、五月广场母亲会的另外两名成员以及两名帮助母亲寻找亲人的法国修女。他们被埋葬时没有确认身份，直到 2005 年他们的尸体才被确认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ceraudo 与记者兼 ESMA 幸存者 Miriam Lewin 合作寻找飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;导致 Villaflor 死亡的航班的飞行员之所以被定罪，部分原因在于 Ceraudo 和 Lewin 2010 年在佛罗里达州劳德代尔堡追踪 PA-51 Skyvan 后发现的飞行日志。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 2012-2017 年审判的检察官梅塞德斯·索伊扎·赖利 (Mercedes Soiza Reilly) 表示：“这些记录引导我们找到了飞行员，从这些名字中，我们能够在为系统性灭绝计划服务的镇压结构中找到他们。” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过艰苦的搜索，包括深入研究飞机观察爱好者跟踪飞机的网站，Ceraudo 和 Lewin 找到了这些飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在五架 Skyvan 飞机中已知曾用于死亡飞行，其中两架在 1982 年与英国的福克兰群岛战争中被摧毁。另外三架飞机于 1994 年出售给位于卢森堡的 CAE Aviation 公司。其中一架飞机被出售给 GB Airlink，该公司用它提供从佛罗里达州到巴哈马的私人邮件服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英国重申福克兰群岛属于英国，阿根廷寻求新的谈判&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这同年，在德文森蒂和其他人权活动人士发起运动后，阿根廷政府决定购买这架飞机，结果发现这架飞机穿着凤凰城的跳伞服。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“多么令人难以置信的故事，对吧？”德文森蒂说。 “因为他们在没有降落伞的情况下被扔了出去，而现在他们却用它来跳伞。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;把这么旧的飞机找回来并不容易。它在牙买加起飞后不久发动机就坏了，在牙买加滞留了两周。由于恶劣天气，它还在玻利维亚滞留了几天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了为军政府受害者伸张正义，自 2006 年大赦法出台后，阿根廷已就独裁时代反人类罪进行了 296 起审判。被击倒了。据检察官办公室称，其中有 1,115 人被定罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;活动人士表示，展示这架飞机将有助于阿根廷人了解独裁政权的现实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“非常重要，因为一代又一代人在民主中出生和生活，没有遭受那些岁月的恐怖。”勒温说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In Malaysia, Umno’s calls to free Najib risk fracturing Anwar’s unity government as first election test looms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3225167/malaysia-umnos-calls-free-najib-risk-fracturing-anwars-unity-government-first-election-test-looms?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/4a9bb8cb-9e8e-44ce-858e-da73fc57d5c9_6fb2e3ad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;本月，要求皇室赦免马来西亚名誉扫地的前总理纳吉布·拉扎克的呼声不绝于耳。穿过巫统总部的大厅，巫统的领导人和代表聚集在那里举行年度大会，讨论即将到来的一系列州选举的准备工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在为期四天的会议上，大家发表了热情洋溢的演讲。在一个局外人看来，连续统治马来西亚六年的政党似乎看到了自己的未来与一位腐败的前领导人的未来深深地交织在一起，这位前领导人成为该国历史上第一个在开始任职时因犯罪而入狱的人。去年 8 月，他因参与掠夺倒闭的 1MDB 主权财富基金而被判处 12 年徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后的几个月里，巫统向国王卑躬屈膝，寻求对纳吉布的全面赦免，纳吉布被发现2020 年，前 1MDB 子公司 SRC International 的 4200 万林吉特（900 万美元）轻易进入他的个人账户，他因违反信托和洗钱罪而被定罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他和他的支持者都坚称自己无罪。并表示这些指控是出于政治动机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在这里，他也在那里[在监狱里]，但我相信他的精神与我们同在，”党主席兼副总理艾哈迈德·扎希德·哈米迪告诉我们他在大会开始时发表施政演讲时，大厅里挤满了人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“巫统最高理事会已做出决议，我们的立场不会改变。当地英文报纸《新海峡时报》援引他的话说：“我们希望为纳吉布伸张正义。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但巫统坚定不移地寻求皇室赦免，这让总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣陷入了困境，因为他需要兼顾这一需要。扩大他的新生联合政府在该国马来穆斯林占多数的吸引力，并实施了他在反对党领袖期间制定了 20 多年的改革议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巫统对马来西亚的不间断统治跨越了该国从英国独立的时期。 1957 年，该党在 2018 年选举中惨败，愤怒的选民因价值数十亿美元的 1MDB 丑闻和不断上涨的生活成本而做出了决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚法官判定该党有罪，“没有刑事不当行为”纳吉布·拉扎克：调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔的希盟（PH）联盟当时在时断时续的政治伙伴、两届总理马哈蒂尔·穆罕默德的领导下，迅速对他的妻子纳吉布采取行动罗斯玛·曼苏尔和巫统高级副手在夺取政权后，新政府急于履行其铲除腐败的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使在希盟政府上任 22 个月后遭遇政治政变，审判仍在继续，不断提醒人们，猖獗的腐败指控继续困扰着纳吉及其倒台的政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果公众对巫统失去信心还有任何挥之不去的疑虑，那么这些疑虑已在最后得到了平息。在今年的全国民意调查中，该党在议会 222 个席位中仅获得 26 个席位，马来选民将自己的命运投向了长期竞争对手泛马来西亚伊斯兰党（PAS），“绿色浪潮”——反映了伊斯兰政党的色彩——横扫了全国。国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;巫统的拯救恩典在十一月大选结束几周后到来。由于没有任何一个政党或联盟赢得足够的席位来赢得统治权，该国现任立宪君主苏丹阿卜杜拉苏丹艾哈迈德沙阿选择安瓦尔担任总理，条件是他与敌对政党组建联合政府。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就这样，巫统再次获得了席位，与安华的希盟联盟中的死敌联手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，旧习惯很难摆脱。虽然安瓦尔联合政府中的各党派有意识地努力，至少看起来是在同一立场上，但巫统坚持追求纳吉的自由，充其量只会造成一种尴尬的伙伴关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“巫统对纳吉的立场使得在即将到来的州选举中，希盟和安华的情况变得复杂，因为该联盟试图将自己定位为廉洁治理的支持者，”政府事务咨询公司 Vriens &amp; Partners 副总监 Shazwan Mustafa Kamal 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种不安巫统对纳吉的立场与希盟试图摆脱这一立场之间的分歧将使竞选变得困难，除非双方一致同意在联合政府竞选期间避免提高纳吉的监禁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计选举将尽早举行下个月将在马来西亚半岛 11 个州属中的 6 个州属实施。结果不会直接影响联邦政府，但民意调查被视为安瓦尔及其政府支持率的晴雨表，尤其是马来人的支持率，他们约占马来西亚 3300 万人口的 60%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计政府的政策方向也将受到州民意调查结果的影响，特别是当掌权者获得马来人支持减少的情况下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这就是巫统在安瓦尔联合政府中发挥关键作用的地方。马来西亚政坛的“古老政党”为其提供了急需的马来代表权，而长期以来，该国的少数族裔华人一直受到指责，据称他们在多种族的希盟联盟中占主导地位，并据称旨在废除马来人的权利和特权.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果没有足够的马来人代表，政府就无法生存，”政府事务和公共政策咨询公司 BowerGroupAsia 的马来西亚董事 Adib Zalkapli 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管它存在弱点，尽管最近的选举表现不佳，但巫统仍然为马来人提供了一个中立或温和的平台，他们可能对土团党或伊党的政治感到不舒服。” 2020 年政治政变后，他担任马来西亚总理 17 个月，随后因政府失去议会多数支持而辞职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊党乘着去年的绿潮，成为议会中最大的政党，拥有 49 个席位分析人士表示，成群结队投票给伊党的马来选民不一定是因为他们接受了伊斯兰党的伊斯兰姿态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据独立民意调查机构默迪卡中心 (Merdeka Centre) 在 2 月份发布的一项民意调查，大约三分之一的马来西亚人最关心的是经济，而只有 2% 的受访者将种族问题视为最关心的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;巫统作为马来西亚主导政党的时间已经到了。巫统会留意改革的呼声吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;巫统在去年的民意调查中遭到马来选民的拒绝，更多是因为人们对其执政期间涉嫌公共资金管理不善的潜在愤怒有关，分析人士说，尤其是在许多人在大流行引发的经济危机中，他们正在努力挽救自己的个人财务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考虑到这一点，继续谈论皇家赦免纳吉布只会损害联合政府的事业。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“如果安瓦尔安排纳吉的赦免，他就有可能疏远希盟自己的支持基础，因为许多人支持希盟推翻纳吉，”新加坡国际事务研究所高级研究员胡逸山说。 “但不安排赦免将会激怒巫统内部的许多纳吉支持者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，安瓦尔的联合政府正面临着如何启动和运行其竞选机制的问题，正如长期以来所认为的那样新伙伴之间的偏见阻碍了制定有凝聚力的战略来赢得选民 — — 尤其是在半岛反对派控制的北部各州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位联合政府消息人士告诉《亚洲周刊》，缺乏沟通希盟和巫统阵营领导人之间的分歧意味着准备工作不协调，尤其是在竞选活动开始之前，采取了不同的信息传递方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“媒体和传播策略一团糟。一些领导者将其作为提升自己的平台，而另一些领导者则希望控制不属于他们职权范围的团队。”该消息人士表示，由于问题的敏感性，该消息人士要求不透露姓名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合政府各组成党派的领导人也迟迟没有向基层成员解释为什么他们现在与长期的政治对手同床共枕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位政府消息人士告诉 This在亚洲的一周里，大多数普通党员仍在努力接受这样一个事实：他们现在必须与领导人几十年来一直诽谤的政党和睦相处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对巫统成员来说尤其是痛处。以及属于希盟联盟的民主行动党（DAP）。多年来，巫统一直指责华人占多数的民主行动党推行反马来议程，甚至声称民主行动党元老林吉祥引发了1969年5月13日致命的种族骚乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一方面，民主行动党长期以来一直将巫统描述为腐败窝点，并坚称由于后者的管理不善，该国最终将成为一个失败的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“仍然存在很多不信任基层之中。消息人士称，需要一段时间才能说服每个人为什么我们都需要共同努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就安瓦尔而言，他的日程安排已挤满了全国各地的露面，以宣传他的马来语和伊斯兰主义者的资格，并让公众相信他的联合政府是最好的选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，总理打破惯例，举办了跨国开斋节庆祝活动，包括在即将举行的六个州举行。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了参观清真寺和伊斯兰学校外，他还接待了国际知名的神职人员穆罕默德·萨拉赫 (Muhammad Salah)、澳大利亚的瓦埃尔·易卜拉欣 (Wael Ibrahim) 和津巴布韦的伊斯梅尔·门克 (Ismail Menk)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在某种程度上，安瓦尔通过利用自己作为现代穆斯林世界领袖人物的品牌，成功地[赢得了一些支持]，”Vriens &amp; Partners 的沙兹万说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“内部存在担忧。安瓦尔阵营认为，最近的支持率调查并不能表明联合政府在过去几个月中取得的进展。为了解决这个问题，安瓦尔一直在不同的州进行旋风般的巡演，利用自己的知名度来尝试获得更多选民的支持。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但单靠个人努力不太可能足以赢得选举尤其是在国盟控制的北部各州，安瓦尔经常被贴上同性恋的标签——这在保守的马来穆斯林中是严格的禁忌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔因鸡奸罪两次入狱，他和他的家人都被指控犯有鸡奸罪。支持者认为，这些指控是为了结束他的政治生涯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年，他在希盟联盟历史性选举获胜后不久，就获得了皇家特赦，并从第二次监禁中获释。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;在叛逃传闻中，安瓦尔能否在州选举前保持联盟完整？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;BowerGroupAsia 的阿迪布表示，让联合政府的各个争吵政党一致行动将是在州选举中取得强劲表现的关键.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为国阵（巫统国阵联盟）和希盟面临的最大挑战是建立统一战线并让选民相互支持，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们已经竞争了几十年，选民可能需要更多时间来适应这个新的政治联盟。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Turned subway into private restaurant’: hungry man sets out 3-course meal on China metro train seats, then tucks in oblivious to fellow passengers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224734/turned-subway-private-restaurant-hungry-man-sets-out-3-course-meal-china-metro-train-seats-then?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/6341fbca-bbca-44da-b915-f1b1fce53739_4b9163b5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一位老人将几个盘子放在地铁座位上的视频吃这些东西在大陆社交媒体上引发了一场关于公共交通上不文明和怪异行为的争论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子被拍到将三个装有不同菜肴的碗和一个盛有米饭的碗放在他旁边的座位上。据新闻网站梦马新闻报道，6 月 18 日，中国东部江苏省苏州地铁系统内的一列火车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;附近其他乘客的存在似乎并没有打扰该男子，因为他正在吃东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该市地铁运营商的一名工作人员表示，地铁列车上禁止饮食，但该男子所在的线路目前正在试运营，免费对乘客开放，因此工作人员不会在车厢内巡逻。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“如果您发现任何违法行为，可以拨打我们的客户服务热线。我们会派人提醒、劝说旅客停止这种行为。”该工作人员说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这段视频在中国大陆社交媒体上引起了轩然大波。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抖音上，4百万人观看，评论2000条。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“地铁上不准大声说话、吃东西、喝水，也不准放手机，这是常识。这是一个封闭的空间，你的行为显然会影响到别人。所以请考虑一下别人的感受。”一位网友评论道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位网友则表示：“他真的把地铁变成了自己的餐厅。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但也有人没想到，男子的行为有问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我以前没有坐过地铁。 I don&#39;t know if you are allowed to eat, but I thought eating was OK, just like on trains,” one person said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you think he did something wrong, let him know. I don&#39;t think it&#39;s necessary to film him and upload the videos online to be subject to various public remarks,” the person added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person sympathised with the man and said: “Maybe he had a tight schedule, or maybe he hadn&#39;t eaten for a long time. Although his behaviour is not civilised, our society should show more tolerance.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inappropriate passenger behaviour on the subway often trends online in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the end of last year, a woman in eastern China crawled like a dog on a subway train full of passengers while two companions walked beside her taking videos that they said were performance art. A subway staffer later persuaded them to leave..&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Shanghai, a young boy pestered other passengers to hold hand rings and play swing games with him on a subway train in 2021. His mother, standing nearby, did not intervene and instead smiled and encouraged the boy.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba Cloud founder Wang Jian says Paris Olympics 2024 presents great opportunities and challenges]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225162/alibaba-cloud-founder-wang-jian-says-paris-olympics-2024-presents-great-opportunities-and-challenges?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/23/87fb41e2-2291-424a-a9a8-55b55fb3b719_141d26c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The 2024 Summer Olympics in Paris will present huge opportunities and challenges for Alibaba Cloud, which is the event organiser&#39;s chosen partner to provide next-generation broadcasting, logistics planning and sensorless tracking services, according to founder Wang Jian.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The event gives the Chinese tech company a unique platform to showcase its cloud-based technologies to the world, at a time when rising geopolitical tension between China and the West is putting its tech companies under greater pressure and scrutiny.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Cloud won the exclusive deal to become the International Olympic Committee&#39;s (IOC) official cloud services partner after beating Amazon Web Services in 2017. The deal, including the provision of cloud-based broadcasting, big data analytics, logistics support and sensorless tracking of athletes&#39; performance on the field, will run until 2028 at the Summer Olympics in Los Angeles, Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Cloud is a subsidiary of Alibaba Group Holding, which also owns the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Alibaba Cloud founder points to skies for Hong Kong moonshot project to lure talent&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While the Chinese company has already provided cloud-based support for both the Tokyo Olympics 2020 and the Beijing 2022 Winter Olympics, next year&#39;s event in Paris will be much more significant, Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the first time, cloud-based broadcasting will replace the traditional satellite-based broadcasting infrastructure “on a full scale”, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We hope this could be a catalytic moment to make cloud technology mainstream, just as [Nikola] Tesla did for [alternating current] electricity at the Chicago World&#39;s Fair in 1893,” he said, referring to the use of electricity to light the fair, which heralded the age of modern power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang acknowledged that rising geopolitical rivalry between the West and China has further complicated the situation. French media earlier reported that the host country&#39;s National Agency for the Security of Information Systems (ANSSI) had expressed concern and tried to push back on the IOC&#39;s decision to make Alibaba Could its worldwide partner, fearing it could give the Chinese company access to sensitive data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said by working closely with the IOC, Alibaba Cloud will “definitely” be the exclusive cloud services provider for next summer&#39;s Olympics, adding that the 2028 Los Angeles Olympics would present an even greater challenge politically. But Wang hopes that success in Paris will help to dispel any data security concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All licensed broadcasters for the 2024 Paris Games will receive live footage exclusively through a cloud infrastructure built by Alibaba and the Olympic Broadcasting Services (OBS).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Cloud will also provide other technologies to help the host city optimise logistics planning and streamline backstage operations. For example, they are working with the IOC to build a cloud-based simulation model that can help Paris authorities see how the selection of different venues and traffic arrangements could affect local communities and businesses. The host city will then be able to choose the most cost-effective option and reduce operating costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Alibaba co-founder Joe Tsai to take over as chairman from Daniel Zhang&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Another example is using 3DAT (3D Athlete Tracking) technology jointly developed by US chip giant Intel and Alibaba Cloud to gather biomechanical data on athletes via cameras powered by artificial intelligence. This will allow sensorless tracking of the athletes on the field, improving efficiency and cost.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This represents a major paradigm shift,” Wang said. “It will be a historical moment for me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang is widely seen as the man who laid the technological foundations for Alibaba&#39;s emergence as an e-commerce giant. When Wang joined Alibaba in 2008 from Microsoft Research Asia, the concept of cloud computing was still in its infancy. He built up the group&#39;s cloud business from scratch despite repeated internal questioning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his 2016 book Being Online, Wang details his experiences developing the cloud business with the trust of co-founder Jack Ma. Ma wrote in a forward for the book that “when I first met Dr Wang, I was mesmerised by his understanding of the internet and hated the fact that I could not have met him earlier”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Cloud is now the biggest cloud provider in China, despite seeing its market share fall to 32.6 per cent in the second half of 2022 from 34.5 per cent in the first half, according to an April report by research firm IDC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pulling off the job at next year&#39;s Paris games will not be an easy task, as it requires major operational changes from the IOC and broadcasters, Wang said. Geopolitical tensions and local regulations pose additional difficulties, he said, adding that compliance challenges include completing security tests and putting in place local support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It takes time to figure [all this] out,” Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba is currently in the midst of a sweeping reorganisation, which will see the cloud unit spun off into an independent business. Cloud, one of the company&#39;s most important growth engines, will be listed in 12 months, with Alibaba&#39;s Group chairman and CEO Daniel Zhang Yong, relinquishing those roles in September to focus solely on the cloud business, which he already heads.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s transgender teens struggle with confusion and pain as specialised healthcare is for over-18s only]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3225277/hong-kongs-transgender-teens-struggle-confusion-and-pain-specialised-healthcare-over-18s-only?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/fcf19063-e650-42df-8db9-3977be035050_c224ca80.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong teenager Yuki Liu was born male but sensed from childhood that being a boy was not right.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The child dreaded approaching puberty, and resented the changes that came, such as a deepening voice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The feeling became more intense. I could not stop crying and I would hit my head or cut my wrist,” Liu, now 18, recalled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I could not accept myself living as a male. It was agonising whenever I thought of such a future. I realised then that identifying as transgender felt right to me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By 15, Liu felt an urgent need for help in transitioning to a girl. But although gender-affirming healthcare was available in Hong Kong, providing social, psychological, behavioural or other medical help, people under 18 were not eligible for such treatments at public hospitals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although Liu already considered herself transgender, she was not ready to come out to her parents, who could have given consent and paid for treatment available in the private sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Children and teenagers struggling with questions about their gender have little access to public healthcare services and social support in Hong Kong, although doctors in private practice have seen growing demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For teens such as Liu, the lack of professional help only adds to obstacles they face at home, in school and medical settings.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Rights of 2 transgender men breached over ID cards, top Hong Kong court rules&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Transgender people experience gender incongruence, which means they do not identify with the gender assigned to them at birth. That may lead some to also experience gender dysphoria, which refers to psychological distress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To resolve the issues they face, they may undergo various aspects of gender transition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Social transition would mean changing their names, pronouns and the way they express themselves. Legal transition would see them changing their names and gender on official identification. Medical transition would mean undergoing hormone treatment or gender reassignment surgery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the United States, new diagnoses of gender dysphoria among patients aged six to 17 almost tripled from 15,172 in 2017 to 42,167 in 2021. In the United Kingdom, there were more than 5,000 referrals to the government-run Gender Identity Development Service in 2021-22, up from under 250 a decade earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Hong Kong, transgender people aged 18 or above may go to the Gender Identity Clinic (GIC) established at Prince of Wales Hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hospital Authority had no available figures of transgender people receiving services at the GIC, but service attendances rose from 950 in 2019 to 1,131 in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those under 18 may only receive child and adolescent psychiatric services at public hospitals, but health authorities could not provide data on this group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the private sector, psychiatrists can prescribe hormone drugs to achieve a more masculine or feminine appearance and help reduce gender dysphoria, or refer patients to endocrinologists more specialised in hormone therapy.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trans activist in Hong Kong court battle for ID card gender change publishes book&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Psychiatrist Dr Gordon Wong Chun-bun, who has treated gender dysphoria for four years in the private sector, has noticed a rising number of transgender teenagers among his patients and attributed it to greater awareness and access to information.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“More people may also come out and share about their journey on social media, which may convey that coming out and transitioning are not as scary as others may think,” he said. “There is also more information about how and where to seek help.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said around a dozen of his new referrals each year were transgender young people, and the youngest was 12.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They may be just the tip of the iceberg as many may not have the financial resources to see private doctors,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another psychiatrist in private practice, Dr Cheung Ngo, said he saw 10 to 20 new patients younger than 18 each year with gender issues, the youngest aged 15 to 16.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The onset of gender incongruence can begin in childhood. It is ideal for transgender people to seek help before adulthood,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In reality, however, many teenagers did not reveal their situation to their parents, he said, while many might not be able to afford sending their children to the private sector, where treatments could cost HK$1,500 to HK$2,000 a month. Some parents might refuse to allow their children to get such treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zephyrus Tsang, a trans male activist and doctor who co-founded Quarks, a peer network for trans youth, said he had met a number of secondary school students who identified as transgender in recent years, the youngest aged 14.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most had not received any medical services as they were not supported by family. Many trans people might experience mental health issues or suicidal thoughts, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Dangerous to buy hormone drugs online&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Unable to access gender-related healthcare in the public sector, Yuki Liu, who had begun using the pronouns she and her, bought hormone drugs online to appear more feminine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Luckily, the medicines were not counterfeits,” she said. “I have a friend who was receiving treatments at the government&#39;s gender identity clinic so I just followed her prescription.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheung warned that without a doctor&#39;s prescription, patients might take a higher dosage of drugs than they needed and this could be risky.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For hormone drugs, when you take the optimal dose, the changes produced in the body occur very slowly. When people don&#39;t see the changes they desire, they may keep raising the dosage, which can harm their liver,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“People may also not know the correct way to take the medicine. Some drugs are recommended to be placed under the tongue to minimise the impact on the liver.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dr Rose Ting Zhao-wei, an endocrinologist in private practice who has been seeing trans patients for around six years, said she also gave puberty blockers to teenagers to allow them time to explore their gender identity before beginning hormone therapy. The treatment was costly, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some trans women patients had been taking contraceptive pills, which could induce a similar effect as hormone drugs, before seeing her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ting said taking hormone medicines without a doctor&#39;s prescription might lead to higher risk of blood clots in the veins.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong transgender man in legal push to access public toilets without fear&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Psychiatrist Wong said transgender youths faced multiple disadvantages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Youth itself means being in a disadvantaged group. They have limited resources and autonomy and rely on others financially,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Trans people are another disadvantaged group, facing discrimination and stigma. They may worry that their parents will not accept them and kick them out of their home, and they may be bullied at school.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said delaying gender-affirming treatment could result in more irreversible changes that may aggravate the teenagers&#39; anxiety and unhappiness, and even affect their school performance and social interaction.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Lack of support for parents&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yuki Liu tried to keep her identity a secret even after her parents discovered her feminine clothes and wigs in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She showed signs of emotional distress for two years before her mother encouraged her to open up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cherry Liu, 50, who works in the business sector, recalled: “While hugging Yuki, I told her, &#39;No matter if you are a girl or a boy, you are still my precious baby. Your health and happiness matter the most&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although she was supportive, she said the process of accepting Yuki&#39;s identity was painful for both parents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We had many doubts. We had no idea why it happened as we had not observed any signs when she was younger,” she said. “But at the same time, I could see that my daughter has become a lot happier.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s top court urged to grant transgender right for ID card change&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;She also had many concerns about Yuki&#39;s future, including possible side effects from surgery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I simply wish she will find someone who will love and cherish her,” the mother said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuki was more fortunate than Adam, who began transitioning from female to male at 18. He underwent hormone therapy, which deepened his voice, and surgery to remove breast tissue and create a more masculine chest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Without his parents&#39; support, he went through it alone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have not succeeded in having an in-depth conversation with my parents on this matter,” said Adam, now 21.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The only time we spoke about my identity was when they accompanied me to see the psychiatrist, but then they had a huge reaction and could not accept it. They pretend nothing has happened and avoid talking about it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bobo*, who used to work in the banking industry, said she felt helpless when her 14-year-old daughter told her she identified as a boy and had suicidal thoughts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was able to put her child&#39;s well-being first and accepted the major changes that followed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But her husband, conservative and unable to accept the situation, insisted on calling their child his “daughter”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My son would even bang his head against the wall,” recalled Bobo, in her 50s. “My husband insisted we could change our child&#39;s thoughts. Then my son began to cut his wrist and had nightmares in which he was being buried in pink flowers, lifeless in a dress.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the beginning, she had no idea how and where to seek treatment for her child, and did not know what might trigger emotional distress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I was very scared every day that he would harm himself,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Almost a decade later, Bobo now considers herself the mother of a trans man, 23. After her unwavering efforts, her husband came around.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I told him you either accept having a son or lose our child,” she said. “If we, as family members, do not accept him, no one is going to accept him. Son or daughter, we will love him the same.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;I am by nature a girl, not a boy&#39;: life-changing Leslie Cheung movie&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Bobo said she hoped there would be more support for parents as it would be crucial for the children&#39;s transition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without knowing what to do with their children, some may choose to ignore them. A lack of acceptance from parents along with discrimination from outsiders could mean huge humiliation to the child,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sakura Lam, a public education officer for advocacy group Gender Empowerment, said parents experienced intense emotions when they found out their children were transgender.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recognising the problem, the group started a support group for parents of transgender children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The pain of the parents is not less than that of their children,” Lam said. “Some may worry about their children&#39;s future. Some may blame themselves and even think they ate something wrong during pregnancy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even when parents were supportive, she added, other family members might not be and that could be difficult, too.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;In school, &#39;everything was grim&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yuki Liu remembers her secondary school days as a grim part of her life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was not allowed to wear the girls&#39; uniform or keep her hair long, was teased and bullied by some of her classmates and teachers, and even the social workers did not know much about dealing with transgender teens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I always burst into tears during lessons,” she recalled. “My class teacher would scold me for my hair length and sometimes treated me unfairly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In Form Three, some classmates would distribute my photos and laugh at me. They would say I was disgusting and tell me not to go near them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong transgender man behind legal victory slams inaction over ID card changes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Fortunately, in higher forms, she found a group of friends who were supportive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They were the little beam of light in the grim environment at school,” she said. “Teenagers are surrounded by either home or school. If the environment in school and at home is bleak, along with feeling dreadful when looking at our bodies, everything will be grim.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu&#39;s mother said that after she appealed to the principal and teachers, the school allowed her daughter to use the disabled toilets, but refused to change the “disabled” sign to “gender-neutral” or “unisex”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My daughter is not disabled,” she said. “They said if she preferred, she could use the toilet at a nearby shopping centre during lunch.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Education University counselling professor Diana Kwok Kan, who specialises in the mental health of the LGBTQ community, said Hong Kong schools lacked guidelines on how to handle students with doubts in their gender identity and gender dysphoria.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said it would be ideal if medical professionals treating transgender teenagers could collaborate and work with school social workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Schools had different attitudes to transgender students, and she had to frame her communication with teachers based on each school&#39;s religious background or position on gender matters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She suggested taking a leaf from Taiwan, which passed a law in 2004 requiring all schools to provide gender education and teachers to receive relevant training.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking forward, Yuki Liu said she hoped to undergo gender reassignment surgery before finishing university.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I wish I can live a simple life and never be distressed by gender-related matters,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;*Names changed at interviewees&#39; request.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Preserving Fanling golf course or building public housing is not a binary choice]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224997/preserving-fanling-golf-course-or-building-public-housing-not-binary-choice?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/23/2e784220-f736-45e1-bfd8-ad3c03d50aa7_0580b788.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;I do not play golf and have not even taken a swing at a driving range. I have made golf jokes about how I did not want to spend my time hitting a small ball into a small hole very far away, or how golf commentators are always soft-spoken as they do not want to wake the television audience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, real knowledge is knowing the extent of one&#39;s ignorance. Golf must be a great sport, given that so many people embrace it, and a great place to conduct business, with so many deals struck on the course – never mind the US$10 billion global market for golf clubs alone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Architects and designers always have to learn new things, sometimes on a very steep learning curve, going from amateur to semi-expert in a short time. That was what happened to me when I had to design a golf course in my third and final year of graduate school. I learned about birdies and bogeys, fairways and the rough, as well as player handicaps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Golf course design is a science even though it may not appear so, possibly because of the manicured grass and connection to nature. An 18-hole course needs to provide a variety of challenges, including each hole&#39;s playing length, terrain, altitude and surrounding obstacles. Lose any of the holes and the course is ruined.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A truly great course with an appropriate legacy carries its value because of the full experience it offers. This is what attracts the Aramco Team Series, the World City Championship or any international golf tournament. This is the beckoning of “Hello Hong Kong”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong Golf Club general committee captain Andy Kwok Wing-leung has emphasised that keeping the three 18-hole courses at Fanling is critical in hosting reputable tournaments and bringing in the LIV Golf tour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While we might not know the Saudi Arabia-backed LIV tour&#39;s requirements for Hong Kong to become a host city, we do know that confirming such a deal would drive the economy and tourism much more than the signing of any symbolic memorandum of understanding during Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu&#39;s Middle East trip in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Enter the question of public housing. To build or not to build? Build, of course, but why does it have to be that particular plot of land?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a society where the wealth gap is wide and opinions are polarised, issues that involve the pastimes of the affluent and public well-being will be sensitive and destined to upset somebody, whether it is district councillors, environmentalists, golfers, the underprivileged or others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No policy can please every stakeholder. However, in an open society, all voices should be heard and considered so decisions can be made using critical thinking and a balance of interests. This process warrants debate, negotiation and compromise.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong needs more, not less, public engagement in project planning&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;If Secretary for Development Bernadette Linn Hon-ho merely denounces the opposing opinions expressed during the Town Planning Board&#39;s recent public consultation hearing – as she believes only those who are against the government&#39;s proposal attend such meetings – why host a hearing at all?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Linn also said that, “We expected to receive a lot of objections during the hearings. It&#39;s not surprising and we should not change our original ideas only because there are more objections.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If Linn learned anything from Carrie Lam Cheng Yuet-ngor, who was development secretary from 2007-2012, she would know that making a firm, unwavering stance without listening does not make her strong and determined. On the contrary, stakeholders will view her as arrogant, stubborn and out of touch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The best leaders are those who listen and make decisions after hearing all the evidence. We have learned hard lessons in recent years, and we should know that we are setting ourselves up for failure if we do not give ourselves room to back down and reconsider.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Withdrawing the requisition for land from the Hong Kong Golf Club would not be a concession but a considered, empathetic move. Stepping back from a former administration&#39;s proposal would show how we have evolved and become smarter and more rational. Times have changed since the idea to build public housing on the golf course was proposed in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If Linn believes opposing voices are over-represented or mostly come from club members, she can consider forming an independent expert panel with the city&#39;s best architects and urban planners, or study in detail the alternative proposals and sites put forward.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Destroying historic Hong Kong golf course for flats would be supremely foolish&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Perhaps a full disclaimer is necessary. I support public housing, social equality and the Society of Community Organisation and am not a member of any golf clubs. However, being supportive of public housing does not mean we have to bulldoze what the city&#39;s elite have built, just as being supportive of keeping the golf course in its entirety does not mean we are turning our backs on people who need public housing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the government cannot find enough land to build the needed housing while keeping a legacy golf course with great ecological and economic value intact, it means we haven&#39;t fully employed our problem-solving skills and creative thinking. This might be where an independent expert panel can offer fresh ideas for the Development Bureau and Civil Engineering and Development Department.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this new chapter for Hong Kong, there is no need to punish anybody or any private clubs to prove a point. Housing and land-use issues do not have to be a zero-sum matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pilgrims perform final rituals in Mecca, Saudi Arabia before heading to Mina for haj]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3225281/pilgrims-perform-final-rituals-mecca-saudi-arabia-heading-mina-haj?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 06:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/d044f0d8-a8c0-4dba-81c0-217bc939236e_9f46563f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Pilgrims streamed into Mecca&#39;s Grand Mosque in Saudi Arabia on Saturday to perform their final rituals before heading to Mina in preparation for the haj, the fifth pillar of Islam and one of the largest religious gatherings in the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They moved through the white marble courtyards of Islam&#39;s holiest site to perform the tawaf, the walking circuit around the Kaaba, the cube-shaped structure covered in a black, gold-embroidered cloth, their fervent recitations ringing through the air.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Saudi&#39;s US$700 billion wealth fund is a fan of Alibaba, Flat Glass Coupang&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;People on the ground floor closest to the Kaaba shuffled due to the sheer number of participants. Those on the upper floors were able to walk more briskly, even run. Pilgrims raised their hands in supplication, took selfies or video, and phoned their relatives as they performed the tawaf.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They then walked or ran between two hills in a re-enactment of Hagar&#39;s search for water for her son, Ismail, a story that occurs in different forms in Muslim, Christian and Jewish traditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pilgrims must enter a state of spiritual purity, known as ihram, for the haj.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Men wear seamless white robes, a rule intended to promote unity among rich and poor. Women cover their body and hair.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In between rituals and the five daily prayers, which bring the area to a solemn standstill, pilgrims sought out shade and flocked to the many shops and air-conditioned malls encircling the Grand Mosque to relax before the arduous days ahead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Saudi Arabia has restored full pilgrim capacity for this year&#39;s haj, following three years of dramatically reduced numbers owing to the coronavirus pandemic, with more than 2 million Muslims expected to take part.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think this year (the) crowd is too much” said Mahboub Morshed, a 42-year-old software engineer from Bangladesh, referring to the thinner attendance of previous years. “But the government and this management (Ministry of Haj and Umrah) is trying to manage this very smoothly.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US, allies consult as security crisis unfolds rapidly in Russia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225282/us-allies-consult-security-crisis-unfolds-rapidly-russia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 07:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/71e17c9d-3a3a-470a-b4d0-1ff681240f66_87ad780c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden and top administration officials coordinated with more than half a dozen Western allies on Saturday as developments in Russia that pitted President Vladimir Putin against a mercenary leader who had played a key role in the Kremlin&#39;s war against Ukraine unfolded at a bewildering pace.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around the time of reports that Yevgeny Prigozhin, head of the private military outfit Wagner Group, had agreed to leave Russia as part of a deal that would spare him prosecution in Russia, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said in a call with Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba that Washington&#39;s support for Russia&#39;s neighbour “will not change”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The brief readout from the State Department also said that Washington “will stay in close coordination with Ukraine as the situation develops”. Blinken delivered roughly the same message in a separate call with Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin delivered a similar message in separate calls with his counterparts in Canada, France, Germany, Poland and Britain, according to a readout by Pentagon press secretary Pat Ryder.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier in the day, Biden spoke with his counterparts in Germany, France and Britain, a call in which the four leaders “affirmed their unwavering support for Ukraine”, according to the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The White House said Biden, who departed Saturday afternoon for the presidential retreat Camp David, and Vice President Kamala Harris were briefed by his national security team.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those officials included Blinken, Austin and National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan, who travelled to Camp David with the president, Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Mark Milley, Director of the Office of National Intelligence Avril Haines, CIA Director William Burns and US Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russian mercenary boss Prigozhin to move to Belarus under Wagner deal, Kremlin says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The White House statement said Biden and Harris would receive briefings throughout the day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Biden administration officials had yet to offer any assessments of the situation in Russia, several members of the US Congress speculated on the fast-moving events, offered support or both.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Florida&#39;s Marco Rubio, a Republican member of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, suggested that Prigozhin&#39;s move to Belarus under a deal that the Kremlin said was brokered by Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko did not necessarily mean that Putin had prevailed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If in fact Wagner is standing down it is likely because [Army Chief of Staff Valery Gerasimov and Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu] are being replaced by officials loyal to Prigozhin,” Rubio said on Twitter. “That would make him the most powerful man in Russia now.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former US Ambassador to Nato Kurt Volker made a similar assessment in a CNN interview earlier on Saturday, before the Kremlin announced Prigozhin&#39;s move to Belarus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think it&#39;s beginning to unravel there in Russia,” Volker said. “I think that this is really going to be a struggle of the state versus Prigozhin. I have to think the state is still going to pull it out, but I think it&#39;s the end for Putin.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Volker added that Nato should take the opportunity of the apparent rift between Putin and Prigozhin, whose forces had taken vast swathes of Ukrainian territory that Kyiv&#39;s forces have recently begun to claw back, to deliver significantly more weapons to Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We ought to help the Ukrainians with some types of equipment we have still not given them yet, like long range artillery and cluster munitions and aircraft, because now is the time for the Ukrainians to really press forward,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And then Nato really needs to make clear that it is going to bring Ukraine as a member for real this time,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;California Representative Ted Lieu, who sits on the House Foreign Affairs Committee, tweeted that the “escalating conflict between the Wagner Group and the Russian military would not be occurring if Russia&#39;s illegal invasion of Ukraine was going well. Clearly it is not.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk: MMA cage fight with Mark Zuckerberg ‘might actually happen’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225283/elon-musk-mma-cage-fight-mark-zuckerberg-might-actually-happen?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 07:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/1864e514-a4ab-4d23-9153-868d571e84b8_419950f6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Elon Musk said on Saturday he will start training if the mixed martial arts (MMA) cage fight he has provoked with fellow billionaire media mogul Mark Zuckerberg takes shape.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Twitter owner Musk tweeted on Tuesday he was up for a cage match in Las Vegas with Zuckerberg, chief executive of Facebook parent Meta, who has trained in jiu-jitsu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I haven&#39;t started training yet. So if this does happen, I will,” Musk said in a talk on Twitter with Ashlee Vance, the author of a book on Musk and the space race.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The match “might actually happen” said Musk while attending a birthday party in Europe, adding it was possible that it could go badly if Zuckerberg takes the match seriously.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk also said SpaceX has made well over 1,000 changes to Starship following the vehicle&#39;s first test launch in April, which failed to reach orbit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Space Exploration Technologies Corporation has changed how the vehicle operates on its path to orbit and it now stands a much improved chance of success with its second attempt, according to its chief executive officer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So I think the probability of the next flight working – or getting to orbit – is much higher than the last one,” Musk said. “Maybe it&#39;s like 60 per cent; it depends on how well we do at stage separation,” he said on a Twitter Spaces on Saturday with Bloomberg senior reporter Ashlee Vance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Investment in the Starship project is likely to approach US$3 billion this year, Musk said. Starship is SpaceX&#39;s next-generation rocket, designed to carry cargo – and eventually people – to deep space destinations such as the moon and Mars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk announced that SpaceX has “made a sort of late breaking change” to the way that Starship separates during launch, when the large Super Heavy booster breaks free from the Starship spacecraft mid-flight. He noted that SpaceX has decided to do hot staging, a process where the engines on the Starship vehicle ignite while the Super Heavy booster is still attached.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Meet the newest employee at Elon Musk&#39;s SpaceX. He&#39;s 14.&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“This is something that the Soviets and Russians have used in their space designs,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During Starship&#39;s first test flight, which launched from SpaceX&#39;s Starbase facility in Boca Chica, Texas, US the rocket successfully cleared its launch pad, but suffered multiple engine failures during the vehicle&#39;s climb.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Starship was meant to separate from Super Heavy, the two vehicles remained attached as the entire rocket spun out of control. SpaceX was forced to activate the rocket&#39;s flight termination system, which blew up the rocket.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk was pressed on whether his commitment to space exploration has wavered in light of his acquisition of Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re trying to get to Mars as fast as possible,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk declined to discuss several topics broached by Vance, including the status of his recently created artificial intelligence company that might rival OpenAI.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said it would be “illegal” to talk about plans for a possible initial public offering for Starlink, SpaceX&#39;s constellation of satellites that provide high-speed internet access in remote areas.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>