<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong police charge mainland Chinese mother over abandoning 12-year-old son at hospital]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3229406/hong-kong-police-charge-mainland-chinese-mother-over-abandoning-12-year-old-son-hospital?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 16:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/7e8ed5e2-e4d3-4884-b5a0-226f25e7934c_e14f1f70.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港警方周日指控一名中国大陆母亲虐待或忽视孩子本月早些时候，她的 12 岁儿子被发现被遗弃在医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方透露，这名 37 岁的陈姓母亲将于周一被带到九龙城法院接受首次听证会。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方称，该女子于周六从内地入境香港时被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;12岁弃婴的母亲“愿意返回香港”接人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;男童陈希尔顿，持有香港身份证，7月21日在油麻地广华医院被发现，没有受伤。他被发现戴着黑框眼镜，身穿深蓝色短袖T恤、卡其色短裤和黑色凉鞋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方早些时候的调查显示，这对母子是通过高速过境的。 7月18日乘火车前往油麻地佐敦道入住宾馆。凌晨 5 点，她带他去了医院，并告诉工作人员他有咳嗽和腹泻。男童告诉院方，母亲将他独自留在病房。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他已暂时入住屯门儿童青少年院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;针对事件，行政长官李家超已责成当局确保男孩的福祉，并指示警方调查这对父母是否面临法律后果。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Crumbling buildings show Hong Kong needs to focus on important safety issues]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3229261/crumbling-buildings-show-hong-kong-needs-focus-important-safety-issues?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/7a5388d5-51c6-4258-93e2-79318d9aef16_1b98b774.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;两个月前，我收到屋宇署关于防盗门的法定通知在我公寓的后门。这有点令人惊讶，因为自从我买下这套公寓以来，四分之一个世纪以来，那扇门从未有过任何修改。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，因为有人不厌其烦地签发了法定许可证通知，包括常见的一系列可怕威胁——巨额罚款、长期监禁等等——我认为最好去看看。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;门的问题立即显而易见。这是一种老式的外开式门窗，大概是前任主人几十年前安装的，一旦发生火灾可能会很危险，因为打开门窗会挡住狭小的后厅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;门是非法的，必须离开。快速致电承包商后，他们拆除了旧门，订购并安装了一扇新的安全门，并向屋宇署提交了一份进度报告。所有这一切都是在六周内完成的。那么，一切都很好，只是心中挥之不去的怀疑，我们大家是多么幸运，能够在潜在危险的情况下生存了这么多年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;似乎并不是每个人都那么谨慎和谨慎。及时处理此类事务。本月早些时候，旺角一座建筑物三天内两次发生混凝土坠落事件，第一次造成停放车辆内的人受伤，第二次造成道路堵塞。此后又发生了涉及其他建筑物的案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在接下来的几天里，媒体报道揭示了令人震惊的情况。首先，屋宇署于2014年向该大厦发出强制检验令，最终委任认可人士进行勘察，并就需要进行的补救工程拟定报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;工程招标工作已到位，但尚未指定承包商。在情况被认为严重到足以发出检查令九年后，实际上没有进行任何修复工程或拆除非法建筑物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这可能还不是最糟糕的。掉落的混凝土来自一个正在建设中的新天篷（也是未经授权的）。换句话说，关于需要完成哪些工作的报告已经过时了。是否需要再次进行调查并进行新的招标，从而进一步拖延？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从个案中退一步，从更广阔的角度来看，我们可以看到问题有多大。约 7,000 栋建筑物已接受强制检查令，但仍有 4,000 栋建筑物尚未完成检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;问答：香港的“非法建筑物”是什么，以及如何在不违反规定的情况下更换公寓法律&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;有一项补贴计划，帮助贫困旧楼居民支付维修费用。负责管理该计划的市区重建局最近透露，截至今年一月，已批准的 1,100 多份申请中，只有 110 份完成了工程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是一个多方面的问题，需要解决。多方面的解决方案。第一部分必须是公共教育，向人们解释为什么他们需要爱护自己的财产。有些人可能会觉得买了一套公寓后他们的工作就完成了，但现实生活并非如此。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将您的房产作为真实资产进行维护需要保持良好状态，而这需要花钱。由于许多公寓楼都有多个业主，业主立案法团可以帮助解决这个问题。确保有这样一个组织，并且能够胜任这项任务，是麦美娟局长领导下的民政事务局的工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从麦美娟上周的评论来看，麦美娟意识到责任落在了她的肩上。这是一个需要长期不懈努力、乏味工作的领域。我们都应该祝愿她一切顺利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，主要责任应由屋宇署署长余宝美和发展局局长林汉豪承担。毕竟，我们谈论的是建筑安全，并间接谈论住房供应。如果现有房屋在供应过程的某一点正在崩溃，那么将我们所有的精力投入到建造新房屋是没有意义的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正是在这里，我意识到了主要的危险。尽管过去曾作出各种努力来划定界限，但违例建筑工程的情况仍处于失控状态。有人记得前任行政长官在担任较低职位时曾建议新界居民向政府登记所有此类作品吗？那个计划到底发生了什么？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我现在在新界看到的都是三层楼的屋顶结构的房子。我们见过一位行政长官候选人拥有如此大的非法地下室，以至于破坏了他的竞选活动，也见过一位司法部长的房产经过如此广泛的改造，以至于无法俯瞰它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有人想要一个政府如此专横，以至于对自己家里的非危险、轻微违规行为负责的普通公民感到害怕，但我们必须找到一种方法来区分可以容忍的轻微、非危险行为和对他人构成风险的改变。如果林恩能更多地着眼于大局，而不是破坏香港在粉岭高尔夫球场的世界级设施，她可能会更好地做到这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt; div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In a climate-ravaged Indian village, marginalised farmers sing about ‘floating in tears’ after years of erratic weather]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3229355/climate-ravaged-indian-village-marginalised-farmers-sing-about-floating-tears-after-years-erratic?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/d68a73e0-a8e3-4f73-8633-b2694d81ee95_86d60809.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;51 岁的印度农民 Probir Mandal 最近在他的土地上种植了两种传统水稻品种的种子卡利塔拉的一英亩土地是孙德尔本斯的最后一个边境村庄，这里是印度-孟加拉国边境上世界上最大的红树林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他热切地希望能下雨，这样他就可以移植 gobindobhog 和 kamini 树苗&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我祈祷下雨，”曼达尔说。过去，由于意外的干旱、飓风和洪水导致产量低，他损失了 25,000 印度卢比（300 美元）三年。 “十多年来，我们一直受到不稳定天气的困扰，这使得生产水稻变得极其困难。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么南亚季风延迟对全球大米供应来说是“坏消息”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;为了表达他们对缺雨和天气变化的绝望，曼达尔和另外两名当地农民用孟加拉语创作了大约 50 首歌曲，概括了孙德尔本斯地区经济和社会边缘化农民所面临的挑战——该地区经常遭受干旱灾害的破坏。气候变化引起的降雨、洪水、气旋风暴和龙卷风。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tridhara（孟加拉语，意思是“三个支流”）是一个成立于 1982 年的文化团体，三位农民创作了 Bhatiali 歌曲 - 一种形式民间音乐赋予河流及其社区生机 - 描述了孙德尔本斯农民的斗争、损失和恢复的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一首歌中，曼达尔写道：“灾难性的大雨，你这个破坏者，洪水淹没了我的农田，破坏了我幸福的家园……我是一个不幸的农民，泪流满面。”在另一篇文章中，他写道：“农民为国家提供食物，农民的死亡是国家的耻辱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tridhara 联合创始人、58 岁的农民帕拉斯·蒙达尔 (Palas Mondal) 表示，全世界对这一事件知之甚少。孙德尔本斯地区的农民，该地区以食人皇家孟加拉虎最后的栖息地之一而闻名，但他们的歌曲将向世界讲述那里的人类生活。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为名为 RICE 的项目的一部分（复原力、创新、文化和赋权）由生态逻辑基金会 (ELF) 发起，这家总部位于新德里的非营利组织于 2021 年录制了 Tridhara 的 42 首歌曲，并拍摄了 6 个以歌手兼农民为主角的视频。这些歌曲和视频随后在 YouTube 上发布，以拉近孙德尔本斯稻农与全球稻米消费者的距离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ELF 联合创始人皮纳基·罗伊 (Pinaki Roy) 表示，孙德尔本斯的稻农将 19 首歌曲的歌词翻译成英文。孙德尔本斯人被视为“不幸的”未来气候难民。但由于没有人比这些农民更了解土地和生态系统，录制这些歌曲是一次“新生的尝试”，让他们有发言权和“代理感”来讲述自己的坚韧故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒙达尔说这些歌曲凸显了农民的困境，随着农业部门开始优先考虑工业化农业流程和高产杂交种子，他们感到被剥夺了权力。但他说，当洪水或飓风风暴期间河堤决堤时，高产品种无法抵御附近河口的咸水侵入田地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;33 岁的文化和环境地理学家 Mehebub Sahana 告诉我们本周在亚洲，由于全球变暖、气候变化和环境变化，孙德尔本斯沿海地区（包括卡利塔拉）热带气旋和风暴潮洪水的频率和强度更高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“气候变化引起的孙德尔本斯沿海地区的飓风、洪水、盐分入侵、土地退化和河岸侵蚀影响了人们的生计。”曼彻斯特大学研究员兼讲师萨哈纳说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1999 年飓风过后艾拉在西孟加拉邦造成了超过 78 人死亡，Tridhara 的歌手兼作曲家 Bishnupada Sarkar，65 岁，在一首歌中写道：“残酷的艾拉，你把我们金色的[西]孟加拉邦变成了火葬场。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;飓风“艾拉是孙德尔本斯人民生活的转折点，”蒙达尔说。 “人们开始以前所未有的方式迁移到其他邦——卡纳塔克邦、泰米尔纳德邦和安得拉邦——以每日打赌的方式工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tridhara 的歌曲中也描述了强迫迁移的弊端。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萨卡说，曾经在他唱歌时用传统乐器为他伴奏的农民也迁移到其他州寻找工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很少有人像拒绝迁移的蒙达尔一样继续从事稻米生产。尽管损失惨重，但仍坚持种植。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，由于缺乏买家，蒙达尔因无农药生产传统黑米品种而损失了 28,000 印度卢比（340 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我们无法进入城市市场，”蒙达尔说。 “中间商以边际价格从我们这里购买产品，但以高价出售给城市市场。我们不能要求他们盈利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;天气的变化迫使许多当地农民转而从事鱼虾养殖和家禽养殖，还有一些人开始驾驶公共交通和经营杂货店来赚取收入。萨哈纳补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但萨哈纳表示，将有关孙德尔本斯人民日常斗争的歌曲存档非常重要，因为它们反映了他们对气候变化和气候变化及其对生态和社会经济影响的看法。系统。 “这些歌曲将有助于识别不同的弱势群体，”萨哈纳补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;档案管理员兼歌手苏拉夫·莫尼 (Sourav Moni) 指出，印度乡村的才华横溢的艺术家缺乏应有的认可，他们唱着土地和河流的歌曲，并在他们周围过着生活。 “这些歌曲需要保存，我们不能失去它们，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s Poyang Lake marks earliest dry season on record, sparking drought concerns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3229393/chinas-poyang-lake-marks-earliest-dry-season-record-sparking-drought-concerns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/129d51d7-c2c2-4b01-a488-b6ffbe28166f_185e6424.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国最大淡水湖迎来70多年来最早的旱季，引发人们对干旱情况再次出现的担忧，去年水体面积缩小至平时的四分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于东部江西省的鄱阳湖于7月20日进入枯水期是自 1951 年有记录以来的最早日期，比去年提前了 17 天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据江西省水文监测中心的数据，星子水文站 7 月测得的水位为 11.99 米（39.3 英尺） 20日，为有记录以来的最低水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于水位持续下降，中心呼吁关注潜在影响，敦促加大水资源管理和抗旱力度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;江西师范大学生命科学学院教授李彦阔表示，他对今年的干旱感到担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于降水较少，水位相对较低......据我了解， “到目前为止，感觉今年干旱很严重。”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鄱阳湖是候鸟的重要越冬栖息地，有数十万只候鸟从候鸟的繁殖地飞来。每年西伯利亚东北部到该湖过冬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该湖记录了超过350种鸟类，其中包括被列入国际自然保护联盟濒危物种红色名录的23种。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;这片湿地也是世界上约 99% 的极度濒危西伯利亚鹤和超过 80% 的濒危东方白鹳的冬季家园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在过去的十年里，它夏末秋季水位创历史新低，备受关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国干涸的鄱阳湖还能成为候鸟过冬的家园吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;湖水膨胀和收缩由于季节性水位变化，雨季的面积约为 3,000 平方公里（1,158 平方英里），旱季的面积不足 500 平方公里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从 10 月开始，旱季水位较低到三月，为候鸟留下了丰富的植物、鱼类和其他食物来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，在过去的十年中，夏末和秋季，该湖的水位下降得更快，旱季也更长。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;科学家发现，在长江上游修建的水坝是导致长江干季提前的关键因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;水坝——尤其是三峡大坝——开始保留水9月份，长江水位下降，鄱阳湖入江水流加快。因此，该湖提前进入枯季。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但李说，在过去的两年里，气候的作用已成为导致该湖提前枯季的原因。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;去年夏天，中国经历了60年来最严重的干旱和热浪，引发了水电短缺，影响了农业和工业生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年，鄱阳湖于8月6日进入枯水期100天。早于历史平均水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;恢复鄱阳湖大坝计划，旱季切断鄱阳湖与长江的联系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;江西省原副省长、中科院教授胡振鹏南昌大学表示，去年该地区的干旱是1949年以来最严重的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据胡教授2月份在中国《防旱救灾》杂志上发表的研究，2022年7月至10月的降水量约为1 -过去五年同期平均降雨量的三分之一。但蒸发量比历史平均水平高出 34%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖泊的干旱导致更多的候鸟停在人工湿地（荷塘或稻田）而不是天然湿地寻找食物，这可能会导致李说，当鸟类与家禽距离较近时，它们传播病毒的风险就会增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，干旱预警和预防至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“干旱的负面影响是像洪水一样严重。 “这会影响灌溉用水、候鸟和生态系统。”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南昌大学胡教授建议建立干旱预警系统来控制水库、堤坝和较小湖泊的水位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“随着全球气温不断升高，类似于2022年的严重干旱的频率可能会增加，”胡在研究中写道。 “我们需要转变战略，从抗旱转向防旱减灾。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mourning and anger continues after Chinese school roof collapse]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3229397/mourning-and-anger-continues-after-chinese-school-roof-collapse?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/7ce9f4e7-ea18-4ff3-9f95-0c00eabbb63b_6a56fcf1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国东北地区学校体育馆屋顶倒塌事件中遇难者的家人和朋友标志着周六是具有重要文化意义的哀悼日，全国各地的普通民众向遇难者表示哀悼，并向遇难者致以哀悼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人传统上认为，人死后的第七天是亲人灵魂安息的日子。她们最后一次重访这个世界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周日，黑龙江省齐齐哈尔市屋顶垮塌，造成10名中学女排队员和教练死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;周六早些时候，一位母亲在网上发布的消息中表示，她在女儿第二天被海葬之前，已经准备了一些化妆品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的孩子，你的书包被发现了[在废墟]昨天你的手机却不见了，只有奖牌和你攒下来的零用钱，你知道我看着这一切有多伤心吗？据湖南省长沙电视台拥有的一个在线视频帐户显示，这位母亲写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国城市因学校倒塌后未能及时通知家长而受到批评&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我知道你爱美丽，第二天早上醒来时，我会带口红、腮红和眼影去太平间和海葬。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国高度审查的互联网上，社交媒体用户与家人一起悲伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;病毒视频显示，校门外放置了数百杯珍珠奶茶、零食、酸奶和鲜花，以悼念死者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据信是全国各地的人订购的，由外卖骑手送货上门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的朋友在网上看到一些帖子，说有人付了珍珠奶茶或果汁的费用送到学校，所以“他点了一些，送货员给他拍了一张照片，可见很多人都做了同样的事情。”一位距离齐齐哈尔约 1400 公里的山西省的互联网用户在社交媒体平台微博上写道。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“我们为这些年轻人感到非常遗憾，因为他们在生命中最美好的时光经历了这样的悲剧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人在评论死者悼词时继续表达对这起事故的愤怒三十四中在线发布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“七天来，痛苦摩擦着银河，化作星星，化作明月，化作你们的脸，留在你们家人的心里。”崇拜你的老师、同学”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们只想知道是谁蹭了屋顶，蹭了人心”，一位微博用户写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “这是一场人为灾难，”另一位写道，而第三位则补充道：“请你不要打扰天地吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这起事故引发了人们的疑问：它是如何以及为何会发生的？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;初步调查显示，屋顶上非法存放建筑材料，导致屋顶倒塌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;建筑工程师付建一告诉上海新闻门户网站论文称这是一个“低级常识性错误”，本应由地方当局和监管机构制止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;悲剧发生后，中国教育部已下令全国中小学和大学加强处理&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;全国学校体育场屋顶塌陷，至少10人被困&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据澎湃新闻报道，安徽、安徽、宁夏、吉林、河北、河南等地，部分高校已发布新的安全须知。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong bringing green power to Indonesia? Mainland Chinese tech behind 2 firms’ bids to service rural areas with air travel, electricity]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3229402/hong-kong-bringing-green-power-indonesia-mainland-chinese-tech-behind-2-firms-bids-service-rural?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 15:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/e3f18a06-ee15-415b-afab-22e066e390ac_be5802d0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;两家香港企业正在利用中国内地的绿色技术提供电力和航空运输到印度尼西亚的农村社区。&lt;/​​p>;&lt;p>;香港人 Brian Chan Pak-lam 的目标是年底前在 Bangka 岛上开设一座生物质发电厂，而前银行家 Henry Hooi Hing Lee 则计划使用电池驱动的飞机提供航空服务中国大陆制造。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多周二在雅加达会见行政长官李家超时，强调绿色电力和交通是香港企业值得探索的高潜力领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚拥有 2.76 亿人口和遍布其广阔群岛的 18,000 个岛屿，是东南亚国家联盟（东盟）中面积最大、人口最多的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港与印度尼西亚签署 15 项协议李约翰宣扬东盟关系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;今年上半年，东盟获得了 452 亿美元的外国直接投资，而香港则以 35 亿美元的规模跻身三大投资者之列，仅次于新加坡和中国内地。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;商人陈，经营 PT。 Rimba Palma Sejahtera Lestari 表示，邦加的渔业社区依赖柴油发电机，需要稳定的电力供应才能繁荣发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了出口渔获，他们需要制冰，而制冰又需要电力。为了维持更大出口量的冷链和储存，他们需要稳定的电力供应。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的香港家族企业 ELL Environmental Holdings 于 15 年前开始在印度尼西亚投资。该公司于 2016 年收购了苏门答腊岛现有的一座生物质发电厂，并决定在东部的 Bangka 建造一座新发电厂，所用的专业知识和设备主要来自中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈预计新工厂和生物燃料供应链为岛民创造更多样化的就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，印尼电力市场的竞争力不如大陆，根据与当地政府的协议，他的公司可以收取更高水平的电价。&lt;/p>;&lt;他补充说，即便如此，直接供电将使邦加渔民的成本不到柴油发电机费用的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们预见到印度尼西亚的许多岛屿需要经济发展，这将需要他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但随着 2 月份印度尼西亚总统大选的临近，他的公司将所有新计划搁置至少 12 个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港，印尼领导人在雅加达会谈期间重点关注更深层次的经济联系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“只有当选总统提名内阁后，部长的选择变得明确，我们才能知道政策的变化，”他说。 “我们必须小心，因为影响可能会持续20至25年。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前银行家Hooi是马来西亚人，在香港生活了27年后，他形容自己“大部分时间是香港人”当他注意到岛上居民的交通困难时，他在印度尼西亚发现了一个机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多村民无法走出社区，因为飞行成本太高，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他正在计划使用中国辽宁通用航空学院设计的小型电池驱动飞机推出一系列新的航空服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港和印度尼西亚交易所考虑交叉上市、联合产品&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;他表示，四座 RX4E 电动飞机的运营成本将比传统飞机更便宜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它可以帮助建立交通、医疗服务和牙科服务、农业、测量、通勤飞行和生态网络-旅游业，”他说。 “村民可以有更多机会参与或做他们无法做的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三年前，他创立了初创公司 Volar Air Mobility 来营销中国电动飞机，并与多家公司签署了多项协议马来西亚和印度尼西亚的合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括 PT Bum Desa，这是一家监管印度尼西亚各地数千家农村合作社的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度尼西亚人通过 TikTok 直播销售热潮获利&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;另一个热衷于将游客飞往龙目岛的林贾尼山。火山口湖现在只能通过三天的徒步才能到达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一位负责旅游业的部长发现这个想法很棒，因为游客不用徒步三天，而是可以在两个小时内看到这个湖，并花上”Hooi 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他希望明年向客户交付第一架 RX4E，但必须首先获得中国和印度尼西亚当局的适航认证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港贸易发展局助理首席经济学家薛冠南表示，印尼正在婆罗洲南部建设新首都，并致力于成为全球经济强国，因此提供了丰富的基础设施机会。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;随着印度尼西亚对海沙出口的转变，人们担心海洋生物数量增加，岛屿消失&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“他们特别关注绿色基础设施，全世界也是如此。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;薛建议在印度尼西亚做生意的新来者确保他们有一个可靠的当地合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“必须找到一个了解当地文化和风险的合作伙伴，他知道要与哪些政府机构联系才能进入当地市场，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 15:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Back on track: Europe’s night trains make bumpy comeback]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3229394/back-track-europes-night-trains-make-bumpy-comeback?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 14:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/e352275c-0d4b-47f3-9539-ed4ae9cd37fc_fafea9c8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由于低碳足迹，夜间列车在欧洲卷土重来，但是经过多年的忽视，复兴之路坎坷不平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运营商承认火车已经过时——乘客偶尔会遇到延误、技术问题或厕所故障——而公司则在超载的网络中竞争。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;尽管面临挑战，国家铁路运营商还是给了夜间列车另一个机会，而初创企业也纷纷加入这股潮流，因为气候问题促使旅客放弃烧煤油的飞机，转而选择更清洁的交通方式。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;奥地利位于西欧和东欧的十字路口，在政府的支持下一直处于这一复兴的中心，尽管低成本航空公司威胁要让卧铺火车载入史册。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥地利铁路运营商 OeBB 是该行业的先驱，拥有欧洲最大的夜间列车车队，为 150 万名乘客提供包括床位车厢的车厢服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家国有公司一度考虑放弃其夜间服务，但它却反其道而行之，而是投资了它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的夜间列车几乎已经订满了，”OeBB 发言人 Bernhard Rieder 表示，夏季旅行在欧洲正如火如荼地进行。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;OeBB 运营 20 条路线，连接维也纳和欧洲其他城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在夜间列车服务方面拥有悠久的传统，”Rieder 说道，并指出了这个阿尔卑斯国家的山区地形如何打造高速连接困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;27 岁的顾问阿斯特丽德·雷特 (Astrid Reiter) 预订了从维也纳到苏黎世的夜间列车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这很好，因为你基本上在不同的国家醒来，”她说。 “如果一切顺利的话，这是一种非常方便的出行方式。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充道：“我确实希望除了奥地利铁路公司之外的其他公司开发更多的夜间列车，让人们更容易乘坐更快的列车夜间列车。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rieder 承认，其服务质量“目前并不总是像我们希望为客户提供的那样高”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有需求他说，“超过 25 年没有对夜间列车的需求”，导致制造业陷入停顿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年，OeBB 从德国企业集团西门子订购了 33 辆新夜间列车，以扩大其覆盖范围并取代部分其老化的车队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一批列车具有现代设计、更多隐私和更多淋浴设施，预计将于今年年底投入使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chris Engelsman， co-founder of the Belgian-Dutch startup European Sleeper, also complained about a shortage of “proper night train coaches”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Established in 2021, his company inaugurated a Berlin-Brussels link in May.&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“The train is not always up to the modern standards, but despite that many people would like to travel by night train and the enthusiasm is quite big,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are breakdowns sometimes or the toilets are not working or electricity is not working properly, things like that,” he added, blaming the “lack of investment for decades”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Best places to see on world&#39;s longest train journey: Singapore to Portugal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Competition from low-cost flights and a lack of coordination between different European rail operators and companies are other obstacles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is difficult to compete with some flights&#39; “unreasonably low ” prices, according to a recent report by NGO Greenpeace, with the aviation sector benefiting from subsidies and tax exemptions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rail transport, on the other hand, is “subject to various taxes and fees”, in particular for using the infrastructure, said Philipp Kosok, an analyst at the German think tank Agora.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Operating night trains is very difficult, complex and expensive,” Kosok said, adding that the infrastructure was “overloaded” even at night when freight trains ply the rails.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is also no centralised site to consult timetables and compare prices, with some in the industry complaining of a lack of political will.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ There&#39;s not really a European approach to train travel at the moment,” Engelsman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French startup Midnight Trains co-founder Adrien Aumont said his company&#39;s aim was to “reinvent” the night train “to make it a truly competitive means of transport against aviation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aumont had the idea to create the company when his partner “decided never to get on a plane again”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His startup is partnering with a night train maker to relaunch the once popular Paris-Milan-Venice line in 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I realised that it was almost impossible to travel in Europe [without flying]. People were asked to get off the planes, but without necessarily offering them solutions,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He slammed a service that “has deteriorated” over time, far from the legendary and luxurious Orient Express.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia says 3 Ukrainian drones brought down in ‘terrorist attack’ on Moscow]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3229398/russia-says-3-ukrainian-drones-brought-down-terrorist-attack-moscow?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 14:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/30/78870729-99a3-403f-8505-616791c2ebc7_d0ed8f88.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s defence ministry said it had brought down three Ukrainian drones in the early hours of Sunday morning that had been trying to carry out what it called “a terrorist attack” on Moscow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nobody was hurt and there was only minor damage to the facade of two office buildings in the Moscow City business district, Sergei Sobyanin, Moscow&#39;s mayor, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The area, several miles from the Kremlin, is known for its modern high-rise towers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fact that hostile drones have in recent months begun reaching the heart of the Russian capital, even if they do not inflict serious damage, is uncomfortable for the authorities who have told the public that Russia is in full control of what they call its “special military operation” against Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There were no casualties or injuries,” Sobyanin said in a short statement on the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The defence ministry said two drones had crashed in the Moscow City district after being brought down using radio-electronic equipment. Air defences had shot down one more in the air over the Odintsovo area in the Moscow region, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On the morning of July 30, an attempted terrorist attack by the Kyiv regime using unmanned aerial vehicles against targets in the city of Moscow was foiled,” the ministry said in its statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An unverified video apparently filmed by a passer-by which surfaced on social media showed flames shooting into the air near buildings after what sounded like an explosion and a young woman wailing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My friends and I rented an apartment to come here and unwind, and at some point, we heard an explosion and it was like a wave, everyone jumped,” said a young woman, who only gave her name as Liya.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And then there was a lot of smoke and you couldn&#39;t see anything. From above, you could see fire.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some glass panels in one high-rise building were blown out and glass and debris littered part of the pavement below, according to a Reuters reporter on the scene, which had been cordoned off by police and emergency services.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Moscow says it intercepted two Ukraine missiles over south Russia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The incident followed what Russia said was a similar Ukrainian attempt to attack Moscow with two drones in the early hours of Monday. It spoke at the time of taking harsh retaliatory measures against Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In another attack on July 4, the Russian military said four drones were downed by air defences on the outskirts of Moscow and a fifth was jammed by electronic warfare means and forced down.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The attacks on Moscow come several weeks into a Ukrainian counteroffensive to claw back territory captured by Russia since large-scale hostilities erupted in February 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s foreign ministry has said such attacks “would not be possible without the help provided to the Kyiv regime by the US and its Nato allies”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian Deputy Prime Minister Mykhailo Fedorov said after Monday&#39;s attempted attack that there would be more drone strikes. There was no immediate reaction from Kyiv to the latest incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Agence France-Presse&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Are you OK?’: Chinese man spends US$120 buying all instant noodles from vendor after ‘you can’t afford it’ insult, becomes online joke]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3228960/are-you-ok-chinese-man-spends-us120-buying-all-instant-noodles-vendor-after-you-cant-afford-it?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/11f75ba9-bc78-4baa-93de-095b3a7dc061_498c5bf0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A video of a man in China who felt insulted by a street vendor and bought all his packet noodles for 850 yuan (US$120) to throw them on the ground has gone viral on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unidentified man from Shandong province in eastern China was verbally abused by a street vendor selling noodles at a night market on July 24. The reason for the vendor&#39;s scornful comment was the man&#39;s complaint that 14 yuan (US$2) for a bowl of instant noodles was too expensive, Star Video reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He continued to ask for the ingredients in a bowl. However, it astonished him after the vendor replied that there was only an egg and two vegetable leaves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“How is it possible to sell at 14 yuan each? Too expensive, isn&#39;t it?” he asked the vendor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vendor ignored his questions and waved him away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What are you doing?” the man asked the vendor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the vendor&#39;s son, who was by his side, stood up and shouted at him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you can&#39;t afford it, then get out of there,” the son told the man.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Irritated, he asked the price for each packet of noodles and said he would purchase all of them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He then paid 850 yuan, smashed the packets on the ground, and paid an additional undisclosed compensation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The son made an apology, but it is useless. Can&#39;t I smash the things I own?” the man said afterwards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The viral video has sparked discussion on Chinese social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “He scolded you, and you rewarded him with 850 yuan. Are you OK?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person said: “It&#39;s a youthful indiscretion.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Videos and posts on social media about customer service conflicts often trend in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an incident in June, a woman in eastern China was charged an extra 300 yuan (US$42) because she and her friends were “not creating a vibrant enough vibe” in a bar, she said in a post that went viral on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, a Chinese barbecue restaurant manager in eastern China knelt to beg forgiveness from a customer who complained about the long queue, which shocked many internet users.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Young Indonesians secure Singapore citizenship as many lament ‘skills mismatch’ back home]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3229314/young-indonesians-secure-singapore-citizenship-many-lament-skills-mismatch-back-home?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/c1d35bc9-d0d2-4a6e-829f-9e962df8d904_0156f8bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A growing number of young Indonesians, drawn by generous scholarships and attractive job prospects, are renouncing their citizenship to become Singaporean, alarming officials as Southeast Asia&#39;s largest economy seeks to become a developed nation by 2045.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia&#39;s immigration agency said earlier this month that almost 4,000 Indonesians had gained Singapore passports between 2019 and 2022, most of them students in the city state, aged 25 to 35. Last year, 1,091 people made the switch, up from 811 in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Silmy Karim, director general at Indonesia&#39;s immigration agency, said the country was losing its best and brightest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For Indonesia it is not good, as we&#39;re losing superior talent,” he said, as cited by CNN Indonesia. He noted that Singapore had a policy of targeting young talent from around the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore pledges support for Indonesia&#39;s new US$34 billion capital Nusantara&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The revelation was unusual because it was the first time Indonesia had singled out a nationality in relation to its data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singapore, a city state of 5.45 million people, has in recent decades sought to augment its population with new arrivals, mainly from other Southeast Asian nations, as well as China and India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official data shows that around 15,000 to 20,000 new citizenships are granted each year, in tandem with some 30,000 citizen births annually. Authorities in the city state have declined to reveal the breakdown of new citizens by their original nationalities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singapore&#39;s passport was named the most powerful in the world earlier this month by the Henley Passport Index, which ranks nations according to the number of places people armed with their passports can visit. A Singaporean passport allows visa-free travel to 192 destinations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bhima Yudhistira, executive director at the Jakarta-based Centre of Economic and Law Studies think tank, said that immigration official Silmy&#39;s comments were meant as a wake-up call for Jakarta to improve the calibre of its workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Silmy himself studied overseas – including at the George C. Marshall European Centre for Security Studies and the Nato School, both in Germany.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is a criticism of the quality of civil servants, including at the immigration department,” Bhima said. “There really is a brain drain and if you let it, Singapore will get a lot of value from the people who actually enjoy support from the Indonesian government.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since 2011, Jakarta has provided scholarships for top students to study overseas, under the Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education (LPDP) scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recipients are obliged to work in Indonesia for several years after graduating. However, from 2013 to 2022, 413 graduates did not return, the fund said last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to global recruitment consultancy Morgan McKinley, the average monthly salary of a full-time worker in Singapore in 2023 is S$5,783 (US$4,360). In Indonesia, data from the statistics agency showed the average monthly salary of graduates last year was 4.3 million rupiah (US$286).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If given an option to live in Singapore, many Indonesian workers would seize the opportunity, “regardless of whether they will become citizens”, said Indonesia-born Sulfikar Amir, an associate professor of science, technology and society at Singapore&#39;s Nanyang Technological University (NTU).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is an indication of their displeasure with the conditions in Indonesia, and a sign for the government to build a better employment ecosystem for young people,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Indonesia&#39;s migration revelation stoked heated online discussions among Indonesians on the pros and cons of living in Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some acknowledged the city state had a strong passport, thriving job market, modern healthcare and world-class public transport, but said Indonesia trumped its neighbour in terms of natural landscapes and beauty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Septian Hartono, 36, gained Singapore citizenship in 2020. He moved to the city state in 2003 after securing a scholarship from NTU, which required him to work in Singapore for three years after completing his studies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When he graduated in 2007, the Singapore government sent him a letter saying he would be granted permanent residency if he worked in the city state. He became a permanent resident later that year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It may sound innocent, but it&#39;s one effective way to unconsciously [make you] sink roots in Singapore, as in total you would live here for seven years,” said Septian, who works as a medical physicist.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have seriously considered several times returning to Indonesia. But in the end, there was a skills mismatch,” he said, especially in his biomedical sector, where the gap was “quite obvious”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Biomedical is one of the key industries in Singapore, so the whole ecosystem is already very mature from training to industry,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Septian estimated that around one-third of the Indonesian students in his graduating class of 2007 had also become Singapore citizens. He married one of them, with whom he now has two children and in 2018 they decided to start the citizenship process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It just makes more sense,” he told This Week in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The couple became Singaporean two years after their application, while their children still hold dual citizenship.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia does not recognise dual nationality for adults, and children with multiple passports are given until they are 18 to decide which citizenship they will keep.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aside from higher earning power, Singapore&#39;s way of life – particularly its efficient public transport – was another attraction for Septian, who said that he despises driving.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jakarta has notoriously clogged roads that can result in commuters spending as much as six hours getting to and from work each day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In Singapore, you can go anywhere easily. I can imagine that I wouldn&#39;t be able to survive in Jakarta,” Septian said, adding that he was “amazed” that people managed to drive in the Indonesian city each day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, he noted that while Singapore is “really convenient”, it is also “expensive”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;To be sure, not every Indonesian living in the city state has taken the full leap, including NTU&#39;s Sulfikar, who has lived there since 2008.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has not applied for permanent residency, let alone a passport, as he still enjoys benefits from his status as an overseas talent, such as an educational allowance for his children and a housing subsidy, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He did acknowledge that it was less convenient to travel with his current passport, however. “I still use my Indonesian passport, which makes it hard for me to travel everywhere as I still need to apply for a visa first,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore jails Indonesian tourist who encashed tickets he found in casino&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to Sulfikar, scholarships remain one of Singapore&#39;s most powerful tools to recruit promising Indonesian talent, and its universities have been proactive in this regard.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said his university, for example, provides 100 scholarships every year for foreign students, including those from Indonesia, China and India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representatives from Singapore universities know which schools in Indonesia, to target, often meeting top students and testing them on the spot.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who perform the best are offered scholarships, including full tuition and a S$3,000 (US$2,260) monthly allowance, as well as money towards books, housing and round-trip tickets for flights home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They only have to bring their suitcases to Singapore,” Sulfikar said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singapore isn&#39;t the only place courting top Indonesian talent. LPDP data shows that between 2013 and 2022, 58 per cent of some 15,000 Indonesians who received overseas scholarships went to European universities, while 20.7 per cent studied in Australia and New Zealand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia Awards – Indonesia, the largest scholarship programme offered by Canberra, has been running for 70 years. Much like Singapore, it also offers generous packages including full tuition, pre-departure training, living allowances, flight tickets and educational support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But even as some have committed themselves to Singapore, their love for Indonesia remains strong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Septian visits the country twice a year, saying it is “impossible to erase” his Indonesian upbringing. Even though he is of Chinese descent, he says he gets on better with ethnic Malays in the city state than the majority Chinese-Singaporean population, because of cultural similarities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In some sense, I don&#39;t need to maintain my identity as an Indonesian, as it implies that it would require effort. Naturally, I&#39;m different from others here,” he said. “What I miss the most about Indonesia is the food. This may sound cliché, but you can&#39;t replicate it here.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Philippines forecasts heavy rains as Khanun turns into typhoon]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3229390/philippines-forecasts-heavy-rains-khanun-turns-typhoon?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 13:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/30/386a86a0-0e3a-42ed-9f21-65598fc11232_7f7ec8b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Philippine weather bureau warned of heavy rains, floods and landslides in mountainous areas of the country, with intensifying severe tropical storm Khanun forecast to develop into a typhoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khanun is expected to “steadily intensify within the next three days”, Pagasa said in its 5am advisory. “It is forecast to become a typhoon between late evening today or tomorrow early morning and reach its peak intensity on Tuesday”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Khanun is on a northward path over the Philippine Sea and appears to be heading away from land mass, heavy rainfall is expected as the storm and super typhoon Doksuri, which hit the country last week, boost the Southwest Monsoon, the weather bureau said. This will bring “occasional” monsoon showers over the western parts of Luzon and the Visayas, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Philippine travellers stranded as flights cancelled amid super typhoon pummelling&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The water level of the capital region&#39;s Marikina River reached 16.1 metres (52.8 feet) on Saturday evening, nearing the 18-metre level that triggers a forced evacuation of certain parts of Marikina City, the Philippine Daily Inquirer reported, citing the local government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippines is affected by an average of 20 tropical cyclones a year, making it one of the world&#39;s worst-hit countries, according to Pagasa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Doksuri, which struck last week, destroyed more than 1.3 billion pesos worth of agricultural crops and caused an estimated 2.66 billion pesos of damage to infrastructure, including bridges and roads, according to local media reports that cited the agriculture and public works departments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The super typhoon affected half a million people mostly in the northern parts of main Luzon Island and left 14 dead, according to the National Disaster Risk Reduction and Management Council. It flooded more than 258 villages in the Luzon provinces of Bulacan and Pampanga, located north of Manila.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khanun is moving at 15km (about 9 miles) an hour with maximum sustained winds of 95km an hour near the centre and gusts of up to 115km an hour, Pagasa said. It&#39;s forecast to move north northwestward before veering northwestward on Monday, according to the weather bureau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tropical storm may exit the Philippines on Monday evening or early Tuesday before turning west northwestwards and passing close to Japan&#39;s Okinawa Islands in the Ryukyu archipelago on Tuesday morning and then entering the East China Sea.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>