<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s largest journalist group faces financial strain, plunging membership as outlets close and reporters leave, re-elected chairman says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3223652/hong-kongs-largest-journalist-group-faces-financial-strain-plunging-membership-outlets-close-and?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 18:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/b37c2752-49e1-42e2-9e2d-bbc9a5c53d58_78e07471.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港最大的记者协会正面临财务困难，其媒体机构的会员数量也在减少其再次当选的主席曾表示，该集团关闭，记者完全离开该行业或城市，对该集团的生存发出警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;再次当选香港主席的 Ronson Chan Ron-sing记者协会 (HKJA) 在周六的年度大会上表示，只有大约 220 名正式成员仍然存在，而包括其他类别在内的总数在 300 到 400 之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他援引不同规模的新闻机构关闭下降、记者换工作或离开城市以及学生毕业后选择不加入这个行业是导致数据不佳的部分原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方在声明中抨击记者机构“未经证实的猜测”&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;“我们的会员数量远远少于三年前，这对我们产生了巨大的影响，”他在协会会议后解释说，会议选举了新的执行委员会。他说，该组织也面临财务困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈在 2021 年表示，该组织有 600 多名成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，香港记协召开了一次特别会议，讨论该组织的未来，包括在越来越大的政治压力下解散的可能性，但最终它决定在“可预见的未来”继续运作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周六的会议上，该协会的执行委员会成员总数从 7 名增加&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还接纳了漫画家尊子为终身常任理事，他的漫画系列上个月因被市政府官员指责存在偏见而被中文报纸《明报》删除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;另外，驻港外国记者会 (FCC) 在其新领导层发表的声明中表达了对尊子（本名黄其群）漫画被取消的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “FCC 指出，停止出版 Wong 的漫画的决定进一步打击了香港的新闻自由，”该俱乐部表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它指出，政府一再表示，新闻和言论自由正如《基本法》、香港的小宪法和《国家安全法》所规定的那样，没有受到威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“FCC 支持媒体专业人士根据美国法律继续享有这些自由的权利香港，”它说，并补充说该俱乐部已就其决定与《明报》取得联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报在 5 月下架了尊子的系列作品，但没有给出任何解释。该决定结束了他对该出版物 40 年的贡献。他的两部日常漫画以将幽默与时事批评融为一体而闻名。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;记者在香港车辆检查案中未获得疑点利益：法官&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;几位政府高级官员，包括秘书长保安邓炳强和民政及青年事务局局长麦美娟抨击了这些卡通片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超早些时候表示，香港媒体应确保他们的报道不包括虚假、有偏见、诽谤和误导的信息。他还为公共图书馆将这位漫画家的书籍下架的决定辩护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;FCC 上个月选举了新的理事会，Gen.T 的区域负责人 Lee Williamson 是其旗下的一个平台生活方式杂志 Tatler，担任总裁一职。他接替了香港大学新闻与媒体研究中心主任 Keith Richburg。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 arrested in Hong Kong after 4,400 dodgy credit card transactions made to buy HK$2.7 million worth of goods for resale]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3223651/3-arrested-hong-kong-after-4400-dodgy-credit-card-transactions-made-buy-hk27-million-worth-goods?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 18:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/d9938fca-9452-4891-a7b6-f5af55802644_6ad01dd3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港警方逮捕了三名男子，他们涉嫌使用被盗的信用卡信息每天购物通过超过 4,400 笔网上交易转售价值约 270 万港元的必需品，官员警告商家和公众在网上购买时要格外谨慎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三名年龄在 20 至 29 岁之间的嫌疑人正在处理婴儿配方奶粉周五，伪装成快递员的人员在上水的一个仓库找到了他们和洗衣粉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查人员在接到当地人的举报后，发现了这个已经活跃了大约一个月的集团警方在周六的新闻发布会上说，这家零售商涉嫌未经授权的交易&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港零售商的网上商店每天都使用从法国、美国、沙特阿拉伯和新西兰的持卡人那里窃取的信用卡信息购买商品新西兰高级督察麦伟光说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方调查发现，这些货物将被转售以牟利。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方查获价值 1.15 亿港元的非法毒品– 一些里面的饼干&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mak 说进行了 4,400 多笔交易，总价值约为 270 万港元。 “骗子希望通过小额交易来逃避银行的监控，而持卡人也更难发现小额交易。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这三人都是中国大陆居民，持有前往香港的旅行证Kong 因涉嫌串谋诈骗和违反逗留条件而被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方表示，截至周六，他们仍被拘留，可能还会逮捕更多人，并补充说调查仍在继续。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;警方将与国际刑警组织合作，收集情报并与其他执法机构分享最新的信用卡诈骗模式。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;来自假冒“Scameter”应用程序的网络钓鱼信息提示香港警方警告&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;警司陈伟基敦促银行和网上商户扩大使用一次性密码，以确保信用卡持卡人在网上购物时，无论金额大小，都能得到充分的通知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“持卡人还应避免使用一次性密码的自动填充功能。银行总是在短信中描述密码的用途，人们在手动输入密码之前应该仔细阅读，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公众应该提防钓鱼短信，并考虑使用带有Chan 补充说，降低支出限额以防止信息被盗时的财务损失。对未经授权交易的投诉激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据这些措施，银行将需要征得客户同意才能更改信用额度，并为持卡人提供在线自助“按钮”以立即停用他们的卡周一公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港网络诈骗受害人今年首 3 个月损失 8.3 亿港元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;信用卡持卡人也可以禁用或设置无卡消费上限&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;监管机构在今年前五个月收到了 382 起关于未经授权的信用卡交易的投诉，接近 2022 年全年的 391 起。2020 年仅报告了 88 起此类案件2019 年为 51 起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 12 月，在疑似受害者向贷方的社交媒体账户大量投诉后，当局命令渣打银行调查涉及本地客户的信用卡欺诈案件激增。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thailand’s first pet-friendly cinema opens to four-legged film-goers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223649/thailands-first-pet-friendly-cinema-opens-four-legged-film-goers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 17:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/97906e92-e69b-49b6-9c90-7735eb99d579_69962fe5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一只穿着黄色裙子的毛茸茸的白猫坐在曼谷电影院的座位上而在附近，一只穿着螃蟹塞巴斯蒂安服装的吉娃娃正准备和主人一起观看迪士尼的“小美人鱼”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一只小猎犬甚至戴着红色假发和美人鱼尾巴引导爱丽儿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;星期六，他们是数十名四足电影观众中的一员，他们推着婴儿车抵达首都边缘的泰国第一家宠物友好型电影院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国的宠物行业被认为是行业数据显示，2021 年养狗约 830 万只，猫养猫 370 万只，位居亚洲第二，仅次于中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在冠状病毒大流行期间，养宠物的人数进一步增加，现在一些企业正试图变现&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;37 岁的马诺把他的救助猫卡蒂带到了电影院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们有时带他去上班......今天就像一个实验，”他告诉法新社.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在看《小美人鱼》。他会喜欢在屏幕上看到所有的鱼。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Major Cineplex 发言人 Narute Jiensnong 说，这些动物必须穿上尿布并坐在袋子里，同时调整声音和灯光以使其舒适。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“曼谷不是一个非常适合宠物的城市，”Narute 告诉法新社，并补充说这个概念建立在他们对儿童友好的剧院之上。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;家里有 1,000 只狗的韩国男子怀疑虐待动物&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Narute 指出，由于主人不再在家工作或处于隔离状态，一些在大流行期间获得的宠物患有分离焦虑症。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在儿童电影院里，孩子们会跑来跑去周围尖叫或大喊……我认为宠物电影院也一样。每个来的人都会养一只宠物，并且会理解（如果狗叫的话），”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这不是唯一一家向毛茸茸的游客敞开大门的企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候, 瑞典家具巨头宜家宣布，欢迎小型猫狗光顾其泰国门店，只要它们坐在婴儿车里即可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;电影院外，一只名叫 Tungchae 的重达 62 公斤的阿拉斯加雪橇犬发出失望的嚎叫– 乘坐配备风扇的 1.5 平方米狗推车抵达 – 被认为太大而无法进入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管电影院有动物福利保障措施，但并非所有宠物主人都对这个想法感到兴奋。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;一位长期居住在曼谷的外籍人士表示，虽然她的猫经常在家里的沙发上看电视时在她身边睡着，但她绝不会带宠物去电影院，认为这个概念“不自然”，“酷刑”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“被关在这个笼子里，我不知道这对动物来说是否愉快，”她告诉法新社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这太荒谬了，狗是不允许进入的在（大多数曼谷）公园，但他们可以去电影院或咖啡馆。接下来是什么，你把你的狗或猫带到按摩院？”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Money is more important than life’: Chinese influencer, 26, obsessed with boosting blog traffic, dies after alcohol-fuelled live stream]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3223279/money-more-important-life-chinese-influencer-26-obsessed-boosting-blog-traffic-dies-after-alcohol?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/546f8c1a-cbe6-4625-ac3f-d7009a526af7_f6034ef2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位急于为他的博客增加流量的中国影响者在被击倒后死亡在现场直播的饮酒比赛中，两瓶中国烈酒接二连三地喝了下去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;夺走了 26 岁网络名人“中原黄哥”生命的以酒精为燃料的现场直播引起了人们的关注。大陆社交媒体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的死是继另一名网红“三千哥”上个月在直播中喝了四瓶同种酒后去世的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《南方都市报》报道，“中原皇格”参加了“三千格”的葬礼，誓言少喝酒，为自己的死亡埋下了可怕的伏笔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新离世的网红来自在中国中部的河南省，他的短视频平台上有超过 170,000 名粉丝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他分享了 30 多个视频，包括吃生辣椒、打开椰子和榴莲等吸引眼球的绝技。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;饮酒比赛的视频显示，他点燃了浸有酒精的纸巾，然后迅速喝掉了半瓶酒。然后他吃了一些大葱，喝完了瓶子，再打开一瓶继续喝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据了解，他在手机上直播时已经喝完了两整瓶，然后被发现失去知觉&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这场悲剧凸显了人们在网上赚钱的距离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的妻子告诉极目新闻：“他想通过直播赚钱来偿还债务。”他欠了几十万元的债。结婚后，我们不知疲倦地工作以谋生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他直播间的背景中，也出现了金钱和死亡的幽灵，那句中国名言：“人死于财。 ，鸟儿为食而死”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还可以看到“金钱比生命更重要。没钱生不如死”、“我不吃不喝，就是要钱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，他老婆说他是个善良有责任心的人，给她和他们洗澡了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于选品不专业，又怕假货，“中元黄阁”在直播时避而不卖，让网友摸不着头脑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果他又不是利用流量来卖产品，为什么要这样毁掉自己的健康？”一个人问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人对他的死表示悲痛和理解。 “整体环境和生存压力推动了这种行为。生命短暂，我们应该珍惜我们所拥有的，比如我们的健康。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，中国政府已采取措施打击这种极端的网络行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 《网络主播行为规范》禁止主播展示自残、暴力、血腥、高危行为、吸烟酗酒等内容。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Zimbabwe citrus firms gain access to China’s massive food market]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223417/zimbabwe-citrus-firms-gain-access-chinas-massive-food-market?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/ef1fc8ab-15de-4a2b-a7c5-f394a9168c90_ade52a63.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在中国海关当局批准后，津巴布韦的柑橘种植者现在可以进入庞大的中国市场允许向中国出口新鲜水果的果园和包装厂名单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国驻哈拉雷大使馆宣布，6 月 1 日，中国海关总署 (GACC) 列出了 11 个注册的津巴布韦柑橘园和 6 个中国当局选择柑橘包装厂向中国出口柑橘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“津巴布韦新鲜柑橘现在可以出口到中国，中国是世界上最大的柑橘消费市场，”大使馆在 Twitter 上发帖称。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大使馆透露，津巴布韦现在可以向中国出口柑橘、甜橙、葡萄柚、柠檬、酸橙和酸橙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它说，果园和包装厂寻求向中国出口柑橘中国必须在津巴布韦土地、农业、渔业、水利和农村发展部注册，并获得津巴布韦当局和中国海关的批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;津巴布韦共有 4,000 公顷柑橘种植土地，其中气候非常适合种植农作物。南非是非洲大陆最大的柑橘类水果和其他园艺生产国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国进入夏季，津巴布韦的柑橘生长季节可以帮助弥补中国市场的缺口。当中国国内柑橘生产处于夏季淡季时，中国一半的柑橘进口来自南半球国家澳大利亚和南非。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;津巴布韦农业部长约翰巴塞拉说，中国海关总署的柑橘清单果园和包装厂是津巴布韦种植者向中国市场出口的成功基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在我们可以将柑橘直接出口到庞大且利润丰厚的中华人民共和国市场。这是提高柑橘产量的重大呼吁，”Basera 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说该国正在与中国就蓝莓、鳄梨和辣椒制定进一步的协议。津巴布韦去年向新加坡、阿拉伯联合酋长国、马来西亚、香港、荷兰、英国和赞比亚出口了 57,283 吨柑橘产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着中国向非洲农场开放，前路漫漫green lanes&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这项批准是在津巴布韦和中国敲定柑橘出口协议以简化产品进入中国的一年后，也是在 2015 年哈拉雷寻求中国市场时启动该程序七年后因为它的柑橘类水果。津巴布韦必须满足双边植物检疫协议中规定的要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约翰内斯堡南非国际事务研究所的中非研究员 Lauren Johnston 表示，各国要获得植物检疫准入权还有很长的路要走中国市场，因为进口大多数新鲜食品“存在进口次要物种的风险，包括可能损害中国自身食品供应的害虫，更不用说影响人口健康了”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，果农必须符合质量标准，中国当局制定的严格的植物病害控制和安全措施。出口到中国的津巴布韦柑橘必须经过冷处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“水果进入中国是中国决心……实现农产品来源多元化的另一个信号，不再依赖少数几个市场，例如美国和澳大利亚，”约翰斯顿说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也表明中国决心在中国和非洲之间培育新的出口市场，尤其是在农业领域，因为“这不仅可能有助于提高农业生产率以供消费Johnston 表示，在非洲人口不断增长的情况下，这也有助于提高农村收入并相应地促进减贫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;津巴布韦加入了越来越多的非洲国家行列，这些国家的食品已获准进入中国市场&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些非洲国家最近签署了协议，允许向中国出口辣椒、腰果、芝麻和香料等农产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坦桑尼亚现在可以向中国出口鳄梨和大豆。肯尼亚的鳄梨、茶、咖啡和玫瑰也达成了类似的交易；来自埃塞俄比亚的咖啡和大豆；来自纳米比亚和博茨瓦纳的牛肉产品；和来自卢旺达的咖啡。南非是中国柠檬、葡萄柚、橙子和软柑橘等水果的主要来源市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;观察人士表示，允许来自非洲的食品的举措也符合中国国家主席习近平在论坛期间的承诺关于 2021 年中非合作论坛（FOCAC），为非洲农产品进入中国开辟“绿色通道”，加快检验检疫程序，扩大免征关税的产品数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国、津巴布韦在哈拉雷筹备选举之际寻求加强联系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国去年免除了来自数十个最不发达国家（其中大部分在非洲）的 98% 的应税商品的关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，从津巴布韦进口的主要商品大多是资源性的，包括原烟草、铬矿、镍矿、铁合金和花岗岩。 2022 年，中津双边贸易额同比增长 29%，达到 24.3 亿美元，中国是津巴布韦第三大商品进口国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国出口到非洲的大部分是制成品– 从纺织品到电子产品 – 而非洲对中国的销售主要是原材料和未加工产品，导致对中国有利的贸易顺差。为帮助平衡贸易，习近平在 11 月承诺在未来三年内将从非洲国家进口的价值增加到 3000 亿美元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s falling birth rate may have more ‘disastrous’ effect than declining numbers in major cities]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3223647/chinas-falling-birth-rate-may-have-more-disastrous-effect-declining-numbers-major-cities?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 17:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/4c61aa82-1e12-42c9-81d0-a1661b52af5c_8702af51.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国大城市的人口减少不应该引起太大的恐慌，因为出生率下降一位分析师和一份官方报纸表示，人口增长仍然是该国面临的最大挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大陆四大城市——北京、上海、广州和深圳——报告称，去年居民人数有所下降，官方数据显示，人口总数超过 275,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特大城市北京和上海对这种下降并不陌生，因为它们制定了严格的人口流入政策以限制城市的快速扩张。然而，对于 2010 年至 2022 年间全国人口增长最快的制造业和科技中心广州和深圳来说，这是一个新趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年广州居民人数减少 76,500 人至 1,873 万人2022 年，深圳人口减少至 1768 万人，减少了 1.98 万人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是自 1979 年已故最高领导人邓小平设立经济特区以来，深圳人口首次出现负增长，此举将昔日沉睡的渔村变成了今天的经济强国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国营经济日报在周六发表的评论中说，虽然需要认真对待这四个城市的人口下降，但它应该&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“京沪常住人口减少是超大城市根据资源条件和功能定位，积极合理控制人口规模的结果”，文章&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两个城市在过去十年中都控制了人口流入，以缓解交通拥堵和生活条件恶化等“大城市病”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至于制造业强国广州和深圳，文章称，去年实施的严格的 Covid-19 控制措施迫使许多来自内陆省份的农民工因工作枯竭而返回家乡。它补充说，两市所在的广东省预计今年人口增长将再次回升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;评论称，城市治理、产业链搬迁和生活成本等多重因素可能会影响人口增长&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年中国人口出现六十年来首次下降，减少 85 万至 14.118 亿，年出生率降至每 1,000 人 6.77 人的历史低点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界第二大经济体日益严重的人口危机可能对经济增长产生深远影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黄文正，高级研究员总部设在北京的智库中国与全球化中心表示，一些大城市人口的偶尔小幅下降可能不会反映长期趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国面临的最大问题是其年轻人口减少人口，尤其是 [下降] 新生儿。这将对中国的所有行业产生长期的灾难性影响，并对整个国家未来的投资信心产生非常负面的影响，”黄说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;是否应该为中国的人口危机加深？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;此外，东京和莫斯科的经验表明，在人口总体下降的情况下，大城市的人口缩减速度可能会慢于小城市，因为大城市继续吸引来自其他地区的移民他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于未来中国人口下降的速度可能比日本和俄罗斯快得多，从长远来看，人们到大城市仍是趋势”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，黄警告说，对特大城市规模的过度控制可能会限制未来经济发展的机会，因为可以带来活力和创新的年轻农民工将被赶走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;此外，他说，北京和上海等大城市拥有土地资源来容纳进一步的城市扩张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“高房价和交通拥堵是人口增长和城市发展的代价。如果你不想通过控制城市规模来付出这些代价，那就意味着你也无法从中获得好处。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan’s refugee law changes empower government amid distrust in immigration system]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3223644/japans-refugee-law-changes-empower-government-amid-distrust-immigration-system?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 16:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/bdc31168-46b1-437d-b89c-b59915039da7_6c674007.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;经过激烈的辩论和无数挫折，日本于周五颁布了有争议的移民和移民修正案难民法使政府能够将屡次申请难民的人驱逐回原籍国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，尽管政府试图向其批评者保证，它将“适当回应”它看到的难民案件，但它的能力在赋予自己对弱势群体更大的权力之际，确保全球越来越多的弱势群体的安全受到严重质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一桥大学副教授 Naoko Hashimoto 在众议院表示众议院司法事务委员会 4 月表示，“如果该法案按原样通过，将相当于间接按下按钮处决无辜者”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本通过有争议的修改移民法的法案&lt;/p h3>;&lt;p>;移民控制和难民承认法修订的核心是对人们可以向该国申请难民承认的次数的有效限制。任何尝试三次或以上的人现在都有资格被驱逐出境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着全球难民形势在全球范围内恶化，联合国难民事务高级专员公署表示，2022 年难民人数全球被迫流离失所的人数首次超过 1 亿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法务大臣齐藤健表示，在 2021 年修订法律失败后，这些变化是“紧迫的事情”，因为现行立法保护犯有谋杀等严重罪行的个人在申请难民身份时不被驱逐出境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据日本移民服务局的数据，截至年底，已有 4,233 名外国人拒绝遵守驱逐令2022 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中有相当一部分人尽管坚称如果返回本国将面临生命危险，但仍未获得难民身份批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于日本，难民接纳最早始于 1981 年，同年它加入了联合国 1951 年的难民公约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后，关于该国对难民采取勉强态度的辩论被 2002 年一家五口逃离朝鲜的案件点燃并试图进入中国北部沉阳的日本领事馆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们被中国警察拖出领事馆的镜头引起了轰动，导致 2005 年修订了难民法。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;在其变化中，它引入了对难民身份申请人的驱逐出境豁免权，并建立了由外部专家判断是否批准案件的难民审查顾问制度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2010 年，现已解散的民主党日本政府进一步更改规则，允许潜在难民在提交申请后六个月内通过工作维持生计。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随之而来的是申请数量急剧增加，到 2017 年，难民申请达到创纪录的 19,629 份。由于怀疑许多人通过虚假申请来逃避驱逐出境和获得工作许可，该机构于 2018 年收紧了规定，并开始寻求限制免于强行遣返的豁免权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管采取了更严格的措施，但该机构的一名高级官员该机构坚称它确实“为那些真正需要它的外国人提供了救济”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在 2001 年至 2020 年期间，日本平均批准了不到 1% 的申请，这一比例明显低于许多国家其他国家。 2022 年，德国授予了创纪录的 202 人难民身份，其中包括 147 名阿富汗人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，日本难民协会估计，到 2021 年，德国向大约 39,000 人（占申请人的 25.9%）授予了难民身份，而在同一年，美国批准了大约 20,000 人，占申请人总数的 32.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在日本议会辩论中披露的信息也加剧了人们对该系统在日本管理方式的不信任：是否给予难民身份的判断集中在少数具体的考试顾问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多司法判决也暴露了日本授予难民认证的随意方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在3 月，大阪地方法院命令政府给予一名 30 多岁的乌干达妇女难民身份，这名妇女说她担心该国对 LGBTQ 人群的严厉对待会受到迫害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名妇女在辅导员提出上诉后提出上诉分配给她的案件并没有要求她在面对面的会议中提供有关她的情况的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本公布了有史以来第一个关于难民身份承认的指南&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;日本律师Network for Refugees 表示，据悉有超过 50 起法院上诉成功，以撤销该机构拒绝的难民身份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该网络的代表 Shogo Watanabe 表示，这些数字表明，应该被承认为难民的人却没有。他说，修改后的法律“非常明显地表明移民机构的管理比人权更重要”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“必须建立独立于移民机构的审批制度，以作为难民的最后手段。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia’s Umno caught between rock and hard place as identity crisis grips ahead of state polls]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3223636/malaysias-umno-caught-between-rock-and-hard-place-identity-crisis-grips-ahead-state-polls?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 17:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/3aba073e-a979-4d2e-a8d7-2856180f26d5_96f7f1ca.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;马来西亚前执政党巫统在寻求重建形象时面临一场艰巨的艰苦战斗作为多数马来穆斯林的拥护者，同时在六个州选举之前适应其在联邦联合政府中的少数角色的新现实，这可能决定该组织在该国政治舞台上的持续相关性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;分析人士表示，未来两个月将举行的民意调查将衡量总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣政府的受欢迎程度，尤其是在占东南亚国家 3200 万人口 60% 以上的马来人中。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;The outcome, however, is unlikely to have a direct effect on Anwar&#39;s government, but it may set the tone for its policies moving forward if the results lean heavily in favour of the Malay nationalist Perikatan Nasional opposition front.&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Umno is also seen as a key cog to the performance of Anwar&#39;s multiracial administration in the elections due to its strength as the sole significant Malay party that could take on the rivals Bersatu and the Pan-Malaysian Islamic Party (PAS). &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As former foes lead Malaysia, wary public hopes unity is not &#39;just for show&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Should there be those who play up sentiments, claiming that Umno&#39;s political cooperation would erode the position of Islam, the Malays and the bumiputeras, I would like to stress that Umno are no political chameleons,” Umno president Ahmad Zahid Hamidi told the party&#39;s general assembly on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We will continue to defend the four articles enshrined in the federal constitution,” he said, referring to provisions guaranteeing the rights and privileges of the Malays.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But that goal is easier said than done after Umno – which ruled Malaysia for decades – suffered a string of defeats, including at the 2018 national polls that saw its traditional support base erode sharply on the back of widespread anger over soaring living costs and allegations of rampant corruption under then premier Najib Razak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A period of political upheaval in the following years and victories in two state polls appeared to have given the party a boost. Yet, that sentiment turned sour after Umno won just 26 of the 222 parliamentary seats in last November&#39;s general election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Malay voters disillusioned with Umno powered a “green wave” – so-called to reflect PAS&#39; party colours – that gave Perikatan a near clean sweep of the northern states in Malaysia&#39;s peninsula.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PAS also emerged as the single largest party in parliament with 49 seats.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The split in votes, however, also meant that no party or coalition managed to secure enough seats to claim the right to form government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The situation paved the way for Umno&#39;s rescue from political oblivion. To break the deadlock, the king chose Anwar as prime minister on condition that he form a unity government that includes their sworn political rivals – and Umno had just the right numbers to seal the deal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ahmad Zahid said in his policy speech that this was a necessary “political adjustment” to make sure Umno gets a seat at the table. It was a profitable gambit: he was made a deputy prime minister and several senior Umno leaders were given key ministerial positions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Malaysia&#39;s jailed ex-PM Najib is seeking a royal pardon. What happens next?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Anwar also threw his weight behind Umno&#39;s efforts to reset, making a historic return to the party&#39;s headquarters to attend the launch of its general assembly on Friday, 25 years after he was sacked following an acrimonious spat with his former mentor and ex-Umno president Mahathir Mohamad.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ahmad Zahid stressed that Umno needs to be “progressive” in finding its place in Anwar&#39;s multiracial administration, but at the same time made it clear that the outfit must also do what it can to regain its position as the party of choice for the Malays.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If we truly want to see Islam and the Malays at the forefront, our inclusion in government … will strengthen a Malay-Muslim agenda that is moderate and progressive,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong schools get national security Q&A kit for pupils to learn over summer break, but principals say homework too tricky for youngsters]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3223639/hong-kong-schools-get-national-security-qa-kit-pupils-learn-over-summer-break-principals-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 17:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/10/f9214ed4-3831-49cb-a40a-7ee4c9f5dfde_0990a9d0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s education authorities have issued a set of 62 questions and answers on national security and Chinese history for students to learn on their own during the summer holidays, but some principals have said they are too difficult for younger children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It went out with a circular from the Education Bureau to all local primary and secondary schools this week, suggesting activities they could plan and available resources for marking the third anniversary of the introduction of the national security law in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bureau said the 62 multiple choice questions, answers and references aimed to strengthen students&#39; understanding of their country and national security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It encouraged students to go through them on their own during the two-month holidays, and added that teachers should follow up on their progress.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;National security: fund requires exit clauses in Hong Kong school contracts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Some principals told the Post they needed more clarity, including guidelines on how to use the materials and what teachers were supposed to do.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The questions are quite difficult and it is impossible for kids in the lower grades to understand, let alone answer them,” Yaumati Catholic Primary School (Hoi Wang Road) Principal Polly Chan Shuk-yee said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The circular also says teachers should follow up on the students&#39; progress, and we want to know what, exactly, that means.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Titled “National Security Education Summer Self-learning Materials”, the set of questions covers Hong Kong and Chinese political history, policy developments and cultural heritage, and is meant for primary and secondary schools.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One question asks students to name the Chinese leader who said during a meeting with a United States congressional delegation in 1978 that “China could not bear the imperative to not use force to solve the Taiwan problem, otherwise it would practically cut off a method to resolve the Taiwan problem, including a peaceful resolution”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Principals said few students, and even some teachers, were likely to know the answer was Deng Xiaoping, China&#39;s late paramount leader.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another question asks students to identify the duties of the Hong Kong government&#39;s Committee for Safeguarding National Security, with more than one correct answer from a choice of four.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other questions are about the contents of a mainland policy paper on resolving housing difficulties faced by poor urban families in 2007, the dates of Unesco World Heritage site listings of various attractions in mainland China and Macau, and matching political quotes with speakers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong lawmaker queries using government cash for national security education&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Principal Chan said students could work on just one question a day during the holidays as suggested by the Education Bureau, but the contents were complicated and she questioned if younger children could grasp them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The burden will probably end up landing on the parents,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chu Wai-lam, vice-chairman of the New Territories School Heads Association and headmaster of Fung Kai No 1 Primary School in Sheung Shui, said even older primary students were likely to only “partially understand” the topics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But, like some other educators, he viewed the set of questions as a suggestion for lesson planning rather than a compulsory activity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said teachers could group the questions by topic and create lesson plans, before asking students to complete the quiz afterwards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Agreeing that schools had flexibility, Langton Cheung Yung-pong, a primary school principal and honorary chairman of the Hong Kong Aided Primary School Heads Association, said: “I think if this was mandatory and we were meant to strictly adhere to these questions, we would know without a doubt.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that in the past, the Education Bureau had used “very tough” language when announcing compulsory activities for schools.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This time, it appeared different. “Teachers can adapt the questions and topics to their students&#39; level using their professional judgment,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Responding to the Post, a bureau spokeswoman said the national security law package was meant to encourage continuous learning in national education, and schools and teachers had leeway in deciding how to use the materials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The guidelines do not have fixed learning methods,” she said. “Schools and teachers may decide how it should be used, while students can also learn by themselves by using the explanatory information in the materials.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Many Hong Kong schools get failing marks on national security teaching&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, education sector lawmaker Chu Kwok-keung said there was “room for improvement” at the government&#39;s end as the materials were “not of very high quality”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For one, there are several glaring typos,” he said. “One question asks about the &#39;1988 financial crisis&#39; when it should be 1998.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another question spotted by the Post states that the first meeting of the Leading Group for the Development of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macau Greater Bay Area was held in 1985, but the correct year is 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chu said: “It will be better for learning if the government produced videos or stories for students to watch each week. This seems like a very rigid approach.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Las Vegas police investigate reports of UFO sightings after resident says aliens crashed in his backyard]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223643/las-vegas-police-investigate-reports-ufo-sightings-after-resident-says-aliens-crashed-his-backyard?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 16:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/10/7190ddfa-45f6-4b7f-9943-3e1e913ce63a_7c20bbf0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Big, shiny eyes. Towering nearly 10 feet tall. 100 per cent not human. Aliens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That&#39;s the 911 emergency call that came into dispatchers last month from a Las Vegas area resident reporting extraterrestrial life in his backyard, just about an hour after local police witnessed an object falling from the sky.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The paranormal investigation by police did not turn up any answers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On May 1, 2023, at approximately 12.29am. LVMPD dispatch received a call about a suspicious situation,” the Las Vegas Police Department said in an email statement. “Officer conducted a preliminary investigation and closed the event as unfounded.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At around 11.50pm (local time) on April 30, body camera footage from an officer with the Las Vegas Metropolitan Police captured a bright, glowing object cutting through the sky, according to local TV channel 8 News Now.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 40 minutes later, a local resident placed a 911 call to report that something “100 per cent not human” was staring at him from his backyard soon after he and his family saw an object fall from the sky, the station reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Nasa joins hunt for UFOs, hiring experts to solve &#39;perplexing mysteries&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“There&#39;s like an 8-foot person beside it, and another one&#39;s inside us, and it has big eyes and it&#39;s looking at us – and it&#39;s still there,” the caller, who said that he and his family had seen something fall from the sky, told the dispatcher.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I swear to God this is not a joke, this is actually – we&#39;re terrified,” the caller said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local TV channel 8 News Now first reported the story and obtained the video and audio from that weird evening, including the 911 call and body camera footage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dispatcher clarified the situation with the caller, careful to choose the right words.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So, there&#39;s two people – there&#39;s two subjects in your backyard?” the dispatcher asked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Correct, and they&#39;re very large,” the caller said. “They&#39;re like 8 foot, 9 feet, 10 foot. They look like aliens to us. Big eyes. They have big eyes. Like, I can&#39;t explain it, and big mouth. They&#39;re shiny eyes and they&#39;re human. They&#39;re 100 per cent not human.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two officers responded to the caller&#39;s home, KLAS reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m so nervous right now,” one of the responding officers said while en route to the house. “I have butterflies bro.” He continues to say that people “saw a shooting star, and now these people say there&#39;s aliens in their backyard.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officers interviewed the family on their front lawn.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What did you see?” one of the officers asks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was like a big creature,” one witness said, adding it was around 10 feet tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The officer tells them about the incident his colleague saw just before the call came in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m not going to BS you guys. One of my partners said they saw something fall out of the sky, too,” the officer said. “So that&#39;s why I&#39;m kind of curious. Did you see anything land in your backyard?”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UFOs: the community still believes and science is listening&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A man in a robe said some of his family members saw “a big something with light” plummet from above.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police continued to investigate that evening, asking neighbours if they too had witnessed any unusual objects fall from the sky. KLAS reported the investigation lasted for several days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US Department of Defence is tracking more than 800 cases of “unidentified aerial phenomena,” often called UFOs, from the past 27 years, according to government officials, who added that only 2 per cent to 5 per cent of cases can be explained.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Some flights delayed after 2 planes collide on ground at Tokyo’s Haneda airport]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3223641/some-flights-delayed-after-2-planes-collide-ground-tokyos-haneda-airport?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 15:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/10/f969dd84-e886-4710-bc0c-df5bb1ada9df_b6f6fec3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Some flights were delayed at Tokyo&#39;s Haneda airport on Saturday after two planes appeared to have collided on the ground near a taxiway, public broadcaster NHK reported, citing Japan&#39;s transport ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No injuries occurred, NHK and one of the airlines said, but the incident led to the closure of one of four runways at the airport from about 11am (local time).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The runway reopened about two hours later after it was cleared, said Isamu Yamane, a deputy administrator in the transport ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;I just felt horror of death,&#39; says man next to Korean who opened plane door&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;NHK showed footage of jets from Taiwan&#39;s Eva Airways and Thai Airways on the ground. Part of the wing of the Thai Airways plane looked to be broken, and what appeared to be fragments could be seen near the runway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thai Airways said its Bangkok-bound flight was on a taxiway preparing for take-off when a winglet – a part at the tip of its plane&#39;s right wing – collided with the rear of an Eva aircraft that was also on a taxiway headed to Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The collision damaged the Thai aeroplane&#39;s winglet, meaning it was unable to operate the flight, the airline said. The Airbus A330 aircraft carried 250 passengers and 14 crew members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eva was not available for comment immediately.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan&#39;s transport ministry did not respond immediately to a request for comment. Thai Airways said Japan&#39;s civil aviation authority was investigating the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 15:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>