<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Why the US must look beyond its rivalry with China and engage Southeast Asia on its own merits]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/opinion/article/3224310/why-us-must-look-beyond-its-rivalry-china-and-engage-southeast-asia-its-own-merits?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/c09bbe6b-4198-4a58-98ec-c8918fe7d64a_f55e7f26.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;2011 年 11 月，美国总统巴拉克奥巴马宣布美国外交政策将制定“重心”转向亚洲。但随后在 2017 年 1 月，随着刚刚就职的总统唐纳德特朗普启动了他的“美国优先”议程，将美国从他称为“扼杀工作”的跨性别国家中拉出来，这一转变的关键部分——加强经济互动——发生了逆转-太平洋伙伴关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;放弃 TPP 造成的损害是巨大的。美国严重促进与亚洲贸易的前景受到削弱，对美国的信任受到打击，非 TPP 成员国中国扩大与该协会 10 个成员国已经存在的贸易和经济联系的道路敞开&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普不太关心东盟，尽管这些成员国拥有超过 6.75 亿人口，并且共同构成了全球经济的重要组成部分。作为美国总统，他通常蔑视多边组织，并跳过大多数东盟峰会和其他大型亚洲区域会议，而中国、日本和韩国的领导人从未错过这些会议。他还保留了一些重要的大使职位多年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有出现肯定让东盟领导人感到不安，因为在东南亚，人际关系真的很重要，“在那里”很重要。在一部 1979 年的同名讽刺电影中，彼得·塞勒斯扮演了一个普通的园丁，他对植物和生长的评论不知何故使他被认为是美国总统的理想人选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乔·拜登总统的政府认识到这一点的重要性在那里。它正试图通过由 14 个成员组成的印度洋-太平洋经济繁荣框架来增加经济参与；但由于它没有扩大市场准入，该集团——包括东盟 10 个成员中的七个——不太可能产生太大的热情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个大问题是保护主义和反华情绪更加强烈和深入在美国比奥巴马发起他的支点时。拜登不会推动贸易自由化措施，即使他可以，如果特朗普赢得美国大选，这些措施也可能在 2024 年被取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国在东盟的影响力在增长，尽管中国仍被视为最重要的影响力：调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中美关系恶化在东南亚引起了比以往更多的关注，每个国家对北京和华盛顿都有自己的看法。近年来，出现了一系列关注中国与东南亚有时令人担忧的关系的好书，现在有一本专门介绍美国与该地区的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它的标题是不完美的伙伴——美国和东南亚，由经验丰富的外交官 Scot Marciel 撰写，他现已从美国国务院退休。他清楚地知道华盛顿应该做什么，不应该做什么；最不应该做的事情是尝试将东盟变成反华组织的“行不通”。相反，美国需要将该地区视为其自身优势的增长和关键，而不是作为大国与中国竞争的重要地盘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国的做法“不能简单地成为其中国的必然结果战略”，马西尔断言，并补充说华盛顿不应该认为东南亚对中国的抵制，比如对南中国海领土主张的抵制，意味着它对北京的看法与美国一样，认为北京是“主要是恶意影响”。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;他认为，无论华盛顿做什么，中国都将在东南亚产生重大影响。由于显而易见的原因，中国将继续主导美国关于亚洲的讨论，因为东南亚是一个“杂耍”。马西尔目前所在的斯坦福大学智库有 12 名分析员在中国工作，只有两名在东南亚工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前外交官表示，美国需要继续出现并促进与东南亚的关系。他写道，在一个“长期以来对美国在该地区的持久力持怀疑态度的地区，始终如一地出现在最高层是必不可少的”，并补充说华盛顿需要成为一个“始终如一、可靠和良好的伙伴”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Marciel 非常有资格撰写有关美国和东南亚的文章。在 35 年多的时间里，他在华盛顿担任亚洲高级职位，并在 2021 年 2 月的灾难性政变之前担任驻东盟、印度尼西亚和缅甸大使。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的书既是回忆录又是入门读物，与对潜在投资者或刚接触东南亚的人有帮助的背景。内容丰富的文字在一些地方并不完美。关于越南的章节提到了 1964 年的东京湾事件，但没有任何背景，这让年轻的读者很难理解它是什么。印度尼西亚章节中有几个日期略有错误，APEC（亚太经合组织论坛）的全名被错误地命名为亚太经济合作组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，有一个很多非常扎实的材料。最精彩的章节中有两章是关于缅甸的，这极大地揭示了政变前这个长期封闭的国家正在发生的事情。马西尔与昂山素季相处了很长时间，他写到她要求他和美国政府不要使用“罗兴亚人”这个词。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我们自己土地上的客人”：难民营中的罗兴亚人赢得了胜利&#39;return to Myanmar&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;外交生活中的一些个人经历​​有助于保持文本的高度可读性。 Marciel 讲述了他如何在 1993 年被派往越南——美国仍然对该越南实施贸易禁运——成为河内的“存在”，而当时华盛顿没有任何人居住在河内。为了执行任务，他携带了近 50,000 美元的现金来支付酒店和其他费用。美国驻曼谷大使馆交出现金包的官员“警告我，如果我被抢劫或丢了钱，我将为此承担个人责任”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marciel 写得很好，而且很有道理幽默，并非每个外交官都如此。关于出现的主题，他写道，参加东盟会议“就像去你配偶的家庭团聚。这可能不是你做过的最难忘的事情，但参加活动会带来回报，不参加肯定会让你付出代价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Richard Borsuk 曾在东南亚担任记者和新闻编辑40 多年，其中 11 年在雅加达（1987-1998）担任《华尔街日报》驻印度尼西亚记者。他与人合着了一本关于印度尼西亚历史的书，“Liem Sioe Liong 的三林集团：苏哈托印度尼西亚的商业支柱”，于 2014 年出版。Borsuk 目前是南洋理工大学 S. Rajaratnam 国际研究学院的兼职高级研究员，新加坡。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https //feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Grammy rules say only human creators can win, amid rise of AI music]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224416/new-grammy-rules-say-only-human-creators-can-win-amid-rise-ai-music?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 07:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/a1ebd100-0c09-4da7-b838-48f47941f36e_67819246.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“只有人类创作者才有资格”获得格莱美奖，唱片学院于星期五，授予世界上最受认可的音乐奖项的机构试图遏制人工智能 (AI) 在行业中的使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纯 AI 作品被禁止，但一些在 AI 帮助下创作的音乐可能符合某些类别的资格，学院更新后的规则手册写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不包含人类作者身份的作品不符合任何类别的资格。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;音乐创作者现在必须至少为一张专辑的 20% 获得提名。过去，专辑中的任何制作人、词曲作者、工程师或特色艺术家都可以获得年度专辑提名，即使他们的贡献很小。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一届格莱美颁奖典礼在1959 年，以奖励 1958 年的音乐创作者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 11 月，OpenAI 推出了 ChatGPT，这是一款由微软公司支持的免费聊天机器人，可以根据简单的输入生成类人对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AI 应用程序具有人工智能如雨后春笋般涌现，允许用户为静态照片制作动画，在电影中创建化身，以及创作歌曲、散文和文章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多行业的人们越来越担心人工智能会取代人类。例如，美国作家协会 (WGA) 和美国演员工会 (SAG-AFTRA) 正在努力解决在编剧和表演创意领域使用 AI 的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;好莱坞作家将成为工作室谈判失败&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;WGA 希望在编剧中遏制 AI，而 SAG 演员希望确保其成员能够控制他们数字角色的使用并获得适当的补偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;WGA 编剧继续5 月初举行罢工，但尚未与工作室就人工智能的使用等问题达成一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果 SAG-AFTRA 无法就类似问题达成协议，演员们也可能继续罢工。&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s booming one-man bookstore on WeChat shows how Tencent is taking on ByteDance in live-streaming e-commerce]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224369/chinas-booming-one-man-bookstore-wechat-shows-how-tencent-taking-bytedance-live-streaming-e-commerce?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/dfa759c5-7d72-490b-a461-888ecbec6c5d_9596acee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;赵健曾经在南京经营一家占地9000平方米的大型书店；现在，他在镜头前经营着一家网上单人商店。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;向电子商务的转变为这位 30 岁的商人带来了意外收获。在合适的时机和微信渠道的支持下，赵发现他一天可以卖出的书数量与他过去在其占地面积超过 20 个篮球场的实体店一周的销量一样。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;腾讯控股一直在 Channels 宣传赵的故事，Channels 是该公司广泛使用的微信消息应用程序上的短视频平台。今年 6 月 18 日的购物节于 5 月下旬开始，赵先生平均每天售出价值 100 万至 150 万元人民币（140,000 美元至 200,000 美元）的书籍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深圳-这家总部位于中国的科技巨头正在寻求在中国在线零售市场获得更大的份额，现在正在加强对其平台上商家的支持。在本月购物节期间，腾讯已将商家的“技术支持费”降至 1%。正常税率在 1% 到 5% 之间，具体取决于产品类别。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直播已成为中国的一种新购物方式，特别是对于习惯于在视频中看到的商品进行订购的年轻消费者而言由商家和有影响力的人推荐。抖音是字节跳动旗下的中国版 TikTok，它已积极采取行动，通过销售将用户注意力货币化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南华早报的所有者阿里巴巴集团控股公司也押注直播流媒体到吸引消费者。在最近的一个案例中，阿里巴巴邀请足球明星莱昂内尔·梅西加入淘宝商家的直播。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;像如今的许多中国在线零售商一样，赵说他每天直播，通常是晚上 7 点 30 分到晚上 11 点 30 分，每30分钟介绍一本新书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些书我会[和读者]讨论几次，”赵在接受腾讯安排的采访时说。 “比如，我每周讲两三遍《资治通鉴》。我在直播间引导读者按照目录逐章阅读。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵现在在微信频道拥有超过 180 万粉丝，最初他是通过应用的朋友圈功能增长的，类似于 Facebook 的 Feed，他说。这最终吸引了不在他社交圈内的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的粉丝中，30%以上在北京，20%以上来自上海、浙江、江苏和广东，赵说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;深圳希望成为全球直播电商中心&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;借助微信 13 亿月活跃用户的庞大基础，渠道一直在快速增长，估计有根据数据分析公司 QuestMobile 的数据，截至去年 6 月，每月活跃用户为 8.13 亿。这使其超过同月抖音的 6.8 亿用户和快手的 3.9 亿用户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然创始人马化腾在 2018 年的内部会议上将渠道称为公司的“新希望”到 2022 年底，腾讯已经衡量了其将功能货币化的方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在电子商务方面，与视频帐户中的直播相关，实际上存在非常大的机会，并且部分其他短视频公司已经证明了这一点，”腾讯总裁刘炽平在 5 月份的分析师电话会议上表示。 “但我们希望循序渐进，以便我们能够正确构建基础设施。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2020 年 1 月推出测试版以来，微信渠道推出了一系列电子商务工具和激励计划帮助商家通过直播带货，腾讯从中抽取佣金。据该公司称，去年商品总价值（衡量平台上销售的商品总价值）增长了 800%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为腾讯吸引更多有影响力的人加入其平台的努力的一部分，微信在三月份宣布将允许内容创作者在他们的频道上设置付费订阅。它还将在评论部分增加新的广告空间，同时让频道所有者从收入中分一杯羹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;腾讯的谨慎做法是确保用户体验和内容质量的正确举措，首席执行官张毅表示广州市场研究公司艾媒咨询的副总裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于腾讯来说，最重要的前提是留住微信用户，而不是因为商业化而流失用户，”张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，腾讯距离将渠道变成摇钱树还有很长的路要走。相比之下，一段时间以来，抖音一直是一个成熟的收入来源，根据 The Information 的一份报告，去年的商家总价值为人民币 1.41 万亿元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;短视频应用也在吸引广告商远离其他应用社交媒体平台。根据中关村互动营销实验室和普华永道 1 月份的一份报告，抖音是去年广告收入增长的唯一互联网类别。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;商业市场，Channels 凭借其广泛的用户基础和强大的社交网络在未来迎头赶上并非不可能，”张说。 “但对于腾讯来说，他们也在关注抖音直播暴露出的问题[向他们学习]。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 07:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Antony Blinken’s visit to China could be a success even without breakthrough agreements: analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224415/antony-blinkens-visit-china-could-be-success-even-without-breakthrough-agreements-analysts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 06:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/84ea9ce4-d5a9-4d43-b145-e93c1eb2adf6_e1124442.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯备受期待的中国之行的成功衡量标准是分析人士认为，不是它是否会产生突破性协议，而是它是否重新建立了对这种关系的一些可预测性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国领土上空发现疑似中国监视气球等事件后，经过数月的双边争吵 -关系的挫折导致布林肯 2 月访华的计划脱轨——分析人士认为，华盛顿高级特使即将到来的访问更重要的是检验两国关系的未来，而不是将要进行的任何实质性讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿智库布鲁金斯学会高级研究员瑞安哈斯说：“这次访问是探索过程的第一步，以确定是否存在足够的共同意图来试图缓和这种关系的轨迹。” p>;&lt;p>;布林肯的访问让他有机会在中国崛起的情况下重申美国的核心原则，并且“甚至可能在外交介入方面做得比整个政府做得更好一点”，迈克尔·奥汉隆 (Michael O&#39;Hanlon) 说，布鲁金斯学会的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次访问，无论是直接的还是隐含的，都可以帮助发出那种回归常态的信号，我们的目标是引导中国回到和平崛起的道路上，而不是将其视为我们的下一个敌人，”奥汉隆补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯定于周日和周一与中国高级官员举行会议。他将成为2019年以来首位访华的美国内阁级官员、2018年以来的第一任国务卿，以及乔·拜登总统2021年1月上任以来级别最高的美国政府官员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家预计布林肯将按照惯例获准与中国国家主席习近平会面，但尚未发布官方声明。布林肯还预计将在 2 月与习近平会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈斯说，习近平与布林肯会面的部分原因是因为中国领导人希望在访问美国时给予他们同样的访问权限。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;在布林肯访问之前，中国敦促美国避免实力的“幻觉”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;如果两国不见面，那将发出一个信息，表明事情出了问题，据称布鲁金斯学会的另一位研究员帕特丽夏·金 (Patricia Kim)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平实际上只是为比尔盖茨腾出时间，所以如果他不为秘书腾出时间，那将是惊人的，”她指的是中国领导人的周五在北京与微软联合创始人兼亿万富翁慈善家会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯本周的访问也准备作为亚太经济合作组织领导人峰会等重大全球会议的开场白11 月的旧金山和 9 月的 20 国集团领导人峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计这将为包括商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多 (Gina Raimondo) 和财政部长在内的其他美国高级官员访问中国奠定基础珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 两人都表示有兴趣踏上旅程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯的访问是在美国高级官员举行多次会晤后进行的，包括他 2 月份在慕尼黑与中国最高外交官王毅的会晤，以及国家安全顾问杰克沙利文 5 月在维也纳与易建联会面。雷蒙多和美国贸易代表凯瑟琳戴伊上个月在美国会见了中国商务部长王文涛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，美国中央情报局局长威廉伯恩斯和美国助理国务卿丹尼尔克里滕布林克负责东亚和太平洋事务的两人最近都从中国访问归来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，专家们表示，自今年早些时候拜登和习近平 11 月在美国会晤后，外交取得进展的可能性已经减弱G20巴厘岛。本月早些时候，中国国防部长李尚福拒绝在香格里拉对话会上与美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀 Lloyd Austin 会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登印太事务特别顾问库尔特·坎贝尔周三表示，布林肯此行有三个目标：建立沟通渠道，讨论“重要挑战，消除误解，防止误判”；就美国对一系列问题的关切发表意见；探讨应对跨国挑战的潜在合作，包括如何增加人与人之间的交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但拜登政府已明确表示，参加会议并不是为了取得任何突破。它还强调竞争推动关系，中国是美国最大的地缘政治挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为回应，北京周五表示，华盛顿不应打着竞争的幌子遏制和打压中国，并将中国视为它最大的挑战是“严重误判”。几天前，中国外交部长秦刚敦促布林肯“表现出尊重”，停止损害中国利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美中关系是走向解冻还是只是一个管理分歧的时代？&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;观察人士说，双方在会后宣读中的语气很重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于北京官员来说，布林肯的访问是他们“魅力攻势”的一个方面，将有助于他们“即使没有具体进展”，布鲁金斯学会另一位高级研究员 David Dollar 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;注意到中国经济放缓以及国内外私营部门对中国经济的信心下降，Dollar 表示此行可能向欧洲展示以及中国在美国的盟友认为北京愿意与华盛顿合作“阻止恶性循环”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，布林肯的访问可能会强化“欧洲不愿在技术上与美国全面合作”与中国竞争和遏制中国”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国外交部长秦刚和美国特使打破外交僵局&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;哈斯表示，此次访问将对布林肯及其团队提出“纪律考验” “消除噪音”，关注中国人在闭门造车中传达的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但拜登不太可能声称在建立“护栏”以“负责任地管理”双边竞争方面取得进展，专家说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一家位于华盛顿的研究机构昆西研究所的迈克尔·斯温表示，由于美国在很大程度上以零和竞争的方式构建了这种关系，中国将对任何此类护栏持怀疑态度&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在取得任何重大进展之前，Swaine 说，“双方都需要认识到每一方都在助长这种消极动态”。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>; &lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s culture police spark fears of overkill as Communist Party steps up ideological drive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3224401/chinas-culture-police-spark-fears-overkill-communist-party-steps-ideological-drive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/7bee7ef0-c13f-4cbd-b307-5c6ed41fca68_86bad3b0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国的文化执法——最近打击单口相声的核心随着执政的共产党推进其以习近平主席的学说为主导的意识形态运动，这一场景如火如荼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但观察家警告称，官方可能会过度使用权力来控制文化 –几十年前发起的——更上一层楼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，单口喜剧演员李浩石因被认为“侮辱”人民解放军的笑话在北京接受调查后，执法行动引起了全国的关注。由对李的行为的举报引发的调查还对代表他的喜剧团处以超过 1400 万元人民币（200 万美元）的罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化执法部门重点关注单口相声、现场表演、游戏室和电影制片厂最近作为其坚持主流社会主义价值观的承诺的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这种驱动方式引发了人们对本已有限的艺术印象空间的担忧，面对党的目标是使中国的网络、名人和媒体与政府政策和“习近平思想”保持一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多伦多大学政治学教授 Lynette Ong 表示，文化执法似乎旨在“净化人们的思想”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就像意识形态统治指导人们，告诉他们什么可以相信或不可以在公共场合相信、实践或说出什么，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;上周一，李的案子再次引起媒体关注，一则通知说，他演出的北京剧院也被罚款10万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李剧团所在的上海笑果文化传媒旗下公司也被罚款当天的另一份通知称，因“从事未经授权的商业演出业务”，罚款 7 万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海小果周二表示，最新的处罚也与李案有关，同时承诺“我们未经官方许可，绝不会恢复任何演出”。作为对李事件的惩罚，上海小果在全国范围内的所有表演都被暂停。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是因为党的中央领导层在习近平的政治学说下推动意识形态“思想统一”——习近平中国特色社会主义思想新时代特征——2018 年写入宪法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平本人也一直在推动马克思主义与中国传统文化的融合，并在十年前将文化工作提升到国家安全的高度.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;从毛到习：共产党领导人如何塑造其意识形态&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;除北京外，其他城市的文化执法人员似乎也在监管娱乐场所和&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据国有媒体《重庆日报》报道，西南部特大城市重庆的官员上周视察了娱乐场所，其中包括经营流行“密室逃脱”和角色扮演谋杀悬疑游戏的企业。报告称，他们确定了被视为“血腥暴力”或“歪曲历史”的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它没有具体说明任何惩罚，只是说那些犯有“轻微罪行”的人——并且已经纠正了他们—— &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据媒体报道，最近几个月，东部城市宁波和西北部的定西的执法人员也在全市范围内对单口相声俱乐部进行了检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;组织者在中国的线下活动已经需要获得相应地方文化监管部门的批准，单口相声节目等活动需要提交剧本进行提前审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化执法部门被纳入2018 年党和国家机构改革计划，旨在加强行政执法，并在市场监管、生态环境保护、交通运输和农业等领域建立专职队伍。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国新农村法治力量被指强硬反农民策略&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在文化和旅游部的指导下，该部队负责监督与文化、历史文物、出版、广播和电视、电影和旅游有关的问题和事件。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;香港大学法律与社会学教授刘思达指出，这支部队并不是2018年新成立的，该部早在2011年就出台了相关规定，并于2018年生效。 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，十多年来，文化执法部门有了这项部门条例的坚实法律基础，”刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，挑战在于在他们的执法中。最近对单口相声的打压体现了中国行政机关在应对引人注目的案件或事件时经常采取的“运动式执法”方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“问题不在于这些表演的合法性”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上月底，中国东北黑龙江省文法队在佳木斯市举行了穿制服活动，告诫大家“坚决守住思想文化安全底线”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，陕西和浙江省的同行举办了类似的活动，而北京、上海、福建和云南省的同行也举办了类似的活动&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京市文化执法总队党委书记曹鹏程敦促官员们以这次活动为契机，“打造一支全方位硬化的文化‘铁军’”。他呼吁官员们成为习近平的“忠实捍卫者”，他们必须随时准备“维护首都文化市场的政治、意识形态和文化安全”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多伦多大学的王说打击喜剧俱乐部是政府试图控制的文化活动的延伸，这一过程始于多年前。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是派出专门的力量来控制这些活动正在将其推向极端。这几乎让我想起了文化大革命，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在改革后的中国，政府一直试图施加控制，但其中很多实际上是通过监管：通过通过某些鼓励社会自我调节的法律。 [但现在] 就他们能做什么或不能做什么来指导社会，我认为这是将其提升到另一个层次。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ong 补充说，控制不仅与自上而下的指令有关，而且可以采取谨慎的地方官员掌握着另一个维度，他们急于避免任何不当行为并预测中央政府的路线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鉴于总体政治环境和中央政府[言论自由]空间的收紧，地方一级的人们变得更加厌恶风险。因此他们可能会采取额外的预防措施来停止某些活动，即使他们没有收到任何信号。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Brazil and China officials resume bilateral defence talks but also discuss fishing complaints]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224414/brazil-and-china-officials-resume-bilateral-defence-talks-also-discuss-fishing-complaints?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/25cac9f7-028e-4036-9784-8acfa0711d8a_54956b4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;巴西利用周五中国海军代表团的访问来抱怨涉嫌非法捕鱼中国军舰往返巴西和非洲大西洋沿岸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;军事随行人员于周四抵达，预计访问将持续两天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由中国人民解放军海军部长袁率领华志集团还包括海军副参谋长李鹏程上将；中国驻巴西武官张林洪； &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西海军司令 Marcos Sampaio Olsen 海军上将和海军参谋长 José Augusto Vieira da Cunha de Menezes 海军上将在巴西利亚接待了他们的客人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;会议指出，自 2020 年以来因大流行而推迟的双边防务谈判将恢复。熟悉此事的消息人士证实，此次访问是由巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦斡旋，并提前几天安排的——因此可能不会签署任何军事协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西军方抱怨中国巴西报纸 Folha de S. Paulo 报道说，渔船离开非洲海岸，在没有被追踪的情况下航行通过大西洋水域，并从事非法捕鱼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所谓的非法、未报告和无管制 (IUU) 捕鱼当外国船只在其他国家的专属经济区非法捕鱼时，就会发生这种情况，联合国海洋法公约将其定义为距离一个国家海岸 200 海里以内的区域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Global Fishing Watch， a non-governmental organisation that promotes transparency in the fishing industry and helps government agencies fight illegal fishing, told The Post that up to one in five fish caught at sea are the result of IUU fishing, a market estimated to be up to US$23.5 billion a year&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brazil&#39;s Lula heads to China with plans to promote BYD takeover for Brazil Ford factory&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to a report published by Investigative Journalism Reportika in February, Chinese vessels account for 60 per cent of all IUU fishing cases reported in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, American University in Washington reported in October that the crime had led to the decline of fish stocks and the extinction of protected marine species in South America.&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Besides economic losses and the consequences for the environment, Brazil is also concerned about regional security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Filipe Porto, a fellow at the Brazilian Naval War School&#39;s Conjuncture Assessment Centre, said that the strengthening of Chinese military ties with African coastal nations, as well as alleged Chinese interest in building a naval base in Argentina to consolidate its presence in the South Atlantic, raised concerns by Brazilian military officers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The military doctrine adopted by Brazil , Porto said, provides for the protection of the region in partnership with the countries that share the Atlantic coast. Despite the unease, however, the Lula administration has pushed for greater engagement with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The armed forces have the tactical and operational autonomy to patrol the area and detect crimes such as illegal and unregulated fishing, but the power to do something about it rests with the presidency,” Porto said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Brazilian military has a long tradition of alignment with the West, many officers have studied at American schools and may even take a more hawkish attitude towards China, but the Navy is the most pragmatic of the armed forces … The IUU fishing [issue] will certainly be addressed diplomatically and militarily.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese embassy in Brazil sent a statement to The Post that China conducts fishing in distant waters following international laws and regulations and “adopting a zero-tolerance attitude towards illegal fishing”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The embassy also noted that Beijing had instituted voluntary moratoriums in certain parts of the high seas and that China is committed to “science-based conservation and sustainable use of international fisheries”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Daniel Ellsberg, who leaked Pentagon Papers on Vietnam war, dead at 92]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224413/daniel-ellsberg-who-leaked-pentagon-papers-vietnam-war-dead-92?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 05:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/5c1cbf4e-9303-4068-befb-fae9afb28e27_6f46838f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Daniel Ellsberg, the whistle-blower who leaked the “Pentagon Papers” about the Vietnam war – changing public perceptions of the conflict – died on Friday, his family announced. He was 92.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ellsberg was a military analyst when he released thousands of documents to US media in 1971 that revealed successive United States administrations had lied to the public about the Vietnam war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 7,000 classified pages determined that, contrary to the public assertions of US government officials, the conflict was unwinnable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The leak was recounted in the 2017 Hollywood thriller The Post, which detailed the nail-biting behind-the-scenes story of the papers&#39; publication.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ellsberg announced in March that doctors had told him on February 17 that he had terminal pancreatic cancer and only around six months to live.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He was not in pain, and was surrounded by loving family,” his wife and children said in a statement announcing his death.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They highlighted that his last months had been well spent despite his illness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He was thrilled to be able to give up the salt-free diet his doctor had him on for five years,” they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;One of world&#39;s most famous whistle-blowers defends Assange&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Hot chocolate, croissants, cake, poppyseed bagels, and lox gave him extra pleasure in these final months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He also enjoyed rewatching his favourite movies, including several viewings of his all-time favourite, Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid,” added his wife Patricia, sons Robert and Michael, and daughter Mary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The New York Times initially published excerpts of the Pentagon Papers until the administration of President Richard Nixon obtained a court injunction barring the newspaper from continuing to do so on national security grounds. The Washington Post then took up the mantle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ellsberg was charged under America&#39;s Espionage Act but the case ended in a mistrial in 1973 after illegal evidence gathering by the government came to light.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Announcing his diagnosis on March 3, Ellsberg reflected on his history-changing actions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When I copied the Pentagon Papers in 1969, I had every reason to think I would be spending the rest of my life behind bars,” he wrote. “It was a fate I would gladly have accepted if it meant hastening the end of the Vietnam war, unlikely as that seemed [and was].&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Yet in the end that action – in ways I could not have foreseen, due to Nixon&#39;s illegal responses – did have an impact on shortening the war,” Ellsberg added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He continued to speak out against war through the remainder of his life, repeatedly criticising US interventions overseas, particularly in Afghanistan and Iraq.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Napalm girl&#39; photographer returns to place he took this iconic image of the Vietnam war exactly 43 years later&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“What we&#39;ve done to the Middle East has been hell,” he told the publication Democracy Now in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ellsberg was a staunch anti-nuclear weapons campaigner. In 2017, he published a massive tome about the nuclear threat seen from the inside, titled The Doomsday Machine: Confessions of a Nuclear War Planner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ellsberg continued his activism even after his diagnosis, speaking to reporters about the continuing threat of nuclear war, particularly the threat posed by Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Daniel was a seeker of truth and a patriotic truth-teller, an anti-war activist, a beloved husband, father, grandfather, and great-grandfather, a dear friend to many, and an inspiration to countless more. He will be dearly missed by all of us,” his family said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 05:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: Vladimir Putin says Russia’s nuclear bombs now in Belarus, in warning to the West]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3224410/ukraine-war-vladimir-putin-says-russias-nuclear-bombs-now-belarus-warning-west?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 03:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/41a8503d-932d-41a7-bdf1-04582c89f4e0_ee3117c7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;President Vladimir Putin said on Friday that his deployment of tactical nuclear weapons to Belarus, something he confirmed for the first time had already happened, was a reminder to the West that it could not inflict a strategic defeat on Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking at Russia&#39;s flagship economic forum in St Petersburg, Putin said Russian tactical nuclear warheads had already been delivered to close ally Belarus, but stressed he saw no need for Russia to resort to nuclear weapons for now.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As you know we were negotiating with our ally, [Belarusian President Alexander] Lukashenko, that we would move a part of these tactical nuclear weapons to the territory of Belarus – this has happened,” said Putin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The first nuclear warheads were delivered to the territory of Belarus.但只有第一个，第一部分。 But we will do this job completely by the end of the summer or by the end of the year.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move, Moscow&#39;s first deployment of such warheads – shorter-range nuclear weapons that could potentially be used on the battlefield – outside Russia since the fall of the Soviet Union was intended as a warning to the West about arming and supporting Ukraine, the Russian leader said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is precisely as an element of deterrence so that all those who are thinking about inflicting a strategic defeat on us are not oblivious to this circumstance,” Putin said, using a diplomatic term for a defeat so severe that Russian power would be diminished on the world stage for decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lukashenko, a staunch ally of Putin, said late on Tuesday his country had started taking delivery of Russian tactical nuclear weapons that included some three times more powerful than the atomic bombs the US dropped on Japan in 1945.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Russian leader announced in March he had agreed to deploy tactical nuclear weapons in Belarus, pointing to the US deployment of such weapons in a host of European countries over many decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why Russia wants tactical nuclear weapons in Belarus&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The United States has criticised Putin&#39;s decision but has said it has no intention of altering its own stance on strategic nuclear weapons and has not seen any signs that Russia is preparing to use a nuclear weapon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Russian step is nonetheless being watched closely by Washington and its allies as well as by China, which has repeatedly cautioned against the use of nuclear weapons in the war in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin said the West was doing everything it could to inflict a strategic defeat on Russia in Ukraine where Moscow is locked in the biggest land war in Europe since World War II after invading its neighbour last year in what it called “a special military operation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Russia had no need to resort to nuclear weapons for now, Putin said, signalling no change in Moscow&#39;s nuclear posture which envisages such a move only if the existence of the Russian state is threatened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nuclear weapons have been made to ensure our security in the broadest sense of the word and the existence of the Russian state, but we … have no such need (to use them),” Putin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he said talks with the West to reduce Russia&#39;s vast nuclear arsenal, the world&#39;s largest, were a non-starter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Just talking about [the potential use of nuclear weapons] lowers the nuclear threshold.我们有更多的北约国家，他们想减少我们的数量。 Screw them,” Putin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sounding defiant as he addressed his country&#39;s political and business elite, he said a Ukrainian counteroffensive against Russian forces in Ukraine had so far not had any meaningful success. Kyiv&#39;s forces were suffering heavy losses and had “no chance” against Russia&#39;s military, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Putin ponders: should Russia try to take Kyiv again?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ukraine would soon run out of its own military equipment, making it totally reliant on hardware supplied by the West, undermining its ability to fight for long, he suggested.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recalling his stated objectives at the start of the war to “demilitarise” and “denazify” Ukraine, Putin said: “As for demilitarisation, soon Ukraine will stop using its own equipment altogether.什么都没有了。他们打仗的东西，用的东西，都是从外面引进来的。 Well, you can&#39;t fight like that for long.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Independent military analysts say Ukraine has outperformed Russia&#39;s much larger army in nearly 16 months of war, forcing it into major retreats around the cities of Kyiv, Kharkiv and Kherson.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine&#39;s military chiefs said on Friday that advancing Ukrainian troops were facing “desperate resistance” from Russian forces around the city of Bakhmut, which Russia captured last month after the longest battle of the war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine says it has recaptured seven villages and 100 square km (38 square miles) in the early stages of its counteroffensive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Russia&#39;s defence ministry said on Friday its forces had repelled numerous attempted counter-attacks by the Ukrainian army at different frontline locations in the last 24 hours, inflicting severe losses on Kyiv&#39;s forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin said Western-supplied hardware such as German-made Leopard tanks was regularly destroyed and if Kyiv got US-made F-16 fighter planes from its allies, they would go up in flames too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“F-16s will also be burning, there is no doubt. But if they will be stationed outside Ukraine and used in combat operations we will have to look at how to engage and where to engage those assets being used in combat operations against us.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That, he said, represented “a serious danger” of dragging Nato further into the conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 03:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pittsburgh synagogue gunman Robert Bowers guilty of killing 11 in the deadliest attack on Jews in US history]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224409/pittsburgh-synagogue-gunman-robert-bowers-guilty-killing-11-deadliest-attack-jews-us-history?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 03:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/ef79d233-e208-44a3-9021-5aaf78c347fc_b6cf9581.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A truck driver who spewed hatred of Jews was convicted on Friday of barging into a Pittsburgh synagogue and shooting everyone he could find, killing 11 congregants in an act of antisemitic terror for which he could be sentenced to die.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The guilty verdict was a foregone conclusion after Robert Bowers&#39; own lawyers conceded at the trial&#39;s outset that he attacked and killed worshippers at the Tree of Life synagogue on October 27, 2018, in the deadliest attack on Jews in US history.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jurors must now decide whether the 50-year-old should be sent to death row or sentenced to life in prison without parole as the federal trial shifts to a penalty phase expected to last several weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bowers was convicted of all 63 criminal counts he faced, including hate crimes resulting in death and obstruction of the free exercise of religion resulting in death. His lawyers had offered a guilty plea in return for a life sentence, but prosecutors refused, opting instead to take the case to trial and pursue the death penalty. Most of the victims&#39; families expressed support for the decision.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am grateful to God for getting us to this day,” Rabbi Jeffrey Myers of the Tree of Life Congregation, who survived the attack, said in a written statement. “And I am thankful for the law enforcement who ran into danger to rescue me, and the US Attorney who stood up in court to defend my right to pray.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jury deliberated about five hours over two days before reaching a verdict. Bowers, wearing a dark jumper and blue shirt, had little reaction, as has often been the case throughout the trial. Several survivors and relatives of the deceased victims&#39; were in the courtroom, bearing quiet witness. A few sniffles were heard in he gallery as the judge intoned “guilty” dozens of times.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bowers turned a sacred house of worship into a “hunting ground”, targeting his victims because of their religion, a prosecutor told jurors on Thursday. Reading the names of each of the 11 victims he killed, prosecutor Mary Hahn asked the jury to “hold this defendant accountable … and hold him accountable for those who cannot testify.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bowers, who was armed with an AR-15 rifle and other weapons, also shot and wounded seven, including five responding police officers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hostages freed in Texas synagogue stand-off, gunman dead&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Prosecutors presented evidence of his deep-seated animosity toward Jews and immigrants.在超过 11 天的证词中，陪审员了解到鲍尔斯在极右翼流行的社交媒体平台 Gab 上广泛发布、分享或点赞反犹太和白人至上主义内容，并赞扬了希特勒和大屠杀。 Bowers told police that “all these Jews need to die”, Hahn said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Survivors testified about the terror they felt that day, including a woman who recounted how she was shot in the arm and then realised her 97-year-old-mother had been shot and killed right next to her. Andrea Wedner, the trial&#39;s last witness, told jurors she touched her mother&#39;s lifeless body and cried out, “Mummy,” before Swat officers led her to safety.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Carole Zawatsky, CEO of the Tree of Life Congregation, said on Friday she hoped the verdict would provide survivors and victims&#39; family members with “some level of comfort and helps to ease the pain, even if ever so slightly”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With Bowers&#39; guilt established, survivors and family members of the deceased victims are expected to tell the jury about the devastating impact of his crimes. The penalty phase is expected to start June 26.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bowers&#39; lawyers did not mount a defence at the guilt stage of the trial, signalling they will focus their efforts on trying to save his life. They plan to introduce evidence that Bowers has schizophrenia, epilepsy and brain impairments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Defence lawyer Judy Clarke had also sought to raise questions about Bowers&#39; motive, suggesting to jurors that his rampage was not motivated by religious hatred but his delusional belief that Jews were committing genocide by helping refugees settle in the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three congregations that shared the synagogue building – Dor Hadash, New Light and Tree of Life – have spoken out against antisemitism and other forms of bigotry since the attack. The Tree of Life congregation also is working on a plan to overhaul the synagogue building – which still stands but has been closed since the shootings – by creating a complex that would house a sanctuary, museum, memorial and centre for fighting antisemitism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trial took place three years after President Joe Biden said during his 2020 campaign that he would work to end capital punishment at the federal level and in states that still use it. His attorney general, Merrick Garland, has temporarily paused executions to review policies and procedures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But federal prosecutors continue to vigorously work to uphold already-issued death sentences and, in some cases, to pursue the death penalty at trial for crimes that are eligible, as in Bowers&#39; case.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[University shutting its Confucius Institute after US House panel raises concerns with Pentagon]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3224408/university-shutting-its-confucius-institute-after-us-house-panel-raises-concerns-pentagon?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 02:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/caa6ecc3-3915-4029-9e14-c23e0f5a0a18_65fd1d15.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A university in upstate New York will shut its Confucius Institute weeks after a US congressional committee initiated a review into its Pentagon contract worth millions of dollars for hypersonic missile research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alfred University will be closing its Confucius Institute, effective June 30, according to Mark Danes, the vice-president for marketing and communications at Alfred University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While our community has benefited from the cultural programming provided by the Confucius Institute that we have operated since 2008, current geopolitical concerns regarding China make it difficult to continue to run it,” Danes told the South China Morning Post on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, a lawyer for Alfred notified Representative Mike Gallagher – chairman of the House Select Committee on Strategic Competition Between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party – of the closing, noting that though the university “does not engage in classified research, it has for multiple years engaged with the Department of Commerce and the FBI to strengthen its export control policies and processes”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 31, Gallagher had written to US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin and the university president Mark Zupan, asking how Alfred received a five-year contract worth $13.5 million a year earlier despite continuing to host a Confucius Institute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gallagher drew Austin&#39;s attention to the “looming deadline” under a section of the 2021 National Defence Authorisation Act that prohibits the Pentagon from “providing funds to institutions of higher education that host a Confucius Institute” after October 1, 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Confucius Institutes are Beijing-backed language and cultural centres that China says are a bridge of friendship to the rest of the world. In recent years, though, critics in Washington have accused these schools of partnering with American universities to gain access to crucial intellectual property and promote propaganda.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A bipartisan congressional report in 2019 found “no evidence that these institutes are a centre for Chinese espionage efforts or any other illegal activity”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US House panel reviewing university with Pentagon contract for ties to China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, Gallagher said he was glad to see Alfred “finally doing the right thing”, calling Confucius Institutes as “only one tool in the CCP&#39;s toolbox” to “gain access to sensitive research and technologies that fuel the PLA&#39;s advancement”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alfred also partners with the China University of Geosciences in Wuhan, a national university overseen by the Chinese Ministry of Education, that allegedly conducts classified research on advanced weaponry for the Chinese military. Gallagher did not say whether Alfred would also cut ties with it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The committee&#39;s staff did not immediately respond to an inquiry about whether Alfred&#39;s collaboration with the Chinese university remained an issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alfred had been asked to submit copies of emails, letters and electronic documents regarding its agreement with the geoscience university by Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gallagher claimed that the Chinese Communist Party “will use research partnerships, talent programmes, and other initiatives”, vowing to “continue to dig into the facts to make sure that no American taxpayer dollars are supporting research partnerships that the CCP can exploit for its own purposes.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s hypersonic &#39;trump card&#39; has been in service for several years: source&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The statement on Thursday said that the University of Toledo in Ohio, St. Cloud State University in Minnesota and the University of Utah still receive Pentagon grants to conduct sensitive military research while “publicly operating CCP- affiliated Confucius Institutes on their campuses”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the National Association of Scholars, an American conservative group, 13 Confucius Institutes continue to operate in the US while around 108 centres have either closed or are in the process of closing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A report by the association in March claimed that at least 58 universities maintain “close relationships with their former Confucius Institute partner”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese envoy to EU denies committing to halt sanctions-busting shipments to Russia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224407/chinese-envoy-eu-denies-committing-halt-sanctions-busting-shipments-russia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 01:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/46a7aa6a-7282-4035-8b1d-cd712cf2c74e_260af1f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China has not committed to stopping its companies from helping Russian military buyers breach EU sanctions, its top envoy to the bloc said on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s Ambassador Fu Cong made the comments after European Union diplomats agreed earlier this week to provisionally remove five Chinese entities from an export restriction list.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EU sources said they made that decision following a diplomatic commitment from Fu to exert pressure on the firms to stop re-exporting banned goods to the Russian war machine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the diplomat told the Post and two other media outlets in an interview in Brussels that “the Chinese government did not commit [to] anything … that&#39;s the bottom line”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We understand the concerns of the EU in terms of trying to prevent the circumvention of the sanctions, meaning that some of the items from the European market might be re-exported to Russia and so … according to their view, that needs to be resolved,” Fu said. “We&#39;ll see what happens in the future.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EU ambassadors will convene on Monday and are expected to green-light the eleventh sanctions package on Monday, with the Chinese companies removed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday two EU diplomats said that the move was a test of whether Beijing was acting in good faith. Speaking on Friday, a diplomat said Fu&#39;s latest words were “surprising to say the least”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu said it was “good news” that the companies had been taken off, but refused to be drawn on what his government would do to ensure the trade was halted.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China &#39;firmly opposes&#39; possible German ban of Huawei, ZTE 5G equipment&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re glad that the Chinese companies have been removed from the list, and it shows that dialogue can work,” said Fu, speaking on the sidelines of a Chinese business forum in the Belgian capital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eight companies based in mainland China and Hong Kong were on a draft list of entities accused of reselling European chips and microelectronics that can be used in high-grade weaponry, such as cruise missiles. Three remain on the list, but they were found to be effectively Russian entities operating out of Hong Kong, EU sources said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The interview comes at a tumultuous time for EU-China relations. On Thursday, the European Commission told member states they should ban Huawei and ZTE from their 5G networks – the first time the bloc&#39;s secretariat has gone after the Chinese telecoms giants by name.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu said that ban was “purely out of some ideological and geopolitical considerations by the United States, and I&#39;m sorry to see that European governments have yielded to the US pressure”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Next Tuesday, commission chief Ursula von der Leyen&#39;s flagship economic security strategy will be unveiled in proposal form. It will not name China directly, but is expected to lay out high-level ways of “de-risking” Europe&#39;s ties with the world&#39;s second largest economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The desire of the EU governments for a resilient supply chain” was understandable, Fu said, and warned against “conflating economic security with national security”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He called the potential for an EU-wide ban on China&#39;s two blue-chip telcos “quite concerning, because this might be a foretaste of a what de-risking may really entail”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have been saying that the EU side needs to clarify what they mean by de-risking. And here, this is a concrete example of using fabricated excuses to drive the Chinese companies out of the European market, and this is quite concerning really,” Fu said, adding that there was “no evidence” that the companies provided a security risk.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Germany eyes &#39;systemic rival&#39; China in first-ever national security strategy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, EU industry chief Thierry Breton directly linked the move to wean the bloc off dependencies on China and Russia for energy and raw minerals with 5G.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We eliminated our dependencies in other critical sectors, for example, on energy, in record time when many thought at that time it was impossible,” Breton said. “The situation with 5G should be no different. We cannot afford to maintain critical dependencies that could become a weapon against our interests.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu said Beijing would “safeguard to the best of our ability the legitimate interests of the Chinese companies” but would not “predict any counter actions from our side”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brussels is also looking at ways to restrict EU companies from investing in some hi-tech sectors of the Chinese economy, such as artificial intelligence, quantum computing, and semiconductors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu said it was “too early to talk about retaliating”, but said he was “following the discussion on this issue very closely, with some concern”.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 01:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>