<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Beijing backs Hong Kong’s disciplined services after demonstrations against police athletes at international sports event in Canada]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3230433/beijing-backs-hong-kongs-disciplined-services-after-demonstrations-against-police-athletes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 22:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/b6a22486-dd7a-48c3-8c41-1ae97ee6bf92_aa3cf6b9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在香港纪律部队庆祝成立之际，北京向香港纪律部队保证坚定不移的支持在加拿大举行的世界警察和消防运动会上获得了有史以来最好的奖牌数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，该市代表队在今年的世界警察和消防运动会上赢得了 275 枚奖牌，他们在履行职责时得到了支持，在加拿大举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港派出了一支由 350 人组成的代表队（主要由警察部队的运动员组成）参加这项每两年举办一次的赛事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奖牌总数包括 97 枚金牌、90 枚银牌和 88 枚铜牌，这是香港在奥运会上最成功的表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但香港参与在温尼伯举行的这项赛事也引发了争议和抱怨，认为香港出于人权原因，不应允许警察参与竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拿大的一些活动人士对香港警察受到欢迎感到不满，并强调了 2019 年社会骚乱期间针对抗议者的所谓暴力行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但北京设立的三个负责香港事务的机构谴责“反中乱港分子”在周日结束的奥运会期间骚扰香港队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国务院港澳事务发言人港澳办对周二回国的香港队的出色表现表示祝贺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示：“我们向他们致以崇高敬意和热烈祝贺。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;发言人补充说，中央对香港纪律部队充满信心，支持他们依法履职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;矛头直指“反中乱港分子”发言人表示：“我们对这些卑鄙行为和令人作呕的表演表示最强烈的谴责。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;数千名警察巡逻香港天安门广场周年纪念日&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京驻香港维护国家安全办公室通过其微信账号向该团队表示祝贺，并赞扬制服部队在2019年社会动荡期间的辛勤工作。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;该办公室表示，他们为香港由混乱走向秩序、由稳定走向繁荣做出了贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“反中乱港分子对香港纪律部队的抹黑，清楚地表明： ……他们是违法分子的克星。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中联办发言人还痛批“逃亡海外的反中乱港分子”以及“一些人”。西方政客和反华团体”试图将体育赛事政治化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发言人表示，中央政府将支持政府将那些“逃离香港的扰乱分子”绳之以法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发言人表示，中央政府将支持政府将那些“逃离香港的破坏分子”绳之以法。 p>;&lt;p>;香港国安警察上个月悬赏 100 万港元（合 128,000 美元），奖励提供信息以逮捕八名反对派人士，其中包括出生于加拿大的郭永亨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些居住在加拿大的香港人在奥运会开幕式上抗议该市代表队。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港人利用宽松的要求申请加入警察&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;反对派政客保守党也对加拿大政府允许香港官员入境参加比赛表示失望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港政府二号人物、布政司陈国基于周二在机场，并表示球队让这座城市感到自豪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈还批评了一些“别有用心”的人试图将体育赛事政治化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些事件曾经发生过再次表明，不稳定势力仍未放弃……并利用各种借口和场合对香港纪律部队进行污蔑抹黑，肆意抹黑攻击香港，企图破坏香港的国际形象和繁荣稳定。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈补充说，反港势力对香港稳定和国家安全的影响不容小视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的奥运会于7月28日至8月6日举行。 ，是一项奥林匹克式的比赛，有来自全球 50 多个国家和地区的代表警察部门、其他执法机构和消防员的 8,500 多名运动员参加。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong labour chief meets Cambodian and Bangladeshi consuls general over plans to bring in more domestic helpers, as authorities respond to Indonesian fee rise]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3230434/hong-kong-labour-chief-meets-cambodian-and-bangladeshi-consuls-general-over-plans-bring-more?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 23:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/5542d0d0-39b9-4b91-add1-20ee96f9dd85_a777f949.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港劳工处处长周二会见柬埔寨和孟加拉国总领事，讨论引进香港劳工及福利局局长孙玉汉表示，他解释了政府在扩大进口方面的立场。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我向两位总领事表示，香港政府欢迎更多本国公民来港从事外籍家庭佣工工作， ”孙先生在其官方 Facebook 页面上发帖称。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港印尼家庭佣工接受培训呼吁缓解收费担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;劳工处将探讨措施，引进更多据该部长称，该部门安排了这些会议，因为印度尼西亚上周宣布将执行修订后的费用政策，根据该政策，香港雇主必须在以下情况下多支付数千美元： &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家警告称，不会受理不遵守规定的雇主的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙重申政策变化不应增加当地雇主的负担或影响就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，一位消息人士告诉《华盛顿邮报》，印度尼西亚海外工人安置和保护国家委员会负责人取消了原定于周二访问该市的行程，因为他需要&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部门上周与印尼招聘机构 Aspataki 会面，讨论该政策的实施，该政策取消了此前向在国外寻找工作的外佣征收的安置费。工人们只需要支付培训费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该政策经过国家两次修订，要求雇主承担高达 20,000 港元（2,560 美元）的全部招聘费用，多出数千美元根据机构和佣工工会的数据，目前的收费为 7,000 至 13,000 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港劳工局长对印尼家庭佣工费用上涨表示担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;数据入境事务处的数据显示，2022年，该市有33.8万名外籍女佣，其中印尼籍约14万，菲律宾籍超过19万。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙称，少数外籍女佣来自其他国家包括印度、泰国、斯里兰卡、孟加拉国和柬埔寨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孟加拉国家庭佣工的输入始于2013年，并于2015年达到顶峰，达到650名工人。其领事馆网站称，目前约有750名来自柬埔寨的女佣在该市工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为五年计划的一部分，该市于2017年迎来了第一批1,000名柬埔寨女佣。缓解城市人口老龄化带来的人才短缺问题。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Greater effort needed to protect Hong Kong victims whose intimate photos posted online without consent, NGO says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3230435/greater-effort-needed-protect-hong-kong-victims-whose-intimate-photos-posted-online-without-consent?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 23:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/6c484953-cd7e-438f-ab20-9adb17d4c3ae_481023bb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;反性暴力危机中心敦促香港隐私监管机构提供更大的保护RainLily 周二表示，从 2021 年 4 月到 2023 年 3 月，它收到了 646 份与图像性暴力相关的援助请求。它已帮助个人要求在线平台删除 1,342 张未经同意的亲密内容照片。其中近 1,200 张（即 89%）最终被删除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该非政府组织表示，许多案例都试图删除显示面部特征的单张照片。但根据《个人资料（私隐）条例》，在没有其他个人资料的情况下传播私密影像并不违法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“个人资料私隐专员公署应进一步检讨隐私图像在什么级别可以被定义为个人数据，并以更积极主动的方式帮助那些遭受非自愿传播隐私图像的人，以满足公众的期望。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专员公署表示，一般来说，如果相关个人的身份被确定为亲密图像，则可能构成该条例规定的个人资料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;副执行董事Doris Chong 表示，RainLily 注意到，要求帮助删除网上私密照片的请求有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管 2021 年 10 月引入了特定的刑事犯罪，但 RainLily 的一线经验表明，那些面临未经同意的分发和威胁的人”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菅直人补充说，非政府组织要求在线平台删除图像的服务有助于避免受害者身份暴露。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;数据显示，大多数受害者是女性（71.3%），而大约五分之一（22.2%）是男性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该非政府组织处理的图片中有一半是由受害者认识的人分发的，包括亲密伴侣（27.5%）和网上熟人（15.8%）。但三分之一的受害者无法识别发布照片的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kan 表示，大多数受害者担心这些照片会被亲人发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们担心家人、朋友和同事可以在网上找到这些图片。即使内容被删除，他们仍然害怕这些图像被再次上传，甚至在网上受到身体羞辱，这对受害者造成了创伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 1,342 张亲密照片中，42%它们是在色情网站上发现的，其中近四分之一是在社交媒体平台上发现的（25%），其他是在搜索引擎上发现的（22.7%）。其余的则在内容农场（5.3％）和图像托管网站（5％）上发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，RainLily 透露了帮助受害者删除图像的各种挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;该非政府组织表示，与其他平台相比，色情网站上发布的内容以“指数级规模”传播，25 个网站从未对非政府组织做出回应，也没有采取删除行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;近 40% 的香港人香港青少年接触不良性内容：民意调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;大多数网站只禁止侵犯所有者版权的材料。但未经同意的亲密图像的版权大部分属于“摄影师”，这给彻底删除此类内容带来了困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该非政府组织还指出，Telegram 上的频道经常发布内容农场网站的链接。内容农场上的帖子包括未经同意的图片、受害者的个人信息以及围绕该图片捏造的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相同的内容在这些频道的子群体中传播。这些分支机构拥有成百上千的订阅者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;报告遭受网络性骚扰的男性多于女性：调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“虽然这些平台有政策和举报渠道，但他们不回应和举报Kan 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基于图像的性暴力相关刑事犯罪于 2021 年生效。不过，该非政府组织表示定罪率和起诉率较低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它说法律有局限性。例如，当肇事者被指控时，没有法律义务删除所分发的内容；这些图片只有在法律诉讼开始后才会被删除，但为时已晚，无法阻止这些图片在网上传播。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Italian dairy factory owner dies, crushed by 25,000 wheels of cheese]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230424/italian-dairy-factory-owner-dies-crushed-25000-wheels-cheese?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 22:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/c13840a3-3b82-4ac7-bee0-9cbb33b1da79_e4240c04.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;意大利北部贝加莫附近一家乳品厂的老板在货架上装载着数千件物品后死亡奶酪轮倒塌并把他埋了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;整个晚上，救援人员试图从大量坚硬的格拉纳帕达诺奶酪下面救出这名男子，每轮奶酪重 40 公斤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Giacomo Chiapparini消防队员安东尼奥·杜西 (Antonio Dusi) 说，74 岁的他仓库里的一个架子破裂，产生多米诺骨牌效应，导致奶酪倒塌，他被埋在了奶酪下面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;救援人员“必须用手移动奶酪和架子， ”杜西说，并补充说，“花了大约 12 个小时”才终于找到了基亚帕里尼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日晚上，这名男子正在他位于米兰不远的小镇的乳品厂的仓库里工作，当时一名男子发现了他的尸体。正在成熟的大奶酪轮上的金属架子倒塌了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很快，高高的架子一直延伸到天花板，里面堆满了奶酪，一个接一个地倒塌，直到埋葬了该男子，说发言人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最高的架子高达 10 米（33 英尺）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚第一个金属架子是如何倒塌的，但怀疑是材料疲劳或技术故障造成的。发言人补充说，预计将进行调查以确定是一颗还是几轮奶酪杀死了该男子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;仓库位于小镇位于贝加莫附近的罗马诺迪伦巴第亚 (Romano di Lombardia)，总共装有 25,000 轮格拉纳帕达诺奶酪 (Grana Padano)，这是一种类似于帕尔马干酪的硬奶酪，在意大利非常受欢迎。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia drops lead prosecutor in corruption case of deputy PM Ahmad Zahid, amid fears of political meddling]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3230427/malaysia-drops-lead-prosecutor-corruption-case-deputy-pm-ahmad-zahid-amid-fears-political-meddling?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 21:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/98ff5c76-35e6-4515-8cbd-fc91679dc91f_040a145f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;马来西亚总检察长撤销了涉及副总理艾哈迈德的腐败案件的首席检察官扎希德·哈米德 (Zahid Hamid) 申请提前退休后，批评者担心政治干预审判的程度仅次于 1MDB 丑闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;艾哈迈德·扎希德 (Ahmad Zahid) 是总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣 (Anwar Ibrahim) 政府的重要成员，该政府巫统和国阵 (BN) 联盟的昔日竞争对手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扎希德曾担任总理纳吉布·拉扎克的副手，他于 2018 年被指控犯有 47 项腐败、滥用权力和贿赂罪，涉及超过 72 名据称，他的百万林吉特（1580万美元）与他的家族慈善基金会有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚巫统正在努力应对马来人基础的下降和民意调查临近时的软形象&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在周二的一份声明中总检察长伊德鲁斯·哈伦 (Idrus Harun) 表示，他根据副检察官拉贾·罗泽拉·拉贾·托兰 (Raja Rozela Raja Toran) 在 4 月份提出的提前退休申请，将她从该案中免职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该申请已获得批准并将生效” 2023 年 11 月 1 日，”Idrus 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Raja Rozela 将从 8 月 30 日开始休假，他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Raja 从 2018 年一开始就负责起诉工作。罗泽拉将案件审理至 2022 年 1 月，当时吉隆坡高等法院认定检方已对副总理立案，并命令他进行辩护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的职位由杜苏基·莫赫塔尔 (Dusuki Mokhtar) 接替。负责公共利益和重大案件的部门负责人，拥有30多年的高级检察官经验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总检察长发表声明之前，马来西亚狂野的社交媒体上充斥着各种猜测&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对党土团党法律与宪法局副局长萨莎·莱娜·阿都拉提夫对在审判的关键时刻将拉惹·罗泽拉免职提出质疑，称这给马来西亚司法自由带来了负面印象。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“任何表明存在干涉或国家对腐败软弱的迹象或看法都会对我们作为商业场所的声誉产生不利影响，”周六参加州选举的萨沙·莱纳(Sasha Lyna)说。 “没有人愿意与腐败政权做生意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚的安瓦尔任命腐败缠身的艾哈迈德·扎希德·哈米迪为副总理&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;艾哈迈德·扎希德重返内阁是在选举陷入僵局之后。 2022 年 11 月大选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他与安瓦尔·易卜拉欣 (Anwar Ibrahim) 的希盟 (PH) 联盟结成不太可能的联盟后，他的回归引发了一波关于这对正在进行的审判意味着什么的猜测。自 1998 年以来，他一直是国阵联盟的死敌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月，反对派国民联盟 (PN) 联盟指责安瓦尔达成协议，撤销对艾哈迈德·扎希德的指控，以换取国阵支持安瓦尔竞选&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔表示，他去年 11 月任命丑闻缠身的艾哈迈德·扎希德 (Ahmad Zahid) 为副手，这意味着每个人在被证明有罪之前都是无辜的。安瓦尔本人在 1999 年和 2014 年被监禁期间一直坚称自己是清白的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，总检察长的解释并没有平息猜测，马来西亚公众指出，伊德鲁斯的前任阿卜杜勒·甘尼·帕泰尔也同样被免职。以健康原因为幌子下台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是在他于 2016 年试图因 1MDB 丑闻逮捕时任总理纳吉布之后。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong-built first electric public minibus to hit road by end of year, vehicle maker says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3230425/hong-kong-built-first-electric-public-minibus-hit-road-end-year-vehicle-maker-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 21:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/a000f7d5-cd1f-4003-955e-830afd5ddb2f_81dd1d25.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由城市公司建造的香港首辆电动小巴将于作为推动绿色交通的一部分，将于今年年底推出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;信兴新能源董事总经理周二表示，其价值 200 万港元（256,000 美元）的 Moonca 模型是第一个获得环境保护部批准的模型Department，旨在打入新兴的电动小巴市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;信兴集团子公司的负责人 Gary Ng Fuk-keung 补充道，这款新车是不可避免的赚钱起点迈向电动公共交通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望打入小巴市场。这是大势所趋，香港的小巴迟早都会转为电动车。”吴说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每辆小巴的售价约为200万港元。预计今年年底交付首批车辆。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;信兴集团是香港最大的电器分销商之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该集团的生产推广电动小巴是该署斥资 8,000 万港元推广电动公共小巴试验计划的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府在一年内资助了 40 辆电动小巴，涵盖了 80% 的成本。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;那些错过该计划的人可以利用新能源交通基金获得 50% 的资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的税收优惠推动了电动汽车的大规模转变，但在哪里充电吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Moonca是一款由高效钛酸锂电池驱动的19座汽车，是信兴新能源与内地公司格力奥钛新能源子公司广通汽车的合资企业.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;车辆可以通过受电弓、连接电线的屋顶阵列或在充电站充电，电池可在大约 18 分钟内充满 90% 的电量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A充电 10 分钟相当于在路上行驶 50 公里（31 英里）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng 表示，该集团已做好大规模生产的准备，但运营商可能需要等待政府在一些换乘站安装更多高架充电桩&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据试点计划，我们的目标是在一年左右生产约 20 个 Mooncas，”他说。 “当然，当运营商意识到我们的模式将有利于他们的业务时，我们希望吸引尽可能多的买家并获得更多订单。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;加速电动汽车的发展&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;政府于 2021 年制定了到 2050 年实现碳中和的目标，以保护环境，随后推出了小型客车试点计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府公布了旨在普及电动汽车并逐步停止购买新内部汽车的路线图。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府表示，将制定 2025 年采用电动商用车的时间表，并正在考虑开展绿色公共交通和运输车辆的试验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;p>;香港现时约有4,146辆小巴，包括3,299辆绿色小巴及847辆红色小巴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府于2018年推出一系列税收优惠，鼓励私家车车主买卖内燃机汽车&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，特斯拉是根据税收减免计划购买的最受欢迎的品牌，占总数的 23,820 辆，即 70%，其次是梅赛德斯-奔驰（3,174 辆）和宝马（1,750 辆） .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年 2 月，香港注册电动私家车数量为 50,665 辆，较一年前的 28,742 辆大幅增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方统计数据显示，电动汽车占香港汽车总量的 7.8%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但截至去年底，公共和私人场所的电动汽车充电桩只有 5,434 个，大约每 10 辆车就有一个充电桩。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s I&T development behind quicker immigration clearance at Shenzhen checkpoint, mainland Chinese official says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3230426/hong-kongs-it-development-behind-quicker-immigration-clearance-shenzhen-checkpoint-mainland-chinese?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 21:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/a989b1e1-c550-4b00-b54c-90dcca890709_6bd57929.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国内地皇岗口岸将加快旅客通行速度，双重目的是缩短旅客通行时间深圳一位高级官员表示，深圳出入境口岸办公室主任王刚周二表示，深圳出入境口岸办公室主任王刚表示，入境旅客在出入境上花费的时间以及对香港创新科技（I＆T）发展的贡献通过该设施的中国大陆人只需要检查一次身份证件，而无需在大多数其他过境点进行双重检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些变化将通过合一地点安排来实现，该安排结合了移民内地与香港一站式清关。该设施目前已关闭，预计将于 2026 年完成翻修。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王在接受大陆媒体采访时还指出了该检查站在落马洲河套地区的重要性，该地区将成为香港-深圳航线的所在地&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“‘一区两园’发展的核心依托皇岗新港。”深港创新科技合作区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“港口转型可以腾出更多土地、释放更多空间，让这些科创区进一步扩张和发展。”&lt;/ p>;&lt;h3>;“香港应效仿澳门，通过简单检查加快通关速度”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据安排，香港将能够关闭落马洲口岸，腾出更多土地来发展新田科技城——位于城市北部的一个拟建创科集群。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;皇岗目前与落马洲相连，落马洲是香港与内地的 14 个边境检查站之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王的保安局局长邓炳强于五月证实，两市同意在口岸实行“一地两检”安排，并积极探讨在口岸实施“协同检查、联合通关”程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;王说，双方检查单位的工作不会发生重大变化，但公众的通关时间会缩短。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内地官员还宣布，罗湖口岸深圳方面将实施一项常旅客计划，旨在加快该设施的常规用户（例如学生、商人和技术专业人员）的处理速度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他没有透露实施该计划的时间表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王表示，罗湖口岸是年初内地与香港恢复免检疫旅行以来最繁忙的口岸，共有2300万人次过境。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港建议简化出入境手续北都会口岸&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;福田在过去7个月以2100万人次的游客量位居第二，其次是深圳湾、西九龙高铁总站、莲塘-香园围和文锦渡。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;王指出，罗湖口岸是深圳改革开放的象征，两地很多人对罗湖口岸内地一侧都有感情。该设施将被保留，让人们体验集体文化。他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港为人才探索更便捷的跨境旅行，以刺激创科中心的发展&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;各个口岸均设立了柜台，以方便兑换人民币和王说，鼓励更多香港居民在深圳消费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还展示了二维码，帮助用户下载移动支付应用程序，而周边地区也安装了免费Wi-Fi。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;同时，王办在其官方微信公众号上宣布了18项便利旅客通关的新安排。这些措施包括提供免费咨询服务、手机充电站和行李手推车。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s AI players from Alibaba to state-run institute rush to open source their models in race for global influence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3230410/chinas-ai-players-alibaba-state-run-institute-rush-open-source-their-models-race-global-influence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 20:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/d54dafcf-2dbe-41f8-bd6e-228810ba045d_7cb1f07f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国大型科技公司、初创企业和机构正争相与其他国家分享他们的大型语言模型 (LLM)（支撑 ChatGPT 等聊天机器人的软件）在人工智能 (AI) 霸主地位的竞争中竞相获取全球用户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京人工智能研究院北京人工智能研究院（BAAI）是一家政府支持的机构，专注于基础人工智能研究及其在医疗和生命科学等领域的应用，成为最新一家开源新人工智能模型的中国主要参与者，其 BGE 模型可免费用于商业用途&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年 6 月，该学院还开放了 Aquila 模型，根据模型简介，该模型已经过 70 亿个参数的预训练，其中 40% 是中文，60% 是英文Github 上的介绍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;模型的能力部分取决于其参数数量。例如，OpenAI 的 ChatGPT 接受了 1750 亿个参数的训练。虽然目前大多数开源中国 LLM 拥有 6 至 130 亿个参数，但 BAAI 表示计划推出拥有 330 亿个参数的更高级版本的 Aquila。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BAAI 此举是在阿里巴巴的云部门之际做出的。 《南华早报》的所有者 Group Holding 上周开源了两个 70 亿参数的人工智能模型，基于其 4 月份推出的旗舰产品“统一前文法学硕士”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可在阿里巴巴自己的存储库 ModelScope 上获取和美国平台Hugging Face，这两种模式可供学者、研究人员和公司免费使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;开源是阿里巴巴和BAAI等参与者扩大其在该领域影响力的一种方式， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前大家的热情很高，各家公司也推出了很多LLM产品，竞争也很激烈，但模式都处于同一水平。”张说。 Yi，咨询公司iiMedia创始人兼首席分析师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“开源大型[AI]模型是[脱颖而出]的一项策略，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这可能是对于不太知名的公司尤其如此。中国搜索引擎搜狗创始人兼首席执行官王小川创立的人工智能初创公司百川于 6 月宣布开源其 130 亿参数的 Baichuan-13B 模型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于北京初创公司智普AI在6月份表示将开源其ChatGLM2-6B模型，该模型有60亿个参数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为开源本身也是一种商业模式......无论大小公司”，北京人工智能初创公司 Modelbest 的首席执行官李大海在 6 月份接受《华盛顿邮报》采访时表示。 h3>;在中国，关于ChatGPT热能否赚钱的争论&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;许多公司希望在不自己训练模型的情况下部署LLM的计算能力——林永华表示，这一过程需要高昂的费用BAAI副院长兼总工程师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“重新发明LLM轮子的成本很高：不仅计算能力和数据昂贵，而且这个过程还消耗大量的电力和能源，”林在2017年对中国媒体表示。六月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Modelbest 的 Li 表示，开源为公司提供了一种低成本的方式来接触潜在客户，让他们了解公司的技术能力。 “这是一种非常好的[寻找]销售线索的方式，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Modelbest 在 5 月份开源了其 100 亿参数的中英双语 CPM-Bee 基础人工智能模型，并表示已收到超过100家公司的免费使用申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= “color:orange” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China food security: floods leave grain crops filthy, inviting pests and disease as Typhoon Khanun looms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3230399/china-food-security-floods-leave-grain-crops-filthy-inviting-pests-and-disease-typhoon-khanun-looms?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/58bcec00-7c8d-4311-b324-5940089a8db4_501e6c12.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;被称为中国北方粮仓的地区的农民恳求帮助减轻作物损失from floods as Typhoon Khanun threatens output with more heavy rainfall that could bring bugs and blight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Water levels across Heilongjiang province have been falling since Monday after Typhoon Doksuri caused flooding across northern China since Friday, but farmers are struggling to rescue the most affected crops in the nation&#39;s top grain-producing region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In two days, videos uploaded by farmers asking for assistance went viral on Chinese social media, as they feared that all of the silt that has accumulated on blossoming rice crops could reduce yields.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We want to use a high-pressure water gun to flush the silt off, but this is too much work, and we desperately need help from real experts from all fields,” a Heilongjiang woman said in one of the videos.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Typhoon Doksuri hit China&#39;s northeastern provinces of Heilongjiang, Jilin and Liaoning, known as the country&#39;s breadbasket. They contributed more than one-fifth of the country&#39;s grain production, one-fourth of the country&#39;s grain commodities, and one-third of its grain export last year, data from the State Council shows.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More frequent extreme weather is ringing alarms across China&#39;s agriculture sector, intensifying Beijing&#39;s push for self-sufficiency amid rising tensions with the US and global market disruptions stemming from the Russia-Ukraine conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heilongjiang&#39;s Wuchang city, known for the country&#39;s best-quality rice, has seen a small percentage of its farmland – more than 2,720 hectares (6,721 acres) – affected by flooding, including 2,436 hectares of rice, according to China&#39;s Ministry of Emergency Management on Friday. In total, the city has 194,266 hectares of rice farmland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wuchang&#39;s agricultural output accounted for more than 40 per cent of the region&#39;s gross domestic product, and its rice production reached 1.92 million tonnes in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing steps up food security with stiff assessments of local-level cadres&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In 2021, the city accounted for 2.6 per cent of Heilongjiang&#39;s total grain output, while the province itself accounted for 14 per cent, 15 per cent and 44 per cent of the national production of rice, corn and soybeans, respectively, data from Guosheng Securities showed on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From August 1-4, the province&#39;s Shangzhi city saw its heaviest rainfall since 1957, resulting in crop damage that has affected more than 42,575 hectares, Xinhua said on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jilin province&#39;s Shulan city, an important maize producer in China, has also been battered by floods, with more than 14,466 hectares of arable lands being affected, and loss estimates surpassing 43 million yuan, Thepaper.cn reported on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week, China&#39;s Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs arranged for 432 million yuan worth of disaster relief and dispatched 11 working groups and hundreds of experts to grain-producing areas to provide technical guidance on preventing pests and improving yields.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When rice gets silt, it&#39;s not realistic to wash it down with a high-pressure water gun, it would be too costly to do so,” said Huang Bangquan, a professor specialising in plant genetics at Hubei University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Rice yields will definitely be reduced [this time], but not to the point of losing the harvest,” said Huang, adding that even if the rice is contaminated with silt during the flowering period, it can still be self-fertilised.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he also warned that flooding leads to more pests and diseases in crops, making these the leading risks currently facing farmers in the northeast.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For some regions that are at risk of crops being wiped out, farmers could opt to grow some short-season crops in time, which would more or less make up their losses,” Huang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What is the state of China&#39;s food-security drive, and is it succeeding?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s summer harvest fell for the first time since 2018, largely due to the rains that hit the wheat-growing province of Henan in late May amid the harvest season.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, China&#39;s Ministry of Emergency Management said the current flood-control and post-disaster reconstruction tasks are considerable, and Typhoon Khanun looms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[With another typhoon coming], the situation of flood control and relief is unpromising and arduous,” Minister Wang Xiangxi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang added that the agriculture sector needs to be more prepared for extreme weather in the long term, with measures taken to protect forests and grasslands, build more water facilities, and breed crop varieties that can grow amid extreme weather.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese mother jailed 7 years for overstaying in Singapore for son’s education: ‘it’s worth it’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3230414/chinese-mum-jailed-7-years-overstaying-singapore-sons-education-its-worth-it?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 20:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/08/01c57f2b-8dff-43be-8fc0-50a060698227_bfbbe6f1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Chinese woman who overstayed in Singapore for more than seven years claimed she did so for her son&#39;s education and that it was “worth it”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kang Lihong, 48, was sentenced to the maximum six months on Tuesday for overstaying in Singapore under the Immigration Act.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She also received a S$2,000 (US$1,480) fine in lieu of caning as she cannot be caned since she is a woman.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court heard that Kang was last issued a long-term visit pass valid from March 2015 to April 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When her pass expired, she was given a 62-day visit pass that was valid until June, in order for her to leave the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;He was fired. Then he padlocked his ex-colleagues inside their Singapore office&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;However, Kang did not leave Singapore. Instead, she remained illegally in the country for seven years, one month and 10 days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was arrested by the Immigration and Checkpoints Authority at her address on August 1 this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman was remanded and appeared in court via video-link. She did not have a lawyer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking through a Mandarin interpreter, Kang said: “The reason why I overstayed is because my child was studying in secondary school, so if I go back to China, I&#39;m afraid that my child cannot stay in Singapore.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said her son was “still very young”, so she wanted to stay in Singapore to take care of him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After my child graduated and started working, my child asked me to go back to China, but then Covid-19 happened so I was not able to fly back,” said Kang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She claimed that she “already had the intention to surrender” but ICA arrested her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I hope that my case will not affect my child,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the judge asked her how old her son currently was, she said he was 25.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Why would the child be studying in secondary school, and the child is 25 today?” asked the judge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman answered that he studied for five years in secondary school.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that air tickets were very expensive when Covid-19 struck, after her son graduated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I was afraid if I go back to China, and anything bad happens, it would be very troublesome. So that is why I overstayed,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prosecution pointed out that the woman&#39;s son was already 18 at the beginning of her offences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So in that sense, she is not required to remain in Singapore to take care of her child,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman answered that no one was paying for her son&#39;s school fees when he was in polytechnic. “如果我不留在这里，他的教育就会停止，”她说。 “He couldn&#39;t pay his own school fees.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that there is “no choice” as a mother, adding that she was proud of her son and had to support him as his father was unable to.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I admit my mistake but I think it&#39;s worth it,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In sentencing, the judge said the reasons given by the accused for offending were insufficient, with no extreme or exceptional circumstances that qualified as mitigating.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After hearing the sentence, the woman asked repeatedly if the sentence could be shorter.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore to get sausages lab grown in just 8 days thanks to a Dutch start-up&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The decision stands,” said the judge, and the woman started to cry, saying she wanted to call her son and asking “can&#39;t it be shorter”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The penalties for overstaying in Singapore for a period exceeding 90 days are a jail term of up to six months, at least three strokes of the cane, or a fine up to S$6,000 if caning is not possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This story was originally published on &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 20:50:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong cosmetics saleswoman arrested over alleged money laundering involving HK$900 million in crime proceeds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3230420/hong-kong-cosmetics-saleswoman-arrested-over-alleged-money-laundering-involving-hk900-million-crime?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 20:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/08/52e8ff78-6639-446b-8aed-097db370e414_4ccfd4c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong customs officers have arrested a cosmetics saleswoman on suspicion of laundering nearly HK$900 million (US$115 million) in alleged crime proceeds through 13 bank accounts using two shell companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 39-year-old woman was detained in Tsuen Wan on Tuesday after officers from customs&#39; financial investigation bureau raided her flat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inspector Michael Ng Sze-chai of the bureau said the suspect was allegedly a core member of a local money-laundering syndicate that had processed HK$896 million in illegal funds through the 13 accounts between May 2021 and January this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An investigation revealed that the woman had set up two shell companies on three days in January 2021, according to the Customs and Excise Department.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The two companies claimed that they were involved in the import and export business and the trading of cargo such as electronic products, but the investigation found they had no actual business,” Ng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that the woman, who worked as a cosmetics saleswoman and earned about HK$10,000 a month, had allegedly set up the 13 bank accounts used to launder the funds over a 21-month period.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The suspected crime proceeds [in local and US dollars] came from about 600 bank accounts through about 1,800 transactions,” he said, adding that most of the accounts were set up in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“All of the illegal funds were then transferred out of the 13 bank accounts in hundreds of transactions and moved to another 100 bank accounts.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The largest single transaction amounted to HK$9.4 million, according to the inspector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A source familiar with the case said that most of the 700-plus accounts involved in the money-laundering case belonged to shell companies that were set up by travellers from mainland China and other places.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police arrest 19 in crackdown on money laundering syndicate&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“They set up the companies and business bank accounts and then left the city,” the insider added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Customs officers began investigating the syndicate about three months ago after suspicious transactions were detected in one of the business accounts belonging to the suspect.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After gathering evidence, officers from the financial investigation bureau, which was set up on August 1, arrested the woman on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was detained on suspicion of money laundering – an offence punishable by up to 14 years in jail and a HK$5 million fine. As of Tuesday evening, she was still being held for questioning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng said customs was investigating the origin of the illegal funds, how the cash was generated and its final destination.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong student among 6 arrested as police clamp down on money laundering group&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Before the bureau was officially set up this month, the financial investigation division under the syndicate crimes investigation bureau was responsible for investigating money-laundering activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new bureau, led by Senior Superintendent Suzette Ip Tung-ching, has more than 90 officers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So far this year, customs officers have intercepted six other money-laundering cases involving HK$11 billion in suspected crime proceeds and arrested a total of 46 people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June, officers smashed a money-laundering syndicate that had allegedly smuggled US$91 million in suspected crime proceeds into the city from Turkey using air passengers. Twenty-three local men were arrested in connection with the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, they arrested a jobless public housing tenant accused of running a syndicate that had laundered HK$3.5 billion in illegal proceeds. He was among eight people detained in the operation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong customs cracks second-largest money-laundering case in HK$3.5 billion arrest&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s largest money-laundering case – involving HK$13.1 billion – came to light in 2012 when police arrested a 22-year-old man from the mainland. The amount was the highest recorded in two decades for a money-laundering case involving bulk cash smuggling operations using air couriers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first seven months of this year, the Joint Financial Intelligence Unit, comprising police and customs officers, handled 48,026 reports of suspicious financial activity. Figures showed an increase in such cases from 51,588 in 2019 to 68,538 in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Hong Kong, banks, securities and insurance firms, legal and accounting professionals, dealers in precious metals and stones, money service operators, money lenders and property agents are required to report suspicious transactions.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 20:50:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>