<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[On Apec sidelines, China’s commerce minister condemns semiconductor controls and Japan’s G7 ‘smears’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222194/apec-sidelines-chinas-commerce-minister-condemns-semiconductor-controls-and-japans-g7-smears?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/9b041cce-8303-45b7-831d-1a2fe456ecad_2878882a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国商务部长王文涛谴责七国集团峰会东道国日本“抹黑和抹黑”攻击”中国，并敦促停止半导体出口管制，他称这“严重违反”国际经贸规则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅周五在与日本贸易大臣西村康俊的会晤中提出严正交涉在底特律举行的为期两天的亚太经合组织（APEC）贸易部长会议期间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“日本不顾中国强烈反对和业界意见，执意出台半导体出口管制措施，严重违反了国际经济和贸易规则，损害了工业发展的基础，”王说，根据他所在部门的一份声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1 月，华盛顿与日本和荷兰这两个主要参与者达成协议芯片制造行业，以实施出口管制并削弱北京建立自己的国内芯片能力的雄心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3 月，东京扩大了对 23 种尖端芯片制造技术的出口限制，要求当地公司在销往中国之前获得许可证。该清单于一周前更新，预计将于7月23日生效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中方对此表示强烈不满，敦促日方纠正错误做法，切实维护全球工业稳定和供应链，”Wang 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在 Apec，美国高级官员敦促贸易政策采取“以工人为中心”的方法&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他说中国愿意与日本合作提供一个“公平、透明和可预测的商业环境”，并建立“符合新时代要求的关系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王的评论呼应了他的部门周二的声明，该声明将日本的行为描述为“滥用职权” ”出口管制措施和“严重背离”自由贸易和国际规则，并敦促东京“纠正错误做法”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王还表示北京反对上周针对中国的“攻击”在日本广岛举行的 G7 峰会被《人民日报》旗下的民族主义报纸《环球时报》称为“反华研讨会”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“G7 国家在联合声明中操纵涉华问题，发布一份暗指中国的所谓经济安全文件，干涉中国内政，”中国声明说，指的是该集团对中国在香港、新疆和西藏的政策以及在华东和华南的领土主张的评论&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望日方端正对华认知，以建设性态度切实促进两国经贸关系的稳定和发展，”王毅表示。加强贸易问题对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着 G7 采取行动削减中国风险，日本吸引全球芯片制造商&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;王还在底特律会议期间会见了国际同行，包括美国贸易代表 Katherine Tai。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;中方发表声明说，双方就双边经贸关系以及共同关心的地区和多边问题进行了“坦诚、务实和深入的交流”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South China Sea: Asean and Beijing’s ‘unbridgeable’ conflict could undermine code of conduct for years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3222207/south-china-sea-asean-and-beijings-unbridgeable-conflict-could-undermine-code-conduct-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 19:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/343dc9de-21ea-45f7-b2af-1e2214b6394d_c444dd4b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;尽管南海行为准则取得了渐进的进展，“不可逾越”分析人士表示，中国与东南亚国家之间对爆发点水道的主权主张存在分歧，这可能意味着未来多年的外交充满挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 17 日，中国外交部表示，该行为准则的二读将中国和东盟谈判方在自 2021 年 6 月以来的首次正式会议上达成协议后，将于今年完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在越南下龙市举行的第 20 次高级官员会议上达成了这样做的共识来自中国和东盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，菲律宾表示，它在上周与越南的会谈中同意将缔结“实质性”行为准则作为优先事项。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;菲律宾敦促尽快达成南海行为准则&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;总部位于新加坡的尤索夫伊萨研究所越南研究项目高级研究员 Le Hong Hiep 表示，虽然协议表明谈判在之后取得进展由于大流行而拖延了很长时间，“几乎没有突破”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“行为准则预计至少要经过三读才能缩小双方的分歧……[例如]是否守则应该具有法律约束力，其地理范围或执行机制，”Le 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使在可能需要很多年的三读之后，Le 表示中国和东盟之间的主要差异可能鉴于南海已成为中美战略竞争加剧的战场，中国仍坚持这一立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国与其他声索国，特别是菲律宾和越南之间在海上的零星对抗也破坏了互信并使Le 补充说，各方更难做出妥协。紧张局势并保持开放渠道来管理冲突，分歧“大到可能无法弥合”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国船只无视越南要求离开俄罗斯经营的气田附近区域的要求&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最后星期五，一艘中国研究船向阳红 10 号和五艘护航船进入了越南的专属经济区 (EEZ)，尽管河内一天前已敦促其离开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是自 2019 年以来最重大的一次入侵，斯坦福大学南海 Myoushu 项目负责人 Ray Powell 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，中国还在有争议的南沙群岛周围有争议的水道部署了三个导航信标，此前菲律宾也放置了类似的标记本月早些时候。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，据报道一艘中国海警船拦截了一艘菲律宾巡逻船后，南海险些发生碰撞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lucio Blanco Pitlo III，访问台湾国立政治大学外交学系和外交政策研究中心的学者表示，今年的东南亚国家联盟主席印度尼西亚与该地区的热点问题有着直接的利害关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[印度尼西亚] 可以拉Pitlo 说，由于该国作为该地区非正式领导者的地位，它在推动 [code] 方面的重要性，谈判过程中的一个里程碑可能会限制雅加达的任期”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不能说同样的话明年的轮值主席老挝，”Pitlo 补充说，并指出中国在万象的大规模投资和基础设施项目“降低了人们对这个内陆国家在推动守则方面可以提供什么的期望”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马尼拉可能会举行皮特洛补充说，如果今年晚些时候与华盛顿进行联合巡逻，北京可能会加强其外交，以表明南海问题是邻国之间的问题，可以“由直接当事方解决，无需外部干预”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;除了中国与东南亚南海声索国之间的小规模冲突外，声索国之间也时有发生对抗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周四，越南批评菲律宾在其专属经济区的五个区域放置航行浮标，越南也对南沙群岛的部分地区提出主权主张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾外交部发言人 Teresita Daza 表示，安装这些浮标旨在提高航行安全，符合该国作为沿海国家的权利南海行为准则不太可能在今年年底达成：东盟专家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然菲律宾和越南是南海的声索国Le 表示，在争端中，他们“更多地将对方视为合作伙伴”，将中国视为可以“以他们为代价改变南海现状”的主要和更强大的威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Le 补充说，通过协调双方在行为准则方面的立场，两国将能够在与中国的谈判中更好地保​​护自己的利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bradford 表示，在不同地点出现小规模冲突并涉及参与者的组合“令人不安”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些增加了风险并阻碍了进展，”布拉德福德说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan cuts red tape for private jets, super-yachts for smooth-sailing luxury travel]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3222198/japan-cuts-red-tape-private-jets-super-yachts-smooth-sailing-luxury-travel?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 18:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/b70d6e3d-0a86-49c5-9823-d38e3f57931a_5ce23bef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本想通过削减繁文缛节阻止私人飞机和超级游艇在最后一刻抵达，因为它与新加坡等亚洲豪华目的地竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本 10% 以上的游客来自少数国家超级富有的游客，政府希望鼓励他们中的更多人来访，而且频率更高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅行社表示，该举措可能会吸引飞驰在亚太地区的千万富翁，他们突然有停下来的冲动在京都的一座寺庙旁，或者在新雪谷的滑雪场度过一个下午。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本的高端旅游行业正在蓬勃发展，从东京的新宝格丽酒店到京都的豪华 Sowaka 酒店，以及在位于首都西新桥区的 Aragawa 享用晚餐，人均花费超过 100,000 日元（700 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他们警告说，日本仍然缺乏日本所期望的基础设施环球旅行的富人，例如他们在摩纳哥、迪拜或科罗拉多州阿斯彭习惯的候机室、礼宾服务和豪华轿车服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本政府证实，它打算简化外国-注册外国飞机，作为其吸引高消费游客的更广泛举措的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据交通部的说法，外国私人飞机在降落前提前 10 天通知的要求将减少到只有三天&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这里的政府正在迈出非常重要的第一步，”在日本旅游业工作超过 15 年的旅游营销分析师 Ashley Harvey。 “但在放宽规则方面，他们能做的只有这么多，而且在很多方面，这取决于私营部门能否抓住这个机会并与之合作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但有远见和他补充说，根据承诺，福冈、热海或那霸等沿海城市可能会吸引与蒙特卡洛、迪拜或新加坡同等规模的游艇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本交通部还将引入一个系统，最多可申请 24 个月的登陆在所谓的“不可避免的情况下”提前数小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前正在制定修订民用航空法的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共有 5,962 人乘坐私人飞机抵达日本据共同社报道，2019 年这一数字在 2021 年下降至 1,332，这一下降与冠状病毒大流行有关，但随着旅行重新开始，去年又反弹至 3,142。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰国如何吸引中国游客比日本或澳大利亚多&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;同样，国家政府正在与港口城镇的地方当局合作，想方设法吸引超级游艇的拥有者，超级游艇的定义是长度至少为 24 米的豪华巡洋舰。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;意识到地中海和加勒比地区的一些城市已经将旅游业的大部分建设在满足游艇所有者需求的基础上，日本希望它能够在太平洋提供新的目的地。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;东京都政府计划派遣一组官员前往地中海沿岸的港口城镇，以确定超级游艇所有者的需求，包括停泊设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以及内部的一些泊位东京湾，例如位于市中心的台场区和南部的横滨，地方当局正在考虑在首都以南的小笠原群岛和伊豆群岛开发港口设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Bear Luxe Corp 高端旅游网络的创始人 Hiro Miyatake 表示：“这里的高端旅游市场需求已经大幅复苏，我相信它只会变得更加繁忙。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以，是的，让乘坐私人飞机的人更轻松、更顺畅是积极的一步，但我担心的是，当他们下机并想继续他们的旅程时会发生什么，”他告诉 This亚洲周。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“海关和移民程序需要变得更快、更容易，因为这些人不想一直等待，而且需要有豪华休息室，以便转乘直升机或豪华轿车前往他们的最终目的地Miyatake 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡、香港的游客蜂拥至日本以赚取强势货币&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府正在放宽对抵达日本港口的外国国旗游艇的管理规定，包括海关要求，并允许船员在日本停留更长时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Miyatake 表示，他希望看到私人飞机所有者和豪华游艇运营商的“一站式服务”，可能隶属于交通运输部，计划访问日本的任何人都可以在相关文书工作方面寻求建议和帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本政府为入境游客设定了近期目标，花费 5 万亿日元（35.64 美元）亿）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富裕旅行者的消费比例高于平均水平，2019 年有 287,000 人在旅游时花费 100 万日元（7,100 美元）或更多。而富人仅占游客的 0.9%所有外国游客，他们占旅游总支出的 11.5%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan PM Fumio Kishida’s son to resign as secretary after ‘inappropriate’ behaviour]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222210/japan-pm-fumio-kishidas-son-resign-secretary-after-inappropriate-behaviour?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 18:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/379cff92-5add-484b-974c-353341564e62_3e5af328.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本首相岸田文雄的儿子将辞去秘书职务，首相周一表示，引用儿子和其他亲属显然是开玩笑的照片后的“不当”行为引发了轩然大波。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岸田告诉记者，岸田正太郎将从周四开始卸任他的秘书一职，称这一变动是由于官邸的“不当”行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，一家杂志刊登了岸田小子和亲属假装在官邸举行新闻发布会的照片，包括首相通常站立的讲台。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的行为遭到了反对派的广泛批评。对于最近在广岛举行的七国集团 (G7) 峰会上声望大增的岸田来说，这一消息披露的时机不合时宜。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本的岸田因任命儿子担任执行秘书而被指控任人唯亲&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;一位政府高级发言人表示，正太郎的父亲曾就去年家庭活动期间在首相官邸拍摄的照片向正太郎发出了强烈警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;向正太郎发出了警告在一家周刊杂志报道岸田在楼梯和住宅其他具有象征意义的重要部分以一种被视为不尊重的方式与亲戚合影留念后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府意识到首相的行为内阁官房长官松野博和表示，长子“缺乏适当性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将确保 [设施] 得到妥善使用和管理，以确保此类事件不再发生，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;据周刊文春周刊报道，岸田正太郎和其他约 10 人，包括亲属，于去年 12 月在铺有红地毯的楼梯上合影留念，日本首相传统上在这里首次亮相他们的新内阁阵容拍照通话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理最后一次这样做是在 8 月份的改组之后。在其中一张照片中，他的儿子和其他人穿着休闲装扮成大臣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该杂志发布的其他照片中有两男一女，他们似乎是岸田的亲戚一家人在首相的讲台前摆姿势，该讲台通常用于新闻发布会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;松野说，这些照片是在为亲戚举办的年终派对上拍摄的，首相也出席了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;松野说，虽然首相官邸是领导人及其家人的住所，但它是代表国家开展公务和主持活动的公共建筑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于岸田正太郎的行为，松野表示，他希望自己“在履行职责时更加谨慎。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周四，日本首相告诉记者，他无意解除岸田正太郎的行政秘书职务，尽管他说他对儿子的行为“深感遗憾”，因为这种行为缺乏“适当性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从 Kishida 的长子在 10 月被任命为执行秘书一职以来，事实证明他一再给首相带来麻烦&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本首相岸田因任命儿子担任行政秘书而被指责任人唯亲&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;首相一直被反对党政客批评在任命过程中任人唯亲。松野当时否认了这些指控，称首相的长子是根据他的“个性和洞察力”获得这份工作的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1 月，年轻的岸田发现自己受到反对派政客的抨击，他们说他不恰当地混淆了公共利益和私人利益，在 5 月举行的广岛峰会之前陪同父亲访问其他七国集团发达国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该事件的消息最初来自另一周刊杂志。据报道，作为首相后来所谓的“公务”的一部分，小岸田曾乘坐公务车游览伦敦、巴黎和渥太华的主要旅游景点和购物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府表示他用车没有问题，因为他为他父亲的社交媒体拍照，并代表岸田学长买了礼物。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Brains and beauty: striking PhD student at top Chinese university smashes stereotypes by landing top prize in Miss World pageant]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3221661/brains-and-beauty-striking-phd-student-top-chinese-university-smashes-stereotypes-landing-top-prize?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/c1651bba-64ba-4b69-bafc-5c3b9e925c1a_2174407f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位中国顶尖大学毕业生和未来的人工智能博士生赢得了中国舞台第 72 届世界小姐选美大赛，证明智慧与美丽可以并存。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;24 岁的洪浩云于 2017 年被中国两所顶尖大学之一的清华大学录取。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;她是 20 名主修机械工程的学生中唯一的女学生，她后来从该学科转学到计算机科学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了深厚的学术资质外，Hong 散发着优雅的气质，站在180 公分的身高令人印象深刻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她选择在选秀节目中演唱电影《花木兰》主题曲英文版《我自己》，使她从其他 107 名选手中脱颖而出。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;她说，她想通过展示自信、健康、优雅的形象，打破人们对科学、技术、工程和数学 (STEM) 领域女性的偏见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年夏天的选美皇后将在清华大学攻读人工智能博士学位，专攻机器学习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，她遭到了一些人的批评，认为她参加选美比赛与她的专业追求和学术努力相矛盾。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;对此，她回应说：“我认为有价值的科学研究不仅源于扎实的理论知识，更源于生活经历。这正是本次比赛为我提供的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不在乎别人怎么说研究科学家应该如何或女孩应该如何。我相信，只要我们每个人都走自己的路，勇敢地走向自己想成为的人，这才是最重要的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此前中国社交媒体上也出现过类似的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 3 月，网名@katekateZhuZhu 的牛津大学数学专业博士生朱文婷因讲述自己放弃高薪投资银行事业的故事而受到公众关注。回到学术界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于美貌和大脑的等式，一位网络观察者说：“有些人认为女性科研人员应该蓬头垢面、书呆子、没有爱好，而他们认为选美只是一种肤浅的追求基于物理外观。这种偏见什么时候才能消除？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有人说：“才貌与美貌在女性身上肯定是可以共存的，当然，女性也可以挑战传统的审美标准。女人可以以各种形式出现，她们都很棒！”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 18:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple supplier Foxconn raises pay and bonus packages for new recruits at world’s largest iPhone factory ahead of next product launch]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3222172/apple-supplier-foxconn-raises-pay-and-bonus-packages-new-recruits-worlds-largest-iphone-factory?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/9b741158-536b-4fc4-a50c-1d48cb9660d0_ee30f0a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;苹果供应商富士康科技集团提高了在世界上最大的 iPhone 工厂位于河南省中部省会郑州，距离这家美国科技巨头推出其下一代旗舰设备还有几个月的时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从周一开始，新员工将有权获得高达根据负责 iPhone 生产的富士康综合数字产品事业部周六发布的微信帖子，在工厂工作至少 90 天可获得 3,000 元人民币（424 美元）的工资，同时每小时工资高达 21 元人民币.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该帖子称，该工厂的现有工人可以获得 500 元的推荐奖金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于台湾的富士康，正式名称为鸿海精密工业，已经筹集了工人福利本月两次。例如，5 月 22 日，新员工留职三个月的最高忠诚度奖金从 5 月 3 日的 2,000 元提高到 2,500 元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富士康郑州工厂可容纳约 20 万名工人，在 Apple 预计于今年 9 月发布新款 iPhone 15 之前，富士康正准备迎接今年的另一场繁忙生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑州工人的更高工资和奖金方案凸显了电子产品合同制造商富士康继续组装 iPhone 的承诺在这座城市，尽管 Apple 的制造供应链正在从中国转移。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然中国大陆仍然是富士康的主要制造基地，但去年劳动力成本上升以及严格的 Covid-19 控制造成的中断促使该公司&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple 首席执行官蒂姆·库克 (Tim Cook) 在 2 月份表示，11 月和 12 月中国大陆的制造中断导致该公司的收入自 2019 年初以来首次出现季度下滑，明显指的是去年底郑州 iPhone 工厂的骚乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;富士康首席执行官在访问成都工厂时淡化 iPhone 搬迁谈话&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，富士康董事长兼首席执行官刘永威访问了四川省西南部的省会成都，在那里他告诉工人们，公司没有计划离开这座城市及其“重要”的生产基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是在这家台湾公司开业之后4 月在郑州建立了一个新的全球业务基地，这是加强其对中国市场承诺的努力的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，富士康计划在其位于美国首都钦奈的 iPhone 生产工厂再增加两座建筑物据孟买日报《经济时报》上个月的报道，位于印度最南端的泰米尔纳德邦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富士康的刘在过去一年中已经与印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪会面了两次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;印度塔塔集团表示 2023 年将获得苹果 iPhone 总订单的 5%&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，在这家工业巨头收购台湾公司之后，塔塔集团将成为苹果的第四家 iPhone 代工制造商根据研究公司 TrendForce 的数据，纬创集团在印度南部的工厂正在加速将生产转移到中国以外的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计到 2027 年，印度将组装高达 50% 的苹果 iPhone，高于之前的不到 5%根据台湾 DigiTimes Research 1 月份的预测，目前为 %。报告称，这将使其与中国大陆的生产规模相当。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 18:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘China is not Europe’: EU move to tie Chinese relations to Ukraine war is unfair, Fu Cong says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222197/china-not-europe-eu-move-tie-chinese-relations-ukraine-war-unfair-envoy-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 18:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/8bc9e9a9-6240-4c69-8f22-ba128596adf4_f9a227a4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧洲立法者将战争联系起来是“不公平”和“不明智”的在乌克兰与中欧关系中，中国驻欧盟大使表示，如果欧盟针对中国企业对俄罗斯实施新的制裁，中国将进行报复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在接受英国《新政治家》杂志采访时转载于周日，傅聪在中国驻欧盟使团网站上表示，期望中国采取与欧盟相同的立场是“不现实的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟外交政策负责人何塞普博雷尔早些时候表示本月，如果北京不敦促俄罗斯从乌克兰撤军，中欧关系将“受到严重影响”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们理解欧盟对乌克兰危机的重视。但坦率地说，我认为将中国在乌克兰危机上的立场与中欧双边关系联系起来并不明智。我认为这对中国不公平，”他在采访中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国不是欧洲，中国的利益与欧洲不同，中国与俄罗斯和乌克兰都保持着良好的关系.中国的立场是可以理解的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟准备对俄罗斯实施新一轮制裁，这将首次针对中国企业，而北京的和平努力——最近由特使李辉领导——傅接受了采访– 在西方被批评为“亲俄”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，新制裁最早将于下周通过，预计将限制至少七家中国公司的出口，这些公司被指控规避现有的欧盟通过向俄罗斯出售从欧洲进口的军民两用物品实施制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些公司包括四家已被美国列入黑名单的公司——大陆的 3HC Semiconductors 和 King-Pai Technology，以及香港的 Sinno据英国《金融时报》报道，Electronics 和 Sigma Technology，以及香港的 Asia Pacific Links、Tordan Industry 和 Alpha Trading Investments。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在采访中，傅先生抨击制裁缺乏证据，并警告说“强烈反响”，如果他们继续前进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们愿意以合作的方式解决问题，”傅说。 “我们与欧盟进行了谈判，并要求它提供证据。但欧盟方面表示，没有确凿证据证明有关企业曾将欧盟进口物品转口至俄罗斯。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时捍卫中国在乌克兰问题上的中立立场，重申其作用&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们有自己的外交风格，我认为在现阶段，简单的谴责实际上并不能解决问题。这可能会减少你的外交空间——如果所有国家都站在一个国家一边，那么谁来出面调解和平？但这并不意味着我们宽恕这场冲突中的任何具体行动，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及是谁发动了乌克兰战争时，傅说“历史学家”可以做出决定。当被问及克里米亚是否是乌克兰的一部分时，他也避免直接回答，只说中国代表“所有国家的主权，他希望通过和平谈判解决这个问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;傅还批评呼吁和平的欧洲国家也在等待条件更加“成熟”。他敦促通过和平谈判立即停火，这与李在他的欧洲之行期间所宣扬的信息相同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在莫斯科与俄罗斯官员会面后，李在周末结束了为期两周的和平任务——这是他的最后一站在访问了乌克兰、波兰、法国、布鲁塞尔和德国之后，推动了中国的 12 点建议，为乌克兰寻找解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;梅德韦杰夫认为乌克兰战争将持续数十年，因为美国将军怀疑俄罗斯的胜利&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;但李的努力似乎在欧洲遇到了僵局。据《华尔街日报》报道，一些西方官员告诉他，在冲突冻结之前，俄罗斯的撤军是没有商量余地的，而据报道，他提出了相反的建议——立即停火，让俄罗斯控制其新地区。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;不过，乌克兰外长德米特罗·库列巴周五驳斥了《华尔街日报》的报道，称他已与李访问过的国家的相关欧洲官员取得联系，“没有人”证实李提出承认俄罗斯。 - 被占领土。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着“降低”与中国经济关系风险的呼声越来越高，据说李还告诉他的欧洲同行要维护他们的战略自主权，并将中国视为“经济替代品” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在采访中，傅莹要求欧洲澄清其去风险方法，并强调如果中国反对该战略，中国将反对该战略。 meant excluding China from the global supply chain over areas involving key technologies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the EU side has concerns about dependency on China for certain things, the best way is to really talk to each other … dependency is not dangerous. What is dangerous is to weaponise the dependency,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the US pressures the EU to help curb China&#39;s development in critical sectors, the 27-member bloc has stepped up measures to tackle Chinese economic activities that could be deemed security dangers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu took aim at the US for influencing the bloc for decisions on banning Huawei, limiting semiconductor exports to China, and freezing the Comprehensive Agreement on Investment (CAI), the landmark trade pact between China and the EU that stalled after both sides implemented sanctions on each other over human rights issues in Xinjiang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EU chief Ursula von der Leyen signalled in April that the pact could be shelved permanently as China became more “assertive”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu urged the bloc not to allow the CAI to become “politicalised”, saying some perceptions in the EU towards China were based on “ideology”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China, Russia hold security talks in Moscow amid tensions with the West&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We do not deny that there are differences between us in terms of ideology and specific issues related to human rights. But our view is that our common interests far outweigh our differences. So we should not allow our differences to define our relationship,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Unfortunately, nowadays, there is this narrative about so-called democracy versus autocracy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think this narrative is both misleading and, I would say, even dangerous.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 18:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thousands evacuated as Philippines warns of flooding, landslide risks from Typhoon Mawar]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222200/thousands-evacuated-philippines-warns-flooding-landslide-risks-typhoon-mawar?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 17:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/d5321a96-1cd7-401d-9797-00828288f2fd_b8b2914a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Philippine officials began evacuating thousands of villagers, shutting down schools and offices and imposing a no-sail ban on Monday as Typhoon Mawar approached the country&#39;s northern provinces a week after battering the US territory of Guam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The typhoon is packing maximum sustained winds of 155kpm (96mph) and gusts of up to 190kph (118mph) but is forecast to spare the mountainous region a direct hit. Current projections show the typhoon veering northeast toward Taiwan or southern Japan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although it&#39;s expected to slow down considerably, authorities warned of dangerous tidal surges, flash floods and landslides as it blows past the northernmost province of Batanes from Tuesday to Wednesday. Disaster-preparedness officials said the typhoon&#39;s course could change abruptly and there was no room for complacency.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong to sizzle in coming days, with mercury to hit 38 degrees in some areas&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Even if the sun is up, the weather is so unpredictable nowadays and could change anytime so we should always stay on the side of safety”, Assistant Secretary Raffy Alejandro of the Office of Civil Defence said. “We&#39;re talking here of potential threats to lives”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mawar tore through Guam last week as the strongest typhoon to hit the US Pacific territory in over two decades, flipping cars, tearing off roofs and knocking down power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These typhoons, earthquakes and natural calamities have been a part of our lives”, Batanes Vice Governor Ignacio Villa told the AP by telephone. “We cannot afford not to prepare because that would potentially mean the loss of lives and major damage”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Army troops, police, firefighters and volunteer groups were standing by for search and rescue operations in northern provinces and more than a million food packs have been prepared for any contingency, officials said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 4,800 people have been evacuated to emergency shelters in Cagayan, Batanes and other provinces, Alejandro said. He added that the number of the displaced was expected to rise given the precautionary evacuations that were underway Monday in flood- and landslide-prone regions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Classes and office work, except those involved in disaster-preparedness, have been suspended in most of Cagayan and Batanes provinces, where occasional downpours and gusty wind were reported Sunday night. Flights to and from the provinces have been cancelled and fishing and passenger vessels prohibited from sailing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In at least one province, officials imposed a liquor ban.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Villa said the local government lent ropes to villagers living in high-risk communities to strengthen their houses as the typhoon approached.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 20 typhoons and storms each year batter the Philippine archipelago, which also lies on seismic faults where volcanic eruptions and earthquakes occur, making the Southeast Asian nation one of the world&#39;s most disaster-prone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November 2013, Typhoon Haiyan left more than 7,300 people dead or missing, flattened entire villages, swept ships inland, demolished about a million shanties and houses and displaced more than 5 million in one of the country&#39;s poorest regions in the central Philippines.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japanese destroyer flies controversial flag as it arrives in South Korea for joint drill]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222191/japanese-destroyer-flies-controversial-flag-it-arrives-south-korea-joint-drill?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 17:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/ec4557a5-fc07-40dc-8515-4746dc5bdd3e_3c737930.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Japanese warship arrived in Korea on Monday for a multinational naval drill later this week, bearing a flag that, for many Koreans, symbolises Japan&#39;s past military expansionism and colonisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JS Hamagiri, an Asagiri-class destroyer of the Japan Maritime Self-Defence Force, sailed into Busan Port with the Rising Sun flag hoisted, ahead of the Eastern Endeavour 23 aimed at reinforcing strategic capabilities to prevent and deter the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction (WMD).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan joins the United States, Australia, Canada, Singapore and Korea for the combined training exercise scheduled for Wednesday in international waters near Jeju Island, a day after the opening of a four-day high-level forum of the Proliferation Security Initiative (PSI).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many Koreans associate the flag with a long list of atrocious war crimes committed by Japan during its 1910-45 colonial rule – and see it as a sign that Tokyo will never properly and earnestly address its past.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan and South Korea are cosying up because &#39;it makes perfect sense&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The flag has been one of many sensitive diplomatic issues between the two countries. When the Navy under the previous Moon Jae-in administration requested the Japanese government not to fly the flags during the Jeju International Fleet Review in 2018, it withdrew from the event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to reporters on Thursday, Defence Ministry spokesman Jeon Ha-kyu said the ministry would not take issue with the flag this time, noting that hoisting of identifying flags while entering a foreign port was a “common international practice.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tokyo has maintained that its warships are legally required to raise the Rising Sun flag along with its national flag and, under the international maritime treaty, it is recognised as a mark to show their nationality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seven warships and six planes will be mobilised for the planned exercise, which includes testing systems for the dissemination of information about vessels suspected of carrying WMDs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Seoul official said the exercise does not target any particular nation. Pyongyang is, however, among the most serious threats given its high WMD proliferation risk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Proliferation Security Initiative (PSI), launched by Washington under former President George W. Bush in 2003, aims to stop the trafficking of WMDs, their delivery systems and related materials. The initiative has since grown to include the endorsement of more than 100 countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PSI holds a high-level political meeting every five years to review and set guidelines. The Busan forum is the first one to be held in Asia.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Bid by Hong Kong tycoon Jimmy Lai to get national security charges dropped rejected by High Court]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3222184/last-ditch-bid-hong-kong-tycoon-jimmy-lai-get-national-security-charges-dropped-rejected-high-court?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 16:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/bdc36d85-b467-43f3-b2c6-5c015f507a34_87fe469e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s High Court has dismissed a bid to drop the national security case against publishing mogul Jimmy Lai Chee-ying after finding the proceedings entailed no apparent bias towards his case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A three-judge panel, approved by Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu to oversee the pending trial in September, also held that no unfairness was done to the outspoken Beijing critic by the government&#39;s decision to bar him from hiring the British lawyer of his choice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Monday&#39;s ruling was the second legal setback in two weeks for the tycoon, after the High Court&#39;s chief judge rejected his request to review the ban by the Committee for Safeguarding National Security on the involvement of King&#39;s Counsel Timothy Owen in Lai&#39;s defence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai, 75, earlier applied for a permanent stay of proceedings as he questioned the impartiality of the bench and highlighted what he claimed was a concerted effort to prevent Owen from taking up his case.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Lawyers for Hong Kong&#39;s Jimmy Lai say tycoon denied fair trial, subject to persecution&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The founder of the opposition-friendly Apple Daily newspaper is facing charges of sedition and conspiracy to collude with foreign forces for allegedly attracting international sanctions against Hong Kong and central authorities and inciting public hatred after the city&#39;s anti-government protests in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has spent all but eight days behind bars since December 3, 2020. His 40-day trial without a jury is expected to start on September 25.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Jimmy Lai asks Hong Kong court to overturn government decision on UK lawyer&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Six former senior executives of the now-closed publication have already admitted to a joint collusion charge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing introduced the national security law in 2020, banning secession, subversion of state power, terrorism and collusion with foreign forces.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese defence chief Li Shangfu will speak at Shangri-La Dialogue, ministry says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3222185/chinese-defence-chief-li-shangfu-will-speak-shangri-la-dialogue-ministry-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 16:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/c2e46cde-208f-486d-926a-a589f3de9274_0bd7fe1c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese Defence Minister General Li Shangfu will travel to Singapore on Wednesday and address this weekend&#39;s Shangri-La Dialogue, the defence ministry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Pentagon on Thursday confirmed that US Secretary of Defence Lloyd Austin would also attend the annual event – the region&#39;s biggest defence conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is not known if the Chinese and US defence chiefs will hold talks, either officially or privately, during the gathering.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Defence dialogue between the two powers broke down after former US House speaker Nancy Pelosi defied Beijing&#39;s protests and visited Taiwan in August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington also said Beijing refused to talk to Austin after the US brought down a suspected Chinese spy balloon flying over its airspace in February, and US military leaders say China is not interested in maintaining the lines of communication that contribute to a stable defence relationship.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During last year&#39;s defence conference, after Austin set out America&#39;s vision for the Indo-Pacific, Li&#39;s predecessor, General Wei Fenghe, accused the US of trying to contain and “smear” Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s defence ministry on Monday said Li would also meet the heads of “relevant” countries&#39; delegations alongside the event, without elaborating.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statement said Li would set out China&#39;s new security initiative during his first appearance at the Shangri-La Dialogue, which is organised by the International Institute for Strategic Studies think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan intervention and US conflict among top worries for Chinese: poll&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Li joined China&#39;s top military decision-making body, the Central Military Commission, in October during the Communist Party congress. He was made defence minister following a leadership reshuffle in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As head of equipment development under the military commission, Li was sanctioned by the United States in 2018 for his role in the purchase of Su-35 Russian fighter jets and equipment related to the S-400 surface-to-air missile system. The sanctions do not bar the Chinese and US defence ministers from meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s defence ministry also said Li would meet Singapore officials and defence leaders before leaving on Sunday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>