<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Fly larvae breeds success for Nepali women]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3232317/fly-larvae-breeds-success-nepali-women?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 17:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/b46fe63b-2510-40f5-bb56-d83a1c8c371e_03e7f82a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在距离尼泊尔首都加德满都一个多小时车程的一个村庄里，六名妇女戴着黄色橡胶手套和外科口罩在棚子里工作，轻轻地将黑水虻的湿幼虫挤进小塑料容器中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一名妇女将梨和枯萎的蔬菜切成薄片来喂昆虫，这些昆虫通常被称为“昆虫”。 BSF，被关在两个塑料笼子里，笼子里装有用于人造光和热量的隔热板，以维持 74 平方米（800 平方英尺）的铁皮屋顶棚内所需的温度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富含蛋白质的昆虫卵经过干燥后加工成鱼、鸡和猪的饲料，售价为每公斤 70 尼泊尔卢比（约 0.55 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;于 3 月开业，由以下机构提供 110,000 美元资助芬兰妇女银行通过尼泊尔女企业家协会慈善机构联合会，将苍蝇农场称为喜马拉雅山国家首个此类农场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它由妇女拥有和经营，所有Bhardev 是一个人口约 2,500 人的小村庄，位于首都以南 30 公里（19 英里）处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼泊尔是世界上 10 个最贫穷的国家之一，村庄里的人们主要是自给自足的农民。妇女的经济状况尤其脆弱，除了小型的家庭农场外，没有额外的收入来源或就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼泊尔公务员的平均工资仅为每月 300 美元左右，因此从苍蝇幼虫中赚钱显然是村里妇女的一大进步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她们预计在一个生产周期（45 至 60 天）内收获 3,500 公斤幼虫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;慈善官员 Jeebesh Bikram Adhikary 表示：“这是一种绿色企业典范，可以为女性提供额外收入，而不需要她们投入所有时间，而且对环境友好。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在试验“BSF 能否在极端寒冷和恶劣的气候条件下收获，”Adhikary 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“到目前为止，结果良好，我们希望将来将该设施扩展到奇旺或凯拉利，”他说，指的是尼泊尔南部平原的两个地区，那里的气候更加有利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ramesh Shrestha 经营着一个小养鱼场，准备成为客户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我可以如果农场能够供应，每天最多购买 50 公斤饲料。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领导和管理该农场的女性之一 Mana Maya Shrestha 表示，他们目前的客户主要是家禽&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 47 岁的女士表示，一些女性不想从事此类行业。首先，她发现触摸昆虫及其卵“令人作呕”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我现在已经习惯了，”两个孩子的母亲说。 “我喜欢它们扭动时的感觉。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s mining technology: smart drilling boosts oil and gas production fivefold in Tarim Basin, say scientists]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3232264/chinas-mining-technology-smart-drilling-boosts-oil-and-gas-production-fivefold-tarim-basin-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 17:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/93757cf3-4756-45ae-bf77-aff845bc4d7c_8d29b071.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;智能钻井技术精准探测中国塔里木盆地地下油气并引导中国科学家称，通过钻头达到最佳开采点，产量提高了五倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;智能钻井为中国西北油田的开发提供了新的技术支撑。&lt;/p>;&lt;中国科学院（CAS）报告了八月初进行的生产测试。报告称，“塔里木盆地西部的TP259-2H井日产量为13.5吨石油和42,000立方米天然气，大约是邻近油井产量的五倍。”该项目由中国科学院朱日祥、​​邸青云等，与西北油田勘探开发研究院、中石化中原石油工程有限公司合作开展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塔里木盆地白垩纪油气藏深度超过4000米（13,000 英尺）深，分布复杂且不均匀。它们以层状结构分离，其中岩层厚度仅 2-5 米，但深度波动超过 10 米。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;传统定向钻井技术在开采这些资源方面受到限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;该团队使用智能算法开发了具有米级分辨率的三维地质模型，涵盖“结构、岩石特性和成分”。该模型使他们能够预设钻井目标、设计水平井路径并预测可能的地质结构和油气接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国新疆石油的过去、现在和未来&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;智能钻井系统以3D目标导航技术为“大脑”，以各种仪器为“眼睛”和“肢体”，协同配合，精准完成任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基于电磁的成像仪钻头上装有波浪作为它的眼睛。它向地层发送电磁波并接收反射信号，以探索岩石的电特性和边界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 7 月份的一次采矿作业中，该仪器在深度达 4,538 米的地方连续工作了 229 个小时。米，准确识别砂体等低阻地层，为系统提供重要决策信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三维精准导航技术是系统的大脑。它利用预先建立的地下油气层结构模型，引导钻机到达最佳开采点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;灵活的旋转引导系统和地质导航系统，灵活引导钻机到达指定目标。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新疆塔里木盆地下隐藏着巨大海洋，面积比所有五大湖的总和还要大&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“该项目于2017年启动，现已形成具有自主知识产权的完整解决方案。基于该系统实现了智能深钻的目标。”中科院报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该系统凝聚了数百名研究人员六年多的不懈努力。许多自主研发的仪器经过数百次现场测试和迭代，已完成技术定型，从样机过渡到工程模型。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia says Ukraine fired missile towards Moscow, targeted Crimea with drone swarm]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3232297/russia-says-ukraine-fired-missile-towards-moscow-targeted-crimea-drone-swarm?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/b412f9be-faaa-41de-96d6-8e5d433c0ff8_174d97a0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯周五表示，乌克兰向莫斯科发射了一枚导弹，并用 42 架无人机袭击了克里米亚，这将是迄今为止已知的乌克兰对俄罗斯控制领土最大规模的协调空袭之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部表示，一枚改进型 S-200 导弹在卡卢加州上空被击落，该导弹被击落。与莫斯科地区接壤。卡卢加市距莫斯科不到 200 公里（124 英里）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这枚导弹被卡卢加地区上空的防空系统发现并摧毁，”国防部表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卡卢加州州长弗拉迪斯拉夫·沙普沙 (Vladislav Shapsha) 表示，没有人员伤亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰没有立即对这些报道发表评论，而且几乎从未公开声称对俄罗斯境内或俄罗斯控制的乌克兰领土上的袭击负责。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部还表示，俄罗斯于 2014 年夺取并吞并的克里米亚遭到袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯称对莫斯科的无人机袭击受阻，乌克兰边境附近有 3 人死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;9 架无人机被防空部队摧毁，33 架无人机被电子战压制，并在没有到达目标的情况下在克里米亚上空坠毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科任命的港口城市塞瓦斯托波尔州长米哈伊尔·拉兹沃扎耶夫 (Mikhail Razvozhayev)克里米亚的克里米亚人在 Telegram 消息应用程序上表示，塞瓦斯托波尔郊区的多架无人机被摧毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前还没有有关袭击造成人员伤亡或损坏的报告，俄罗斯将此次袭击归咎于乌克兰。莫斯科附近的俄罗斯机场暂停航班数小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 5 月初两架无人机在克里姆林宫上空被摧毁以来，类似事件激增，此次袭击是最新一起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰已据称，摧毁俄罗斯的军事基础设施有助于比6月份基辅开始的反攻。总统弗拉基米尔·泽伦斯基在本周的一次国际会议上表示，基辅将“解除对”克里米亚的占领。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯没有表现出离开克里米亚的迹象，俄罗斯曾利用克里米亚向乌克兰发射导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但乌克兰军事情报部门表示，它本周协助海军进行了一次“特别行动”，他们在克里米亚西端登陆部队，与俄罗斯军队发生交火，并升起了乌克兰国旗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次任务未得到俄罗斯证实，此次任务恰逢乌克兰独立日，似乎旨在表明乌克兰军队能够在克里米亚开展地面行动，并且该半岛并非无懈可击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰本周的军事情报另据报道，故意引诱一名俄罗斯军事飞行员将他的 Mi-8 直升机降落在乌克兰机场。俄罗斯尚未发表评论。俄罗斯一个受欢迎的支持战争的 Telegram 频道 Fighterbomber 表示，一架直升机迷路并意外着陆。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Prominent defender of Beijing’s policies Hu Xijin warns no one ‘really enjoys’ increasing social controls]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3232296/prominent-defender-beijings-policies-hu-xijin-warns-no-one-really-enjoys-increasing-social-controls?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/a90b775a-a686-4f6e-9e78-7a37088120d4_b0658473.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国政策最引人注目的捍卫者之一已开始公开表达对以下问题的担忧：在北京实施数十年来最严格的意识形态控制之际，社会缺乏开放和宽容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直言不讳的民族主义小报《环球时报》前主编胡锡进似乎发起了罢工周三，他在微博上发表了不同的语气，指出宽容和自由在中国社会的重要性，他说这是在 Covid-19 大流行后发展摇摇欲坠的经济的先决条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们都有他写道：“我们有兴趣创造一种既有原则又有足够的放松和自由空间的社会氛围。”“我们任何人都不应该有意识或无意识地参与推动螺旋式收紧的社会控制越来越多。我认为没有人真正喜欢生活在这种社会氛围中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛通常以遵守官方路线而闻名，并且是 2019 年香港反政府抗议活动的著名批评者。在微博和X（前身为Twitter）等中国和国际社交媒体平台上嘲笑美国对这一流行病的处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“凝聚人心”：中国高考检验对习近平思想的掌握&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;但在周三的帖子中，他敦促人们避免频繁抵制和攻击个人，称这只会产生负面影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，胡锦涛也在表态后发表了看法。喜剧演员李浩石和他的公司因五月份拿中国人民解放军流行口号开玩笑而受到惩罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡在微博上写道，社会应该有“犯错的空间”，避免日益增长的焦虑和恐惧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡在微博上写道，社会应该有“犯错的空间”，避免日益增长的焦虑和恐惧。 >;&lt;p>;一位不愿透露姓名的大陆政治分析人士表示，胡锦涛表达这样的担忧有点令人惊讶，并表示他可能已经收到一个迹象，表明一些重要官员也在反思这一情况&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位学者表示，但目前还不清楚是否有迹象表明总体意识形态控制将会放松。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 10 月，国家主席习近平告诉共产党中央委员会。全国代表大会指出，国家“思想面貌发生了全局性、根本性的变化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，“党的新时代新理论深入人心”和“社会主义核心价值观”正在引起公众共鸣……网络环境不断改善。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛呼吁建立更加开放的社会，这可能是中国意识形态控制与经济政策之间日益紧张的一个症状，拉纳·米特 (Rana Mitter) 表示哈佛大学肯尼迪学院教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，中国人民大学重阳金融研究院执行院长王文也提出了类似的担忧，他指出，中国社会的开放理念“变得有些滞后和保守，特别是地方层面的制度开放正在放缓。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王此前也曾直言不讳地捍卫北京的官方路线，包括 2021 年 8 月发布的一份报告批评王毅在 5 月份的一个自由贸易论坛上表示，一些地方官员将物流、信息和资本的流动视为“世界第一失败”。敏感甚至非常危险”。他说，他们也把正常的国际学术研究交流视为敏感，必须向上级请示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“开放不足，改革不力，是中国发展潜力没有得到充分发挥的重要原因。”目前已释放，经济复苏动力仍不足。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“净化思想”：中国文化警察引发过度杀戮的担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;米特指出，尽管党的偏好非常紧张的意识形态环境，经济仍然低迷，有一种创业精神和增长难以刺激的感觉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经济增长依赖于信息的自由流动和可预测性商业用途。这意味着减少自上而下的控制，为更广泛的社会提供更多的实验机会。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Huawei renews 3G, 4G and 5G licensing deal with Swedish telecoms rival Ericsson in bid to monetise its tech patents]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3232290/huawei-renews-3g-4g-and-5g-licensing-deal-swedish-telecoms-rival-ericsson-bid-monetise-its-tech?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 15:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/10fd4680-c851-442d-96a5-fac86a0d0734_9c9553e4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国电信巨头华为技术有限公司与瑞典同行爱立信签署了一项新协议，双方有权在网络设备和消费设备中使用彼此的蜂窝技术，这是这家总部位于深圳的公司将其专利转化为金钱的最新努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为周五宣布其新的专利交叉许可与爱立信的协议将涵盖全球 3G、4G 和 5G 技术各种标准所必需的专利。华为表示，这将是一项长期协议，但没有详细说明具体期限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为移动通信标准必要专利（SEP）的主要贡献者，两家公司认识到彼此知识产权的价值。华为知识产权部负责人范艾伦在一份声明中表示：“该协议是双方深入讨论的结果，确保了双方专利的利益。持有人和实施者得到公平的服务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爱立信在周五的另一份声明中表示，续订的多年期协议认可了彼此知识产权 (IP) 的价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该协议体现了双方的承诺，即知识产权应受到尊重和奖励，领先的技术创新应在整个行业中共享。”爱立信首席知识产权官克里斯蒂娜·彼得森 (Christina Petersson) 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爱立信预计到 2023 年，其 IP 许可收入将达到约 110 亿克朗（9.98 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;续订的协议延续了两家电信巨头之前就相互许可专利所达成的协议。根据 2016 年签署的协议，华为将根据使用爱立信专利的智能手机和其他产品的实际销售情况支付“持续的特许权使用费”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为是当时最大的中国智能手机品牌，主要持有直到 2019 年该公司被列入美国实体名单后，该公司的手机销量急剧下降，这使得该公司无法使用源自美国的先进 5G 半导体等技术。由于欧盟呼吁更多成员国阻止华为使用其 5G 网络，该公司在欧洲也面临着越来越多的不确定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为手机销量的下降导致其使用其他手机的费用减少公司的专利。华为2021年每年的专利使用费收入首次超过其知识产权支出，并表示2022年其专利使用费收入约为5.6亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月份，华为首次公布了其收费标准一些最重要的通信技术，包括 4G 和 Wi-fi 6。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公司专利组合的增强带来了更高的许可收入，可以抵消华为使用其他方专利所支付的费用。华为欧洲知识产权部负责人埃米尔·张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“华为不仅是专利持有者，也是专利实施者，因此我们一方面不怕支付合理的专利使用费，另一方面也能获得专利保护。”另一方面，为华为的专利支付合理的费用。”张说。 “版权费收入不是我们追求的目标，而是我们创新的成果得到认可。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1987年成立后，华为在2000年代成长为电信硬件领域的巨头主要是通过削弱国际价格竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于中国技术现在在海外面临更严格的审查，特别是在美国和欧洲，华为持有的知识产权可以帮助其应对其他领域销售下滑的情况，并为其大量研究提供资金&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张表示，与爱立信共享技术的协议表明创新不应受到去全球化的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“长期协议将为公司提供更多的业务确定性并最终服务于下游客户，包括运营商和最终用户。”张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Asia should uncage the private sector’s ‘animal spirits’ to get economies out of their rut]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3232250/asia-should-uncage-private-sectors-animal-spirits-get-economies-out-their-rut?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 15:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/d3ad0475-11ce-4e31-92f8-d9d713538587_72031993.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;纵观历史，人类在逆境中的创造力和创新精神都来自于“动物精神” ”。经济学家约翰·梅纳德·凯恩斯 (John Maynard Keynes) 在其 1936 年的开创性著作《就业、利息和货币通论》中精明地指出，人们倾向于采取积极行动，而不是基于数学计算，而是基于“自发的乐观主义”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数决策他说，做一些积极的事情“只能被视为动物精神的结果——自发的行动冲动”，并警告说，如果“动物精神黯淡，自发的乐观情绪动摇……企业就会衰落并消亡”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在大萧条最严重的时期撰写这篇文章时，凯恩斯发现市场无法凭借自身力量摆脱信心的螺旋式下降。需要动物精神来让经济摆脱泥潭（凯恩斯将其定义为流动性或信心陷阱），但凯恩斯建议国家部署财政支出来推动经济发展，而不是依赖市场进行自我纠正。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当今世界陷入了类似的信心陷阱——只有中央银行和政府愿意印钞票作为阿司匹林来治愈低生产率、社会不公正和环境失衡等结构性问题，才能避免这种陷阱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当今世界陷入了类似的信心陷阱。 p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰战争已经导致数千人丧生，浪费了数吨弹药，欧洲一些最肥沃的土壤也遭到破坏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国，经济增长和出口均低于预期，年轻人失业率上升，资本净外流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国股市是唯一一个似乎在对抗地心引力的市场，受到“七大”科技公司占据主导地位前景的提振在人工智能和大数据方面。然而，由于中国既是低端半导体的主要生产国，又是高科技产品的买家，中美贸易紧张局势和制裁的进一步加剧最终将削减企业利润并逆转股市复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;美国科技股市场的成功表明美国股票驱动的金融模式与欧洲、日本和中国银行驱动的模式之间存在显着差异。国际清算银行的数据显示，截至 2022 年底，美国私人非金融部门的银行贷款仅占国内生产总值 (GDP) 的 51.2%，而欧元区为 89.6%，欧盟为 123.9%。日本为 185.4%，中国为 185.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就其本质而言，银行是规避风险、以抵押品为基础的，不愿意为创新和风险投资提供资金。与此同时，它们容易面临信贷、流动性和到期风险，如果作为银行抵押品的主要支持的房地产价值受到影响，它们将面临巨额不良贷款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在金融体系由国内信贷占 GDP 杠杆率较高的银行主导的情况下，要求银行体系增加贷款以重振增长也带来巨大风险。这就解释了为什么2008年以来的量化宽松政策没有改变生产力，反而加剧了债务杠杆和社会不平等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实体经济部门通过创造力、创新和冒险来增长。国家在基础设施和监管领域只能做这么多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，当监管变得更加复杂时，即使央行资产负债表扩大，私营部门也会变得过于依赖国家的指导，从而成为风险- 逆向或寻求被认为更绿的外国牧场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这就是为什么重振私营部门的动物精神对于未来的增长至关重要，因为创新、创业和冒险将为他们创造收入补偿系统损失。如果系统试图通过专注于“贝塔”或被动平均回报来最小化风险，那么“阿尔法”——带来希望的超额利润——就会被严重错过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们以前看过这样的戏剧。邓小平等国家领导人要求包括国有企业在内的中国企业家承担风险，从而释放了他们的动物精神。美国总统罗纳德·里根和英国首相玛格丽特·撒切尔鼓励私营企业并减少国家干预，以促进市场增长。国家冒险信任私营部门承担市场风险，这种组合发挥了作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国私营部门的混乱情况是什么？北京正在采取哪些措施来清理它？&lt;/h3>;&lt;面对疫情、大国竞争、战争和社会抗议带来的前所未有的冲击，以及颠覆性的技术变革和复杂的监管，亚洲私营部门受到冲击，容易产生“流动性偏好”——不进行长期投资在某些情况下，甚至削减债务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据定义，国家官僚机构的动机是对失败的恐惧，而市场则是由成功的希望驱动的。当国家寻求加强监管时，私营部门会用脚投票。投资者将寻求信用风险最低的短期回报。企业家将持观望态度。失业率将会上升，通货膨胀和成本将会增加，未来前景将会降低。归根结底，这是一个信心问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凯恩斯认为，当国家赋予市场权力时，我们就被带出了绝望的荒野。相信市场有其风险，但正如美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格所说：“在危机中，最大胆的做法往往是最安全的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在是亚洲各国政府允许市场的动物精神发挥作用的时候了。让我们摆脱迫在眉睫的衰退陷阱的大胆步骤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 15:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: China quietly recruits overseas chip talent as US tightens curbs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3232287/tech-war-china-quietly-recruits-overseas-chip-talent-us-tightens-curbs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 15:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/ea05d6ed-fca3-451e-ab26-7303bc8e58f0_633a39ab.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;截至 2018 年的十年间，中国一直在寻求招募受过外国培训的精英科学家华盛顿认为这一资助计划对美国利益和技术霸权构成威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国对科学家进行调查期间，中国停止推动千人计划（​​TTP）两年后，中国在新的一项政策下悄悄恢复了该计划。根据三位知情人士的说法，以及路透社对 2019 年至 2023 年 500 多份政府文件的审查，作为提高其技术熟练程度的更广泛使命的一部分。三人告诉路透社，该公司提供的福利包括购房补贴和典型的 3 至 500 万元人民币（即 42 万美元至 70 万美元）的签约奖金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国运营各级政府的人才计划，针对海外华人和外国专家。根据国家和地方政策文件、在线招聘广告以及一位直接了解此事的人士的说法，TTP 的主要替代品是一个由工业和信息化部监管的名为启明的项目。由于问题的敏感性而不愿透露姓名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在吸引科技人才的竞赛之际，习近平主席强调，面对美国的出口限制，中国需要实现半导体领域的自力更生。美国商务部10月通过的规定限制美国公民和永久居民支持中国先进芯片的研发和生产等措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国务院新闻办和商务部均未回应提问关于启明。据官方媒体新华社报道，中国此前曾表示，通过 TTP 进行海外招聘的目的是建设创新驱动型经济，促进人才流动，同时尊重知识产权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;启明或启蒙两位知情人士表示，招聘人员来自包括半导体等“敏感”或“机密”领域的科技领域。与它的前身不同的是，它没有公布获奖者，也没有出现在中央政府网站上，消息人士称这反映了它的敏感性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些文件提到了启明与火炬，火炬是中国的一项长期倡议。科技部重点打造科技企业集群。该部没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据两位知情人士透露，启明创投还与地方和省级主管部门开展的招聘计划以及政府支持的中国芯片公司的招聘活动合作开展业务以及另一位熟悉此事的消息人士。路透社无法独立确定所涉及的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国长期以来一直指责中国窃取知识产权和技术，北京方面将这一指控视为出于政治动机而予以驳回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“外国对手和战略伙伴当被问及中国人才招募计划时，美国政府国家反情报与安全中心发言人迪恩·博伊德 (Dean Boyd) 表示：“竞争对手明白，获得美国和西方顶尖人才往往与获得技术本身一样好。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“当招聘造成内在的利益冲突或承诺时，可能会给美国经济和国家安全带来风险。”中国分析师尼克·马罗表示，通过人才流动来遏制知识产权泄漏是很困难的经济学人智库认为，这种做法“可能会面临演变成种族歧视的政治迫害的风险”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国芯片产业近年来蓬勃发展，但面临短缺问题根据政府智库中国信息产业发展中心和中国半导体行业协会发布的 2021 年报告，今年约有 20 万人，其中包括工程师和芯片设计师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的新生代人才三位消息人士称，与 TTP 一样专注于精英级招聘，该项目更青睐在国外顶尖院校接受过培训的申请者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“大多数入选启明创投的申请者都曾在美国顶尖大学学习过，并且至少拥有其中一位人士说道，并补充说，在麻省理工学院、哈佛大学和斯坦福大学接受过培训的科学家也在中国寻求的人才之列。这些大学没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据路透社对政府文件的审查，尽管有数千名专家提出了申请，但路透社无法确定启明创投或相关项目已招募了多少名专家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;美国官员表示，虽然在美国挖角人才并不违法，但大学研究人员如果在接受美国政府资助进行研究时未能披露与中国实体的关系、非法分享专有信息或违反出口规定，就有违法的风险&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社发现，自 2022 年以来，自称是招聘人员的人在中国平台知乎和 LinkedIn 上发布了十多条招聘启明应聘者的广告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2 月份的 LinkedIn 帖子中，陈标华的雇主是北京人才联动信息技术有限公司，他要求符合启明和火炬资格的候选人将简历通过电子邮件发送给他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该帖子称，陈正在寻找40岁以下、拥有博士学位的“年轻人才”。 - 知名大学和海外经验。他还在寻找在国外学术机构或大公司担任高级职位的求职者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;猎头公司杭州聚奇科技3月份在学术社交网络ResearchGate上发布了一则广告，寻找来自顶尖大学的博士学位人才并拥有世界500强企业的工作经验，帮助中国企业招募5000名海外研究员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;广告中称，此举是为启明和火炬服务，每名研究员可获得高达1500万元人民币，约合美元$2.1 million, in rewards. It said that anyone who recommends a candidate who is then selected for the talent programmes would receive “diamonds, bags, cars and houses”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen and LinkedIn declined to comment. Questions sent to Chen&#39;s employer, as well as to Zhihu, ResearchGate and Hangzhou Juqi Technology yielded no responses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One foreign-trained semiconductor expert at the Beijing Institute of Technology (BIT) was identified on its website as a 2021 Qiming recipient. Ma Yuanxiao is an associate professor at BIT&#39;s School of Integrated Circuits and Electronics, who did his masters at Britain&#39;s University of Nottingham between 2013 and 2015 and his PhD at the University of Hong Kong until 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma and BIT did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Across China, provincial and municipal governments are pouring resources into the recruitment drive, official documents show.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One initiative is the Kunpeng Plan, run by authorities in eastern Zhejiang province, whose 2019 launch was covered instate media. The Zhejiang Daily reported in June 2022 that the programme aimed to attract 200 tech experts in five years, with 48 already recruited.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the eastern city of Wenzhou, local authorities&#39; investment in each Kunpeng professional can reach up to 200 million yuan, including an individual reward, start-up funding and housing, according to a 2022 talent policy report by the city government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A report by the Wenzhou branch of the Communist Party&#39;s Organisation Department, which oversees personnel decisions, said its total budget in 2022 increased 49 per cent from a year earlier, mainly because it had assigned 85 million yuan to Kunpeng and similar programmes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One Kunpeng recipient is Dawei Di, a Cambridge-educated professor at Zhejiang University whose research focuses on semiconductor optoelectronic devices, the university&#39;s journal reported in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Huzhou, also in Zhejiang, employers that recommend candidates to Qiming can receive incentive payments of up to 1.5 million yuan from the city or district governments if those people are accepted, according to a 2021 city directive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;None of the city, provincial or Communist Party authorities, nor Di or his university, responded to queries from Reuters.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Despite Xi&#39;s emphasis on advancing China&#39;s chip know-how, two sources with direct knowledge of the matter said many Chinese semiconductor experts overseas were wary of returning because of China&#39;s political environment and weaker position in chip development relative to the West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They have no idea if the programmes could change overnight or lose government support,” one said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhuji, a county-level city in Zhejiang, reported in October 2022 that it had over 200 applicants for talent programmes, mainly Qiming, but only eight successful candidates from the previous year had returned to China. Zhuji government&#39;s general office did not respond to a faxed request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two people familiar with the matter said some Chinese scientists, especially those with foreign citizenship or permanent residency, worried that joining China&#39;s government talent programmes could mean forgoing international opportunities or becoming subject to US investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In some cases, these people said, those experts will be offered roles at Chinese chip companies&#39; overseas operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Safer to have one foot in China, one foot out,” one said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 15:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South China Sea: Philippine, Australian troops practise retaking island in first joint drills]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3232268/south-china-sea-philippine-australian-troops-practise-retaking-island-first-joint-drills?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 13:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/25/f01127fc-a267-4600-81bb-c3a8cf4b4c4d_e993515e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Australian and Filipino troops held exercises on Friday near flashpoint South China Sea waters claimed by China, with Philippine President Ferdinand Marcos Jnr hailing them as an “extremely important” example of close cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China deploys hundreds of coastguard, navy and other vessels to patrol and militarise reefs in the South China Sea, which it claims almost entirely despite an international ruling that its position has no legal basis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Friday&#39;s joint drills took place at a naval base about 240km (150 miles) east of Scarborough Shoal, a rich fishing ground that China seized from the Philippines in 2012 after a tense standoff.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Considering that there have been so many events that attest to the volatility of the region, this kind of exercise, this kind of close strategic cooperation between countries around the region is extremely important,” Marcos told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is an important aspect of how we prepare for any eventuality,” he said of the drills, which he watched with Australian Defence Minister Richard Marles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia, Japan and the Philippines conducted a joint patrol last week, although a US Navy vessel did not take part as planned, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What will Philippine support of &#39;external players&#39; mean for the South China Sea?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has said he will make the first visit by an Australian leader to the Philippines in 20 years next month to discuss defence cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These are the first major air, sea and land drills between the two countries. They simulated retaking an enemy-controlled island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 1,200 Australian soldiers and 560 Filipino marines stormed a beach in the drill, arriving in amphibious assault vehicles, by parachute and on US Osprey aircraft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two advanced Australian F-35 fighter jets provided close air support, and Australian warships secured the surrounding waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The exercise came after Chinese coastguard vessels fired water cannon and blocked a Philippine resupply mission to Second Thomas Shoal in the South China Sea on August 5.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippine Navy deliberately grounded a World War II-era vessel on the shoal and set up a tiny garrison in 1999 to check China&#39;s advance in the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has demanded the Philippines remove the vessel and defended its actions as “professional”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday, a second Philippine mission managed to deliver supplies to the outpost.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese coastguard said it had decided to allow the resupply on humanitarian grounds as the Philippine vessels “did not carry illegal building materials for large-scale reinforcements”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippines hosted a meeting this week with its fellow members in the Association of Southeast Asian Nations and China to negotiate a code of conduct in the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Quirky China: elderly man plays mahjong in oxygen mask, dog uses torch to fetch owner in dark, karma-seeking man frees US$42,000 fish]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3231967/quirky-china-elderly-man-plays-mahjong-oxygen-mask-dog-uses-torch-fetch-owner-dark-karma-seeking-man?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/48e30fa4-5734-447d-bc9c-6eeb0f46efdb_75e13e0f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A video of a 72-year-old man in China who wears an oxygen mask while playing mahjong has shocked mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man&#39;s daughter, surnamed Tang, shared a video on August 16 showing her father playing mahjong at home in Hunan province in central China, with the caption: “Is there anyone who loves playing mahjong more than my father?” the Xiaoxiang Morning Herald reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang said her father has emphysema and has to wear an oxygen mask connected to an oxygenator around the clock.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He has been sick for many years. He can&#39;t do anything arduous. Playing mahjong is what he does every day,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Of course, I support that. My father feels happy when playing mahjong. He can do anything he likes as long as it does not require much strength.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video sparked widespread discussion online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“His daughter is so filial to him! I salute the father and his daughter,” one online observer said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person added darkly: “I admire his mahjong partners most. They are so brave to play mahjong with him. I wonder if the old man could suddenly pass away due to extreme excitement or disappointment during the game, will anyone bear any responsibility?”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A video of a pet dog called Donggua holding an electric torch while it went to meet its owner in the dark has impressed people on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its owner from a village in Guangdong province, southern China, came home late in the evening on August 18 and asked her dog – through her home surveillance camera microphone – to meet her at the village entrance, reported Xianning TV.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the dog ran out of the yard, the woman was heard saying: “Donggua, wait. Go back to bring the electric torch with you. The torch is on the table. Go find it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the dog found the torch, the woman said: “Come closer to the camera. Put it down on the ground so that I can see it clearly. Yes, right. Open it to see if it still has got power in it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then the woman said: “Bring it to me. Be quick because my mobile is almost out of power.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the torch held in its mouth, the dog quickly ran out of the yard to meet its owner. Five minutes later, in the surveillance video, the dog walked home with its owner while the woman held the torch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video has received 4.8 million likes and nearly 400,000 comments on Douyin alone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What a smart and cute dog it is!” one person said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This dog is more reliable than some husbands,” joked another.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;An entrepreneur in southern China who paid 300,000 yuan (US$42,000) for a 20kg fish at an auction and set it free has caused an online debate about the traditional Buddhist practice of fang sheng in which animals are released back into nature.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a food culture festival in Guangdong province on August 18, a newly harvested species of black fish nicknamed the “Fish King” because of its great size, went under the hammer at an auction, reported Qingyuan TV.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the report, the bidding for the fish started at 100,000 yuan and it was won by a local businessman for 300,000 yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When asked by the auctioneer if he planned to cook the fish by steaming it or braising it in soy sauce, the man, whose identity was not reported, answered firmly: “I plan to release it back into the North River (a local river where the fish was caught).”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The local authorities said the income from the auction would be used to improve the river&#39;s ecosystem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t understand the world of rich people,” one online commenter said of the story.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He has done something of boundless beneficence,” another online observer wrote, referring to the significance of fang sheng in Buddhism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ritual has been practised in China since ancient times and is believed to bring good karma.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, many people in mainland China have bought various animals from markets before setting them free.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese navy says it’s testing the planet’s most powerful coil gun]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3232258/chinese-navy-says-its-testing-planets-most-powerful-coil-gun?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 13:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/25/5e7bc1c6-0738-4ba4-889f-71a6c785fdde_2db4bc4f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Chinese navy is reportedly testing the planet&#39;s most powerful coil gun – a type of electromagnetically powered weapon capable of launching projectiles with very high speed and accuracy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a firing test revealed to the public for the first time, the electromagnetic launcher accelerated a 124kg (273lbs) projectile to a speed of 700km/h (435mph) in less than 0.05 seconds, according to scientists involved in the project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the heaviest known projectile to be used in a coil gun experiment. While the exact dimensions and maximum range of the weapon remains classified, a shell moving at such speeds could hit a target several kilometres away.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese scientists build hypersonic generator to power futuristic weapons&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Coil guns are also known as Gauss guns or magnetic accelerators. The weapon features a series of coils arranged along the barrel of the gun, each one constituting a “stage”. Each coil is energised one after another to create a magnetic field that can levitate and propel a projectile forward.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The projectile typically stays suspended in the centre of the coil during launch, which helps to keep it on a straight course and prevent it from touching the wall of the barrel. It can be fired repeatedly and rapidly without causing wear on components.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coil guns could revolutionise the way that wars are fought, allowing for faster, more accurate and devastating attacks on enemy targets. They could also launch missiles or send satellites into space.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The technology has been around for decades, but challenges in materials science and electronics have made it difficult to build large and powerful models.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the closest competitors to the Chinese coil gun, a 120mm-calibre electromagnetic coil mortar test device at the Sandia National Laboratories in the United States, can fire a projectile weighing 18kg. It is among the largest of these devices ever built.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other systems around the world typically can fire projectiles weighing only a few grams and with a diameter of a few millimetres, according to a study published by Israeli scientists in the journal Scientific Reports in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The larger a coil gun, the better its ability to fire projectiles similar to those fired by traditional artillery. A standard 155mm artillery shell used by the US military weighs around 43kg, while Italy&#39;s Indigo anti-aircraft defence missile weighs 120kg.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The coil gun has a number of advantages over traditional artillery, including higher launch speeds, lower launch costs and shorter preparation time, according to the Chinese team led by professor Guan Xiaocun with the Naval University of Engineering.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It has the potential for revolutionary breakthroughs in terms of speed, range, power, accuracy, safety, flexibility and reliability,” Guan and his colleagues wrote in a paper published in the peer-reviewed journal Transactions of China Electrotechnical Society this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is widely applicable in areas such as weapon systems, near-earth satellites and high-speed missile launches,” they added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Their 30-stage coil gun is still in the testing phase, and it is unclear when or if it will be deployed in the field. However, the Chinese military has been investing heavily in the technology in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Naval University of Engineering has overcome a series of difficulties” in building a large coil gun, said Ma Weiming, lead scientist of the Chinese military&#39;s electromagnetic launch programme in a paper published in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma said the challenges included the design and manufacturing of large-calibre high-magnetic-density coils and compact pulsed power technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that China was currently developing an even more powerful coil gun capable of launching a projectile at a speed of 3,600km/h, which could push the weapon&#39;s kill range to over 100km.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese researchers turn to AI to build futuristic weapons&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The rapid development of coil guns in China was in part due to a breakthrough in sensor technology, according to Guan&#39;s team.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coil guns generate a strong magnetic field when fired, which can interfere with electronic devices and sensors, so research on electromagnetic launchers typically requires measuring the projectile&#39;s flight behaviour through external means.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Guan&#39;s team came up with a new smart projectile equipped with sensors that are shielded from electromagnetic interference thanks to special materials, allowing them to collect high-quality data about projectile flight behaviour. This precise data from internal sensors can help scientists improve the efficiency and stability of coil guns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Maintaining a projectile&#39;s suspension in the centre of the coil during launch can be a challenge, as any deviation from the centre can cause the projectile to touch the wall of the barrel and affect its trajectory.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The onboard sensors helped the Chinese scientists detect issues that were missed by computer modelling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the team, at the start of the launch, the test projectile was at the bottom of the drive coil because of gravity. When the pulsed current was turned on, the test projectile was pushed upwards by the electromagnetic force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because the electromagnetic force was stronger at the tail of the projectile, it caused the projectile to tilt and collide with the inner wall of the drive coil, which made the acceleration data fluctuate, they said. When the test projectile passed through the later stages, it started to wobble because the pulse current was triggered at the wrong time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Discoveries like this can help scientists improve the performance of coil guns. For instance, the wobbling can be reduced by adjusting the trigger time for the pulse current that passes through the coils.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump makes history with scowling jailhouse mugshot]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3232260/donald-trump-makes-history-scowling-jailhouse-mugshot?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 12:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_analysis/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/25/5279696b-9567-4392-9332-a14f0fc58eb2_c2b2ed0e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A camera clicks. In a fraction of a second, the shutter opens and then closes, freezing forever the image in front of it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the camera shutter blinked inside a jail in downtown Atlanta on Thursday, it both created and documented a tiny inflection point in American life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Captured for posterity, there was a former president of the United States, for the first time in history, under arrest and captured in the sort of frame more commonly associated with drug dealers or drunken drivers. The trappings of power gone, for that split second.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Left behind: an enduring image that will appear in history books long after Donald Trump is gone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It will be forever part of the iconography of being alive in this time,” said Marty Kaplan, a professor at the University of Southern California Annenberg School of Communications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the photo, Trump confronts the camera in front of a bland grey backdrop, his eyes meeting the lens in an intense glare.他穿着蓝色西装、白色衬衫和红色领带，肩膀平直，头稍微向镜头倾斜。 The sheriff&#39;s logo has been digitally added above his right shoulder.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ex-US president Trump surrenders in Georgia, mugshot released&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Some of the 18 others charged with him in Georgia smiled in their booking photos like they were posing for a yearbook.不是特朗普。 His defiance is palpable, as if he&#39;s staring down a nemesis through the lens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump facing charges is by now a familiar sight of 2023 to Americans who watched him stand before a judge in a New York courtroom or saw watercolour sketches from the inside of federal courthouses in Miami and Washington, where cameras aren&#39;t allowed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is different.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Anderson Cooper put it on CNN: “The former president of the United States has an inmate number”.确切地说，P01135809。 But until he surrendered to face charges of trying to steal the 2020 election in Georgia, his fourth indictment this year, he avoided having to pose for the iconic booking photo like millions accused of crimes before him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Never mind that Trump, like all Americans, is innocent until proven guilty in court; the mugshot, and all it connotes, packs an extra emotional and cultural punch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A mugshot is a visceral representation of the criminal justice system, a symbol of lost freedom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It permanently memorialises one of the worst days of a person&#39;s life, a moment not meant for a scrapbook. It must be particularly foreign to a man born into privilege, who famously loves to be in control, who is highly attentive to his image and who rose to be the most powerful figure in the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“&#39;Indictment&#39; is a sort of bloodless word. And words are pale compared to images,” said Kaplan, a former speech-writer for Vice-President Walter Mondale and Hollywood screenwriter. “A mugshot is a genre. Its frame is, &#39;This is a deer caught in the headlights. This is the crook being nailed&#39;. It&#39;s the walk of shame moment.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump is unlikely to treat the mugshot as a moment of shame as he seeks a second term in the White House while fighting criminal charges in four jurisdictions. His campaign has reported a spike in contributions each time he&#39;s been indicted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And the imagery itself?特朗普并没有回避这一点。 In fact, his campaign concocted one long before it became real.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump&#39;s bond prohibits intimidating witnesses. Will he abide by it?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Months before he was photographed in Georgia on Thursday evening, his campaign used the prospect of a mugshot as a fundraising opportunity. For US$36, anyone can buy a T-shirt with a fake booking photo of Trump and the words “not guilty”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dozens of similar designs are available to purchase online, including many that appeal to Trump&#39;s critics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now they have a real one to work with. Within minutes of the mug shot&#39;s release, Trump&#39;s campaign used it in a fundraising appeal on its website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“BREAKING NEWS: THE MUGSHOT IS HERE” reads the subject line of the campaign&#39;s latest fundraising email, which advertises a new T-shirt with the image. And this quote: “This mugshot will forever go down in history as a symbol of America&#39;s defiance of tyranny”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump himself also wasted little time, posting it on X, the site formerly known as Twitter, as well as on his own social media platform, Truth Social.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The X post was Trump&#39;s first in more than 2½ years, after his account was banned following the January 6, 2021, attack on the US Capitol by his supporters. Elon Musk reinstated Trump&#39;s account last year soon after acquiring X.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a show of solidarity with Trump, US congresswoman Marjorie Taylor Greene posted to X, a photo of herself smiling broadly in front of a grey background, the sheriff&#39;s logo in the top left corner to mimic the jail&#39;s style – essentially her DIY mug.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I stand with President Trump against the commie DA Fani Willis,” she said, a swipe at the Fulton County, Georgia, district attorney who persuaded a grand jury to indict Trump.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recent history is full of politicians seeking political dividends from their booking photos. They&#39;ve offered large smiles or defiant smirks and tried to make the best of their predicament.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Of course Donald Trump can win again&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yet this is one of just 45 presidents in all of US history – not only someone who held the keys to the most powerful government in the world, but who held a position that for many these days, both at home and overseas, personifies the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To see that face looking at a camera whose lens he is not seeking out – that&#39;s a potent moment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There&#39;s a power to the still image, which is inarguable,” said Mitchell Stevens, a professor emeritus at New York University who has written a book about the place imagery holds in modern society and how it is supplanting the word.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It kind of freezes a moment, and in this case it&#39;s freezing an unhappy moment for Donald Trump,” Stevens said. “而且这不是他可以点击就可以离开的东西。这不是他可以轻易置之不理的事情。那一刻将继续存在。 And it&#39;s entirely possible that it will end up as the image that history preserves of this man – his first mugshot.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>