<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Singapore urges India to exempt it from export ban on non-basmati rice]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3229348/singapore-urges-india-exempt-it-export-ban-non-basmati-rice?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 12:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/657595ac-ee56-4f9e-8ab3-61401d96f654_cc64b699.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新加坡正与印度当局密切联系，寻求印度禁令的豁免新加坡食品局 (SFA) 周五表示，禁止出口非印度香米。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球最大的大米出口国印度上周四立即禁止部分海外销售大米。&lt;/p>;&lt;印度消费者事务和食品部表示，该国将禁止出口非巴斯马蒂白米，该大米约占其出口总量的四分之一。它补充说，此举将“确保充足的供应”并“缓解国内市场价格上涨”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SFA 表示，来自印度的非巴斯马蒂大米约占新加坡进口大米的 17% .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构表示，2022 年，印度约占新加坡进口大米的 40%，并补充说，新加坡从 30 多个国家进口大米。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于厄尔尼诺现象令人不安印度粮食供应紧张，是否会导致价格“飙升”？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“SFA正在与进口商密切合作，增加从不同来源进口不同品种的大米。新加坡也在与印度当局密切联系，寻求禁令豁免。”SFA 在声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度占全球大米出口量的 40% 以上，因此这一决定可能“数据分析公司 Gro Intelligence 在一份报告中表示，“这可能会加剧高度依赖大米进口的国家的粮食不安全”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计将受到禁令打击的国家包括非洲国家、土耳其、叙利亚和巴基斯坦——所有这些国家该公司补充说，其中一些国家已经在与高食品价格通胀作斗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度消费者表示，第二季度印度非巴斯马蒂白米出口量同比猛增 35% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使在印度政府于 9 月份禁止碎米运输并对白米征收 20% 的出口税之后，价格仍然上涨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;根据新加坡的大米库存计划，大米进口商必须持有相当于其每月进口量两倍的缓冲库存。 SFA 在声明中表示，这有助于确保市场上大米供应充足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们定期审查库存缓冲，并随时准备在需要任何调整时与行业密切合作。”该机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管如此，[我们]预计供应会不时中断，虽然政府将尽我们所能将影响降至最低，但我们无法完全减轻对我们食品的干扰供应。”SFA 表示，新加坡的大米总体供应“目前稳定”，“如果每个人只买我们需要的东西”，每个人都有足够的大米。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“消费者还鼓励在发生中断时通过改用其他品种的大米或其他碳水化合物来源来保持灵活性和适应性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这篇文章最初由 &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>; 发表&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwanese military’s plan to use mountain barrier as natural shield called into question as PLA expands presence to the east]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3229321/taiwanese-militarys-plan-use-mountain-barrier-natural-shield-called-question-pla-expands-presence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 12:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/af490ac3-6d5f-4063-ac67-64e6a850ba8a_139d65a5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾军方长期计划在东部地区保留其部队在中国人民解放军不断展示实力后，该岛在遭受中国大陆袭击时受到质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与岛西戒备森严的西部（最靠近大陆的一侧）不同&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;利用这一天然屏障，台湾军方建造了两个大型地下机库，其中一个位于花莲嘉山基地多年来，一年一度的汉光军演一直被用来测试台湾空军和海军从西部调动飞机和舰艇到台湾避难的能力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但解放军一直在加强在东部的活动，定期派飞机进入岛内东部和东南部防空识别区，并派出更多军舰和潜艇进入东海岸附近海域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4月，台湾国防部长邱国正证实，解放军已于2017年在台湾以东约200海里（370公里）的海域部署了山东航空母舰。蔡英文总统在加利福尼亚州与美国众议院议长凯文·麦卡锡会面后举行了为期三天的大型演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;解放军派出 29 架飞机和舰艇前往台湾附近举行年度军事演习&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;北京声称该岛是其领土的一部分，认为这次会议严重侵犯了其主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;解放军在台湾东海岸附近的存在增加引发了人们对防御计划的怀疑，因为&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“山东舰出动飞机并部署在我东海岸进行训练，意味着解放军很快就具备了一位驻台东部的国防军退役指挥官表示：“我们的目标是从后方攻击我们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位不愿透露姓名的军官表示，预计解放军将在东部地区附近集结部队。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们的嘉山基地和池行基地的跑道都被毁了，那我们的战机在那里掩护还有什么意义，因为它们根本就无法起飞。”跑道？” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，在花莲和台东港口避难的军舰受到西太平洋袭击的风险更大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，如果我们不能在很大程度上扩大我们在台湾东部的战力，包括加强我们的反导、防空和舰艇能力，在东海岸的地下基地和港口进行庇护……根本无法保存我们在那里的军队。”他说。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;隶属于主要反对党国民党的台北智库国家政策基金会的安全研究员杰中表示，解放军增加在台湾东海岸附近的行动旨在加强其拒绝进入的能力&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果共产党军队能够确保其在面向台湾东海岸的西太平洋打击位置，他们应该能够使用他们的舰艇——发射战机和巡航导弹摧毁我们在花莲和台东的设施。” 。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为其领土，必须将其置于其控制之下，必要时可以使用武力。与大多数国家一样，美国作为台湾最大的非正式盟友和武器供应国，不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对任何单方面以武力改变两岸现状的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; -自2016年倾向独立的民进党蔡英文当选总统并拒绝接受一个中国原则以来，海峡竞争加剧&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;退役空军中将张彦廷表示相对而言，东部地区比北部和西部地区更安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台湾的主要政治、经济和军事设施都从北部延伸出来。”他说：“如果发生两岸战争，他们应该是中国共产党的首要目标。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;解放军还需要考虑到他说，附近有美军，如果从东部攻击台湾，可能会来救援该岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;解放军向台湾派遣了数十架战机&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;林荫宇，新北淡江大学国际关系与战略研究教授表示，在台湾东部反复进行部队保存演习将有助于台湾军队找到需要改进的地方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“毫无疑问，解放军永远可以使用东风导弹摧毁我们在台湾东部的设施，但我们也有反导系统来对抗它们。”他指的是最近有关北京在台湾对面部署中程弹道导弹的报道。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;林说，虽然解放军的DF-17导弹肯定有能力打击台湾，但他不排除它们也可以瞄准冲绳或菲律宾的美军。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Max Lo，执行董事台湾国际战略研究会的一名成员表示，解放军实力的增强意味着整个台湾岛可能会成为一个战区——国防部长邱部长在五月份的立法院会议上承认了这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国防部必须制定有助于保存和加强我们在台湾各地的力量的计划，”罗说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine troops fire North Korean rockets at Russia, say unpredictable arms ‘do crazy things’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3229343/ukraine-troops-fire-north-korean-rockets-russia-say-unpredictable-arms-do-crazy-things?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 11:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/53c3c7ef-e46c-4337-a5ee-3058d691ef33_7ecc1b54.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;虽然朝鲜领导人金正恩支持俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京的战争努力，乌克兰生产的武器显然已经转向俄罗斯军队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国《金融时报》周五报道称，乌克兰一直在向俄罗斯军队发射难以预测的朝鲜制造火箭。巴赫穆特附近操作多管火箭系统的乌克兰士兵向出口展示了这些武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名乌克兰炮兵指挥官告诉英国《金融时报》，他的部队不喜欢使用这些 20 世纪 80 年代和 90 年代制造的武器，因为它们经常会失火或无法爆炸。一名士兵说，“他们非常不可靠，有时会做出疯狂的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考虑到朝鲜是俄罗斯的盟友，朝鲜使用武器的情况令人震惊。普京周四感谢朝鲜对乌克兰战争的“坚定支持”。俄罗斯国防部长谢尔盖·绍伊古本周也访问了平壤，在该国庆祝朝鲜战争结束 70 周年之际会见了金正恩。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰战争：俄罗斯寻求与朝鲜达成武器换食品协议美国称&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年，美国情报官员表示，在制裁切断克里姆林宫与其典型的军事补给线之后，平壤向俄罗斯出售了数百万枚炮弹和火箭。今年三月，白宫表示有证据表明朝鲜再次向俄罗斯提供武器，这次是为了换取食物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为这项拟议协议的一部分，俄罗斯将收到超过两打武器白宫国家安全委员会发言人约翰·柯比当时表示，“来自平壤的武器和弹药”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰士兵告诉英国《金融时报》，一个“友好”国家从朝鲜“扣押”了火箭弹。船，但没有透露更多细节。一名乌克兰国防官员表示，这些武器可能是直接从俄罗斯军队手中夺取的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们缴获了他们的坦克，我们缴获了他们的装备，这很可能也是乌克兰军队成功实施乌克兰国防部长顾问尤里·萨克 (Yuriy Sak) 告诉英国《金融时报》，并补充道：“俄罗斯一直在各种暴政国家采购不同类型的弹药，包括朝鲜和伊朗。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了朝鲜之外，西方官员也表示俄罗斯还从伊朗获得了武器。 《Politico》本周报道称，中国还利用漏洞绕过西方制裁，向俄罗斯发送军事装备，包括无人机和防护装备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰也一直依赖来自多个不同国家的武器。战争，包括苏联时代的武器和西方国家（包括美国、英国、德国和西班牙）提供的武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阅读原文：&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Barbenheimer’ craze has Hong Kong film fans dressing up to watch summer blockbusters back-to-back]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3229339/barbenheimer-craze-has-hong-kong-film-fans-dressing-watch-summer-blockbusters-back-back?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/70bed7bc-4f55-479c-a271-27f6652437ab_1558102f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港影迷一头扎进“巴本海默”现象，齐聚一堂盛装打扮，前往电影院观看夏季最热门的大片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些电影截然不同。格蕾塔·葛韦格 (Greta Gerwig) 饰演的芭比娃娃是关于这个标志性娃娃的粉红色、毛茸茸的乐趣，而克里斯托弗·诺兰 (Christopher Nolan) 饰演的奥本海默 (Oppenheimer) 是一部关于帮助制造原子弹的科学家的严肃的三小时史诗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;称其为极端病毒式营销或影响社交媒体上的热门话题，但两部好莱坞电影的同一天上映引发了无数迷因，并导致“巴本海默”一词被创造出来，并提出了相继观看两部影片的建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港电影运营商注意到了这种热潮和早期票房收入，但抱怨说这种现象并不是他们的行业从 Covid-19 大流行中缓慢复苏的灵丹妙药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港加入这一派对的人中有大学生。 20 岁的穆罕默德·瑙曼·库雷希 (Muhammad Nauman Qureshi) 在网上看到这些表情包后，与六位朋友连续观看了这两部电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;团体表示，香港电影院取消了 6 月 4 日“敏感”日的私人放映&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;“我认为这是一件非常有趣的事情，”他说。 “你随处都可以看到它——在 Instagram 上、YouTube 上——每个人都在做广告，这真是一件有趣的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位香港永久居民和他的四个朋友通过盛装打扮更进一步为了这个场合，为奥本海默穿深色正装，为芭比穿粉色。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为偶尔有像“巴本海默”这样的东西很好，但我们没有继续这样做，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;25 岁的调酒师 Joshua Collett 和他 22 岁的女朋友、大学生 Valerie Yuen 在 7 月 20 日首映当天观看了这两部电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有新加坡和香港永久居民身份的科利特表示，尽管他过去曾连续看过电影，但这并不是他经常做的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，围绕着电影展开了一场大炒作。夏季上映的两部巨制电影，两位大导演和电影制片人。总的来说，我们度过了一段非常愉快的时光，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于‘欢乐香港’活动期间门票需求旺盛，电影院网站关闭了&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;和其他人一样，这对夫妇没有不仅盛装打扮，而且还在奥本海默面前喝了一杯咖啡和一支烟，以向这位连续吸烟的物理学家致敬，并在芭比面前喝了玛格丽塔鸡尾酒放松一下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们让它成为一种体验，而不仅仅是科利特说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据数据提供商 BoxOfficeMojo 的数据，这两部电影在海外都取得了巨大成功，《芭比娃娃》在上映三天内的北美票房收入为 1.62 亿美元（13 亿港元）。 7 月 21 日，打破了《超级马里奥兄弟大电影》所保持的 1.463 亿美元的年度首周末票房纪录。奥本海默收入 8,240 万美元&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据香港动态的数据，7 月 20 日至 25 日期间，奥本海默在香港收入 1,814 万港元（合 230 万美元），超过芭比娃娃，后者收入 980 万港元图片业协会（MPIA）和香港票房有限公司（HKBO）。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;电影院观众可以享受新片和重映的《欢乐香港》门票折扣&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两者然而，《碟中谍6：航位推测第一部》的收入却黯然失色，该片于 7 月 13 日上映，截至 7 月 25 日的收入为 4,910 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港剧院协会，代表 63 家剧院中的 59 家该市的商业电影院预计“巴本海默”现象将提振夏季的票房收入，但遗憾这不足以帮助陷入困境的行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;董事长袁贤文表示，这一趋势，受到两部电影好评的鼓舞，会鼓励人们观看这两部电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这并不能解决大流行后该行业“不尽如人意”的复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MPIA和HKBO的数据显示今年1月1日至7月25日期间，本地票房收入较2019年的12.26亿港元下降近四分之一至9.22亿港元，这意味着仅恢复到疫情前水平75%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于一部电影来说，票房能达到几千万已经很不错了，但像《巴本海默》这样的营销效果只能帮助我们多赚10到2000万左右。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我们损失了3.04亿港元的销售额，这个数字绝对不是‘巴本海默’效应可以挽回的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会表示，即使在香港之后，业务仍然下降，背后有两个因素香港在三月份取消了最后一项流行病限制——受欢迎的电影减少了，而且随着城市移民潮的出现，电影院的观众数量也随之减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;金城武，香港电影界的“最优秀电影人”相貌演员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;随着 4 月份“电影日 2023”的推出，门票销量激增，这是政府“快乐香港”活动的一部分。电影院观众购买了约 222,036 张 4 月 29 日放映电影的门票，每张票价为 30 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及是否应该再次举办该活动时，袁表示电影院对此持开放态度，但他警告说，重复优惠可能会减少活动的费用。他表示，该行业将转而关注其他赚取收入的方式，包括特许摊位销售、广告和场地租赁。他们也在探索利用电影院作为小型演出的场所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但要让行业复苏，最重要的是电影的质量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果没有好电影上映，即使票价便宜到20至30港元，你做什么都没有用。” “观众很聪明。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thailand’s Thaksin plans a return amid rumours of a ‘super-deal’ placing Move Forward in opposition]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3229310/thailands-thaksin-plans-return-amid-rumours-super-deal-placing-move-forward-opposition?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/ff5bd1c1-51f7-4e78-a1a2-41a5974b4c20_e1a5e7c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;即使在他缺席的情况下，他信仍然是泰国政治的支点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2008 年，一场政变推翻了他的民选政府，两年后，法庭案件层出不穷，这位前总理开始自我流放，在伦敦、迪拜和香港度过。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;但在不到两周的时间里，他信——泰国唯一一位完成任期并再次当选的文职领导人——似乎准备最终回国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果他在 8 月 10 日回国的话正如预期的那样，他将返回一个发生了变化的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;曼谷抗议者告诉泰国参议员，批准皮塔担任总理，否则就“滚蛋”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他家族的为泰党不再自动拥有农村和城市贫民的选票。相反，在公众对其结构改革以及经济和社会平等的信息感到热情之后，更为激进的前进党已成为该国主要的亲民主力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，为泰党仍在努力组建赢得选举后前进的政府被阻止掌权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，74 岁的他信将面临 10 年监禁，他信不太可能服刑很长时间（如果有的话），推测这位亿万富翁曾经是建制派的祸根，可能已经与他曾经的保守派敌人达成了一项“超级协议”，以回归。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管赢得了五月选举，“前进”很可能会转入反对派。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论未来的政治阴谋是什么，他信的出现都将为已经复杂的局势增添引人注目的、不可预测的新动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;经过多年的错误开始之后，他信的回归似乎是真的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“爸爸将于 8 月 10 日回来，”他信的小女儿 Paetongtarn Shinawatra 本周在社交媒体帖子中表示，这是对他信回归的最坚定的确认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“爸爸将于 8 月 10 日回来”。 p>;&lt;p>;就他信而言，他周五在推特上发布了泰国独立摇滚歌手 Sek Loso 的 TikTok 视频链接，并承诺一旦他返回，将一起在舞台上表演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他将抵达曼谷廊曼机场，一大群媒体和政治支持者可能会在那里迎接泰国近代政治史上最重要的人物。国家警察副局长 Surachate Hakparn 表示，这位大亨回国后将接受司法程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“飞机降落后，警察将正常履行职责。他信将不得不出庭并听取他们的决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计法院将命令他直接入狱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他信将面临 10 年监禁他因三项缺席定罪而入狱，其中包括滥用权力和腐败，他说这些都是出于政治动机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他有权以老年囚犯的身份寻求在医疗设施中拘留，然后可以申请批准泰国看守副总理威萨努·克雷安 (Wissanu Krea-ngam) 表示，泰国国王玛哈·哇集拉隆功 (Maha Vajiralonkorn) 已获得王室赦免。很少有人预计他信会真正入狱——尤其是与其他囚犯一起服刑的普通民众。赦免仍然是他免遭拘留的最快途径。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他信的怀旧之情深深植根于内地的“红衫军”农村中心地带，在那里，他首次因其经济政策而受到崇拜。提高农村收入并满足穷人不断变化的愿望。他们的选票帮助他在 2001 年和 2005 年两次赢得选举，这让曼谷的当权派感到不安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他也遭到了保守派的谩骂。许多著名政客花了二十年的时间通过诽谤他和他的家人以腐败和裙带关系毒害泰国政治和社会来赢得声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在泰国政治的温室里，怨恨、相互指责和暴力横行。对于一位备受瞩目但又引起争议的人物来说，不可避免地存在安全风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的女儿 Paetongtarn（即将接任为泰党高层的家族政治衣钵）在她的 Instagram 帖子中承认了自己的担忧虽然她不顾自己的“安全”，但尊重她父亲回来的决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;前进党成为国家最大政党，是自他信去年突围选举以来对保守派势力最严峻的挑战。 2001年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，前进运动呼吁去垄断经济并改革保护君主制免受批评的皇家诽谤法，这是史无前例的，令将军和商界精英的“旧势力”感到不安&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，该党的年轻支持者对他信或领导保守党的前将军和老年政客的方阵几乎没有记忆，甚至更不尊重。并在未经选举产生的参议院中占据席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为泰党希望在下议院获得 270-300 个席位的压倒性席位，但最终仅以 141 个席位排在第二位，失去了许多内陆选票库以推动前进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;该党的权力被稀释，可能会使其成为保守派联盟中更受欢迎的合作伙伴，从而使前进党冻结为反对党。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;他信·西那瓦于 8 月 10 日结束流亡返回泰国：女儿&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;为泰银行面临的难题是找到一种方法，摆脱“前进”的束缚，同时尽可能减少对其亲民主品牌的持久损害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据传本周香港将达成一项“超级交易”他信、Thanathorn Juangroongruangkit（“前进”政治运动的创始人）以及领导第三名的 Bhumjaithai 党的 Anutin Charnvirakul 之间的合作可能掌握政府的关键。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这笔交易据称，允许他信回归，并允许为泰党加入包括 Bhumjaithai 甚至前军事结盟执政党 Phalang Pracharat 在内的联盟，而“前进”将陷入反对派。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anutin，他将他信描述为他的导师是为数不多的能够在未来议会投票中角逐这一职位的总理候选人之一，为泰党的房地产大亨 Srettha Thavisin 和他信的女儿 Paetongtarn 也是如此。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;议会联席会议定于 8 月 4 日举行另一轮投票，三周前，前进党的 Pita Limjaroenrat 被军方任命的参议院阻止成为泰国下一任总理。在那之前，泰国仍然没有政治领导人或新政府，而赢得最多选票的政党（前进党获得 1400 万票）似乎最不可能掌权。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Cheers baby! Video of Chinese father sharing midnight snacks with young daughter, toasting like drinking buddies delights social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3228878/cheers-baby-video-chinese-father-sharing-midnight-snacks-young-daughter-toasting-drinking-buddies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/44c08345-64cc-4704-8c99-32162200369d_17901a7a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个中国父亲与他蹒跚学步的女儿享受午夜烧烤并举杯的视频一个啤酒罐和一个高脚杯形状的奶瓶在中国社交媒体上获得了超过136,000个点赞，让许多人感到高兴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这段视频是由这位被称为“小茉莉”的网红母亲在抖音上发布的来自中国东南部安徽省的钝驴。她经常分享两个女儿的日常生活片段，大女儿绰号“小茉莉”，小女儿叫“六六”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月23日的视频显示，她的丈夫和六六坐在儿童座椅上品尝烤肉串。午夜时分，一起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当六六努力咬一口大块肉串时，她的父亲伸出了手，并配上了标题：“太高兴了！” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;父亲也剥了蒜，问六六要不要吃，六六摇头拒绝，并配文：“我不想要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;两人还玩得很开心；父亲拿着啤酒罐，女儿拿着装满牛奶的高脚杯形状的奶瓶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后的标题幽默地补充道：“等妈妈离开后，我们再打开一瓶。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;这并不是这位网红第一次因父女之间的可爱时刻而受到广泛关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月分享的一段视频显示，在母亲责骂六六后，父亲安慰了哭泣的六六。并获得了超过555,000个点赞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这段午夜祝酒视频在中国社交媒体上也很受欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位观众开玩笑说：“别再诱惑我再吃一个了。”孩子。我已经有了三个孩子，都是男孩。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个人说：“我该怎么办？我很想买同样的高脚杯奶瓶，但里面装的是啤酒。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有人说：“能这样陪孩子玩的男人，一定是个好丈夫！”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;随着过时的传统价值观逐渐适应现代中国家庭的需求，中国父亲越来越多地参与到育儿中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年5月，一名三岁的中国女孩她用玩具手机假装在网上热门漫画中看到的一家虚构商店订购了草莓蛋糕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了“保护她的清白”，她的父亲通过真实的送货平台订购了蛋糕，然后让她大吃一惊，这样她就不会意识到她的手机和商店不是真的。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Climate change: do fund managers make a difference in spurring companies to be green?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3229255/climate-change-do-fund-managers-make-difference-spurring-companies-be-green?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/010ffef-4d9e-490f-8dbf-a81c0a0bc503_6be2de7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;五年前，David Smith 找到了一位中国房地产开发商，该开发商部署了创新的建筑技术与行业相比，它使用的能源、水更少，产生的废物也更少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Smith 在 Abrdn 帮助管理 5000 亿欧元（5540 亿美元）客户资产的尽职调查中发现了这一点，引发了长期的投资者与被投资者之间的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;建筑商使用预制件在场外设施中建造独立式建筑模块，并在交付和在项目所在地安装之前为其安装内部固定装置。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据新南威尔士大学 2021 年环境工程论文，异地施工意味着浪费高达 80%。这还意味着节省运输成本，从而降低成本和降低碳排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种[脱碳]越来越受到市场的回报，”史密斯说，他拒绝透露建筑商的名字，并援引艾伯登的机密。 “然而，该公司并没有谈论这一点，也没有以市场认可的方式披露这一点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Abrdn 的指导和定期电话中，开发商披露了更多有关其能源和水的数据。效率以及产生的废物量。结果，其 MSCI 环境、可持续发展和治理 (ESG) 评级从“B”提升至“A”，这些荣誉有助于其降低融资成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ESG 正在提升议程清单中的位置随着监管机构收紧对上市公司披露风险和机遇、目标和改善 ESG 绩效的行动计划的规定，全球各地的董事会都在讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人类过度排放温室气体导致的气候变化活动，是需要企业采取行动的最紧迫的 ESG 问题之一。 2015 年，190 多个国家承诺将全球变暖控制在 1.5 摄氏度以内，以避免世界气候模式发生变化，从而带来灾难性的社会和经济后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;需要做的事情还有很多，因为只有不到富达国际 123 名分析师在 3 月份的一项调查中，有 60% 的公司预留了足够的资金，以便到 2050 年实现净零排放。这意味着他们在满足 1.5 度目标的先决条件方面做得还不够。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;管理着约 7,280 亿美元客户资产的富达表示，技术差距、缺乏企业动力和资金阻碍了这一进程。欧洲以 69% 的比例领先，大约是中国公司比例的两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富达表示，政府监管、投资者参与和股东行动是加强 ESG 实践的最有效方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Positive progress is being made, but Chinese companies have further catching up to do if they are to get in step with the government&#39;s [emission reduction] targets,” said Tan Jenn-Hui, Fidelity&#39;s global head of stewardship and sustainable investing .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While there is plenty of evidence showing that global asset managers are engaging actively, and that engagement tends to result in success, Asia and China lag behind the US and Europe, said Darwin Choi, a finance associate professor and associate director of the Centre for Business Sustainability at the Chinese University of Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Stock ownership is more concentrated and ESG data is poorer in Asia and China, making ESG engagement less effective,” he said, adding that weaker climate awareness and corporate emissions data quality are key barriers which can be improved through education and regulations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s stock exchange is trying to make the climate-related disclosures under its ESG framework mandatory, as opposed to the current “comply or explain” approach, in its three-month market consultation finished earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) went further, requiring all fund houses to establish governance structures and policies, and disclose how they manage climate risks and opportunities for each investment strategy and fund they manage. The tougher rules are aimed at helping investors make informed decisions and prevent greenwashing, the act of making unsubstantiated environmental claims about investment products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those with at least HK$8 billion (US$1.03 billion) of clients&#39; assets in the city must also disclose the emissions footprint of their fund products calculated from their investees. Drawn by returns and good intention, retail investors have embraced such products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s number of SFC-authorised ESG funds increased by 55 per cent to 188 as of March 31, with the total assets under management rising by 6 per cent to US$151.7 billion from a year ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fund managers who want to achieve the decarbonisation targets of their investment portfolios can either sell down their shares in carbon-intensive companies, or persuade the investees to reduce their emissions at a pace aligned with the funds&#39; targets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latter is the more constructive approach, said Patrick Bolton, a finance and economics professor at Imperial College London.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Once you sell your shares in a company … most likely the shareholder who will replace you will be less concerned about its emissions,” Bolton said at a Hong Kong University Business School ESG forum on June 23. “That is one criticism of the divestment strategy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, engagement must be accompanied by the threat of divestment if no improvement is delivered, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Otherwise, what&#39;s the incentive for a company to engage?”他说。 “Inevitably engagement has to be linked to divestment at some point.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most clients of asset managers do not want to divest for the sake of achieving short-term decarbonisation goals, said Schroders head of Asia-Pacific sustainability strategy Mervyn Tang. Instead, they prefer to balance decarbonisation, returns and portfolio diversification.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What we want to see is companies having a plan to get to net zero and not being behind their peers in that plan,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Engaging with investees on climate issues is not straightforward, said Ben McQuhae, founder of the law firm Ben McQuhae &amp; Co., and a co-founder of the Hong Kong Green Finance Association. He likened the challenge facing global asset managers to an “obstacle course.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, there are major differences in climate risks and opportunities disclosure requirements across the many jurisdictions they invest in, which adds to the costs and difficulty of performing comparative analysis for investment allocation decision-making.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While this is likely to be narrowed over time after the launch of a set of global baseline disclosure standards published by the International Sustainability Standards Board last month, the pace of change is uncertain.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can Hong Kong help cut through the alphabet soup of global ESG rules?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“It is challenging enough to keep up to date with what the regulations say, it can be even more challenging to predict how [the rules] will be applied and enforced in the context of climate or broader ESG disclosures, or to forecast the direction of policy travel,” McQuhae said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ESG ratings agencies and data providers will play an increasingly important role in putting pressure on investees to cut their carbon emissions, by arming investors with independent data and insights on investees&#39; relative ESG performance, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“However, the ratings industry is still in its infancy, and it will take time for the regulatory landscape to settle and for an inevitable industry consolidation to occur,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Transparency on data sources, methodologies and management of conflicts of interest were highlighted in a report published in late 2021 by the International Organisation of Securities Commissions as key ratings and data issues that need to be tackled by securities regulators worldwide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many asset managers are only at an early stage of engagement with investees in Asia on climate and ESG issues, which showed mixed results.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;FSSA Investment Managers, a unit of Japan&#39;s Mitsubishi UFJ Financial Group, started a climate engagement programme with investees in 2021. It assessed the progress of 72 companies that accounted for three-quarters of around US$144 billion of client assets it managed at the end of last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One encouraging engagement experience is Fujian province-based Anta Sports, the world&#39;s third most valuable sportswear company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;FSSA&#39;s ESG report said it has shown “material improvement” last year by committing to establish carbon reduction targets across its entire supply chain, and become carbon neutral by 2050.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, engagement with Chinese industrial manufacturer, one of FSSA&#39;s heavy-emitter investees, has proved disappointing, managing partners Michael Stapleton and Martin Lau told the Post. They declined to name it.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Construction giant tests climate-friendly concrete tech in Hong Kong&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Despite a 126-page ESG report and formation of a carbon-management committee, this firm showed poor “tangible” disclosures by only setting a one-year target to maintain emissions with no medium or long-term reduction targets, they noted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UK-based Legal &amp; General Investment Management, which manages around US$1.4 trillion of client assets, has been reporting on its climate engagement activities since 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year, it put 342 firms on its list for voting sanctions, compared to 80 in 2022 and 130 in 2021, for not meeting its minimum standards on climate change disclosures and mitigation actions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some 14 companies – including five Chinese state-backed ones – were added to its divestment list this year for failing to meet its “red lines”, up from 12 last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong sees Zhaoqing as partner to help modernise construction industry&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The new additions are Air China, which LGIM said has failed to set an emission reduction target, and Cosco Shipping Holdings which LGIM said has failed to commit to using low carbon fuels and has a low reduction ambition compared to its leading peers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China Construction Bank has been on LGIM&#39;s sanction list since 2018 for the lack of disclosure of the carbon emissions of funded activities, and policy to reduce its large financing portfolio to the coal mining and power sectors. All three companies did not respond to requests for comments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Abrdn&#39;s Smith said it is hard to tell whether its engagement might have helped the Chinese developer achieve a higher market valuation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A better view of quality or better ESG rating is not necessarily a valuation issue per se, [even if] research says it is,” he said. “But we think it can help companies reduce the volatility of their shares and attract stickier investors.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia-US military exercise halted after helicopter crash leaves 4 crew missing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3229338/australia-us-military-exercise-halted-after-helicopter-crash-leaves-4-crew-missing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 11:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/d8298cf4-3125-495f-b95f-e7ff39bed695_f0bb771a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Australia paused a major military exercise with the United States on Saturday, after a defence helicopter taking part in the drills crashed into the Pacific leaving four aircrew missing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia&#39;s Defence Minister Richard Marles said the MRH-90 Taipan went down late Friday night in subtropical waters near Hamilton Island, Queensland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It had been taking part in the vast Talisman Sabre exercise, which features 30,000 military personnel from Australia, the United States and several other nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As we speak to you now, the four aircrew are yet to be found” Marles said after a nearly overnight search, which is set to continue on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AFP understands that all four of the crew aboard the helicopter are Australian.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The families of the four aircrew have been notified of this incident and our hopes and thoughts are very much with the aircrew and their families,” Marles added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We desperately hope for better news during the course of this day.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia can be a &#39;reasonable&#39; moderator to ease US-China tensions: ex-minister&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Officials have not yet said what caused the incident, which came as the Talisman Sabre exercise was entering its second week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The drills are designed to test large-scale logistics, land combat, amphibious landings and air operations, and to signal the strength of Western military alliances.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan, France, Germany, and South Korea are also taking part.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin is in Australia with US Secretary of State Antony Blinken for meetings which coincide with the drills.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both men offered their support, as US personnel aided the rescue effort.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s always tough when you have accidents,” Austin said. “But the reason you train to such a high standard is ultimately so you can protect lives.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is not yet clear whether the military drills, which are due to end on August 4 will resume.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia is currently embarking on a major overhaul of its armed forces, pivoting towards long-range strike capabilities in an effort to keep would-be foes such as China at arm&#39;s length.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even before the incident, Canberra had announced it will replace its fleet of ageing Taipan helicopters with US-made Black Hawks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australian officials have complained about having to repeatedly ground the European-made Taipans, citing difficulties with maintenance and in getting spare parts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We just haven&#39;t got the flying hours out of the Taipan that we need. We are confident we can get that from the Black Hawks,” Marles said in January this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia to boost long-range strikes in defence reform as China&#39;s power grows&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In March, an MRH-90 Taipan flying south of Sydney suffered engine failure during a nighttime training exercise, forcing the crew to ditch into the ocean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They survived with only minor injuries, but the entire Taipan fleet was grounded for one month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Australia is set to build missiles for US military forces under a joint plan between the close allies, The Sydney Morning Herald reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It added Canberra will develop a local missile manufacturing industry within two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[San Francisco investigates after ‘X’ logo installed atop Twitter building without permit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229337/san-francisco-investigates-after-x-logo-installed-atop-twitter-building-without-permit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 10:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/32d60b61-b6c3-4b06-abb7-538d81d2dcd7_633b1294.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The city of San Francisco has opened a complaint and launched an investigation into a giant “X” sign that was installed on Friday on top of the downtown building formerly known as Twitter headquarters as owner Elon Musk continues his rebrand of the social media platform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;City officials say replacing letters or symbols on buildings, or erecting a sign on top of one, requires a permit for design and safety reasons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The X appeared after San Francisco police stopped workers on Monday from removing the brand&#39;s iconic bird and logo from the side of the building, saying they hadn&#39;t taped off the pavement to keep pedestrians safe if anything fell.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What Elon Musk&#39;s X offered Gene X Hwang for prized @x Twitter handle&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Any replacement letters or symbols would require a permit to ensure “consistency with the historic nature of the building” and to make sure additions are safely attached to the sign, Patrick Hannan, spokesperson for the Department of Building Inspection said earlier this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erecting a sign on top of a building also requires a permit, Hannan said on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Planning review and approval is also necessary for the installation of this sign. The city is opening a complaint and initiating an investigation,” he said in an email.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk unveiled a new “X” logo to replace Twitter&#39;s famous blue bird as he remakes the social media platform he bought for US$44 billion last year. The X started appearing at the top of the desktop version of Twitter on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk, who is also CEO of Tesla, has long been fascinated with the letter X and had already renamed Twitter&#39;s corporate name to X Corp. after he bought it in October.他的一个孩子叫“X”。 The child&#39;s actual name is a collection of letters and symbols.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday afternoon, a worker on a lift machine made adjustments to the sign and then left.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘It’s raising concerns’: Hong Kong marine experts detect changes in feeding behaviour of injured Bryde’s whale]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3229289/its-raising-concerns-hong-kong-marine-experts-detect-changes-feeding-behaviour-injured-brydes-whale?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 10:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/cf49752e-333b-4dc0-be02-38496c135040_e1184dde.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Marine experts have detected changes in the feeding behaviour of a Bryde&#39;s whale spotted in Sai Kung, warning it could be a result of increased human activity around the mammal following its rare arrival in Hong Kong waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Concerns about the health and safety of the whale, which was first spotted in the city on July 13, have heightened following images of two large wounds on its back and reports of boats swarming the mammal last weekend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compass Chan Tsz-nam, a scientific officer with the Ocean Park Conservation Foundation, told the Post on Friday that while the whale appeared to be in a stable condition, it was feeding for shorter periods, taking longer breaks between meals and also foraging in shallower waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We guess it&#39;s because of what happened during the previous weekend with the number of people going out into the waters,” he said. “It&#39;s raising concerns.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Images provided to Ocean Park and the Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation Department showed tourist-filled boats within just a few metres of the whale, despite repeated calls from authorities and conservation groups to maintain a distance of at least 100 metres (328 feet).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The shocking scenes prompted Chief Secretary Eric Chan Kwok-ki, who is serving as the acting chief executive while John Lee Ka-chiu is overseas, to order the marine police on Wednesday to step up patrols in the waters where the whale was spotted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marine experts said the wounds did not appear fresh, and might predate the whale&#39;s first appearance in the city, but they added that this should provide greater incentive for the public to avoid disturbing the animal.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Propeller wounds on whale spark calls for Hong Kong public to stay away&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Philip Wong Wing-hong, general curator for zoological operations and conservation at Ocean Park, said the whale might stay in Hong Kong waters while it recovered from its wounds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s crucial to create a tranquil environment for the whale to rest and heal, as many injured whales are able to heal on their own,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong added that increased pressure from human activity and other environmental factors could lead to “life-threatening consequences” for the animal, such as an inability to rest or feed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It should be an alarm for all of us,” said Viena Mak Hei-man, vice-chairwoman of the Hong Kong Dolphin Conservation Society. “There is a risk the whale will get injured again if we don&#39;t do more to protect it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s second whale sighting in 2 days as experts say give animals peace&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The mammal, believed to be a Bryde&#39;s whale measuring about seven metres (23 feet) long, was first spotted off the coast of Rocky Harbour near Millionaire&#39;s Beach, or Nam Fung Wan, and nearby waters in Sai Kung on July 13.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It disappeared for days until it was seen at Port Shelter off the campus of the University of Science and Technology last weekend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last Bryde&#39;s whale sightings in Hong Kong or in nearby waters were recorded between June and August of 2021, off Shenzhen&#39;s Dapeng peninsula in Mirs Bay, as well as in Sai Kung. But the mammal is believed to have died after a carcass of the same species was found in waters off Shenzhen on August 30 the same year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the time, Shenzhen authorities had established a temporary protection zone covering 64 square kilometres, which blocked private and recreational vessels from disturbing the whale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But despite calls from local conservation groups for the establishment of a similar protection area in Sai Kung, the Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation Department said such measures were not “feasible” owing to the mammal&#39;s “sporadic” feeding patterns across large areas of water.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Whenever the whale surfaces for feeding and a vessel is found to be too close, authorities will take immediate action, including reminding nearby boats to keep a distance from the animal,” the department said. “Enforcement actions will be taken against anyone who refuse to cooperate to ensure the whale is not disturbed by vessels.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Irresponsible whale-watching behaviour may constitute an act of wilful disturbance of protected wild animals.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Offenders of the Wild Animals Protection Ordinance are liable to one year&#39;s imprisonment and a fine of HK$100,000 (US$12,800) upon conviction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are indications that the warnings are being heeded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The World Wide Fund for Nature&#39;s (WWF) Hong Kong branch said it had sent staff to Sai Kung on Thursday to talk to boat operators about safe navigation if the whale appeared again and to discourage further tourist excursions into the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Amazed onlookers spot whale feeding in Hong Kong&#39;s eastern waters&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Many of them said they would not send passengers to go whale watching,” said Lydia Pang Lee-yan, the interim head of oceans conservation at WWF Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s still ongoing, so we hope the communication can continue,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bryde&#39;s whales are a species of baleen whales that can grow to 15 metres (49 feet) in length and weigh up to 25 tonnes (27 tons).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They are typically found in tropical waters all year round and are known for using their baleen plates to filter food when they open their jaws.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s West Kowloon Cultural District CEO on a mission to beat money woes, says arts hub was ‘jumping on one leg’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3229188/hong-kongs-west-kowloon-cultural-district-ceo-mission-beat-money-woes-says-arts-hub-was-jumping-one?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/f85ecbd5-5871-44cb-bc76-ecf503b8a7c2_bfa7bebe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Betty Fung Ching Suk-yee was shocked when she became chief executive officer of the West Kowloon Cultural District Authority in late 2021, managing the city&#39;s newest arts landmarks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The former civil servant was staggered by the state of the statutory body&#39;s finances. The more she checked, the more worried she became.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When I took over, it was the worst, worst time ever,” she recalled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mandated to get the authority&#39;s financial health and operations on the right track, she found that it only had enough cash to last until the end of 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As I began zooming into the finances of the authority, it was really scary,” she told the Post in an interview.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong art hub&#39;s managing authority searches for money to avert financial crisis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The government had long made clear it was unlikely to inject any fresh funding after pumping in HK$21.6 billion (US$2.8 billion) in 2008 to create an endowment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 40-hectare (99 acres) arts hub, one of the world&#39;s largest cultural precincts, has been in the works since the 1990s, but its first landmark attraction, the contemporary art museum M+, opened only in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Progress was delayed over the decades by a host of issues, from political wrangling to changes in development plans, management reshuffles, the Covid-19 pandemic and the repercussions of building the West Kowloon high-speed rail terminus on an adjacent site.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The financial situation was further complicated by the sudden addition of another star attraction, the Hong Kong Palace Museum, announced in 2016 by then-chief secretary Carrie Lam Cheng Yuet-ngor.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Tourists &#39;should be allowed museum entry&#39; during Hong Kong &#39;0+3&#39; surveillance&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The HK$3.6 billion project, which opened in July last year and showcases China&#39;s national treasures from the Palace Museum in Beijing&#39;s Forbidden City, was included without public consultation, its construction funded by the Hong Kong Jockey Club.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other key components of the arts hub include a Chinese opera facility, Xiqu Centre, contemporary performance venue Freespace, and a family- and pet-friendly Art Park, with the Lyric Theatre Complex slated to open in 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fung was not exaggerating when she described the authority&#39;s dire financial straits. In the financial year ended March last year, its losses doubled to HK$1.56 billion from HK$869 million in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By March this year, however, its losses had been trimmed to HK$718 million, with revenue up 13.7 per cent to HK$635.26 million in 2021-22.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have been a civil servant for 35 years, but I&#39;m now very entrepreneurial,” she said. “我告诉各级同事，他们必须真正以业务为导向。 They have to be very mindful of the money they spend.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the improvement, she said the authority was far from out of the woods.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fung said her priority when she started as CEO was to cut costs aggressively, and that resulted in lowering the deficit by a third to HK$718 million in 2022-23 from the estimated HK$1.07 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That meant its available funds would stretch 16 months longer than expected to 2025, instead of running out at the end of this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Fung said she could not keep cutting costs over the coming year. The staff team was already lean, the facilities still needed air conditioning and security guards, and programmes had to be changed regularly to attract visitors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I can see the bone, no flesh,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;With more facilities, a bigger deficit&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;At the heart of the arts hub&#39;s funding problems lies a lag between income and expenditure in its unique funding model.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The authority was supposed to be funded by income generated from commercial development in the area, including hotels and office towers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the pandemic and changes in the property market caused delays in the tendering of sites.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first commercial plot was only awarded last November, after failing to attract bidders in February. After the authority extended the operation period of the development by 13 years to 47 years, Sun Hung Kai Properties was the sole winning bidder of a 699,654 sq ft (65,000 square metres) parcel of land, estimated at HK$10.5 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Artist Square Tower Project, which would have three office towers with retail, dining and entertainment spaces, was expected to be completed in 2026, the developer said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the agreement, ownership of the development will be transferred to the authority at the end of the operation period.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fung said the revised terms meant the authority would receive less revenue from office rental, and must come up with new ways of financing for 2025-2070.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It will also face a bigger deficit in 2025 when the Lyric Theatre Complex is completed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The more facilities we open, the bigger the deficit we have,” Fung said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said revenue and expenditure were like two legs, running together.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have been jumping on one leg for a long, long time,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said the government endowment had been drained by construction and operation of the infrastructure. With no substantial income coming in, there was a prolonged mismatch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A source close to the authority said the income-generating projects should have been built before the museums and performance venues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Unfortunately, due to god knows what – it could be bureaucracy, unwise decisions, simple mistakes – they did it the other way around,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fung revealed that following the impact of the pandemic on the property market, the authority was revamping its funding model, which the government approved in 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She anticipated a glut of office rental space, which could worsen the vacancy rate of 12 per cent last year. The pandemic also reshaped the city&#39;s working mode, with more people working remotely, further dampening demand for office space.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overall office rents continued to trend down in the first half of this year, according to real estate firm Cushman and Wakefield, with overall office vacancies at their highest since the third quarter of 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The authority is studying how to revamp its business model, for example, by maximising the land use of sites not yet up for tender.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ticket sales a core revenue source&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Unlike some of the best known names around the world, such as the Louvre in Paris, which is largely state-funded, and the four Guggenheim museums which are privately funded, Hong Kong&#39;s M+ and Palace Museum fall under the model of private-public partnerships.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;John Zarobell, a professor at the University of San Francisco who researches museum funding, said there were other museums using the private-public partnership model, but the West Kowloon Cultural District Authority funds were the only one he knew of that did not rely on government support for operations but capitalised on its own development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is unprecedented,” he said. “It&#39;s based on the fact that urban development generates more resources … Rather than harvesting all of those advantages privately, some of them get pushed into the public domain, and not directly to the city government, but rather, to the institutions themselves.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Professor Oscar Ho Hing-kay at Chinese University, who specialises in museum management and was a member of the Museum Advisory Group for the arts hub, said M+ was envisaged as a space for “visual cultures”, mainly less costly works such as comics and cheap street designs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Unfortunately, it seems to be collecting mainstream art such as paintings, sculptures, installations, which are, by comparison, more expensive,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Palace Museum was an unplanned project that added significantly to the cost of the hub.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Running a museum of antiques of extremely high value – the maintenance, insurance, transport – is far more expensive than a museum of contemporary art,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unless there was substantial funding, he said, “it would be a disaster”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong cultural hub seeking bidders for first commercial project&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For a start, visitors will have to pay more to visit the Palace Museum. General admission fees will rise 20 per cent to HK$60 from HK$50 for adults and concessionary fees to HK$30 from HK$25 on September 27.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At M+, adult and concessionary general admission fees remain the same at HK$120 and HK$60 respectively, while special exhibitions adopt a flexible pricing structure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, a standard ticket for the “Yayoi Kusama: 1945 to Now” exhibition was HK$240, and the coming “Madam Song: Pioneering Art and Fashion in China” exhibition will cost visitors HK$140 for a standard ticket.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Admission fees are a core income of both museums, which were also enticing corporations to sponsor their programmes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fung pointed out that the two museums performed well in their cost recovery rate – the percentage of operation costs the institution made, so the higher the percentage, the better.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rates for the two were among the world&#39;s highest at 46 per cent for M+ and 44 per cent for the Palace Museum, she said, compared to 36 per cent for the Metropolitan Museum in New York and 10 per cent for Singapore&#39;s National Museum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unlike the two Hong Kong museums, she added, many museums around the world received government funding for their operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for the city&#39;s government-run museums, such as the Hong Kong Science Museum and the Hong Kong Museum of Art, their cost recovery rate stood at 7 per cent and 2.3 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government currently runs 15 public museums covering visual art, science, and history, among others. They come under the Leisure and Cultural Services Department, which spent HK$1.16 billion on their operations in 2022-2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For M+, one income source in the past year came from exporting the curation services of Japanese artist Yayoi Kusama&#39;s polka dot artwork to the Guggenheim Museum Bilbao, Spain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The show in Hong Kong attracted 280,000 visitors over six months before ending in May this year. In Spain, it attracted 35,000 people in its opening week in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our first ever special exhibition of a one-year-old museum could be shown in Guggenheim – it&#39;s a big deal for any museum in the world,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the longer run, she hoped the government would map out comprehensive policies to support the arts and culture industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While money was always on her mind, Fung was optimistic about the arts hub&#39;s future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But if it was not for the lack of funds, she said, now would have been the time to reap the full potential of the massive project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“People ask me, &#39;Why are you always talking about money?&#39;我必须谈谈钱。 If I don&#39;t have the money, I cannot do anything,” she said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>