<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[All 15 Israel Supreme Court judges to hear judicial overhaul petitions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3229546/all-15-israel-supreme-court-judges-hear-judicial-overhaul-petitions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 01:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/3b18e67a-e5d6-44fe-99ed-bcc773753977_c27a1dc6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;以色列最高法院周一表示，所有 15 名法官都将参加，这是历史性的首次在针对总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡的宗教民族主义联盟作为司法改革的一部分而通过的一项法律的争论的听证会上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最高法院已同意讨论驳回上周批准的一项法案的请愿书，该法案限制其使政府和部长做出的一些决定无效的权力，从而为宪法摊牌奠定了基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法院发言人表示，9 月 12 日的听证会将标志着该国历史上首次延长法官席位&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内塔尼亚胡及其政府推行的司法改革在以色列引发了前所未有的危机，造成了深刻的社会分歧，重创了经济并引起了西方盟友的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分歧已经蔓延到军队，志愿预备役军人表示他们不会去报到，前高级官员警告以色列的战备状态可能面临风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，以色列国防部长约夫·加兰特 (Yoav Gallant) 向议会外交会议表示事务和国防委员会认为，面对日益激烈的抗议活动，军队仍处于战斗准备状态，但从长远来看可能会造成损害。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;司法改革危机正在打击以色列曾经繁荣的经济&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;控制议会 120 个席位中的 64 个席位的内塔尼亚胡联盟表示，需要进行司法改革，以遏制最高法院的越权行为，并称最高法院的政治干预主义过于严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;批评者称，最高法院的越权行为已经变得过于政治干预主义。变化将取消对行政权力的有效检查，并可能导致滥用权力。请愿者包括以色列律师协会以及一个政治监督组织，他们表示 7 月 25 日的修正案“从根本上改变了结构”以色列议会民主和政府特征”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Islamic State claims responsibility for Pakistan bombing; death toll rises to 45]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3229545/islamic-state-claims-responsibility-pakistan-bombing-death-toll-rises-45?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 00:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/51f0e738-f583-4f3e-9ccb-7607bee07913_8f272c3b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;伊斯兰国周一声称对巴基斯坦西北部一次政治集会的自杀式爆炸事件负责由与政府结盟的宗教团体控制，袭击造成的死亡人数上升至 45 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，炸弹袭击者袭击了保守派伊斯兰法兹尔组织 (JUI-F) 的一次集会，该组织以其与强硬伊斯兰主义者的联系而闻名，但它谴责试图推翻巴基斯坦政府的武装分子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴基斯坦西北部巴焦尔地区靠近阿富汗边境的袭击事件加剧了当前的安全担忧。直到 11 月全国大选为止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，强硬派激进组织伊斯兰国在其 Telegram 频道上发表声明，声称对这起爆炸事件负责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此次袭击发生在该组织的 Amaq 机构在 Telegram 上表示：“伊斯兰国对‘民主’发动持续战争的自然背景是敌视真正的伊斯兰教并与其神圣法律相冲突。”国营救援机构表示，死亡人数已上升至 45 人。政府卫生顾问里亚兹·安瓦尔 (Riaz Anwar) 表示，在 130 多名伤者中，有 61 人正在接受治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理谢赫巴兹·谢里夫 (Shehbaz Sharif) 谴责此次爆炸为袭击事件关于民主进程。主要政党之间数月的竞争以及军方否认军方参与民事政治的指控已经给选举前景蒙上阴影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府任期将于八月上半月结束，之后将举行选举选举将在 11 月初之前举行，选举前的准备工作通常充满了政治集会和竞选活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果一系列此类袭击继续发生，推迟选举的理由就会更加充分。”巴基斯坦前反恐负责人哈瓦贾·哈立德·法鲁克表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此类有针对性的袭击可能会影响受影响政党的表现和竞选活动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴基斯坦伊斯兰武装分子的袭击死灰复燃。自去年以来，巴基斯坦塔利班、巴基斯坦塔利班运动 (TTP) 和政府之间的停火破裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TTP 分裂组织声称对白沙瓦的清真寺爆炸事件负责，造成 100 多人死亡在一月。尽管如此，周日的袭击是自 2018 年竞选以来针对政治集会最致命的一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然 TTP 和相关组织是近几个月来大部分袭击的幕后黑手，但该组织与周日的袭击保持了距离。发言人予以谴责&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;巴基斯坦政治集会发生自杀式爆炸事件，造成至少 44 人死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与 TTP 相比，伊斯兰国如此规模的袭击在巴基斯坦较为罕见，因为其影响有限。在场。该组织的一个当地分支机构最初在伊拉克崛起，在邻国阿富汗仍然更加活跃。它在巴基斯坦的最后一次重大袭击是在 2022 年对一座清真寺进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个新的激进组织巴基斯坦圣战组织最近几个月也出现了，该组织鲜为人知，并实施了本月早些时候，该国一处军事基地发生了一系列袭击事件，造成 12 名士兵死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JUI 及其领导人 Maulana Fazl-ur-Rehman 过去曾因反对巴基斯坦伊斯兰武装分子而遭到袭击他们认为，他们针对国家的武装行动并不构成合法的圣战——针对伊斯兰教反对者的斗争。尽管如此，该党还是支持阿富汗的塔利班运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange “ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[GDP worries, new central bank chief, economic action plans: 7 things you may have missed from China’s economy in July]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3229481/gdp-worries-new-central-bank-chief-economic-action-plans-7-things-you-may-have-missed-chinas-economy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/fb2d0031-d0bc-47f1-938b-7ce02d626840_9ffc1f60.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;7 月份中国经济增长继续失去动力，尽管北京方面提供了一些见解它计划帮助世界第二大经济体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有高调的访问和关键职位的人事变动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果您想查看我们的更多报道，请考虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;7月份的主要话题是第二季度经济数据，该数据显示中国第二季度国内生产总值同比增长6.3% 2023 年三个月的增长率。&lt;/​​p>;&lt;p>;这高于第一季度 4.5% 的同比增长率，但与今年前三个月相比，环比增长率为 0.8%，吸引了大部分人受 2022 年冠状病毒封锁造成的去年基数较低的影响，第二季度的总体数据受到关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方数据还表明，大流行后的复苏持续不平衡，私人信心摇摇欲坠，创历史新高。青年失业率高，房地产市场风险悬而未决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;零售额增速回落至 3.1%，部分原因是基数效应，低于 4 月份的 18.4% 和 5 月份的 12.7%，工业生产同比增长4.4%，增速高于5月份的3.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前六个月固定资产投资同比增长3.8% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 1-6 月民间投资同比下降 0.2%，较 1-5 月增长 4% 有所回落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前五个月下降0.1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国第二季度经济数据引发市场不满几天后，北京承诺将私营经济打造为“更大、更好、更好” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些承诺在新的 31 点行动计划中公布，旨在支撑境况不佳的私营部门，支撑经济增长、就业和技术创新，并振兴国民经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;又过了几天，中国 24 名政治局委员发表的一份声明显示，北京正在制定重大政策变革，旨在提振中国疲软的经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国领导层表示，是时候进行变革了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“主要挑战是内需不足、一些企业经营困难等。”新华社援引中共中央最高决策机构的声明报道称，“企业面临的困难重重，重点行业风险较高，外部环境复杂严峻”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治局描述了疫情后中国经济复苏的情况“波浪式发展，挫折中前进”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;令人失望的第二季度经济数据包括6月份的失业率数据，该数据显示了2017年的失业率。 16-24岁年龄组的失业率创历史新高，达到21.3%，高于5月份的20.8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国青年失业率形势复杂，今年有创纪录的1158万毕业生进入劳动力市场。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城镇总体调查失业率仍维持在5.2%不变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据发布第二天，教育部门表示需要在全国范围内进行改革以支持并发展中国的职业培训体系，特别是在战略性行业，因为熟练工程师和蓝领工人的短缺正在阻碍国家的产业升级和经济愿望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们发布了一份包含 11 项“重点任务”的清单供地方当局用来制定职业培训路线图。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中短期内，地方政府的任务是在职业学校与工业公司和研究机构之间建立桥梁，以更好地适应市场&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国长期以来一直关心养活14亿人口，在今年粮食产量下降0.9%的影响下，人们对自给自足的担忧加剧。夏季单产下降，主要原因是在收获前，长时间的降雨袭击了种植面积最大的省份河南的成熟小麦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是中国夏季收成自 2018 年以来的首次下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的粮食安全行动进展如何？是否取得成功？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国高层官员誓言要加强农田保护，更好地利用大片盐碱地，作为北京粮食安全行动的一部分，习近平主席主持召开会议，把开垦新耕地、提高耕地质量提上议事日程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平在会议上指出，“耕地是粮食生产的命脉”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到2022年，中国粮食年产量连续八年保持在6.5亿吨以上。北京的目标是至少保持今年的水平，并到2025年将其提高到7亿吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦是 6 月底至 7 月初访问北京的三位华盛顿高调官员之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦在出发前表示，与中国新任经济官员进行的 10 小时双边会谈她访问期间的访问为稳定紧张关系奠定了坚实的基础，她预计今后会有更多接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京表示，敦促华盛顿取消对中国企业的经济制裁，并呼吁共同努力解决全球问题&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦会见了国务院总理李强、时任央行行长易纲和前经济沙皇刘鹤，并向在北京的美国企业代表发表了讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们耶伦在会见李克强总理时表示：“寻求健康的经济竞争，这种竞争不是赢者通吃，而是通过一套公平的规则，随着时间的推移，可以使两国受益。” “在某些情况下，美国需要采取有针对性的行动来保护其国家安全，在这些情况下我们可能会与中国意见不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，我们不应允许任何分歧影响到美国的利益。造成误解，不必要地恶化我们的双边经济和金融关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国6月份出口同比下降12.4%，进口下降6.8% .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国出口额继 5 月份下降 7.5% 后降至 2853.2 亿美元，这是自 2020 年 1 月和 2 月出货量合计下降 17.7% 以来的最大跌幅。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;对中国所有主要贸易伙伴的出口均出现两位数下降，其中对中国最大贸易伙伴东南亚国家联盟的出口同比下降16.86%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;分析师预计出口将进一步下降，然后在年底触底，但未来几个月进口可能会回升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京已承诺支持出口行业，该行业已过去三年中国经济的主要推动力，但中国面临着全球需求疲软和以美国为首的供应链加速回流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月，中国还对中国实施了事实上的禁令日本海鲜进口因福岛放水计划引发愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国延长了对福岛等日本10个县的进口禁令，同时决定对来自其他地区的所有货物进行全面筛查，而不仅仅是现货- 在担心残留核污染的情况下进行检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;潘功胜晋升为银行行长，进一步巩固了他对中国央行的监督。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;60岁的易纲接替自 2018 年起担任该职务的 65 岁易纲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2016 年起担任国家外汇管理局局长的潘被任命为人民银行党委书记&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;潘在日本会见日本和韩国同行后，在实际任职期间已经承担了一些责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt; div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In London, a plus-sized passenger stuck for 3 hours had to be extricated from first class seat after plane lands]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3229525/london-plus-sized-passenger-stuck-3-hours-had-be-extricated-first-class-seat-after-plane-lands?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/0e45c813-08ff-40ef-976a-487bbee15869_7a184c61.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名大号英国航空乘客在他的头等舱座位上被卡住了据《太阳报》报道，这架航班于周六凌晨从尼日利亚飞往英国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报报道称，在从尼日利亚起飞的六个半小时的航班结束后，这名乘客被困在座位上大约三个小时。据《太阳报》报道，拉各斯穆尔塔拉·穆罕默德国际机场于凌晨 5 点 10 分降落在伦敦希思罗机场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该乘客坐在 1A，这是一个非常理想的座位，通常是为 Executive Club 金卡持有者保留的。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;《太阳报》报道称，在乘客意识到自己无法离开座位后，机组人员介入并试图安抚乘客。然而，该报称，他们无法转移他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后呼叫紧急服务人员将这名乘客救出，《太阳报》审阅了一份工程说明，概述了该计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《太阳报》报道，纸条上写道：“一名体积庞大的乘客被困在 1A 座位上。计划是拆除套房的门，并使用起重机将[他]从座位上弹出。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《太阳报》称，门最终被拆除，并使用起重机将乘客从他的套房中救出。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据旅游网站 Business Class Experts 的说法，英国航空头等舱的座位几乎有两英尺宽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国航空没有立即回应 Insider 的置评请求。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，美国有线电视新闻网 (CNN) 报道了大号乘客呼吁美国航空公司缩小飞机座位宽度并要求较大号乘客付费购买额外座位的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阅读原文上 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong bids farewell to trailblazing Chinese singer Coco Lee, remembered as kind, loyal and gracious]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3229542/hong-kong-bids-farewell-trailblazing-chinese-singer-coco-lee-remembered-kind-loyal-and-gracious?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 23:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/1dc8ad18-d196-4ad8-a694-0a0b65554c60_c15ef63e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;主厅里，一张李玟微笑的照片被花丛包围着周一，香港一家殡仪馆举行了葬礼，家人、朋友和名人与远道北京和马来西亚的歌迷一起向这位为中国歌手开辟道路的流行歌星表示敬意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下午四点后不久，仪式开始前几小时，歌迷们开始聚集在北角殡仪馆外。工作人员帮助为当地一些娱乐界和商界知名人士的到来扫清了道路，他们中的许多人戴着墨镜，穿着黑色衣服，庄严地进入大楼时避免了媒体提问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;整个仪式持续了大约两个小时，其中一半不对公众开放，但在专门的 YouTube 频道上进行了直播。在发表九篇悼词之前，李玟的大姐李南希以普通话和英语向这位歌手致敬，在天后肖像前铺满的兰花和其他鲜花的背景下发表讲话。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“我姐姐在她的音乐会上经常这样说：你可以选择去任何地方，但今天你选择来到这里[并]和我在一起，为此，我感谢你们所有人，”她说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;歌手曾珍妮、密友萧亚轩、华纳音乐亚洲联席总裁乔纳森·瑟宾和李玟来自旧金山的同学也纪念了李玟。本月早些时候，李玟因自杀未遂而去世，享年 48 岁。与抑郁症的长期斗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“善良、真诚、体贴、忠诚、慷慨、有趣、冒险、亲切，这些只是我用来形容我亲爱的朋友的几个词，”高中同学苏珊娜说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现场还播放了致敬粤语流行乐传奇人物刘德华、李克勤以及武术传奇人物成龙的视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Coco，我们我们会永远记住你，希望你在天堂自由自在地载歌载舞。”成龙说道。 “当我们想念你时，我们会仰望星空。我相信你永远是天空中最闪亮的星星之一。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出席者包括著名前解放军歌手韩红和本地歌手曾培德，还有李玟分居的丈夫。布鲁斯·罗科维茨（Bruce Rockowitz）并未被列为周二第二次私人葬礼的八名护柩者之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;身穿黑衣的粉丝坐在殡仪馆外的人行道上和附近的公园里观看直播&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下午6点刚过，公众被邀请入内吊唁，并发放了1,400多张门票。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;已故香港歌手李玟粉丝购买公交车站广告告别明星&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》采访了来自台湾、马来西亚和中国大陆的粉丝，他们表示自己曾从四川、重庆、北京、上海和遥远的西部地区前往&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;35 岁的袁朵拉（Dora Yuan）是李在上海的一个粉丝团体的组织者，她说：“我们很早就来了，向媒体展示她有多少粉丝。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在湖南长沙从事人力资源工作的El Cai Weiyou三天前带着五岁的儿子来到香港参加葬礼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Coco就像我的家人一样，社会的榜样，”她说。 “她是一个很好的人，我11岁时就开始听她的音乐。她的音乐确实激励了我……她的生命太短暂了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据李的家人透露，这位流行歌星于 7 月 2 日在家中试图自杀，并于 7 月 5 日去世。他们说她被诊断出患有抑郁症几年前，但她的病情在过去几个月急剧恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李女士1975年出生于香港，9岁起在旧金山长大，是三姐妹中最小的一个。虽然被说是个害羞的孩子，但她说自己一直梦想着表演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1993年回城参加TVB新秀歌唱奖后，18岁就开始出道，声称凭借惠特尼·休斯顿 (Whitney Houston) 的《Run to You》获得亚军，开启了她第一份唱片合同的大门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李演唱了李安 2000 年获奖作品中的《A Love Before Time》电影《卧虎藏龙》在奥斯卡颁奖典礼上亮相，成为第一位被索尼音乐全球签约的中国歌手，也是第一位也是唯一一位在年度颁奖典礼上表演的中国国籍艺术家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港可能会当局表示，将在星光大道向已故歌手李玟致敬&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周二上午，将在同一家殡仪馆为已故流行歌星李玟举行私人葬礼，她的遗体随后将在海角火化柴湾哥连森火葬场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果您有自杀念头或认识有自杀念头的人，可以寻求帮助。在香港，请拨打 +852 2896 0000 联系撒玛利亚人，或拨打 +852 2382 0000 联系预防自杀服务。在美国，请拨打 988 自杀和危机生命热线：988 或 +1 800 273 8255。有关其他国家/地区的帮助热线列表，请参阅此页面。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Former US president Trump’s bid to quash Georgia investigation rejected by judge]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229540/former-us-president-trumps-bid-quash-georgia-investigation-rejected-judge?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 23:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/ecebe09a-852f-425f-be35-1f5441ec0cbc_2acbe30c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周一主持佐治亚州大陪审团对唐纳德·特朗普调查的法官驳回了前者美国总统试图取消主导调查的检察官的资格，并阻止调查产生的任何起诉，预计调查将在未来几周内提出指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富尔顿县高等法院法官罗伯特·麦克伯尼也拒绝了特朗普的撤销请求一份特别大陪审团报告，其中包括关于在推翻佐治亚州 2020 年选举结果的运动中对谁提出指控的建议，当时民主党人乔·拜登以微弱优势赢得了该州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报告仍处于密封状态，等待对该案的指控.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普在佐治亚州演讲中将联邦起诉书斥为“政治迫害”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周一的裁决可能仅在可能的起诉前几天做出。富尔顿县地方检察官法尼·威利斯强烈表示，她打算在未来三周的某个时间要求大陪审团批准指控，并告诉法官，作为安全预防措施，她的工作人员将大部分远程工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安全路障上周在县法院外设立的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普否认有任何不当行为，并指责当选民主党人威利斯有政治动机。发言人和他位于佐治亚州的法律团队没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;威利斯的发言人拒绝置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普的律师已提出单独的长期出价取消威利斯的资格，下周将由另一位法官审理。该动议被分配给来自另一个县的法官，因为除了威利斯之外，该动议还提到了麦克伯尼；结果，所有富尔顿县法官都被回避听证会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2021 年 1 月以来，威利斯一直在调查特朗普试图扭转 2020 年选举结果的行为，此前不久，特朗普在电话中询问该州最高层选举官员“找到”足够的选票来推翻拜登的胜利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项广泛的调查还审查了特朗普律师的行为，其中包括鲁迪·朱利安尼以及一群在选举中担任候补选举人的个人。将该州的选举人票授予特朗普而不是拜登的努力失败了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特别大陪审团是应威利斯的要求召集的，以协助她的调查。陪审团拥有传票权，但无权提出指控，听取了数十名证人的证词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管法院做出了数十项裁决，但特朗普仍错误地声称佐治亚州和其他地方的选举因广泛的欺诈而受到损害。没有找到证据支持它。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦克伯尼在长达九页的决定中表示，考虑到尚未提出任何指控，特朗普阻止调查的举动还为时过早，而且他将有充足的机会提出质疑麦克伯尼还表示，尽管接受了媒体采访并发布了有关此案的推文，但特朗普并未表明威利斯的行为有偏见。&lt;/p>;&lt;他写道：“地区检察官的鼓动既没有党派倾向，也没有针对个人，这与其中一位激进分子不断的个人谩骂形成了鲜明而令人耳目一新的对比。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Forging ahead’: China boosts its Project GW satellite rival to compete with Elon Musk’s Starlink]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3229451/forging-ahead-china-boosts-its-project-gw-satellite-rival-compete-elon-musks-starlink?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/6041c35a-d9ee-48b0-9ade-3155fc5ea8b0_ed4b6ba7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位中国太空科学家透露了有关中国 13,000 颗卫星项目的更多细节，该项目旨在与 SpaceX 的 Starlink 竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京中国航天空气动力研究院气动专家曲伟表示，GW 项目正在“有序推进”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; GW指的是国网，即全国网络。屈冬玉表示，该项目是由国家发展和改革委员会发起的，该委员会是一个强大的中央政府机构，负责监督重大经济政策和项目的实施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该项目“可能会将其近 13,000 颗卫星置于比这些卫星更低的轨道上”他说：“低轨卫星具有恢复能力强、部署灵活、传输容量大、受地形影响较小等优点，以尽量减少碰撞风险并保持安全距离。”全国政协委员曲江在周四的《政协报》上发表文章写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国要建立自己的星链，关键是掌握可重复使用的技术”火箭技术，”他写道。 “甲烷燃料火箭的发展也至关重要，这是中国最近刚刚取得重要进展的方向。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;星链由美国亿万富翁埃隆·马斯克创立，是美国航天公司开发的卫星网络SpaceX 将提供从太空到地球任何地点的高速、低成本互联网服务。到目前为止，该公司已将 4,500 多颗卫星送入轨道，其中大多数在距地球约 550 公里（342 英里）的地方运行。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国的航天工业“最先进”，但中国可能拥有它最终，星链将成为一个由 42,000 颗卫星组成的巨型星座。一些星链卫星将在低至约350公里的轨道上飞行，以实现更快的通信，但大气阻力可能会带来挑战，缩短其寿命。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚国望卫星将在什么轨道高度运行。中国的天宫空间站绕地球运行的典型高度为390公里，国际空间站的飞行高度稍高，约为410公里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曲在文章中指责星链发起了太空版的“圈地运动”近地轨道，指历史性地夺取英格兰以前平民使用的土地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“星链卫星总数如此之多，使得近地轨道变得非常拥挤和危险。这些卫星还占用大量无线电频段，这限制了其他国家对太空的使用，”他写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“星链卫星的成本已降至如此低的水平，无论何时， ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曲还强调了星链与美军之间的联系。他说，星链卫星可以干扰导航信号、实现协同作战和高精度打击、摧毁在轨目标航天器等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“众所周知，与星链合作，美国部署天基防御性甚至进攻性系统。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚为埃隆·马斯克在偏远地区提供星链互联网服务的许可证&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;星链项目“对安全构成了威胁”他说，以及其他国家在近地轨道上的信息主权。在“国网”之前，中国已经规划了两个规模小得多的通信卫星网络——红岩和红云——“为后来建设中国星链奠定了基础”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月，中国发射了两颗卫星，以测试宽带卫星技术和超宽带卫星技术。 -薄型柔性太阳能电池板，均被视为国望卫星的原型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国具有集中力量完成重大任务的优势，中国版星链正在稳步推进。中国航天事业的发展和中国人民的命运必须掌握在他们自己手中。”曲写道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Jack Ma has an investment in fishery and agriculture start-up in hometown of Hangzhou, corporate data shows]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3229530/jack-ma-has-investment-fishery-and-agriculture-start-hometown-hangzhou-corporate-data-shows?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/fa0ce346-cf5c-43ac-8b0b-42404a5849f9_b4e8c173.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;马云是中国一家新成立的渔业和农业初创公司的幕后推手阿里巴巴创始人、前董事长离开电商巨头后，更加关注该领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一家名为“1.8米海洋科技（浙江）有限公司”的初创公司新成立根据企业注册数据提供商天眼查的数据，该公司于 7 月 20 日在浙江省省会杭州成立，注册资本为 1.1 亿元人民币（1500 万美元）。该合资公司业务范围涉及水产品饲养和加工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家初创公司的控股股东是香港1.8米科技控股有限公司，持股80%，第二大股东是杭州大井投22号艺术文化有限公司是亿万富翁马云2019年为在中国进行投资而创建的企业之一，拥有10%的股权。天眼查数据显示，蚂蚁集团前首席执行官胡晓明也拥有这家初创公司 5.5% 的股份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马云的基金会没有立即回复置评请求。 matter on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new venture, which also covers processing, wholesale and retail sales of agriculture products as well as development of offshore wind power systems, fits Ma&#39;s keen interest in the agriculture and food sector following his retirement from Alibaba, which owns the South China Morning Post. Ma stepped down as Alibaba chairman in 2019 and no longer holds any corporate roles at the company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma has made several international trips to learn about sustainable food production in the past few years. As of May, Ma was a visiting professor at Tokyo College, where he focuses on sustainable agriculture and food production, according to the school&#39;s website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his earlier trip in Japan, he spent time studying fisheries and tuna farming. In a trip to Thailand Ma visited a sea shrimp farming factory, the Post reported in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Alibaba&#39;s Jack Ma and Joe Tsai show up at offices in Hangzhou amid restructuring&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In July 2022, he visited a university in the Netherlands to learn how to improve sustainable food production, following a similar European tour the year before to further his interest in agriculture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba, which is in the middle of its biggest-ever corporate restructuring, has also invested in agriculture-related technology. And DAMO Academy, Alibaba&#39;s research institute, has launched an initiative in the field of “smart breeding”, and is hiring life scientists to help it develop China&#39;s seed industry, according to job postings published earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Jack Ma urges Alibaba to &#39;go back to Taobao&#39; to survive tough e-commerce market&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Founders of other Big Tech companies in China have also shown an interest in the agricultural sector after stepping down from day-to-day operations at their companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Colin Huang Zheng, founder of discount e-commerce empire Pinduoduo, donated US$100 million to Zhejiang University to support basic research in biomedical science, agriculture and food, after stepping down as chairman of the company in 2021.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 22:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Guyana’s President Mohamed Irfaan Ali wraps up China trip with pledge to expand cooperation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229531/guyanas-president-mohamed-irfaan-ali-wraps-china-trip-pledge-expand-cooperation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/0dd375af-0c2d-4ed0-a2e1-b4356824908f_3bd79510.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China and Guyana have said they will seek ways to work together in sectors such as agriculture, energy and mining as the South American country&#39;s President Mohamed Irfaan Ali wrapped up a visit to China on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a statement released by Beijing on Monday, the two countries reaffirmed their commitment to “further strengthening bilateral relations and expanding cooperation in various fields”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The two sides recognise the important value of trade and investment for deepening economic cooperation, and are committed to creating a positive business environment and promoting bilateral trade and investment activities,” the statement read.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said they would also explore cooperation in sectors such as manufacturing and service industries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ali&#39;s week-long trip to China included a meeting with President Xi Jinping and Premier Li Qiang on the sidelines of the World University Games in Chengdu, the capital of the southwestern province of Sichuan. He also visited Beijing and Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Xi Jinping promotes belt and road to leaders of Indonesia, Guyana and Georgia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ali expressed gratitude for Beijing&#39;s support for his country&#39;s economic development, including infrastructure, the Chinese statement added. The two sides also agreed to expand cultural and educational cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In September Guyana signed contracts with the Chinese pharmaceutical giant Sinopharm International to build six new regional hospitals in various parts of the country. Beijing has also helped the South American nation build roads, hotels and airports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s most notable venture in Guyana remains the Arthur Chung Conference Centre, a convention and exhibition venue named after the country&#39;s first president of Chinese descent. It first opened in 2006 and underwent renovations a decade later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Between 2018 and 2022, trade between Guyana and China increased seven-fold from US$265 million to nearly US$1.9 billion, making Guyana China&#39;s largest trading partner among Caribbean countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The volume of traded goods also increased by 213 per cent over the five-year period, with an average annual growth rate of over 42.5 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The South American country has a population of around 800,000 people but is the world&#39;s fastest growing oil producer after discovering its first reserves in 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Guyana rebuffs Taiwan plan for de facto embassy after warning from Beijing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Chinese statement also referred to a memorandum of understanding the two countries signed in 2018, while Georgetown restated its willingness to sign up for the Belt and Road Initiative, Xi&#39;s signature transcontinental infrastructure plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday Xi described the two countries as “good friends who trust and count on each other” and encouraged the two to “share opportunities, meet challenges, seek cooperation and advance development together”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ali told Xi that Guyana “highly values China&#39;s international influence” and “regards China as a highly reliable cooperative partner”. He also said the country is ready to maintain close communication and cooperation with China.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s economic planner wants people to buy more homes and furniture, but some just need a job]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3229528/chinas-economic-planner-wants-people-buy-more-homes-and-furniture-some-just-need-job?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/26b98e09-7890-445a-b49e-1a120f324775_1af84be4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing is trying to get China splashing out on big-ticket items like it used to, and a new plan to that end features incremental measures aimed at improving both the supply of goods and consumer sentiment, but some analysts say that such piecemeal policy tweaks will do little to restore battered confidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Measures unveiled in the consumption-stimulation plan on Monday are extensive but still much more restrained than many had hoped, and this reflects the dilemma Beijing faces in trying to strike a balance between curbing systematic risks and convincing everyday citizens to tap into their savings at a time rife with uncertainties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plan is a far cry from the shock-and-awe stimulus package Beijing unleashed in the wake of the global financial tsunami in 2007. This time around, the country&#39;s top economic planner is instead focused on reducing the business costs for goods and services, in hopes that this will trigger more spending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But while the country&#39;s top economic planner pledged to lower prices to boost spending, it said little about raising income and employment levels – critical fuel for the consumption machine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Covering expenditures across nearly all aspects of life, the plan aims to give full play to “the fundamental role of consumption in economic growth”, the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC) said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coming at a time when China&#39;s post-Covid recovery has lost momentum, with falling exports and suppressed investment figures, the plan includes 20 measures targeting various sectors – from property and cars to dining – and it is in line with Beijing&#39;s recent calls and directives at high-level meetings&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese economy grew by a lower-than-expected 6.3 per cent in the second quarter, from a low comparison base a year prior when nationwide lockdowns were in place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Chunlin, deputy head of the NDRC, said at a press conference on Monday that offline spending saw a “fast recovery” in the first half of the year, citing a boom in domestic travel and the concert industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, “some residents have weak confidence in spending, and they have many concerns”, he conceded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a bid to “stabilise big-budget consumption”, the NDRC decreed that authorities must ensure that first-time homebuyers and those who seek to improve their housing conditions are supported. It also banned local-level governments from issuing further car-purchasing restrictions that had been widely imposed in a bid to cut carbon emissions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additionally, it said the services sector will benefit from more rapid approvals of large-scale concerts and sporting events.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plan&#39;s unveiling also came after the NDRC, at an economic meeting on Sunday, said that expanding household consumption was one of the major tasks for the central government over the remainder of this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials are hoping to see big-budget expenditures recover steadily, with spending on services growing at a “relatively quick growth rate”, while private investment revives, according to an official readout of the meeting on the commission&#39;s website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July, multiple ministries jointly rolled out two separate plans to support purchases of cars, household appliances and furniture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Weak consumer confidence has been one of the top challenges for China since the onset of the pandemic. Last year, consumption accounted for 32.8 per cent of China&#39;s gross domestic product (GDP) growth, down from 54.5 per cent in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shao Yu, chief economist at Shanghai-listed Orient Securities, said spending will still be a very important part of the economy this year, but these types of government policies may not do much to boost growth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While they focus on tax cuts and coupons, the key to boosting consumption is people&#39;s job security and pay rise, he noted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What the government is offering is subtraction – offering lower prices – but what&#39;s more needed is addition – higher income,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite a robust rebound in some consumer sectors this year, the recovery in spending on long-lasting consumer durables – such as homes and vehicles – has remained sluggish, largely due to consumers&#39; weak income expectations, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“People will spend on big items only when there&#39;s more certainty about economic growth,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As China signals property revival, can &#39;risky&#39; real estate still drive growth?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the first half of the year, China&#39;s real estate investment dropped by 7.9 per cent from a year earlier, which led to a decrease in big-budget spending on related expenditures, including household appliances and furniture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the jobless rate among China&#39;s young adults aged 16-24 climbed to a record 21.3 per cent in June, continuing to raise the record from 20.8 per cent in May, according to official figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Standard Chartered also noted an uneven recovery in China&#39;s consumption of different goods and services, in its latest research note.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While spending on cheaper items such as food, clothing and transport saw a robust recovery, bigger expenditures such as rents and utilities fell further below the pre-pandemic 2017-19 trend level, “reflecting the continued slowdown in China&#39;s housing market”, the multinational bank said in a note on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overall, China&#39;s household consumption saw a strong rebound in the first six months, contributing 4.2 percentage points to its 5.5 per cent GDP growth, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is expected to continue to recover in the next half of the year, but “at a slower pace than in the first half as the post-reopening boost dwindles”, it added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan toughens penalties for sexual harassment after wave of #MeToo allegations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3229522/taiwan-toughens-penalties-sexual-harassment-after-wave-metoo-allegations?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 20:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/437156ad-9285-492b-9896-bbaef19e3b97_6c8c2607.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Taiwan has toughened penalties for sexual harassment after a wave of allegations were made against political and other high-profile figures in recent months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The maximum jail term has been increased from two to three years, while the top fine has been doubled to NT$1 million (US$32,000). Victims also have more time to file a complaint – seven years instead of three.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They are among revisions to the Sexual Harassment Prevention Act and the Gender Equality in Employment Act that were passed by the legislature in Taipei on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The amendments follow a series of #MeToo complaints since late May over sexual misconduct that implicated the government and ruling Democratic Progressive Party, as well as prominent figures beyond politics, as the island&#39;s presidential election looms in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the revised laws, immediate action – such as an investigation – must be taken by superiors, supervisors or managers of any organisation to handle harassment complaints made by colleagues and staff. Failure to do so will be subject to a fine of NT$20,000 to NT$1 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Any organisation with a staff of 10 to 29 must set up a complaint system to deal with sexual harassment allegations, as was already required for those with more than 30 employees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But complaints will not be accepted for cases dating back 10 years or more.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The legislation also bars media outlets, individuals or groups from revealing the personal data of victims. A fine of up to NT$600,000 applies for doing so.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Public support for President Tsai Ing-wen plunged to its lowest level in four years in June after her government and the DPP were caught up in the #MeToo claims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsai has apologised twice over cases of sexual misconduct and assault that were alleged to have happened while she was head of the party. One of her senior advisers was implicated in one case and a retired judge in another, though both have denied the accusations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The island&#39;s leader pledged to revise the legislation to better protect victims and toughen penalties for perpetrators.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Facing harsh criticism from his opponents, DPP presidential candidate William Lai Ching-te – who took over from Tsai as head of the party in January – also called for reform to improve party discipline and ensure that all sexual harassment allegations are handled appropriately.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vice-President Lai, who remains ahead in the polls, has also brought in gender equality training for party members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The wave of #MeToo cases emerged in late May when a former DPP staffer posted allegations on social media about a filmmaker working on a promotional project for the party. She also accused a DPP executive of covering up her complaint, leading to the resignation of that executive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sexual harassment claims have also been made against academics, television pundits, exiled mainland Chinese dissidents, former diplomats, judicial officials and celebrities.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>