<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Policeman who killed French teen says sorry to the family, as protests rage]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226008/policeman-who-killed-french-teen-says-sorry-family-protests-rage?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 07:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/c1019b91-9184-4a2b-b99b-6e26725ebfed_cb51f6ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二在巴黎郊区杀害一名法国青少年的警察引发暴力抗议劳伦特的律师表示，他在羁押期间已向全国各地的家人道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他说的第一句话是向家人道歉，最后一句话是向家人道歉。” -弗兰克·利纳德周四晚间告诉 BFMTV。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他很伤心，他早上没有起床去杀人，”利纳德说。 “他不想杀了他。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;17 岁的纳赫尔在南泰尔的一个交通堵塞中被近距离枪击，视频中的视频引发了愤怒和不满，随后法国引发了抗议活动。重新引发了有关警察策略的争论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;利纳德表示，这名警察“对这段视频的暴力行为感到非常震惊”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该警官已被指控犯有故意杀人罪，并被还押候审。利纳德表示，他将于周五对他的当事人被拘留提出上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着当局忙于遏制不断升级的危机，法国警方准备迎接第三晚的暴力示威活动。警方消息人士称，根据一份内部安全说明，未来的夜晚预计将“成为城市暴力的舞台”，“针对秩序力量和国家象征的行动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴黎郊区克拉马尔已经宣布从周四到下周一晚上 9 点至凌晨 6 点实行通宵宵禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;联合国国家谴责法国种族主义和警察暴力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我不” “不要责怪警察，我要责怪一个人：夺走我儿子生命的人，”纳赫尔的母亲穆尼亚 (Mounia) 在枪击事件发生后第一次接受媒体采访时告诉法国五频道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说负责的 38 岁警官“看到一张阿拉伯脸，一个小孩子，想结束他的生命”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国低收入和多民族郊区对治安和种族定性的长期不满是被视为助长骚乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由他的母亲领导的纳赫尔纪念游行最终以防暴警察发射催泪瓦斯结束，他居住的巴黎西部郊区南泰尔的几辆汽车被点燃，他被杀.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四动员了约 40,000 名警察试图维持和平，是周三人数的四倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三晚上，汽车、垃圾箱、学校和政府办公室被纵火焚烧巴黎周边和其他城市，全国约有 150 人被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该地区总统表示，作为恢复平静措施的一部分，巴黎公交车和有轨电车服务于周四晚上 9 点后停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙呼吁保持冷静，并表示抗议暴力“毫无道理”。这些骚乱对马克龙来说是一个新的挑战，他一直在寻求摆脱因退休年龄有争议的提高而引发的一代人中最大规模的示威活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马克龙确保了养老金方面的胜利，但法国的忧郁情绪加深&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;纳赫尔在逃离因交通违规而试图阻止他的警察时被杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经法新社证实的一段视频显示，两名警察站在旁边静止的汽车上，有人用武器指着司机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;听到一个声音说：“你的头将会中弹。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警察然后汽车突然开走，似乎开始点火。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;里尔当局周四加强了旨在防止新暴力事件的措施，包括禁止集会和部署无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理伊丽莎白·博尔恩 (Elisabeth Borne) 在巴黎北部一座市长办公室被纵火的小镇发表讲话时表示，“显然，所有事态升级都必须避免”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府迫切希望避免 2005 年城市骚乱重演。事件的起因是两名非洲裔男孩在一次警察追捕中死亡，期间有 6,000 人被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这里有可能再次发生爆炸的所有因素，”一位不愿透露姓名的政府顾问表示。周三。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;四名警察因在法国殴打黑人而受到指控&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;右翼共和党领袖埃里克·西奥蒂呼吁进入紧急状态，允许地方当局设立禁区，但政府消息人士告诉法新社，目前尚未考虑这一选项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们越来越担心警察使用武器阻止拒绝停车接受交通检查的司机。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，有 13 人因拒绝停车接受警察交通检查而被杀，2017 年的一项法律修改赋予警察更大的权力使用目前正在接受审查的武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我在这段视频中看到的是 2023 年法国警察在光天化日之下处决了一名 17 岁的孩子。”绿党领袖马琳·汤德利尔 (Marine Tondelier) 说道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong bourse operator to cooperate with Beijing Stock Exchange, Ningbo government to attract more start-up listings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3225991/hong-kong-bourse-operator-cooperate-beijing-stock-exchange-ningbo-government-attract-more-start?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/2ac0c017-7138-4f30-b26a-f2d173b828a3_18e18d6e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;运营亚洲第三大股票市场的香港交易及结算所已签署协议该交易所运营商周四表示，该交易所本周将与北京证券交易所和宁波市政府合作，探讨如何让初创企业和优质公司更容易在这里上市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为备忘录的一部分根据与北京证券交易所签署的谅解备忘录（MOU），两所将鼓励企业申请在对方市场上市，并在推广、投资者教育、研究和人员交流等方面开展合作。香港交易所近年来已与上海和深圳的交易所签署了类似的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港交易所联席首席运营官、前上市部主管陈宝仪与北京证券交易所（BSE）副代表签署了谅解备忘录首席执行官李永春周四在中国首都。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们支持发行人在北京和香港市场上市，凸显了孟交所致力于深化改革和进一步开放市场，满足市场需求。 BSE 首席执行官隋强在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这将使更多公司在扩大规模和国际化形象时利用这两个市场。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;隋补充道，两所交易所之间的合作将有助于“北京成为国际科技创新中心，并加强香港作为国际金融中心的地位”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港交易所总裁尼古拉斯·阿古津表示，该协议“为“这是两个交易所之间长期、加强合作的方式”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们期待与 BSE 一起为该地区的企业和投资者提供支持，将资本与创意相结合，推动实现共享、长期的合作。” ”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国家主席习近平于 2021 年 9 月宣布设立北京证券交易所的计划，两个月后，81 只股票在第三个内地交易所开始交易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据其网站数据，孟交所目前有 203 家上市公司，总市值为 2639.3 亿元人民币（364.3 亿美元），周四成交额为 23.8 亿元人民币。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;规模远小于香港交易所，香港交易所拥有超过 2,600 家上市公司，价值 34.12 万亿港元（4.37 万亿美元），总成交额为 820 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，香港交易所与宁波市政府签署了谅解备忘录周一，中国东部浙江省的主要港口和工业中心，探讨如何支持有兴趣在香港上市的当地公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们将联合举办研讨会，介绍当地的情况资本市场向宁波企业倾斜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宁波拥有10,000多家制造企业，生产从新材料到智能家电等各种产品。近年来，香港加快发展数字化、高端装备等新经济产业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港过去14年七次成为全球最大IPO市场今年的表现举步维艰，第一季度排名跌至第七位。根据路孚特 (Refinitiv) 的数据，2023 年前三个月，该国仅举办了 17 起 IPO，筹资 8.37 亿美元，这是自 2009 年全球金融危机期间以来最糟糕的第一季度表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“谅解备忘录和其他促销活动香港交易所的努力应该有助于鼓励更多内地初创企业来港上市筹集资金，”香港证券及投资学会董事徐联安表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多内地公司可能大家对香港市场不太熟悉，而港交所也面临上海科创板和深圳创业板的竞争，以吸引科技初创企业筹集资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“港交所加大宣传力度香港交易所将有助于改善今年低迷的IPO市场。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US weapon to jam Chinese and Russian satellites is running two years late]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226007/us-weapon-jam-chinese-and-russian-satellites-running-two-years-late?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 07:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/a1e6bdc7-17e2-4948-b62d-3ff9976bcc0e_cb824b93.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一种美国便携式武器，可在冲突初期暂时干扰中国和俄罗斯的通信卫星首次交付晚了两年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;L3Harris Technologies Inc. 生产的潜在 30 个 Meadowlands 系统中的第一个原定于 2022 年交付，但现在预计于 2024 年 10 月交付。美国太空军官员。太空系统司令部在一份声明中表示，测试期间遇到的问题“已经解决，该计划正在进入最后的集成和测试阶段”。该公司表示，“技术问题是由于意想不到的挑战造成的，需要对子组件进行复杂的返工”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;L3Harris 太空优势总经理查尔斯·克拉克森 (Charles Clarkson) 表示，该公司与该司令部合作，增加了测试，以确保干扰器能够正常工作。 “将拥有更强大的运营执行力并降低风险”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅多兰兹计划延迟的披露让我们得以难得一睹美国针对中国和俄罗斯卫星的“反太空”能力的高度机密世界。&lt;/p>;&lt;美国军方官员一直不愿讨论这些能力，尽管他们详细介绍了中国和俄罗斯的一系列进攻性地面和天基能力，他们称这些能力将在天体战斗中针对美国卫星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去关于这些能力的争论太空部队作战主任戴维·米勒少将本周在空军协会研讨会上表示，太空是否“是一个作战领域”“美国国会在创建太空部队时就已经给出了答案”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我们必须着手提供发现、修复和阻止任何对手发现和瞄准美国军队或盟军能力的能力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国称美国间谍卫星靠近其太空资产是“国家情报总监办公室在今年的年度威胁评估中表示，中国拥有旨在瞄准美国及其盟国卫星的武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新的干扰系统官员们表示，不会产生空间碎片，因为它释放的能量旨在对通信卫星造成暂时的“可逆”干扰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meadowlands 计划估计耗资 2.19 亿美元，是一个轻型版本的庞大的“反通信系统”于 2020 年初宣布投入运行。Meadowlands 的雷达天线安装在轮式拖车上，有两个设备架，而不是早期系统上的 14 个设备架，因此更易于部署。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;空军协会高级常驻研究员查尔斯·加尔布雷思 (Charles Galbreath) 表示，“梅多兰兹的占地面积减少和容量增加将显着提高其对反通信系统的效用”，他刚刚完成了一项由空军协会赞助的反太空研究。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;中国为 Meadlowlands 提供了多个潜在目标，该卫星计划在海外进行运输和部署。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国拥有 700 多颗卫星，“其中约一半用于遥感”以及情报、监视和侦察”，太空军负责情报太空作战的副局长格雷戈里·加格农少将在三月份的空军协会研讨会上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们的在轨卫星舰队可以跟踪我们，可以感知我们，可以看到我们，可以将这些数据连接到他们的火力网络，现在可以以我们从未理解或迄今为止必须面对的方式使美军处于危险之中，”加格农说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ex-Florida deputy Scot Peterson acquitted of failing to protect students in Parkland school shooting]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226005/ex-florida-deputy-scot-peterson-acquitted-failing-protect-students-parkland-school-shooting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 04:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/805298a1-e135-42f9-be2e-569c72fa50d6_070a3d86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周四，佛罗里达州陪审团宣判一名前副警长无罪，该副警长被指控未能保护学生2018 年帕克兰马乔里·斯通曼·道格拉斯高中发生大规模枪击事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年 2 月 14 日，一名枪手进入一栋大楼并开枪，导致 17 人死亡、另外 17 人受伤，当时值班的学校资源官员斯科特·彼得森 (Scott Peterson) ，被指控犯有 11 项忽视儿童、过失和伪证罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;60 岁的彼得森将头靠在面前的桌子上，当法官大声宣读“无罪”时，他如释重负地抽泣起来。 ”对每项罪名的判决。陪审团的裁决使他免于被判处 97 年徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;裁决后，彼得森在法院告诉记者，他想与在这场事故中丧生的学生的家长交谈。射击。 “如果他们需要真正了解所发生事件的真相……我会在他们身边，”他强忍着泪水说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提起此案的布劳沃德州检察官办公室在一份声明中表示，重申了其论点，即彼得森本可以采取更多措施来保护学校社区的成员，并且他的不作为对受害者“产生了可怕的影响”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“检察官在我们国家历史上第一次声明称，“在这起案件中，我们试图追究一名武装学校资源官员的不履行职责的责任。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些参加审判的受害者家长也对结果感到失望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我只能对陪审团成员说的是，我认为你们的学校应该雇用他来保护你们的孩子，”托尼·蒙塔尔托说，他的女儿吉娜是枪击事件中遇难的学生之一。蒙塔尔托拒绝了彼得森的谈话提议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国校园枪击案凶手想要毁掉情人节：“没有人会爱我”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;彼得森携带武器，但在枪击发生时从未进去过，根据布劳沃德县警长办公室和监控视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他是少数因未能采取行动或提供护理而被起诉的执法人员之一。这起极其不寻常的案件的结果可能会开创一个法律先例，并促使全国各地的检察官在发生其他枪击事件后不要对类似官员提出疏忽指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彼得森没有在持续两年半的审判中作证。十月，陪审团免除了帕克兰枪击事件中的枪手尼古拉斯·克鲁兹的死刑，而是要求判处终身监禁，不得假释。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五月，美国纪念近十年来美国最严重的校园枪击事件一周年，德克萨斯州尤瓦尔迪市的一名枪手造成 19 名儿童和两名教师死亡，另有 17 人受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方等待更多时间在此案中，他花了不到一个小时进入学校并与枪手对峙，引发了广泛的批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德克萨斯州公共安全部的一份报告发现，一名尤瓦尔迪警察本可以在枪手进入学校之前开枪射击他，但他犹豫了在等待主管的许可期间。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In India, women-led start-ups face gender hurdle when seeking funding]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3225999/india-women-led-start-ups-face-gender-hurdle-when-seeking-funding?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/086c6c69-7b83-41b3-b00f-e2d007c8bf25_122a65c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当印度女商人 Aditi Bhutia Madan 回忆起在大吉岭的童年时，她想起了松树林，喜马拉雅日出和她祖母的妈妈——美味的饺子激发了她创办自己的公司的灵感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为前印度厨艺大师参赛者，Madan 对自己的烹饪技巧充满信心，但她不知道如何获得正式的认可融资来发展她的 Yangkiez By MomoMami 品牌——这是印度许多女性企业家面临的主要障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，Madan 一直面临着高利贷者的挑战，要求过高的利率或要求获得她企业的股份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“面临很多挑战……首先，因为你是一名女性，”她告诉汤森路透基金会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当 40 多岁的 Madan与数千名女性企业家一起参加 NSRCEL 的女性创业计划 (WSP)，NSRCEL 是印度班加罗尔管理学院的一个企业孵化器，该计划为参与者提供商业技能培训，包括融资的艺术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;之后在真人秀《Shark Tank India》中首次亮相时，她从投资者那里获得了 750 万印度卢比（91,000 美元），用于公司生产部门的能力建设和基础设施开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我什么都不知道她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在万事达卡女企业家指数（该指数衡量女性在全球商界的发展情况）的 65 个国家中，印度排名第 57 位，而该国只有五分之一的女性企业家根据政府数据，企业由女性领导。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;获得资本的机会不平等是一个主要障碍。当女性企业家确实向潜在投资者寻求融资时，她们更有可能被拒绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们仍然发现很难让（女性）做好投资准备，”WSP 的 Ankita Pegu 说道，已帮助超过 400 家女性主导的初创企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“一线希望”：亚洲女性从疫情推动的在线支付增长中获利&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;女性主导的企业面临着未得到满足的挑战根据世界银行私营部门国际金融公司 (IFC) 的数据，信贷缺口超过 114 亿美元，女性企业家仅获得印度公共部门银行向企业提供的未偿信贷的 5.2%。许多印度小企业要么自筹资金，要么靠家庭支持融资——这两种方式对于女性企业家来说都更加困难。贝恩公司和谷歌的一项调查显示，43% 的女性表示她们的家庭和配偶不支持她们的事业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是许多女性面临的第一个障碍，她们的家庭不愿意支持她们总部位于班加罗尔的非营利性女性创业促进组织创始人 Sucharita Eashwar 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;大部分融资缺口源于普遍存在的性别歧视和持续的保守思想。女性在 13 亿人口的国家中扮演的角色。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Preksha Kaparwan，33 岁，自学了设计、编码和网站开发，后来与他人共同创立了人工智能数据分析初创公司——位于德里的 AlphaaAI。 2019 年和 2022 年总部位于旧金山的 Super AI。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即便如此，她表示，在推介会议上，投资者对她的待遇与男性同行有所不同。有些人根本没有问她任何问题，而另一些人则转而谈论天气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为投资者，你必须对面前的性别保持中立，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为投资者，你必须对面前的性别保持中立。” p>;&lt;h3>;亚洲最大的薪酬差距：为什么印度女性的价值如此被低估？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Jibin Mathew 表示，潜在投资者在做出融资决定之前更有可能考虑女性的年龄和婚姻状况， WSP 的助理经理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“（他们认为）也许再过两年她就会结婚，投资者认为这可能会损害他们的投资。如果她结婚了，那么就会有关于家庭的问题，”马修说。 “男性企业家从来没有被问过这些问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国的研究表明，投资者更有可能向男性提出与他们的抱负和成就相关的“晋升”问题，这往往会产生积极的回应 - 并且&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《管理学会杂志》2018 年发表的一项研究发现，女性更常被问到有关安全、损失和潜在风险的“预防”问题，这些问题阻碍了“企业家筹集资金的能力”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2021 年，印度风险投资资金中只有 0.3% 流向了女性领导的初创企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;急于解决这种不平衡问题，企业家转型- 投资者阿尼莎·辛格 (Anisha Singh) 五年前设立了 She Capital 基金，旨在帮助女性企业创始人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在列出她的基金的成功案例时，她表示没想到会发现“为女性、为女性提供支持”创始人太难了”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究发现，由女性创立和共同创立的初创企业能产生更多收入并创造更多就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，银行也犹豫不决。总部位于德里的非盈利组织 Dhriiti 的执行董事 Nidhi Gupta 表示，他们资助女性企业家，并对她们的成功表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;正在酝酿的变革：印度采茶工人转向美容来抵御诱惑性贩运者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;有时，参与项目的女性在申请贷款时会被银行工作人员要求提供男性亲属的签名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;超过 85% 的女性企业家面临着根据非营利组织 Bharatiya Yuva Shakti Trust (BYST) 2022 年的一项调查，该机构在利用公共部门银行的贷款服务方面面临挑战。该计划旨在为贫困社区的企业家提供指导。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管印度政府提供财政支持非营利组织“促进妇女和女童经济发展倡议”(IWAAGE) 的一项研究显示，在针对女性主导企业的计划中，只有 3.4% 的女企业家从中受益。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;面对这些实际问题，Pegu 表示，对于女性企业创始人来说，这可能是“一段孤独的旅程”。她补充说，WSP 等项目可以提供以女性为中心的社区意识，以对抗男性主导的世界。专家表示，与专业社区和网络的联系不畅会导致资金来源和市场信息方面的信息空白。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;培训——例如良好推销艺术的培训辛格表示，对于投资者来说，这也是帮助女性充分发挥潜力的关键。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我知道你了解自己的业务，”她说。 “（那么）你为什么要把它交给其他人来谈论它？”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Three people stabbed in ‘hate-motivated’ attack during gender class in Canada]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226006/three-people-stabbed-hate-motivated-attack-during-gender-class-canada?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 05:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/46445416-7793-45eb-acdf-843db109f74a_044420d6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名嫌疑人被指控在课堂上刺伤一名教授和两名学生加拿大滑铁卢大学关于性别问题的袭击，警方称之为出于仇恨动机的袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;滑铁卢地区警方称，曾在滑铁卢大学学习的国际学生乔瓦尼·维拉巴-阿莱曼 (Geovanny Villalba-Aleman) 面临三起袭击严重袭击罪、四项持武器袭击罪和两项出于危险目的持有武器罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;滑铁卢警察局长马克·克罗威尔 (Mark Crowell) 表示，接受警方讯问的嫌疑人想要做出关于性别认同的“声明”，并在攻击前要求教授核实该课程是关于性别研究的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名38岁的女教授，一名20岁的学生一名女学生和一名 19 岁男学生伤势严重，但没有生命危险，被送往医院。当时班上大约有 40 名学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些学生试图阻止袭击，包括向嫌疑人扔椅子，而其他学生则逃离了房间。克罗威尔说，嫌疑人最初伪装成受害者，然后警方确认了他的身份并逮捕了他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克罗威尔说，当局发现针对 LGBTQ 群体的仇恨事件有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “这是我们看到的一个令人不安的趋势，尤其是在骄傲月期间，”克罗威尔说。 “我想我们都知道现在社会存在两极分化。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名没有犯罪记录的嫌疑人于周四出庭参加保释听证会。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;反 LGBTQ 的强烈反对扰乱了美国的骄傲活动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;滑铁卢大学传播副校长尼克·曼宁 (Nick Manning) 表示，嫌疑人于 2022 年秋季学期结束时从该大学毕业。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;曼宁表示，刺伤事件发生在哲学 202 课程中，根据大学网站，该课程的重点是“性别问题”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该课程的网站描述称，“将检查该课程的结构”。通过当代讨论探讨哲学史上的性别。什么是性别？我们如何“做”性别？我们怎样才能“消除”性别——我们想这么做吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们整个社区都非常担心这种情况会在这里发生。这是一个很大的震惊。”曼宁说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该大学的学生优素福·凯马克 (Yusuf Kaymak) 告诉 CTV 新闻，他当时在课堂上，大约有 40 名学生。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“那家伙基本上走进去问老师他是不是教授，他说‘是’，然后他拿出一把刀，之后，每个人都跑了出去，”凯马克说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些学生质疑为什么他们花了几个小时才收到有关所发生事件的紧急警报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究生 Mara Crassweller 表示，她花了大约三个小时才收到学校发来的紧急警报。刺伤。 23 岁的会计专业学生布丽安娜·伊根 (Brianna Egan) 表示，她的课程与性别研究讲座位于同一栋楼，在周三刺伤事件发生前几分钟就放假了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“说实话，这有点可怕，尤其是大学花了多长时间才做出回应，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在骄傲月期间，亚洲穆斯林占多数的国家中的 LGBTQ 群体‘理所当然地偏执’&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;大学副教授詹姆斯·拉什 (James Rush)总统承认，尽管周三早些时候进行了测试，但警报系统“没有像我们通常预期的那样迅速启动”。拉什说：“这是一次非常不幸的延误。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉什发誓要对所发生的事情保持透明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学生们预计将聚集在大学的艺术广场默哀片刻。周四下午晚些时候。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理贾斯汀·特鲁多在一份书面声明中称刺伤事件“令人震惊且不可接受”。 “这种类型的暴力必须始终受到谴责。我们的心与受伤的教授和两名学生在一起。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China becoming world’s go-to for shipbuilding after ‘boom of overseas orders’, but global de-risking threatens to rock the boat]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3225973/china-becoming-worlds-go-shipbuilding-after-boom-overseas-orders-global-de-risking-threatens-rock?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 04:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/a3537051-d90e-42bb-94ce-f98b4d215a27_b9659c54.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着中国加大力度在全球造船业占据更多市场份额，一些在充满政治色彩的去风险之际，西方国家准备退出，以避免过度依赖中国制造业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国船舶工业集团公司在 2019 年合并后成为世界上最大的造船企业，而官方的新华社上周表示，该船厂今年“海外订单激增”，生产计划计划到 2027 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年，中国占全球造船厂的 48%根据海运业专业服务公司劳氏船级社的数据，2022年中国造船产量、新接订单和手头订单量，韩国为25%，日本为15%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分别占全球市场份额的 47.3%、55.2% 和 49%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国汽车工业协会的数据，这些数字使中国领先于竞争对手韩国和日本。国家造船工业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国成为世界主要造船中心可能会导致其他国家考虑用它来满足其他造船厂已经满负荷生产的订单的迫切需求，”总部位于华盛顿的美国韩国经济研究所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据英国船舶经纪公司 BRS Group 的数据，全球造船厂数量从 2007 年的约 700 家减少到 2022 年的约 300 家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;你需要知道的是：中国第一艘国产大型邮轮的时间表&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;BRS发现，全球75%的造船能力属于九大造船集团，而中国的68%的能力仅属于9家造船集团。三。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，德国对中国不断增长的市场份额表示警惕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在去年 5 月的一份声明中，德国造船和海洋工业协会敦促其政府与其欧洲邻国 - 进行“航运政策的根本性改变”，以便该行业能够更好地与中国和韩国的造船商竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明称，这两个亚洲国家的政府为该行业提供了大力支持.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果造船政策没有根本性改变，欧洲将失去在未来10年建造任何大规模远洋商船的能力，”该协会表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如今，欧洲航运业（尤其是德国航运业）已经高度依赖中国的供应。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国政府表示，计划使用 40 亿英镑（50 亿美元）来支撑其航运业。拥有自己的造船业并防止进一步失业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美中贸易战已经引发西方盟国更广泛的努力摆脱中国作为制造基地的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; Why is China&#39;s first home-grown large cruise liner a breakthrough?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Manufacturing prowess cannot be turned on like a light switch,” said Stephen Olson, a senior research fellow at the Hinrich Foundation and a former trade negotiator with the Office of the US Trade Representative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Once production moves out, it is not just the factories, machinery, and equipment that is lost. Human capital, in the form of a skilled and experienced workforce, is also lost.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In many instances, it is quicker and easier to build a new factory than it is to build a skilled workforce.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Where possible, foreign contractors will consider steering away from China, Ramage added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Uncertainty caused by sudden sanctions exposure and navigating Byzantine government regulations will cause many countries looking to fill long-term contract orders with Chinese shipbuilders to consider de-risking before becoming too dependent on China,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, South Korea and Japan are the dominant players in ship construction, but countries in Europe, North America and elsewhere will likely have their own strategies over time to sustain their domestic industries, said Park Sung-gu, the Seoul-based president for North East Asia with Lloyd&#39;s Register.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And Western shippers looking for new vessels are likely to avoid China as part of the wider global trend of industrial decoupling, said Guilherme Campos, an international business advisory manager in Dezan Shira &amp; Associates&#39; Shenzhen office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Given the recent trends on doing business with Chinese companies and the fact that lots of Western companies are black listing companies simply because they are Chinese, then it&#39;s predictable that foreign companies will try somewhere else,” Campos said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday at the World Economic Forum in Tianjin, Chinese Premier Li Qiang blamed “the West” for calls on “de-risking”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea is well placed to support world demand for environmentally friendly ships as operators chase decarbonisation goals, Park said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its shipbuilders lost money in both 2021 and 2022, while Hanwha Group merged with the loss-making Daewoo Shipbuilding &amp; Marine Engineering in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For Korean shipbuilding, the key challenge is to differentiate its offering,” Park said, who added shipbuilding costs are less in China primarily due to lower labour costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea is seen as better equipped to build technologically advanced ships for a range of uses, such as passenger cruise liners and vessels for liquid natural gas transport.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China only launched its first home-grown large cruise liner earlier this month, with the 135,500-tonne Adora Magic City the last type of high-end ship that the country had yet to produce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But top South Korean shipbuilders, such as Samsung Heavy Industries, are still reporting losses despite a pickup in orders, according to an annual review for 2023 by BRS Group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China CSSC Holdings, the Shanghai-listed subsidiary of the China State Shipbuilding Corporation, reported an operating income of 59.558 billion yuan (US$8.2 billion) in 2022, representing a year-on-year decrease of 0.31 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its net profit attributable to the parent company stood at 172 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 19.62 per cent, while its loss increased by 214.59 per cent, year on year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Shipbuilding is not an industry that makes money,” BRS Group said in its report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The industry has been trying to develop various strategies to counter low prices, and one of the main findings has been to reduce global shipbuilding capacity via yard closures and consolidations.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 04:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU seeks to project united approach towards China ahead of high-level Brussels meetings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3225892/eu-seeks-project-united-approach-towards-china-ahead-high-level-brussels-meetings?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 04:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/4e40784d-5ef3-472e-a9af-3169b99aae18_0f571dbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Brussels is eager to project a united EU approach in its China policies despite some divergent positions among members, as the 27-nation bloc&#39;s leaders gather in the Belgian capital for a two-day summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a letter to EU leaders ahead of the high-level meetings, EU Council President Charles Michel said discussions on China – expected to be held on Friday – would give an opportunity to “reconfirm” the bloc&#39;s “broad and united stance” towards the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;European Union leaders were expected to assert that “engagements with China will continue on global challenges”, according to a leaked EU draft of conclusions seen by the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bloc would “de-risk and diversify where necessary and appropriate, in order to achieve a balanced, reciprocal and mutually beneficial economic relationship” with Beijing, the statement read.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The European Union does not intend to decouple or to turn inwards,” it added. “Its policies are not designed to harm China nor to thwart China&#39;s economic progress and development.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, divisions persist within the bloc over how to deal with China owing to each nation&#39;s varying national interests concerning de-risking and national security, according to some senior EU diplomats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week, EU chief Ursula von der Leyen unveiled a road map for de-risking economic ties with China. But diplomats from France, Germany, Italy and the Netherlands were among those expressing concern about “national security” and seeking a watering down of the plan&#39;s conditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While there is broad support for reducing Europe&#39;s dependencies on China and finding alternative suppliers for critical goods, some have voiced concern that the European Commission is moving too quickly and too expansively.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hungarian foreign minister takes aim at EU&#39;s China &#39;de-risking&#39; strategy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;During a meeting with Chinese Premier Li Qiang in Berlin, German Chancellor Olaf Scholz said Berlin did not plan to decouple from Beijing as it sought to maintain trade relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French President Emmanuel Macron expressed a similar sentiment when he met Li in Paris last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, Fu Cong, the Chinese envoy to the EU, stressed that “de-risking should not become decoupling in another name”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu described recent developments in the EU involving Huawei Technologies and ZTE as “concerning”, referring to the European Commission&#39;s recent proposal to ban Huawei and ZTE from 5G networks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no evidence that they are harming cybersecurity, and in our view, these baseless accusations go against the spirit of fair play and fair competition,” Fu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, EU foreign policy chief Josep Borrell said de-risking was not without its own risks and that it was important for EU nations to debate the subject further.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In remarks to the EU Institute for Security Studies in Paris on Wednesday, Borrell said the EU&#39;s attempt to cut energy imports from Russia had led to the bloc depending on renewables.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But this effort had increased the bloc&#39;s exposure to China, he said, which controls 80 to 90 per cent of the refining and end-products needed to transition to green energy practices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So, it is not always easy to say objectively where de-risking ends and decoupling begins,” Borrell said, adding that Europe needed “a real debate” on the matter. He added that although EU institutions could propose measures “it is member states that decide”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;It&#39;s &#39;complicated&#39;: EU de-risking push casts shadow over Chinese premier&#39;s trip&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Aside from economic security for some EU nations, “Beijing&#39;s position on Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine is the key order of the day, leading to differences over dealing with China”, according to Grzegorz Stec, analyst at the Mercator Institute for China Studies, a think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These differences in priorities at times lead to frictions,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s decision not to formally condemn Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine has proved another sore point in its fraught relations with the EU.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing, which downplayed an attempted uprising against Russian military leaders by the Wagner paramilitary group over the weekend, has deepened wariness about China&#39;s alliance with Moscow among certain nations in the bloc, according to some EU officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As Russia&#39;s friendly neighbour and comprehensive strategic partner of coordination for the new era, China supports Russia in maintaining national stability and achieving development and prosperity,” the Chinese foreign ministry said in a statement after the Wagner revolt.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Baltic nations and Poland have expressed frustration with China over its close ties to Russia and have pushed for the EU to adopt a harsher tone towards Beijing as a result.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s actions in the Taiwan Strait have also proved divisive in the EU, with nations like Lithuania, which has diplomatic relations with Taipei, advocating a stronger stance against the Asian giant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron, who was criticised for his comments during a trip to China in April when he said the EU should not be drawn into the Taiwan crisis, told CNN over the weekend that he was “dead against Chinese aggression on Taiwan”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EU leaders are expected to state that the bloc “is concerned about growing tensions in the Taiwan Strait”, according to the draft statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The European Council opposes any unilateral attempts to change the status quo by force or coercion. It reconfirms the EU&#39;s consistent &#39;one-China policy&#39;,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;European Union chief cautions Beijing against taking Taiwan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The draft statement also highlighted the EU&#39;s concerns regarding forced labour and the treatment of human rights defenders and members of ethnic minorities in China&#39;s autonomous regions of Tibet and Xinjiang. It welcomed the EU-China human rights dialogue that the bloc resumed in February after a round of tit-for-tat sanctions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Human rights organisations have previously slammed the dialogue as “meaningless”. A dozen groups have written a joint letter to EU leaders ahead of the Brussels gathering to call for the bloc and its member states to “proactively mainstream efforts on human rights in China across all EU-China relations”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The letter urges the EU to pursue “a concerted, strategic approach to challenge Chinese government policies, practices and narratives that undermine human rights”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 04:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India and Philippines vow stronger cooperation as both eye China’s regional claims with unease]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3226004/india-and-philippines-vow-stronger-cooperation-both-eye-chinas-regional-claims-unease?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 03:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/5d9b5d90-3c0c-40cc-8307-3c5a3ab0c0f9_50ba8fa2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The foreign ministers of India and the Philippines pledged on Thursday to bolster bilateral cooperation as they took up common cause against China&#39;s long-running territorial claims in the South China Sea, asserting shared interest in a “free, open and inclusive” Indo-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A message of solidarity emerged from the meeting in New Delhi, as India joined the Philippines in calling for adherence to international law, namely the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea as well as a 2016 international arbitration ruling in Manila&#39;s favour and against Beijing&#39;s claims of large swathes of the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A joint statement issued after Indian Foreign Minister Subrahmanyam Jaishankar and Philippine Foreign Minister Enrique Manalo co-chaired the fifth instalment of the India-Philippines Joint Commission on Bilateral Cooperation said the two diplomats held a “wide-ranging and substantive” discussion on regional and international issues of mutual concern, underlining the need for the “peaceful settlement of disputes”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The UN Convention on the Law of the Sea, an international agreement first adopted in 1982, lays out rules governing all uses of the oceans and their resources, including freedom of navigation. With 169 parties, UNCLOS prescribes a 200-nautical-mile exclusive economic zone from the continental coast of a sovereign state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China and the Philippines have long accused each other of violating UNCLOS, with several other countries in the region also opposing Beijing based on their own territorial claims. China, India and the Philippines are all parties to the treaty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s claims in the South China Sea centre on a nine-dash line surrounding several islands and waters of disputed sovereignty. The 2016 ruling in the Hague case rejected the legality of the nine-dash line. Beijing refused to accept the non-binding verdict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For years India maintained a neutral stance on the issue. However, after deadly clashes along its own disputed border with China in 2020, it called the South China Sea a “part of global commons”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Manalo on Wednesday described the Philippines&#39;s territorial disputes with China as a “major challenge” in its ties with the Asian giant. But he added that the “differences we have with China are not the sum total of our relationship”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Philippines could be &#39;graveyard&#39; if US-China rivalry gets out of hand: Duterte&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Speaking at an event organised by the Indian Council of World Affairs, a New Delhi-based think tank, Manalo said negotiations among the claimants to establish a code of conduct for the South China Sea had been under way over the past four to five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We may not be seeing light at the end of the tunnel, but we see the tunnel and that&#39;s where we are,” said Manalo of the effort.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, Jaishankar and Manalo pledged to continue working together in matters of defence. Manila said it would consider New Delhi&#39;s offer of a concessional line of credit to meet its “defence requirements, acquisition of naval assets, and expansion of training and joint exercises on maritime security and disaster response”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, the two agreed to place an Indian defence attaché in Manila.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;No question about that&#39;: mutual China challenges discussed in Biden-Modi talks&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The show of unity followed vows of cooperation uttered by Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and US President Joe Biden during their bilateral talks last week in Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A joint statement from the White House said the two leaders “emphasised the importance of adherence to international law”, particularly as reflected in UNCLOS and the maintenance of freedom of navigation and overflight, including in the East and South China seas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A mutual defence treaty ally of Washington, Manila in April announced it would allow the US army to gain access to four new bases on its territory. This took the total number of US military bases there to nine. Beijing responded by warning that a larger American military presence in the Philippines was “endangering regional peace”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the US does not have any territorial claims in the region, it asserts the right to innocent passage under its own freedom of navigation. Beijing has said Washington&#39;s actions involving military ships and aircraft violate international law. The US is not a signatory to UNCLOS.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can downtown San Francisco emerge from its slump before the Apec summit?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3225809/can-downtown-san-francisco-emerge-its-slump-apec-summit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/b79d4cb8-5b89-4d0c-a3af-4175409db63d_c1837555.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As someone with many close friends in the United States, particularly in the state of California, I am saddened by recent media reports of the deterioration of San Francisco&#39;s once-prestigious downtown district. I have a personal interest in the area and have maintained a home there for many years. Before pursuing my career in Hong Kong, I completed university in Los Angeles county and before that I attended high school in Pennsylvania. I have also remained closely involved with my alma mater.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It seems the problems in downtown San Francisco were exacerbated by factors that combined to create a perfect storm. The catalyst was the Covid-19 pandemic. Lockdowns, social-distancing measures and work-from-home policies kept people away, forcing many businesses to close or dramatically reduce their operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the pandemic, many people did not return. Instead, they chose to continue to work from home for lifestyle reasons and convenience. This was particularly true of those in the tech sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Their sustained absence from the area has hindered its recovery and fuelled an escalation in office and retail vacancies, while poor transport infrastructure has resulted in serious traffic congestion, as residents opt to use their cars rather than take public transport, making the area even more unpleasant. A sluggish tourist market has also compounded the problems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The impact on the area&#39;s hotels, restaurants and other businesses that rely on pedestrian traffic and tourism has been immense. The recent announcement by Park Hotels and Resorts that it has stopped making mortgage repayments on its Hilton San Francisco Union Square and Parc 55 San Francisco – in effect pulling out of the two hotels – is a major blow and a reflection of a lack of confidence in the tourism sector. Combined, the properties account for almost 3,000 rooms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By contrast, we have been fortunate in Hong Kong. People were keen to return to their offices and normal social interaction, and we are experiencing a revival in tourism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Homelessness has long been a major factor underpinning the urban decay in downtown San Francisco; the city has one of the highest homeless rates in the country. Downtown San Francisco is the epicentre and the sight of people sleeping rough or living in makeshift structures is, sadly, far too common. Drug abuse is often visible and residents simply do not leave any items inside their cars for fear of theft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many people believe the introduction of Proposition 47, also known as the Safe Neighbourhoods and Schools Act and passed by referendum in 2014, paved the way for an increase in petty and organised crime. Certain felony offences were recategorised as misdemeanours, which were less severely punished.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The divide between the haves and have-nots appears to be increasing and high crime rates have propelled an exodus of commercial and retail tenants, along with major shopping centre operator Westfield, exacerbating the urban decay. Many retailers are citing local conditions and employee safety as primary reasons for closure after a spate of attacks on staff by shoplifters, and decreasing footfall. It is widely believed that many smaller tenants are waiting for their leases to expire and are unlikely to renew. The neighbourhood seems set to continue on its downward spiral.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But we must not lose sight of the fact that San Francisco has a history of reinventing itself, and economic recovery is under way in most parts of the city. Mayor London Breed has acknowledged downtown&#39;s challenges. Earlier this year, she outlined her five priorities to redefine, reimagine and revitalise the area: to provide an economically diverse and resilient job engine, a welcoming, clean and safe environment, a dynamic destination active at all hours, every day, a world-class transport experience, and an equitable economy that supports full participation by all.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Time will tell if the mayor can deliver on her priorities, with adequate funding and appropriate policies for the revival of this once-great district. It will be in the global media spotlight in November during the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (Apec) summit, which leaders, including from China, are expected to attend at a venue within a short walk of the area. Hopefully, there will be early and visible signs of progress that breathe new life and energy into the district before then, so it can once more make a meaningful contribution to the lives of San Franciscans and tourists alike.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google to remove news links in Canada over law on paying publishers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226003/google-remove-news-links-canada-over-law-paying-publishers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 02:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/c4c12ebf-9fee-4b78-bc27-95e4ca43d76f_63444411.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Google will remove links to Canadian news from search results and other products in Canada when a law requiring internet giants to pay news publishers comes into effect, the Alphabet-owned company said on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Google joins Facebook owner Meta Platforms in announcing an end to news access for Canadian users of their platforms after Bill C-18, or the Online News Act, was passed into law last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The law is expected to come into effect in six months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heritage Minister Pablo Rodriguez, who introduced the bill last year, has said platforms do not have any obligations under the act immediately and that the government was open to consulting them on the regulatory and implementation process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Canada&#39;s media industry has called for tighter regulation of tech companies to prevent them from elbowing news businesses out of the online advertising market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have now informed the government that when the law takes effect, we unfortunately will have to remove links to Canadian news from our Search, News and Discover products in Canada,” Google said in a blog post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We don&#39;t take this decision or its impacts lightly and believe it&#39;s important to be transparent with Canadian publishers and our users as early as possible,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The act outlines rules to force platforms such as Facebook and Google to negotiate commercial deals and pay news publishers for their content, a step similar to a groundbreaking law passed in Australia in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;EU orders Google break up digital ad business for &#39;abusing dominant position&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US technology companies have said the proposals are unsustainable for their businesses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Google has argued Canada&#39;s law is broader than those in Australia and Europe, saying it puts a price on news story links displayed in search results and can apply to outlets that do not produce news.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The search engine giant had proposed that the bill be revised to make the displaying of news content, rather than links, as basis for payment and to specify that only businesses that produce news and adhere to journalistic standards are eligible.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>