<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong national security law: UK foreign minister says Jimmy Lai case raised with China’s vice-president earlier this month]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3221848/hong-kong-national-security-law-uk-foreign-minister-says-jimmy-lai-case-raised-chinas-vice-president?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 21:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/1e8d7918-b8cd-4af9-8f3e-d2401940e4d8_0470be8e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英国外交部长周四透露，他已提起被监禁媒体的案件本月早些时候，持有英国护照并在香港面临与中国副主席勾结指控的大亨黎智英。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交部长詹姆斯·克莱弗利重申他的指控，即香港当局利用北京-在英国最新的六个月一次的香港议会报告中颁布了国家安全立法和煽动法，以“针对知名的民主人士、记者和政治家，以压制他们并抹黑他们”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“被拘留的英国双重国籍人士黎智英就是其中之一。我本月早些时候向中国国家副主席韩正提出了他的案子，我们已经向香港当局提出了最高级别的问题，”Cleverly 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，现为 -已停业的《苹果日报》以及 47 名被控颠覆非官方初选的反对派活动人士等，今年将根据国安法接受审判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“其中许多人已被还押两年多没有保释。 2019 年抗议活动期间被捕的数千人仍在等待了解他们是否会面临审判，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括总部位于伦敦的香港观察在内的多个团体敦促 Cleverly 直接筹集资金本月早些时候副总统访问伦敦参加查尔斯国王的加冕典礼期间，赖与韩的案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港法院维持禁止英国律师参与对赖的审判的决定&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;赖将于 9 月在没有陪审团的情况下接受审判，罪名是煽动叛乱和与外国势力勾结。周一，高等法院将裁定是否撤销国家安全案件，以回应赖的律师关于对他的定罪有明显偏见的论点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;聪明的说，中国仍处于“持续的非状态”。遵守”最新报告中的《中英联合声明》，指的是伦敦和北京 1984 年签署的协议，其中规定了该城市 1997 年回归中国统治的条款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们一直坚持与我们的合作伙伴一起谴责公民权利和政治权利以及香港自治权的不断侵蚀。中国应恪守其所有国际承诺，包括《联合声明》，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报告的大部分内容都致力于逮捕和监禁反对派成员、正在进行的国家安全案件以及越来越多地使用殖民地-时代的煽动法，据称该法已导致活动人士、公务员和普通公民被捕或定罪，主要是为了非暴力言论自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“诸如在法庭听证会上批评法官和发表言论等行为海外网上的反政府内容被裁定为煽动性内容。包括黎智英和前泛民政客在内的知名民主人士因违反[国家安全法]的罪行被判入狱，”它说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新闻自由受到越来越大的压力。对记者的起诉仍在继续。他们中的一些人仍被拘留，等待判决或面临审判。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报告称，国家安全立法和煽动叛乱法继续损害城市的生活方式，并补充说英国政府将“领导努力审查中国政府的行动”及其国际合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然该报告涵盖了去年 7 月至 12 月的这段时间，但 Cleverly 指出最近拟议的对该市区议会的改革，这将大幅削减直选议席数。他还提到了最近对《法律执业者条例》的修订，该条例将赋予香港领导人对海外律师参与国家安全案件的最终决定权。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港黎智英的律师表示，大亨拒绝接受公平审判, 受迫害&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“曾经属于司法机构的权力已经转移给行政长官。那些面临国家安全指控的人不再有权在法庭上质疑政府的决定，”他写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，Cleverly 通过寻求建设性关系，同时与北京就&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，最新数据显示，今年 1 月至 3 月期间，有 9,411 名香港人申请了英国国民（海外）签证计划，这是伦敦定制的移民途径。随着香港实施国家安全法，该计划于 2021 年 1 月 31 日推出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 10 月至 12 月，共有 8,222 人获得签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;自 BN(O) 签证计划推出以来，截至 3 月，已收到多达 172,500 份申请。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US-China trade war: officials to take another run at restarting trade talks, easing tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3221849/us-china-trade-war-officials-take-another-run-restarting-trade-talks-easing-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/2aa23dce-150f-4e55-ab7a-145025b5096a_45b39361.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国商务部长将利用本周访问美国的机会尝试重启北京周四证实，与美国同行举行贸易谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四和周五在底特律参加 Apec 贸易部长会议的商务部长王文涛将与美国商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多举行会谈和贸易代表凯瑟琳·戴，商务部发言人舒珏婷说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国贸易特使戴“希望”中国商务部长出席亚太经合组织&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“中方将与美方就中国问题进行沟通-美国的经贸关系和双方共同关心的问题，”她在北京的新闻发布会上说，但没有详细说明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这将是王毅与雷蒙多的首次面对面会谈，后者王毅于 2021 年上任。王毅最后一次会见戴泰安是在 11 月的另一次亚太经合组织会议上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次会议将是世界前两大经济体在近期双边关系恶化导致一再陷入僵局后重新接触的又一次尝试&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国国家主席习近平和乔·拜登去年 11 月在巴厘岛同意改善包括贸易在内的广泛问题上的沟通后，预计会谈将集中在贸易问题上，专家卢翔表示。中国社会科学院的美中关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以，这次交流很可能会在务实领域进行，”他说。 “比如降低关税，这首先对美国本身有利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于随着美中贸易战的开始，双边关系在 2018 年开始恶化，任何关系的改善都可能始于&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1月，时任中国副总理兼中美全面经济对话主席刘鹤在瑞士达沃斯与美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦破冰会晤。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;但当一个据称是中国间谍的气球在 2 月飘入美国领空时，这种势头就停止了。美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯因此取消了原定的访华计划。雷蒙多 3 月份的中国之行也被推迟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[王与戴和雷蒙多的会晤] 是良好的开端，但它们不会改变双边关系的下行轨迹，”戴维·兰普顿 (David M. Lampton) 说，美中关系全国委员会前主席、约翰霍普金斯大学SAIS名誉教授，现任职于SAIS外交政策研究所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;兰普顿说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中美之间的紧张关系已经超越了贸易战，而是升级为全方位的战略竞争，尤其是在高科技领域。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;最新一波出台之际，北京以“严重的国家安全风险”为由，禁止美国最大的存储芯片制造商美光科技向中国的关键信息基础设施运营商销售其产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相关的网络安全舒在周四的新闻发布会上谈到禁令时说，审查是维护中国国家安全的必要措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“欢迎各国企业、各类产品和服务进入中国市场，因为只要他们符合中国法律法规的要求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管“前所未有的高水平”关系，中俄贸易已经“趋于稳定”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;兰普顿表示，对美光的制裁是与改善投资和商业关系不相容，助长了西方从中国“去风险”的冲动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“同样，将中国从全球供应链中剔除的战略会滋生战略不信任并鼓励自力更生的思维在中国，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.最好的&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[HKeToll: Hong Kong’s Lion Rock Tunnel to start electronic payments on Sunday, but officials admit there will be no immediate cut in congestion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3221842/hketoll-hong-kongs-lion-rock-tunnel-start-electronic-payments-sunday-officials-admit-there-will-be?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 20:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/3997e8bc-0a7f-4179-93e0-4d300ce74fb2_bfbe34bb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港新的电子收费系统将于周日扩展至狮子山隧道 –但交通官员承认，他们预计过路处的交通拥堵情况不会立即缓解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但交通主管周四表示，他们有信心在早前的顺利实施后，在隧道实施 HKeToll 系统将会取得成功5 月 7 日在青沙管制区和 5 月 21 日在城门隧道启动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去一个月，我们在两条隧道运行新系统方面积累了一定的经验.因此，我们相信该系统将在狮子山隧道成功实施，”运输署署长 Rosanna Law Shuk-pui 解释说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们预计该系统在初期阶段不会显着缓解交通拥堵.但我们相信，随着驾车者对系统的使用越来越熟悉，并且所有收费站都被拆除，预计车辆通过隧道的速度会更快。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;电子系统将允许司机支付香港统一费用8 美元（1 美元），无需在收费站停车或排队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新的支付方式将于周日凌晨 5 点上线，因此将永久关闭一些车道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;隧道九龙塘一侧的七条车道将被缩减为三条。沙田入口的车道数目将从六条减半为三条。收费站将永久关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;整个隧道将从凌晨 4.30 到凌晨 5 点关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;部分公交线路将受到影响 – N170、N182、N271、N281 和N373，以及61S、63S、65S、501S、616S、805S等6条新界通宵专线小巴路线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前往九龙塘的车道将于周六晚上10时起分阶段封闭，至沙田将于周日凌晨 1 点开始封闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;检测到 16% 的香港汽车没有完全设置通行费应用程序&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但至少一条车道和三个收费站将保留双向随时开放至凌晨 4 时 30 分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运输署表示，每天有 90,000 辆车辆通过连接九龙塘和沙田的狮子山隧道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每天约有 6 万辆车辆使用青沙管制区，而每天有 5 万辆车辆通过城门隧道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总交通工程师（新界东）何君恒说，该署已发出约电子收费系统的 740,000 个标签，占全市持牌车辆的 91% 以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约 80% 的标签持有人已开设香港易通户口，其中 70%已经设置了自动付款方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ho 补充说，在较早的两个过境点引入该系统后，每天大约有 10 起投诉向该部门提出不正确的收费。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港自动隧道收费系统首个工作日顺利启动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;罗强调，使用城门隧道的车辆中有 5% 没有携带标签。她表示，青沙管制区的数字较高，但仍为个位数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;港易收费站要求道路使用者申请标签，在隧道扫描车费，开通专线网上户口及建立付款方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;已使用付款方式设立HKeToll户口的车主，在通过隧道时会收到交易成功的通知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有付款方式的司机HKeToll 标签或尚未设置付款方式的人将收到电子付款通知，并须在 14 个工作日内结清帐户，否则将面临 175 港元的附加费，21 天后提高至 350 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;如果司机拒绝付款，他们将面临法律诉讼。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s economic recovery is being held back by lagging private sector, household concerns, senior adviser warns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3221794/chinas-economic-recovery-being-held-back-lagging-private-sector-household-concerns-senior-adviser?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/5cd1bfec-f82e-485a-bbf7-6fa9cf394e2b_1b299421.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国民营经济复苏速度与国有经济差距拉大一位高级政府顾问本周警告说，企业已经成为经济全面反弹的一大障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘元春说，需要更积极的财政政策——尤其是中央政府——来支持小企业和家庭，上海财经大学校长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前的政策执行力还不足以支持全面的经济复苏，”刘在周一由中国宏观经济论坛组织的网络研讨会上说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财政部统计数据显示，第一季度国有企业利润同比增长 12.4% 至 1.12 万亿元人民币（1587 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但刘说民营企业，尤其是供应链下游和服务业的中小企业，利润进一步下滑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为中国经济的支柱，民营企业贡献巨大超过一半的国家税收、60% 的国内生产总值、固定资产投资和外国直接投资，以及超过 80% 的城镇就业。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国科技监管机构会见大型科技公司包括滴滴 CEO 在内的老板们&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但从 2020 年初开始近三年的 Covid-19 严格限制措施下，它首当其冲地承受着经济压力，这加剧了监管打击对科技巨头和私人补习的影响。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“从民营企业的角度来看，当大量资金和补贴项目涌入国有企业时，财政政策产生的复苏效应并不明显，”刘说。 “虽然市场主体的信心有所提升，但仍然比较低迷。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，2019年底中国复工以来民间固定资产投资年初至今增速根据国家统计局的数据，去年 12 月的增长率从 12 月的 0.9% 下降到 4 月的 0.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，家庭收入的缓慢增长，尤其是低收入群体的收入，抑制了刘补充说，人们的消费意愿进一步阻碍了经济复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年一季度，我国人均可支配收入10870元，扣除价格因素同比增长3.8%，但低于预期。高于同期4.5%的GDP增速。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前，国民收入分配出现收缩性分布，即大量资金用于投资而非消费”刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国火热的新消费趋势显示消费疲软挥之不去&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“收入下降会导致需求下降，进一步影响价格，进而影响利润，导致价格下降和工资收入减少的循环。如果这个周期发生，将对下一阶段的复苏产生负面影响。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;收入增长乏力与青年失业率飙升同时发生。根据国家统计局的统计，4 月份 16-24 岁年龄段的失业率创下 20.4% 的历史新高，高于 3 月份的 19.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1160 万大学毕业生创下历史新高分析师表示，今年进入就业市场，未来几个月情况可能会恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘说，以金融业为首的各行各业都出现了一波减薪潮，而房地产和股票则表现不佳市场进一步削弱了中国家庭的收入前景，这不利于预期和消费的恢复。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国需要让一些地方政府因债务增加而申请破产&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他补充说，地方政府财政状况不佳导致北京的财政政策难以在基层实施，中央政府需要承担更大的责任，提前使用财政工具并出台更多扩张性政策。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“现阶段，中央政府承担更大的责任非常重要，”刘说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Wagner boss says handing Bakhmut to Russian army, Japan scrambles jets]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3221845/wagner-boss-says-handing-bakhmut-russian-army-japan-scrambles-jets?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 21:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/7b5fa428-7332-4d80-bf31-4637072a8f39_6647cfd8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯瓦格纳雇佣军团长周四表示，他的部队已经开始转移阵地在乌克兰东部的爆发点巴赫穆特市向俄罗斯军方报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，在莫斯科宣布中国特使将讨论乌克兰问题之际，日本表示在其海岸线附近发现俄罗斯“情报收集”飞机后紧急起飞战斗机周五与外交部长谢尔盖·拉夫罗夫 (Sergey Lavrov) 会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在巴赫穆特，瓦格纳表示，在声称已在周末完全占领这座被摧毁的城市后，它开始撤出其战士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰否认巴赫穆特已落入俄罗斯之手，坚称其仍控制着这座废墟城市的“微区”，并表示仍在侧翼推进。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯的瓦格纳老板说，他的 20,000 名士兵死于巴赫穆特&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;巴赫穆特之战已经进行了将近一年，将这座城市夷为平地，并摧毁了领导俄罗斯进攻工业中心的瓦格纳新兵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们今天从巴赫穆特撤军.我们正在向军方移交阵地、弹药和一切，”瓦格纳老板 Yevgeny Prigozhin 在一段视频中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们撤退，我们休息，我们准备，然后我们将接受新的任务，”补充说Prigozhin 身穿战术防弹衣，头戴军用头盔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周早些时候，他承认约有 10,000 名他为在乌克兰作战而招募的战俘在战场上阵亡。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;这位 61 岁的克里姆林宫盟友去年参观了俄罗斯监狱，说服囚犯与瓦格纳战斗，以换取承诺在他们返回时大赦——如果他们幸存的话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦格纳的宣布是在莫斯科军方几天后宣布的表示已在俄罗斯领土上部署喷气式飞机和大炮，以打击从乌克兰越境的“破坏”组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在基辅，总统沃洛德米尔·泽伦斯基指责俄罗斯通过发射新一波伊朗制造的攻击无人机来恐吓乌克兰人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“敌人继续通过发射 36 架 Shaheds 来恐吓乌克兰。泽伦斯基在社交媒体上说：“没有人达到他们的目标。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我感谢我们的防空部队取得了 100% 的结果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰军方说，俄罗斯俄罗斯可能以乌克兰西部的关键基础设施和军事设施为目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯在冬季对乌克兰的基础设施（包括能源设施）进行了空中轰炸，但最近这些袭击有所减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在呼吁西方盟友提高防空能力后，基辅越来越善于击落一波又一波的俄罗斯巡航导弹和无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，俄罗斯任命的克里米亚负责人宣布防空系统拦截了几架无人机目标是 2014 年从乌克兰吞并的领土的各个部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“六架无人机在克里米亚的不同地区被击落或拦截，”谢尔盖·阿克肖诺夫在社交媒体上宣布，并补充说没有人受伤。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰战争：越境突袭领导人警告俄罗斯准备发动更多袭击&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在莫斯科，俄罗斯联邦安全局安全部门表示已逮捕两名据称计划以核电为目标的乌克兰人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;FSB 在一份声明中称，其目的是“对俄罗斯造成严重的经济损害并损害其声誉”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在日本，东京的军方紧急起飞战斗机喷气式飞机，称两架俄罗斯飞机在泽连斯基参加广岛七国集团首脑会议几天后沿着其部分海岸线飞行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本与西方盟友一道，就莫斯科的乌克兰攻势对莫斯科实施制裁。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Korean ‘rivalry’ heads to space, as South launches first home-grown rocket and North prepares spy satellite]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3221838/korean-rivalry-heads-space-south-launches-first-home-grown-rocket-and-north-prepares-spy-satellite?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 20:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/8e802932-5c79-4eea-ac4b-ff3da80ae11b_4d24e381.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国被迫推迟发射其本土空间的一天后火箭，该国周四成功将实用卫星送入轨道，标志着其发展航空航天业努力的一个重要里程碑，因为竞争对手朝鲜正在推动将其第一颗军事间谍卫星送入轨道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ Nuri 的第三次飞行已成功完成，”科学部长李钟浩说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后进行了有效载荷分离，八颗卫星中的六颗被确认已成功分离，因为它需要更多时间来检查部长说，剩下两颗卫星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;200 吨重的 Nuri 火箭于当地时间下午 6 点 24 分左右从位于该国南部海岸的纳罗航天中心发射升空，并到达了目标轨道飞行约 13 分钟后，距离地面 550 公里（342 英里）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次发射标志着韩国在发展自己的航空航天业方面取得了飞跃，”Lee Sang-ryul 说，韩国航空航天研究所 (KARI) 所长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nuri 的第三次飞行标志着首次尝试使用国产运载火箭装载和发射“商业级”卫星，KARI 在一份声明中说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它说，这次飞行的目的是在太空中验证本地开发的复杂雷达，即合成孔径雷达 (SAR)，并执行包括测量宇宙辐射在内的太空研究任务。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;与光学相机相比，SAR 受天气影响较小，可以在没有日光的情况下使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nuri，也称为 KSLV-II，于 2021 年 10 月进行了首飞，搭载了 1,500公斤虚拟卫星有效载荷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管它达到了 700 公里的目标顶点，但由于其第三级过早关闭而未能达到预期的轨道速度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 6 月的飞行，第二次涉及国产太空火箭，通过将一颗虚拟卫星和四颗名为 CubeSats 的微型卫星送入轨道，表现要好得多，这标志着韩国首次使用国产火箭发射卫星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;KARI表示需要更多的飞行才能使 Nuri 作为将本地开发的卫星送入轨道的运载火箭更加可靠。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2010 年开始的耗资 2 万亿韩元（15.2 亿美元）的 Nuri 项目将持续到 2027 年增加三个火箭发射； 2025 年一颗下一代中型卫星，2026 年五颗微型卫星和 2027 年另外五颗微型卫星。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国如何从 SpaceX 那里抄袭以实现其太空野心&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lee智库韩国防务网络的分析师 Il-woo 排除了将 Nuri 转化为军用导弹的可能性，因为与使用固体燃料的弹道导弹不同，Nuri 是液体推进的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;固体燃料消除了需要在发射前为导弹加油，这会增加响应时间并可能被敌人发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相反，Nuri 允许韩国通过不时建立许多小型卫星网络来增强其太空侦察能力以及未来自己选择的地方”，Lee 在《亚洲周刊》中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国计划在未来 10 年内再投资 2 万亿韩元（15 亿美元）开发另一个 KSLV- III 运载火箭预计将于 2030 年上线，到 2032 年发射 1.5 吨重的机器人月球着陆器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nuri 的飞行之际，邻国朝鲜正在升级其航天中心以满足金正恩领导人日益增长的需求金正恩上个月呼吁该国将其首颗间谍卫星送入轨道，以监视美国军队及其在亚洲的盟友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国国家安全顾问赵泰勇表示，任何可能的发射平壤可能会导致进一步的制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有可能在不久的将来发射。在这种情况下……最终将加深朝鲜在国际社会中的外交孤立，”赵告诉韩联社新闻电视台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金正恩上周访问了卫星发射筹备委员会，并批准了其“未来行动”计划”，朝鲜中央通讯社表示，暗示发射可能迫在眉睫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果真的发生，这将是朝鲜自 2016 年 2 月以来首次发射太空火箭，当时平壤声称已将地球-尽管国外持怀疑态度，但仍将观测卫星送入轨道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在他们试图在太空中建立的东西方面，两个朝鲜之间肯定存在竞争，”教学和学习主任军事历史学家大卫西尔贝说在华盛顿康奈尔大学的项目中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“卫星的用途之一是瞄准核武器，”Silbey 说。 “朝鲜拥有这种高端能力，真的值得担心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;天空无止境：美军在韩国发射太空部队&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;由于联合国安理会决议禁止进行弹道导弹试验，平壤长期以来一直声称它有权拥有用于卫星发射的民用太空计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士警告说，来自朝鲜太空计划的技术可用于推进其弹道导弹技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“朝鲜很可能在 ICBM（洲际弹道导弹）试验中使用使用固体燃料推进剂的运载火箭伪装成太空卫星发射，”Lee Il-woo 说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;詹姆斯·马丁防扩散研究中心的高级研究员大卫·施默勒说，如果朝鲜能够成功发射成像卫星并将其送入轨道，它将使用这些图像来尝试并完善他们的目标清单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“来自朝鲜的潜在威胁在理论上将保持不变，但有了更好或更新的图像，该威胁将更加完善 - 并更有效地部署– 如果使用，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bloomberg 的补充报告&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South China Sea: Vietnam demands Chinese ship leave its exclusive economic zone]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3221839/south-china-sea-vietnam-demands-chinese-ship-leave-its-exclusive-economic-zone?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 20:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/e175e397-ca1b-4e2d-aa40-af3b20fc9b17_74600d69.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;越南周四指责一艘中国测量船及其护卫舰侵犯其主权，并且要求北京将这些船只从其水域撤走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南和中国长期以来一直卷入南中国海潜在能源丰富海域的领土争端，这是一条战略性航道，每年有超过 3 美元通过每年有数万亿美元的贸易往来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“越南要求中国立即将调查船向阳红 10 号、中国海警船和渔船撤出越南水域，”外交部发言人范秋恒在一份政府声明中说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明补充说：“越南已与中国多次接触，并根据国际法和越南法律采取措施，确保越南的合法权益。”&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;越南批评中国、菲律宾在南中国海的行为&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国驻河内大使馆没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周越南批评了一个国家最近的行为中国研究船在东南亚国家专属经济区（EEZ）的同一区域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国表示，科学研究是在中国管辖范围内的正常活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国根据它所说的旧地图，越南声称几乎整个南中国海都是其领土，包括位于越南专属经济区和其他四个东南亚国家内的水域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hang 还表示，越南呼吁国际社会共同维护南海秩序、和平与安全，为两国共同利益的发展作出贡献。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In China trade, Uruguay businesses will ‘for sure’ use more yuan, says consul general in Guangdong]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3221802/china-trade-uruguay-businesses-will-sure-use-more-yuan-says-consul-general-guangdong?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/3b09a0be-27a4-443e-b573-f9c2c1094b6d_2ab47350.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着他的国家高达三分之一的出口产品进入中国市场，乌拉圭驻广州代理总领事表示，以人民币结算贸易将是一个方便的选择，乌拉圭政府在货币使用方面保持开放态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国- 周三在东莞市举行的拉丁美洲私营部门论坛上，Facundo Fernandez Guerra 告诉《华盛顿邮报》，乌拉圭当局正在采取“一切措施使双方的业务更容易”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们愿意讨论…… further exchanges and different currency exchanges,” he said. “是的，可以肯定的是，企业将来会使用更多的人民币进行交易。这是一种趋势。 And it shows how China&#39;s influence is increasing in different parts of the world.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fernandez Guerra highlighted that “it&#39;s a business decision” on what currency to use, but “at the end of the day, [the Uruguayan government is] trying to achieve the facilitation of business … to make things easier.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Which 8 nations are using China&#39;s yuan more, and how will it affect US dollar?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Uruguay is an open country and the country that can easily promote free currency trade,” he added. “美元、比索和欧元都是一样的。 Uruguay will not put any control on currency and trade exchanges.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brazil has begun to accept trade settlements and investments in yuan, with an agreement reached between central banks in February. Argentina also said in April that US$1.04 billion worth of Chinese imports would be paid for in yuan that month instead of US dollars, and then US$790 million per month from May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Figures from China Customs showed that the bilateral trade value between China and Uruguay was US$7.44 billion in 2022, an increase of 14.9 per cent from a year earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official data showed that China was the top trading partner of Uruguay, largely owing to imports of Uruguayan beef, soybean and wool. The South American nation is the third-largest beef producer and the fourth-largest soybean provider for China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fernandez Guerra said that China has been an important trade partner for the country over the last decade, with an average of 33 per cent of total exports going to Chinese customers each year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We want to maintain the [trade] level that we have nowadays,” he noted. “这里的要点是我们的经济是互补的，[引领]当今的贸易水平。 The trade has increased 60 times now compared with 35 years ago.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Uruguay aims to seize opportunities to diversify the variety of its “quality” goods sold to the Chinese market, according to Fernandez Guerra, amid China&#39;s growing emphasis on food security and its concerns over safety issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re trying to promote chicken.我们正在努力推广葡萄酒。我们出口橄榄油。 Those are the products we&#39;re exporting to the world, but we&#39;re not exporting [them] to China.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China eyeing free-trade deal in US &#39;backyard&#39; to test South American pragmatism&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;With a focus on exporting beef, soy and rice to China, Fernandez Guerra explained, his country is now “in a particular stage where we can make a big step to include different sectors to diversify the exports”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, Uruguay&#39;s foreign minister, Francisco Bustillo, visited China for five days with expectations that the two sides could speed up negotiations for a bilateral free-trade agreement that has been formally discussed since last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fernandez Guerra said that the absence of a free-trade agreement between both countries remains a challenge for Uruguayan businesses, as it means “all trade” the country has now “is not free trade, with tremendous taxes”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Uruguayan President Luis Lacalle Pou is expected to visit China in the second half of this year, Fernandez Guerra added, and one of the goals is to advance “the most relevant bilateral agenda”, including the free-trade agreement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brazilian President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva has also proposed a free-trade agreement between China and the Southern Common Market (Mercosur), which comprises Argentina, Brazil Uruguay and Paraguay.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Uruguay has proposed to have a free-trade agreement between Mercosur and China a few times,” Fernandez Guerra noted. “我们捍卫并尊重南方共同市场。如果可能的话，我们会支持谈判。 We&#39;ll also continue to pursue a separate free-trade agreement with China.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regarding US-China tensions, Fernandez Guerra pointed to Uruguay&#39;s pragmatic strategy by “mostly talking about numbers”, and said he expected to see more exchanges in education and technical areas between his country and China.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Milk made in Hong Kong? University rolls out only drink of its kind in city, hopes to reach some supermarkets in future]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3221834/milk-made-hong-kong-university-rolls-out-only-drink-its-kind-city-hopes-reach-some-supermarkets?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/25/d5d10127-0a53-4b8d-9026-36e65fd9b9de_91bce2e1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A university in Hong Kong began selling the city&#39;s only locally produced milk on its campus on Thursday, while expressing hopes that its products would soon hit some supermarket shelves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2017, City University became the first and only local tertiary education institution to launch a veterinary medicine programme. It flew in more than 20 cows from Australia last September to enhance the teaching it could provide and produce milk locally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A farm run by the university in Tai Po, where the cows are housed, features facilities such as barns, feeding tables, milking machines and a room for processing the drink.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Undergraduate veterinary students will attend compulsory courses at the farm during their six years of studies. They will learn basic animal handling, conduct clinical exams, diagnose disease and provide medical treatment for the cattle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At our peak, currently, we are producing about 550 litres (1,162 pints) of milk a day.但在即将到来的 11 月，我们将减少到每天 100 到 200 升，”农场经理 Eryl Done 说。 “The average across the year will be somewhere over 300 litres a day.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This roughly translates to about 1,200 cartons of milk, each at a size of 236ml (8 fluid ounces), hitting the shelves every day.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong hi-tech farm tests growing wasabi indoors as Japan&#39;s harvests drop&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;After three years of preparation, the milk is on sale at the university&#39;s campus in Kowloon Tong for HK$9 (US$1) per carton. The drink is entirely produced by the 24 young pregnant Jersey cows the university raises on its farm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The animals are a breed of small dairy cattle originating from the Channel Islands that Done said was more tolerant of heat than other varieties and produced milk with higher fat and protein content.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Rare leopard cats found thriving in Kadoorie Farm reforested area in Hong Kong&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A check on the Consumer Council&#39;s website showed that similar products by Kowloon Dairy and Trappist Dairy were sold at HK$9 and HK$9.50, respectively. A package of 200ml shelf-stable milk imported from Japan could be found at between HK$10 and HK$16 in supermarkets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Government statistics showed that Hong Kong imported 89,000 tonnes of milk last year, of which a fifth was fresh.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are certainly hoping to sell a significant minority of the [city&#39;s fresh] milk over the counter here,” Done said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our farm is all about sustainability and sustainable production,” said Professor Vanessa Barrs, dean of the university&#39;s veterinary medicine and life sciences college.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our farm gives us and our students so many different opportunities to learn about veterinary medicine. Students start at the farm from the very first year they study veterinary science.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Barrs said the university was investigating the possibility of “making some milk available in one or two supermarkets”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We will sell all of the milk that we produce, but unfortunately, we don&#39;t have the capacity to provide milk for the whole of Hong Kong,” she said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s Apple loss is India’s gain, as 2022 supplier list shows shift in supply chain preferences]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3221814/chinas-apple-loss-indias-gain-2022-supplier-list-shows-shift-supply-chain-preferences?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/25/984d7935-1ce4-4b49-8a26-497624d94ff0_a29e6475.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Apple added five new mainland Chinese suppliers while removing eight in mainland China in its latest financial year ended September 2022, after China&#39;s strict Covid-19 controls disrupted iPhone production last holiday season, according to the latest supplier list published by the US consumer electronics giant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Globally, Apple added 18 new suppliers while cutting 19, resulting in a small adjustment in its supply chain, but one that has made India a clear winner.苹果在该国的生产基地数量从 2021 年的 11 个增加到去年的 14 个，这表明 iPhone 制造商在该国的加速扩张。 It also opened its first two retail outlets in India this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In China, the five new suppliers include metal processing companies Cathay Tat Ming and Bichamp Cutting Technology, as well as Zhuhai CosMX Battery. Sunny Optical Technology, which was the largest supplier of high-end wide-angle lenses for the iPhone 14 series of smartphones last year, was also included.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the eight companies removed from the list are Trio Metal Company Limited, a supplier of wire rods based in southern Guangzhou, and display maker Tianma Micro-Electronics. Shenzhen-based Zhenghe Group, which processes and assembles metal and plastic exterior chassis, was also cut.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple&#39;s latest supplier list, which was published last week, accounts for 98 per cent of the company&#39;s direct spending on materials, manufacturing and assembly worldwide. The tech giant&#39;s supply chain is closely watched, as changes are seen as a sign of China&#39;s shifting role in global manufacturing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Apple &#39;pleased&#39; with better-than-expected China sales amid slowdown&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The bulk of Apple&#39;s manufacturing remains in China, where 151 of its top 188 disclosed suppliers have facilities, compared with 150 in 2021. However, rising labour costs combined with geopolitical tensions with the US and three years of Covid restrictions that just ended this year have pushed foreign businesses to relocate more production to other countries in the region, particularly India and Vietnam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last November, Covid-related protests broke out at the largest iPhone production facility in the world in Zhengzhou. It resulted in shipment delays for iPhone 14 models during the Christmas holiday shopping season.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple has also been diversifying its iPhone manufacturing, having become wary of an over-reliance on Taiwan&#39;s Foxconn Technology, its largest supplier. Shenzhen-based Luxshare and Taiwanese Pegatron both received orders to make the upcoming iPhone 15 series phones, including premium models, marking the first time Apple has tapped three suppliers to produce its most high-end smartphones, according to the Taiwanese newspaper Economic Daily News, citing sources close to the Apple supply chain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Apple should strive to achieve supply chain balance rather than reducing or increasing [suppliers from any region] specifically,” said Eddie Han, a senior analyst at Isaiah Research. “Balancing [its supply chain] would be most beneficial for Apple.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea, US troops hold large live-fire drills near border with North Korea]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3221835/south-korea-us-troops-hold-large-live-fire-drills-near-border-north-korea?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.25 20:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/25/453be0fe-6ffc-41b3-97c7-a7ad4ed75c5e_776e8a84.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The South Korean and US militaries conducted large live-fire drills near the border with North Korea on Thursday, despite the North&#39;s warning that it won&#39;t tolerate what it calls an invasion rehearsal on its doorstep.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The drills, the first of five rounds of live-fire exercises through mid-June, mark 70 years since the establishment of the military alliance between Seoul and Washington. North Korea typically reacts to such major South Korean-US exercises with missile and other weapons tests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the start of 2022, North Korea has test-launched more than 100 missiles, but none since it fired a solid-fuel intercontinental ballistic missile in mid-April. It says the tests are a response to expanded military drills between the US and South Korea, but observers say North Korea aims to advance its weapons development and then wrest greater concessions from its rivals in eventual diplomacy.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;North Korea says US military drills driving region to &#39;brink of nuclear war&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US-South Korean firing exercises, called “Combined annihilation firepower drills,” are the biggest of their kind. The drills have been held 11 times since they began in 1977, according to the South Korean Defence Ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The drills involved 2,500 troops and 610 weapons systems such as fighter jets, attack helicopters, drones, tanks and artillery from South Korea and the United States, according to the South Korean Defence Ministry. The most recent exercises in 2017 drew about 2,000 soldiers and 250 weapons assets from both countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The drills simulated artillery and aerial strikes on front-line North Korean military facilities in response to an attack. The troops later practised precision-guided attacks on simulated targets in the rear areas to “completely annihilate” North Korean military threats, according to a ministry statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said South Korea will seek to establish “peace through overwhelming strengthen” to counter North Korean threats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;North Korea didn&#39;t immediately respond to the start of the drills. Last Friday, its state media called the drills “a typical North Korea-targeted war rehearsal,” saying it “cannot but take a more serious note of the fact” that the exercises are a few kilometres from its frontier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The North&#39;s Korean Central News Agency said the US and South Korea would face unspecified “corresponding responses” to the drills.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, the South Korean and US militaries conducted their biggest field exercises in five years. The US also sent the nuclear-powered USS Nimitz aircraft carrier and nuclear-capable bombers for joint exercises with South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moon Seong Mook, an analyst for the Seoul-based Korea Research Institute for National Strategy, said North Korea could use the South Korea-US drills as a pretext to resume testing activities. He said domestic issues such as North Korea&#39;s push to increase agricultural production during the rice-planting season could still affect its decision on weapons tests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“North Korea can&#39;t help feel some burdens over the South Korea-US joint firepower drills being held for the first time in six years and in the strongest manner,” Moon said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 25 May 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>