<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia state polls: voting begins as PM Anwar Ibrahim faces first major popularity test]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3230866/malaysia-state-polls-voting-begins-pm-anwar-ibrahim-faces-first-major-popularity-test?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 07:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/8fe08036-5f87-49ea-8de3-96b0a153c4a7_9e55ffbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周六在马来西亚六个州开始投票，这可能是第一个严重的政治挑战交给总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣，他希望证明马来穆斯林占多数并没有抛弃他的联合政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 970 万人有资格投票选举这六个州属的下届政府 - 反对派国民联盟（PN）正寻求控制北部的吉打、吉兰丹和丁加奴，而政府政党则控制森美兰、槟城和雪兰莪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;州选举的结果对安华的影响不大。保留联邦权力。但他们被视为支持他和他的政治盟友和前敌人的乌合之众政府的晴雨表，特别是在去年11月大选中向马来民族主义国盟做出重大转变的马来人中。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;TikTok 的主导地位能否让反对派在马来西亚州民意调查中占据优势？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国盟在其竞选策略中瞄准了马来选民基础，微视频共享平台 TikTok 成为其接触马来腹地选民的关键工具&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在数十个竞选站台和社交媒体上，国盟一直保持着简单的信息：安瓦尔和他的联合政府与腐败领导人勾结，未能将马来西亚人民从不断飙升的生活成本和持续的通货膨胀中拯救出来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;最近，备受争议的吉打州首席部长 Muhammad Sanusi Md Nor 和政治评论员 Wan Muhammad Azri Wan Deris（更广为人知的名字是 Papagomo）在 TikTok 上进行了一场直播，吸引了超过 62,000 次观看和 1600 万次点赞。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;穆罕默德沙努西周四表示，选民非常熟悉安瓦尔的“真面目”，他说安瓦尔在二十多年来做出了无数崇高的承诺，以改善所有马来西亚人的命运。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“二十五年来，他一直在乞求被任命为首相。在他获得授权后，八个月后什么也没有发生，”穆罕默德·沙努西在吉打州的一次青年聚会上说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这六个州将进行全民公投，成为“非爸爸”的标志……他在竞选演讲的 TikTok 视频中说道，指的是安瓦尔和布城的行政首都。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔的希盟 (PH) 和合作伙伴国阵 (国阵）希望社交媒体的影响力不会在周六的民意调查中发挥作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11 月的全国大选见证了半岛上的马来选民掀起了一股“绿潮”——所谓的“绿潮”反映了伊斯兰主义者的政党色彩伊斯兰党 – 这使得反对党国民联盟在该国 222 个席位的议会中获得了相当大的全马来少数派席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔一直站在其政府努力扭转马来人支持潮流的最前沿，穿越全国，到达尽可能多的马来人占多数的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五在他的家乡槟城举行的竞选活动中，总理恳求马来选民给予他支持。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论是涉及padi [补贴]、橡胶[小农]、军人房屋、公务员工资、渔民[生存]的问题，我们都在努力在这八个月内最大限度地改善，”安瓦尔说国家通讯社马新社援引他的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“想象一下，我们继续执政五年，Insya-Allah 马来西亚将成为亚洲伟大的国家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，安华的努力，可能没有带来预期的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究公司伊尔哈姆中心周四公布了 7 月份的一项调查结果，称在六个州属的 2,400 多名受访者中，只有四分之一的马来人表示他们对总理的表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士预测，周六的民意调查结果将维持现状，尽管国盟在政府据点槟城和雪兰莪取得进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;独立民意调查机构默迪卡中心周五在一份调查报告中表示，如果希盟和国阵希望减缓国盟在该国两个最富有州属的进展，那么他们的任务就是说服他们的核心支持者站出来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“非马来选民仍然坚定支持希盟，但他们的投票率存在很多问题。”报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚联合政府“不会削弱”马来权力：民主行动党的安东尼洛克&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;专家表示，在 11 月的民意调查中全面拒绝前执政党和国阵关键巫统之后，马来选民可能会寻求一个新的平台来代表他们的身份政治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管最终只获得 28 个席位，但巫统还是成功了在国王选择安瓦尔担任最高职位后，寻找重返政府的途径，条件是他组建一个包括他的政治盟友和对手的联合政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;选举委员会周五表示，预计选民会投票到周六晚上投票结束时，投票率将超过 85%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Simply fixing our degraded soil could have a huge climate impact]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230685/simply-fixing-our-degraded-soil-could-have-huge-climate-impact?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/10/733cdf56-91c5-4152-b9bd-45f8292a712e_8b812480.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;夏季炎热，联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯警告说，“全球沸腾已经到来”。对此我们能做些什么？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;应对气候变化需要系统变革，即使不是不可能，也是艰难的。已故的系统思想家和 1972 年《增长的极限》报告的合著者达纳·梅多斯 (Dana Meadows) 认为，改变复杂系统的关键方法是找到正确的杠杆点，在这个杠杆点上，微小的改变可以产生巨大的影响。那么气候沸腾的明显常见因素是什么？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科学答案是碳排放。大气主要由氮气和氧气组成，但是当阳光照射到大气中更多的碳颗粒时，地球就会变暖。在人类出现之前，存在着更加平衡的碳循环，植物和微生物通过光合作用捕获碳，保持温度平衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着人类学会耕种土壤和燃烧化石燃料，我们加速了碳排放气候变暖，冰盖和永久冻土融化，困住二氧化碳和甲烷，导致海平面上升。这正在威胁我们的食物和水供应、生物多样性，并最终威胁人类的生存。粮食、水和能源短缺可能引发战争和冲突，这只会进一步破坏环境，就像乌克兰战争摧毁了许多农田一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那么粮食生产的杠杆点是什么，供水和碳捕获？答案是：土壤。海洋也很重要，但我们大部分人口生活在陆地上并依赖农业。在陆地、海洋和大气这三个生物圈中，土壤可以说为我们提供了解决问题的最佳机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;管理不善已导致世界上超过三分之一的土壤退化。联合国粮食及农业组织估计，如果不采取任何措施，到 2050 年，土壤退化率可能上升至 90%。土地退化越严重，我们不断增长的人口所拥有的粮食就越少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数农村社区自己种植粮食，但占人类一半以上的城市社会依赖大规模工业化粮食生产。 EAT-Lancet 委员会 2019 年的一份报告发现，世界上有问题的粮食系统导致约 10 亿人挨饿，20 亿人吃太多错误的食物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;超过 40% 的成年人（21 亿人） ）现在超重，而 31 亿人却无法负担健康饮食。工业生产的食品往往包含转基因生物以及大量既不健康也不营养的化学品和防腐剂。美国 30% 至 40% 的食品在生产和运输过程中被浪费，由于物流不畅或过度购买而未被食用或丢弃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工业化食品生产和农业土地越来越多地集中在非常有限的人手中大公司。他们的单一种植农业，例如棕榈油或大豆，在短期内可能是有效的，但最终会损害生物多样性，通过驱逐小农而加剧不平等，并且可能意味着对碳捕获和环境可持续性问题的重视不够。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;森林砍伐暴露了表层土壤，使其养分流失。在最基本的层面上，土壤由细菌、真菌、蠕虫和微生物组成的复杂生态系统组成，可以保护生物多样性、节约用水和捕获碳。拯救土壤确实可以保护我们的未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们越来越认识到，以农民为中心的土壤和粮食生产再生努力不仅可以解决我们的粮食危机和水资源短缺问题，还可以捕获碳。欧洲已成立联盟，探索以农场为中心的农业再生计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰战争引发粮食和化肥供应冲击后，上个月印度宣布限制大米供应，发展中国家进一步感到震惊出口。突然之间，粮食自给自足成为政策议程的重要议题——政客们意识到高粮价正在破坏社会稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们应该在政策上更多地关注国内农民以及在再生农业中使用永续农业来生产作物多样性和土壤再生。重新造林等农业实践也可以捕获碳，并可以通过销售碳信用额创造新的收入来源。不幸的是，全球碳市场尚未均衡运转，因此发展中国家并未从碳价上涨中充分受益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近在亚马逊地区的考古发现表明存在黑土（terra preta），这是一种营养丰富的堆肥土壤。用堆肥改善退化土地可能是恢复土壤质量和多种作物种植的更便宜、更有机的方式。简而言之，技术可以有机地增加粮食产量，不仅有助于提高农村收入，还有助于提高粮食质量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;土壤、森林和水源的再生是具有社会影响力的项目，与公共基础设施（如道路、港口等社会效益高，经济效益低。这些正是社会证券交易所和慈善机构应该支持的项目类型。即使在城市，使用有机堆肥和肥料的垂直农业也可以提高粮食自给自足并缓解供应中断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一切都是天上掉馅饼吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;解决气候变化和社会不公正问题就是用更少的钱为更多的人做更多的事。再生土壤意味着改善有限的资源，为更多的人生产更有营养的食物，减少我们相互竞争的需要。气候变化是环境的变化。那些系统思考、本地化行动和适应的人将会生存下来。那些否认改变的人不会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Signs of Chinese business life return to Afghanistan 2 years after the Taliban’s takeover]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3230359/signs-chinese-business-life-return-afghanistan-2-years-after-talibans-takeover?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/f4a443cb-e1da-4d38-b898-8f53e68b2421_f3b59f71.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;大约 18 个月前移居阿富汗的中国宝石商人段毅 (Duan Yi)近几个月来，喀布尔街头发生了明显的变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外国游客——主要来自欧洲和美国，现在越来越多的中国游客——又回到了这座曾经荒凉的首都。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;李西京也看到了同样的趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为喀布尔唐人街的负责人，李西京已经迎接了数十名尝试重返这座城市的中国商人。自春天以来，从英国到日本的记者也敲过他的门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[唐人街]变得越来越拥挤，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从塔利班控制了战争以来2021年，阿富汗这个饱受摧残的国家，经济和安全并没有像一些人预期的那样崩溃。相反，这个中亚国家已经开始慢慢收拾残局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但对于选择回国并留下来的华商来说，他们知道要对这个好消息持保留态度，并且要病人。虽然塔利班政权自上台以来带来了安全，但恐怖袭击并未停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，包括中国在内的国际社会尚未承认该政权的人权 — — 特别是在受到严格限制的情况下。 ”不过，他表示，虽然妇女权益问题非常重要，但“这不是阿富汗问题的全部，也不是阿富汗问题的核心或根源”。部委声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管街上的大多数企业都像塔利班承诺的那样恢复正常，但该国的经济仍然因外国制裁而受到影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“阿富汗并不像塔利班那样段说：“尽管媒体描述的很可怕，但你总是处于紧张状态。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为喀布尔唐人街的一名高管，李表示，最近几周他与商人的接触日益增多，这是复苏的迹象.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于喀布尔市中心的唐人街社区是大多数初来乍到的中国人的第一站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是两年前塔利班控制阿富汗时，只有大约十几名中国人选择留下来。李说，在整个阿富汗，中国人只剩下不到20人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国宣布与塔利班控制的阿富汗建立陆地联系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“过去两年，当涉及到阿富汗，中国人民一直认为那里有战争和恐怖袭击，但现在越来越多的人回来了。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国人开始再次考虑到阿富汗做生意和投资，李表示他们“需要选择正确的方式或方法”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在国家之间没有正常外交关系的情况下，企业对投资持谨慎态度，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国可能会尚未正式承认塔利班政权，但中国高级官员已与阿富汗同行举行了高层会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;匹兹堡大学治理与市场中心创始主任詹妮弗·布里克·穆尔塔扎什维利 (Jennifer Brick Murtazashvili) 表示，中国由于担心该政权的稳定性，犹豫是否与该政权建立正式关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[阿富汗]的邻国最熟悉阿富汗的历史和治理动态，他们认识到，如果没有一个更具包容性的政府，阿富汗将兰州大学政治与国际关系学院教授朱永标表示，安全仍然是中国最关心的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现阶段， [对中国来说]最根本的问题是敦促阿富汗与恐怖主义划清界限。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4月份，中国发布了自塔利班掌权以来最全面的阿富汗立场文件，列出了11点&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;阿富汗女法官躲藏起来，生怕被塔利班发现&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;《中方在阿富汗问题上的立场》呼吁塔利班政府“采取温和、公正的态度”审慎的国内外政策”，并且文件中的 11 点中有 3 点直接提到了塔利班的反恐活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文件强调了东突厥斯坦伊斯兰运动 (ETIM)，这是北京所控制的一个维吾尔分裂主义组织。穆尔塔扎什维利表示，维吾尔分裂主义团体仍然是中国反恐雄心的主要担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国希望阿富汗能够消除恐怖组织，特别是留在该国的维吾尔小团体。从战略角度来看，这些组织是对中国最大的威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了北京关注的分裂主义组织之外，在阿富汗的中国人也感受到了伊斯兰国呼罗珊组织的威胁。伊斯兰国在阿富汗的分支机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;12 月，伊斯兰国 K 组织在喀布尔隆安酒店发动袭击，造成 5 名中国公民受重伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，1 月，武装分子以伊斯兰国成员为目标。中国代表团参与了喀布尔外交部外的另一起自杀式炸弹袭击，官员称该袭击造成至少 5 人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据悉，Isis-K 还对首都俄罗斯和巴基斯坦使馆的其他袭击负责。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;居住在坎大哈的 37 岁商人孙飞表示，尽管安全形势总体有所改善，但中国人仍然生活在袭击的阴影之下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“安全状况有所好转，但（恐怖分子）开始更多地针对中国人和俄罗斯人。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《孙报》报道，从喀布尔到南部城市喀布尔，有关恐怖袭击的传言甚嚣尘上。龙眼酒店袭击发生前一个月的坎大哈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“（针对华人的）歧视非常明显，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈佛肯尼迪学院爱德华研究员尼尚克·莫特瓦尼 (Nishank Motwani) S. Mason 节目称，武装分子希望通过发动袭击来破坏塔利班的合法性，并在外国投资者、外交官和政府中播下对安全的疑虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“谁将成为助产士？”：阿富汗妇女失业，重新接受护士培训&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“‘伊斯兰国’组织可能会对包括中国公民在内的软目标发动更多袭击，因为这会扩大他们的宣传力度，羞辱塔利班并破坏安全环境”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，穆尔塔扎什维利表示，她相信，即使阿富汗的安全局势有所改善，针对中国人民的袭击仍将继续。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经过塔利班统治两年后，阿富汗没有那么广泛的战斗……一个重要原因是塔利班现在控制了政府，”她说。 “塔利班本身就是我们在该国看到的大部分叛乱暴力的根源。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一月份发生致命袭击后，塔利班发言人苏海尔·沙欣 (Suhail Shaheen) 承诺中国公民将是安全的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现任政府重申有义务维护中国公民和所有前往阿富汗投资、经商或旅游的其他公民的安全，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国宝石贸易商段也曾在巴基斯坦生活过，他对喀布尔的安全持谨慎乐观的态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“说实话，针对中国人的恐怖袭击在巴基斯坦[比在阿富汗]更加危险，但这并不意味着我们并不担心。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun 指出，过去一年坎大哈和喀布尔之间的机票价格更便宜，道路交通也有所增加，这些迹象表明该国的安全状况有所改善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说：“更多人开车的原因是现在没有炸弹袭击或恐怖组织在高速公路上肆虐。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但如果没有国际社会的认可和稳定的安全环境，阿富汗的经济复苏仍将困难重重。即使不需要几十年，也需要数年时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国的经济似乎从重新开放中受益。据世界银行统计，阿富汗今年第一季度政府收入同比增长8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;塔利班领导人声称阿富汗妇女拥有“自由、舒适、繁荣的生活”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;但朱表示，虽然数据显示出稳定甚至改善的迹象，但这很大程度上是由于国际援助而实现的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“塔利班的整个预算仍然存在巨大缺口，部分依靠外援支持，而该国自身的经济计划很大程度上尚未发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于制裁和安全风险，中国企业仍不愿在阿富汗投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;” p>;&lt;p>;“大多数公司在真正了解之后，就会对投资失去兴趣。按照经济规则，这实际上是正常的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国有企业与塔利班之间的商务谈判仍在继续，但朱表示，几乎所有谈判都面临长期拖延。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;今年一月，私营石油公司新疆中亚石油天然气公司（CAPEIC）签署了从阿姆河盆地开采石油的合同，这是塔利班政府自重新掌权以来与外国公司签署的第一份重大开采协议。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;CAPEIC将根据合同每年在阿富汗投资1.5亿美元，根据25年协议，三年内投资额将增至5.4亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们对阿富汗的未来感到乐观阿富汗。毕竟，经过这么多年的战争，它仍然是一个国家。”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他回忆起两年前塔利班重新掌权后在喀布尔与塔利班官员的一次会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“所有的外国人都逃走了，但只有你们中国人——你们已经在这里呆了20年了——还在这里，”他引用了一名塔利班官员当时的话说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 06:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Africa’s ex-leader Jacob Zuma freed as thousands released]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3230865/south-africas-ex-leader-jacob-zuma-freed-thousands-released?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 06:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/39204a5c-82dd-4c1d-8341-6fc4512a9050_b31af333.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;南非总统西里尔·拉马福萨对数千名非暴力罪犯给予宽大处理，其中包括他的前任雅各布·祖马 (Jacob Zuma) 被判藐视法庭罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;祖马，81 岁，周五凌晨被重新送入南非东部埃斯特科特的一所监狱，行政程序完成后不到两小时就被释放惩教署国家专员 Makgothi Thobakgale 在首都比勒陀利亚告诉记者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年祖马的入狱引发了南非自白人少数统治结束以来最严重的骚乱，导致354 人死亡，数千家企业被毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南非最高法院当年因祖马在其任期内未出席针对腐败指控的调查而判处 15 个月监禁，但他服刑时间还不到两年主要反对派民主联盟表示，释放祖马的决定引发了人们对执政的非洲人国民大会政客和其他公民在法律面前平等的质疑，并表示正在考虑采取法律行动来挑战它。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这对每一个南非人来说都是巨大的侮辱，”该党在一份声明中表示。 “先例已经明确设定。如果您是非洲人国民大会的高级成员，您将永远不会为西里尔·拉马福萨总统或任何非洲人国民大会政府领导下的罪行承担责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;释放祖马的最初决定是由时任非洲人国民大会主席阿瑟·弗雷泽做出的。监狱部门和该国前最高间谍声称自己是为了避免进一步的动乱，并否认他与前总统的密切关系在这一决定中发挥了任何作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而最高法院上诉发现祖马的提前释放是非法的，但没有具体说明他被软禁的时间是否应该代替他的刑期，这由托巴卡盖尔决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;被指控诈骗南非的古普塔兄弟被捕在阿联酋&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;首席大法官雷蒙德·宗多 (Raymond Zondo) 领导的一项调查揭露了一个腐败网络，从国家电力和铁路公用事业一直延伸到祖马及其内阁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，只有少数人迄今为止，南非已逮捕了两名商人，而被指控与祖马勾结窃取国库的商人阿图尔和拉杰什·古普塔无法从阿拉伯联合酋长国引渡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;祖马和古普塔兄弟否认有不当行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;祖马将于下周重返法庭，接受与国家军火交易有关的另一项腐败审判。他否认有不当行为。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US hoping for a low-key stopover by Taiwanese presidential contender]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230864/us-hoping-low-key-stopover-taiwanese-presidential-contender?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 05:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/1e35029d-f3e5-44b9-b35b-2dea006acd57_fc46147d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;预计美国和台湾当局将保留民进党总统候选人威廉本周末过境美国的计划与白宫有联系的华盛顿分析人士周五表示，赖清德尽可能低调，尽管这可能无法阻止台海军事演习的增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾副总统赖清德作为 1 月 13 日总统选举的主要候选人，他计划于周六在前往巴拉圭的途中在纽约停留至少一晚，并于周三回程时在旧金山停留不到一天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我认为这次凌日事件不会像一些人预期的那样成为新闻，”美国企业研究所高级研究员扎克·库珀说。 “我确实认为我们会看到大量飞机越过中线以及其他类型的令人担忧的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国人正在努力将其作为现状的一部分，因此我们得到习惯了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个自治岛屿多次安排中途停留，试图加强其国际影响力，北京认为这是极具挑衅性和破坏稳定的。周五，中国海事局宣布从周六中午开始在东海举行为期52小时的军事演习。虽然距离台湾海峡有一段距离，但该地区仍然敏感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴拉圭是少数几个在外交上承认台湾的国家之一。与台湾和乔·拜登总统政府关系密切的分析人士表示，赖智计划周日在纽约与台裔美国人社区成员举行宴会，但预计不会与美国官员或智库代表团会面。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;美国国务院发言人证实，黎智英将会见美国在台协会 (AIT) 主席劳拉·罗森伯格 (Laura Rosenberger)，该机构实际上是美国在台湾的大使馆，地点很可能位于旧金山。不太清楚的是，黎智英是否以及在哪里会与渴望评估他的两岸政策的国会议员和前美国官员坐下来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国将台湾视为一个通过武力与大陆统一的分裂省份如果需要的话。尽管华盛顿的政策是支持台湾的军事防御能力，但包括美国在内的很少有国家承认台湾是一个独立国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在巴拉圭，与台湾的关系不利于中国潜在的经济作用&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;华盛顿分析人士称，美国和台北都对低调过境感兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫在试图巩固双边关系的同时，担心进一步冒犯北京。一位密切关注美台政策的人士表示：“他们不希望发生任何会让局势冻结得更严重的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这方面，美国政府最近几周在华盛顿举行的会议上明确表示了这一点。该人士补充说，在与来访的国务院、五角大楼、国家安全委员会和美国在台协会等机构的黎智英顾问交谈时，他认为副总统需要留在自己的轨道上，“这是政府提出的一个话题，是的，赖副总统必须明白有多个听众在聆听他的信息，而在这种情况下，我们正在倾听每一个字。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府也采取了谨慎的礼节路线，以避免激怒分析人士表示，北京避免与黎智英进行官方接触，因为他是现任台湾官员，尽管这为华盛顿与其他候选人的访问铺平了道路，而这些候选人在技术上仍然是“私人”公民。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北京对美国的抗议因台湾总统候选人来访&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;因此，尽管黎智英副总统不愿访问华盛顿，但其他候选人——国民党的侯裕义；台湾人民党候选人柯文哲；他们补充说，甚至民进党副总统候选人一旦提名，也可能最早在下个月获得访问美国首都的许可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫对来自美国的批评也很敏感。国会和其他机构认为，它对中国过于软弱，对台湾支持不够，从其传递的信息中可以看出，中途停留“符合长期惯例”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民进党则持谨慎态度疏远美国并引发中国的强烈反应，以至于恐惧的选民在一月份转向被认为更接近北京的国民党。与此同时，它希望表现出其独立倾向基础的决心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然台湾总统蔡英文在处理台美中关系方面相对灵活而受到赞誉，但分析人士表示，它仍然黎智英是否会追随她的领导，或者制定更具挑衅性的路线，我们拭目以待。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果中国在未来几天内加强对台湾海峡的空中和海上入侵，分析人士仍然预计，其力度将不及广泛的军事行动。时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西一年前访问台湾后举行的演习——假设赖智星没有脱离剧本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士表示，这可能会安抚中国国内的强硬派，而不会过度惊动国际社会在北京试图吸引外国投资者之际。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计北京还将继续努力限制台湾的国际形象 — — 它最近说服洪都拉斯终止对台湾的外交承认，转而支持中国 — —台北安排美国中途停留的机会较少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果有一个时机成熟的话，他们可能会尝试推翻台湾的另一个外交盟友，”管理人员邦妮·格拉泽 (Bonnie Glaser) 说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中方上个月就黎智英访美向美方提出“严正交涉”。北京外交部上周发表声明表示，中方“坚决反对‘台独’分裂分子以任何名义、任何借口访美，坚决反对美方纵容和支持‘台独’活动。” &#39;分离主义者。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Donald Trump sustains his popularity despite legal troubles]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230737/how-donald-trump-sustains-his-popularity-despite-legal-troubles?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/c896aabe-db9d-4285-ad45-037cb43c5637_6e5e7ec9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普的法律麻烦继续升级。他已三度被起诉，涉及欺诈、非法窃取国家机密和干扰选举等案件。 Moreover, an investigation is open about suspicions of election manipulation in the state of Georgia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump has called these cases part of the “deep state”, a “witch hunt” and “persecution”.在佐治亚州共和党大会上，他甚至声称，“我们的敌人拼命想要阻止我们，因为他们知道我们是唯一能够阻止他们的人。” Meanwhile, many prominent Republicans refrain from confronting Trump&#39;s allegations, fearing that rejecting him will help the Democrats win.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s strategy seems to be working.根据锡耶纳学院 7 月份进行的一项民意调查，54% 的共和党初选选民更喜欢特朗普。 His closest rival, Florida Governor Ron DeSantis, garnered the support of only 17 per cent of respondents, and no other candidate managed to surpass even 3 per cent support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s tactics are divisive.他的言论将保守派分成了两个阵营。 Meanwhile, many observers struggle to explain his political longevity, considering the countless controversies he has fuelled and his ongoing legal challenges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, Trump generates both sympathy and tries to fuel antagonism as an effective political strategy, challenging political norms and making abrasive statements. This approach earns him unparalleled visibility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This strategy also works because political polarisation is rising in the United States. According to Gallup&#39;s annual Values and Beliefs survey, the number of people identifying as conservative or very conservative on social issues rose from 33 per cent last year to 38 per cent, the highest since 2012. Likewise, 44 per cent of Americans said they were conservative or very conservative on economic issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at Gallup&#39;s annual report, it is evident that within the framework of Democrats and Republicans, political moderation is not fashionable. In this context, Trump&#39;s aggressive rhetoric aligns with and accentuates the polarisation among his voters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beyond his rhetoric, Trump is also adept at connecting with his voters. 2020 年的一项研究从特朗普的性格背景对他的总统任期进行了考察，将他描述为一位具有大胆、雄心勃勃、好斗、冲动和主导性人格特质的领导者。 These highlight his ability to arouse people, engage with them and lead them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Setting aside Trump&#39;s leadership style, one must examine Trump&#39;s voter base to understand the dynamics at play. If one takes on board the personality traits described in the study and creates a parallel with sports, many insights can be gained.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump urges NFL owners to fire &#39;sons of b*****s&#39; who protest anthem&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For example, the National Football League – the top professional American football league – is the most popular sports league in the US. An Ipsos poll in January found 44 per cent of respondents considered professional football their favourite sport.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ipsos also examined the characteristics of voters who love the NFL. While 58 per cent of respondents who vote Democrat said games should be cancelled in the event of an in-game medical emergency, 64 per cent of Republicans said the game should continue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This kind of passion and commitment is also reflected in how Republicans still support Trump despite his losses and legal troubles. What sets Trump apart from other Republican candidates and forms a deeper bond with his voters is not just the usual political reasons – profound ideological views or grand economic plans – but people emotionally identifying with their leader.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This bond with voters can also be explained through social media.特朗普是利用社交媒体平台的高手。 Before the 2020 election, he allocated 47.3 per cent of his total advertising spending – more than US$200 million – to social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s discourse on social media is another significant point, attempting to be the “man of the people” and using common language.在一份分析 1 月 6 日国会大厦抗议活动的报告中，我检查了特朗普账户中的 241 条 Facebook 帖子和美国总统乔·拜登账户中的 150 条帖子。 It was surprising to see that Biden&#39;s posts were well constructed and grammatically sound while Trump shared posts even late at night, not bothering to address typos and grammatical errors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is also clear Trump&#39;s “America first” policy has significant support among working-class voters even as it comes in for substantial criticism. Polling suggests the most pressing issues in US voters&#39; minds are inflation and healthcare costs, not isolationism or other theoretical concepts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Considering all these facts, it is unsurprising that Trump remains the strongest Republican candidate.阻碍他连任的主要障碍是走法律程序。 Meanwhile, he remains an irreducible number in the American political equation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 05:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Judge warns Donald Trump not to threaten witnesses in 2020 election subversion case]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230862/judge-warns-donald-trump-not-threaten-witnesses-2020-election-subversion-case?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 04:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/12/8cc6eb1c-e412-482e-a1e1-9b0ba8ce49a8_7acfc626.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A federal judge on Friday granted former US president Donald Trump leeway to publicly share some non-sensitive evidence that will be used in his trial on charges of plotting to overturn the 2020 election, but she warned him to tread carefully before making inflammatory public statements about the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even arguably ambiguous statements by the parties or their counsel – if they can be reasonably interpreted to intimidate witnesses or to prejudice potential jurors – can threaten the process,” US District Judge Tanya Chutkan said on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I caution you and your client to take special care in your public statements about this case. I will take whatever measures are necessary to safeguard the integrity of these proceedings.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chutkan&#39;s warning came at a federal court hearing on Friday where prosecutors and Trump&#39;s lawyers hashed out disagreements over how much evidence in the case Trump can share with the public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chutkan&#39;s decision to permit Trump to share some non-sensitive material went against the objections of prosecutors, who pointed to threatening messages Trump posted last week on social media as evidence that he might try to use details of the confidential evidence to intimidate witnesses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The judge ruled that the government had not met its burden to show why all of the evidence should be subject to a “protective order”, which safeguards evidence from being shared with the public to prevent witness intimidation or tainting a jury pool.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, however, she agreed to protect certain records from disclosure that Trump wanted to share, such as excerpts from the hundreds of transcripts of witness interviews and recordings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She later officially approved a protective order that will allow Trump to share any records that are already in the public domain or that he obtained independently. He is not, however, permitted to share other kinds of materials such as those arising from the grand jury or items obtained through sealed search warrants.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;No way I can get a fair trial&#39;: Trump to seek new judge in 2020 election case&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“He is a criminal defendant.他将像其他被告一样受到限制。此案正在按正常顺序进行。”查特坎说。 “The fact the defendant is engaged in a political campaign is not going to allow him any greater or lesser latitude than any defendant in a criminal case.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The charges at issue in Friday&#39;s hearing are one of three prosecutions currently targeting Trump, the front-runner in the 2024 Republican presidential nomination race.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump has pleaded not guilty to criminal charges that he orchestrated a plot to overturn the results of the 2020 presidential election to keep himself in power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The existence of a political campaign is not going to have any bearing on my decision,” Chutkan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is standard for federal prosecutors to request protective orders before sharing evidence with defence lawyers to protect confidential records and ensure the integrity of the trial.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Often, defence lawyers do not oppose them because doing so slows down the government&#39;s production of evidence, a process known as “discovery”, to help them prepare. But Trump&#39;s lawyers said the scope of the protective order was too broad, and ran afoul of his constitutionally protected free speech rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This kind of blanket order is extraordinary,” Trump&#39;s lawyer John Lauro said on Friday. “We have to face the fact we are in uncharted waters.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Federal prosecutors revealed on Friday that they will soon release to Trump&#39;s defence team 11.6 million pages and records of evidence, in addition to a hard drive containing images extracted from electronic devices.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Prosecutors ask judge to issue protective order after Trump &#39;revenge&#39; post&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The government&#39;s request for a protective order last week cited a threatening message Trump posted last week on social media: “IF YOU GO AFTER ME, I&#39;M COMING AFTER YOU.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since then, Trump has also attacked Smith&#39;s character as well as that of former vice-president Mike Pence, a key witness in the case, calling his former No 2 “delusional.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a condition of his release, Trump agreed he would not try to intimidate or threaten any witnesses in the case, though no one has accused him of violating those conditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chutkan sought to remind Trump&#39;s lawyers about this on Friday, saying she will be watching his statements and “scrutinising them very carefully”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump is separately facing a second set of charges brought by Smith&#39;s office in Florida for retaining highly classified records after leaving the White House and New York state charges over hush-money payments to a porn star. He has pleaded not guilty in those cases as well.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At Friday&#39;s hearing, prosecutors asked the judge not to let Trump view sensitive evidence in a room by himself, noting he has been criminally charged in the Florida case with wilfully retaining classified material.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He has shown a tendency to hold onto material,” prosecutor Thomas Windom said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chutkan ruled that Trump will be allowed to view the evidence without his lawyers present, but during that time he will be banned from having access to electronic devices.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 05:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[FTX’s Sam Bankman-Fried headed for jail after judge revokes bail]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230863/ftxs-sam-bankman-fried-headed-jail-after-judge-revokes-bail?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 05:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/12/91a31e2b-cca9-40e6-8bee-758c083a858f_879f5cdf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A US judge on Friday revoked Sam Bankman-Fried&#39;s bail, after finding probable cause that the indicted founder of the bankrupt FTX cryptocurrency exchange tampered with witnesses at least twice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US District Judge Lewis Kaplan announced the decision at a hearing in federal court in Manhattan, less than two months before the scheduled October fraud trial. He rejected a defence request to delay Bankman-Fried&#39;s detention pending appeal of the bail revocation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision could complicate Bankman-Fried&#39;s efforts to prepare for trial, where the 31-year-old former billionaire faces charges of having stolen billions of dollars in FTX customer funds to plug losses at his Alameda Research hedge fund. Bankman-Fried has pleaded not guilty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He had a blank expression as he was led out of the courtroom by members of the US Marshals Service in handcuffs after removing his shoelaces, jacket and tie and emptying his pockets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His parents, both law professors at Stanford University, were present in the courtroom&#39;s audience.当他离开时，他的母亲芭芭拉·弗里德含泪向他点点头。 His father, Joseph Bankman, placed his hand over his heart as he watched his son be led away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bankman-Fried has been largely confined to his parents&#39; Palo Alto, California, home on US$250 million bond since his December 2022 arrest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Federal prosecutors in Manhattan first made their surprise request to jail Bankman-Fried last month, saying he “crossed a line” by sharing former romantic partner and Alameda Chief Executive Caroline Ellison&#39;s personal writings with a New York Times reporter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ellison and two other former members of Bankman-Fried&#39;s inner circle have pleaded guilty to fraud and agreed to cooperate with the US Attorney&#39;s Office in Manhattan. She is expected to testify against him at his scheduled October 2 trial.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US$3.5 billion? Sam Bankman-Fried and FTX&#39;s most outrageous purchases&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;As part of his bail conditions, prosecutors had been able to monitor his telephone and internet activity. Kaplan said he was concerned that Bankman-Fried showed the writings to the reporter during an in-person meeting at his parents&#39; home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was a way, in his view, of doing this in a manner in which he was least likely to be caught. He was covering his tracks,” said Kaplan, who is known for his no-nonsense demeanour in the courtroom and has also recently overseen defamation lawsuits against former US President Donald Trump and a sexual abuse lawsuit against Britain&#39;s Prince Andrew.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bankman-Fried sat with his shoulders hunched, leaning forward on the table and fidgeting with a Post-it note as he heard the judge order him detained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His lawyer Mark Cohen argued prosecutors mischaracterised his intentions in sharing Ellison&#39;s writings, saying Bankman-Fried wanted to defend his reputation and that he had a right under the US Constitution&#39;s First Amendment to speak to the press.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The defendant fairly believed he could make those comments,” Cohen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a July 26 hearing, Kaplan had restricted Bankman-Fried from speaking publicly about his case, and asked both sides to address whether jail was necessary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gag order has drawn attention from news media, including the Times, which in an August 2 letter to the judge said the measure should be loosened to only restrict comments that could interfere with a fair trial.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A July 20 article in the newspaper contained excerpts from Ellison&#39;s personal Google documents before FTX&#39;s collapse. She described being “unhappy and overwhelmed” with her job and feeling “hurt/rejected” from her personal break-up with Bankman-Fried.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;FTX&#39;s Sam Bankman-Fried and US Justice Department tussle over his communications&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;It was not immediately clear where Bankman-Fried would be held.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many defendants awaiting trial in New York are held at Brooklyn&#39;s Metropolitan Detention Centre, which has been plagued by persistent staffing shortages, power outages and reports of maggots appearing in inmates&#39; food.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Danielle Sassoon, a prosecutor, proposed at the hearing that Bankman-Fried instead be held at the Putnam County Correctional Facility, a medium-security jail about 88km (55 miles) north of Manhattan that holds about 68 inmates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sassoon said the defendant would be able to access an internet-enabled laptop there to review evidence to prepare for trial.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 05:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hunter Biden could face trial as US special counsel named]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230861/hunter-biden-could-face-trial-us-special-counsel-named?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 02:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/12/bd4659cf-4a35-462c-957b-21bf95772ea7_1f39acf6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden&#39;s son Hunter Biden may be headed for trial on criminal charges after talks on a potential plea deal reached impasse, the newly named US Special Counsel in the case, David Weiss, said on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moments earlier, US Attorney General Merrick Garland elevated Weiss, the federal prosecutor who has been handling the case, to special counsel status, which would give him additional authority to continue his investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Republicans in Congress have threatened an impeachment inquiry into unproven claims that Biden benefited from his 54-year-old son&#39;s business ventures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Weiss filed misdemeanour criminal tax and gun charges against Hunter Biden in June and both parties reached a proposed plea deal.但一名联邦法官拒绝接受这笔交易。 Weiss said in a court filing on Friday that the two sides are at an impasse and a trial is likely.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hunter Biden in July pleaded not guilty to charges of failing to pay taxes on more than US$1.5 million in income in 2017 and 2018 despite owing more than US$100,000, prosecutors allege. He did not enter a plea in a separate case where he is charged with unlawfully owning a firearm while using illegal drugs, which is a felony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Hunter Biden trial could create an unprecedented spectacle in US history: the son of a sitting president facing criminal charges while his father campaigns for re-election in 2024, probably against Republican Donald Trump who faces three concurrent criminal trials of his own.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Weiss, originally appointed to his position as US Attorney for Delaware by Trump, began investigating Hunter Biden in 2019. He was allowed to stay on during the Biden administration. His appointment as special counsel gives him more independence than federal prosecutors usually enjoy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Weiss said he might bring different charges against Hunter Biden in Washington or California, where the alleged criminal conduct took place. A lawyer for Hunter Biden did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Top US Republican McCarthy ponders Biden impeachment probe&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Weiss will produce a report when his work is done, Garland said, and the Justice Department will make as much of it public as is possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The appointment of Mr Weiss reinforces for the American people the department&#39;s commitment to both independence and accountability in particularly sensitive matters,” Garland told a press conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Republicans have accused the elder Biden of profiting from his son&#39;s business ventures in Ukraine and China, though they have yet to produce any evidence of wrongdoing. House of Representatives Speaker Kevin McCarthy said in July that the chamber might launch an impeachment inquiry in the autumn.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The White House declined to comment. Biden officials have previously dismissed Republican allegations as “insane conspiracy theories” and has said that Biden did not participate in his son&#39;s business affairs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hunter Biden has worked as a lobbyist, lawyer, consultant and investment banker and has said he has struggled with alcoholism and crack cocaine use.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Republicans said Weiss lacked credibility to continue the investigation. “如果韦斯谈判的甜心交易无法获得批准，那么他作为特别顾问怎么能被信任呢？” McCarthy said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Weiss is the third quasi-independent prosecutor appointed by Garland to handle politically sensitive investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Special Counsel Jack Smith has filed two criminal cases against Trump – one accusing him of trying over overturn his 2020 presidential defeat to Biden and a second that alleges he improperly took sensitive government documents with him when he left the White House and tried to prevent officials from recovering them.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As Hunter Biden reaches plea deal, a look at his troubled past&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Another special counsel, Robert Hur, is probing whether Biden mishandled classified documents after he left office as vice-president in 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hunter Biden has been a focus of several Republican congressional committees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One former associate told the House Oversight Committee that Hunter gave an impression that he emphasised his family ties while he was doing business in Ukraine nearly a decade ago, while his father was vice-president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That witness, Devon Archer, said Hunter spoke with his father daily but said the conversations did not involve business dealings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump also has frequently mentioned the younger Biden in an attempt to tar his father as the two for a possible rematch in the 2024 presidential election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His spokesman Stephen Cheung said Weiss should “quickly conclude” that Biden and his son “should face the required consequences”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A June Reuters/Ipsos poll found half of Americans, including 75 per cent of Republicans and 33 per cent of Democrats, believed the younger Biden received preferential treatment from Weiss. But most said that would not affect their vote next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk asks PM Giorgia Meloni to find ‘epic’ Italian site for Mark Zuckerberg fight]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230860/elon-musk-asks-pm-giorgia-meloni-find-epic-italian-site-mark-zuckerberg-fight?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.12 01:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/12/1d01b02a-e44e-4ec1-80b7-42ebc61ae036_b10b0312.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Tech billionaire Elon Musk, wanting a historic background for his planned fight against fellow tech billionaire and Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg, has turned to Italy&#39;s far-right Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni for a location.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk wrote on his online platform X (formerly Twitter) on Friday that he had spoken to both Meloni and her Minister of Culture Gennaro Sangiuliano.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They have agreed on an epic location,” he wrote, without revealing where it will be.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He did say that “everything in camera frame will be ancient Rome, so nothing modern at all”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those speculating that two of the world&#39;s richest men will battle it out like ancient warriors at the Colosseum in Rome should think again.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It will not take place in Rome,” Sangiuliano said, adding that he had a “long and friendly conversation” with Musk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are thinking about how to organise a great charity and historical event while respecting and fully protecting the sites,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk wrote on his platform that the “fight will be managed by [his] and Zuck&#39;s foundations”, referring to Facebook&#39;s Zuckerberg. Meloni&#39;s office had no initial comment on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Tourist who scratched name into Colosseum says he didn&#39;t know it was so old&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;There does appear to be a difference over where the money raised by such an event would go.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Italian culture minister said there were plans “to donate a large sum, many millions of euros, to two important Italian children&#39;s hospitals”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk, on his social media site, said “all proceeds go to veterans”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prospect of the fight first surfaced in June after Musk challenged Zuckerberg, who agreed. There was much press after that, but things quietened down, so many doubted the two would ever meet in the ring.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk recently repeatedly said that he wanted to fight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He wrote that the event would be broadcast live on his service X as well as Zuckerberg&#39;s Meta, Facebook&#39;s parent company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But those interested in seeing two middle-aged men duking it out with fists instead of posts or share prices will have to wait a bit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk, 52, needs surgery on his shoulder blade. It is rubbing against his ribs, he said, but thinks “recovery will only take a few months”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Death threats’ for Norway’s record-breaking climber who denies stepping over dying sherpa to reach K2 summit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230858/death-threats-norways-record-breaking-climber-who-denies-stepping-over-dying-sherpa-reach-k2-summit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.11 23:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/11/bfdfcecd-be99-4ae9-99fb-57bd416e9feb_15305890.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Norwegian climber who recently became the fastest person to summit the world&#39;s 14 highest peaks has addressed controversy after critics accused her of walking over a dying sherpa to set her record.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a lengthy Instagram post on Thursday, Kristin Harila, 37, said she and her team “did everything we could for him at the time”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Harila and her Nepali guide Tenjin “Lama” Sherpa became the fastest people to summit all 14 of the world&#39;s 8,000-metre mountains on July 27 after reaching the top of K2 in Pakistan&#39;s Himalayas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They completed the feat in three months and one day, surpassing Nepal-born British adventurer Nirmal Purja&#39;s 2019 record of six months and six days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But controversy emerged on social media after drone footage shared by other climbers showed Harila&#39;s team and others on a narrow, harrowing passage, stepping over the body of a fallen sherpa from another team, who later died during Harila&#39;s ascent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was also criticised for celebrating her world record at base camp that evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nobody will remember your sporting success, only your inhumanity,” wrote one critic on Instagram.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The blood of sherpas is on your hands,” said another.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Malaysian climber slammed for not thanking Sherpa who rescued him from Everest&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Harila said she felt the need to give her side of the story due to “all of the misinformation and hatred that is now being spread”, including “death threats”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said she, her cameraman and two others spent “1.5 hours in the bottleneck trying to pull him up”, referring to 27-year-old Mohammed Hassan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She then continued her ascent following a distress call from the fixing team ahead, leaving others behind with Hassan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her cameraman, identified only as Gabriel, was among those who stayed with Hassan, sharing his oxygen and hot water with him “while other people were passing by”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Considering the amount of people that stayed behind and had turned around, I believed Hassan would be getting all the help he could, and that he would be able to get down.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gabriel left after another hour when he needed “to get more oxygen for his own safety”, she wrote. When he caught up with Harila, “we understood that he [Hassan] might not make it down.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was heartbreaking.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On their descent, they discovered that Hassan had passed away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her team of four “was in no shape to carry his body down” safely, noting it would have required at least six people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His death was “truly tragic … and I feel very strongly for the family”, she said, but “we had done our best, especially Gabriel”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She noted that Hassan was “not properly equipped for the climb”, wearing neither a down suit nor gloves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Numerous Instagram users defended Harila&#39;s actions and noted the dangers involved, while others questioned why his operator had not equipped him better, with one cynically remarking that “local life is cheap”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>