<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Deadly violence flares in India’s Manipur state ahead of Modi no-confidence vote]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3230154/deadly-violence-flares-indias-manipur-state-ahead-modi-no-confidence-vote?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 19:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/d760dba2-edf1-45d5-9b04-35dc1a05428c_7c081a86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;东北部再次爆发冲突，至少六人死亡，军械库被抢劫印度曼尼普尔邦因未能遏制早先的冲突而对总理纳伦德拉·莫迪政府提出不信任动议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，周六，两个族群之间发生了长达一天的暴力事件，并发生了针对安全人员的袭击曼尼普尔邦警方和当地报道的社交媒体帖子。警方表示，他们正在突击搜查相关地区，以追回从军械库偷来的武器和弹药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 5 月份以来，少数民族部落群体与占多数的梅泰印度教徒之间围绕平权行动政策的冲突已造成 150 多人死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;印度莫迪因曼尼普尔邦的致命暴力事件面临不信任投票&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;上个月社交媒体上出现的一段视频显示两名妇女遭到性侵犯，引起了人们对该邦种族冲突的关注和愤怒莫迪领导的印度教民族主义印度人民党。这促使莫迪首次就席卷相对偏远、与缅甸接壤的曼尼普尔邦的冲突发表公开评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对党利用该视频事件向议会提出对政府的不信任动议。预计政府将于8月8日至10日讨论并答复该动议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于政府在议会下院拥有压倒性多数，不信任投票不会对政府构成威胁，但这场辩论将为反对派提供一个机会，在即将到来的关键选举之前，在妇女安全等敏感问题上将其逼入绝境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月在印度首都附近的印度教徒和穆斯林之间发生了致命的宗教冲突，曼尼普尔邦的暴力事件再次爆发。并有可能损害莫迪将印度展示为中国的战略制衡和投资替代品的努力。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 19:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mongolia signs digital skills partnership with Google as landlocked nation seeks closer ties with US]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230152/mongolia-signs-digital-skills-partnership-google-landlocked-nation-seeks-closer-ties-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/5f402503-ac66-4783-a92f-127caa345f07_d0fb6a82.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Google 与蒙古政府达成新合作伙伴关系，提供数字设备和培训蒙古的课堂，因为这个夹在中国和俄罗斯之间的东亚国家寻求加强与美国的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该计划，将向蒙古教师提供 20,000 台新的 Chromebook 笔记本电脑，并为 10,000 名教师提供培训蒙古政府在与这家加州公司的联合新闻稿中表示，其中包括提高课堂中技术使用的熟练程度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Google for Education 是蒙古的长期“重要合作伙伴”其表示，该计划旨在让该国学龄儿童为数字化转型的世界做好准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过与 Google 合作的这一举措，蒙古年轻人的生活机会不仅会得到改善，而且我们的繁荣也会得到改善。”蒙古总理 Luvsannamsrain Oyun-Erdene 表示：“初创企业生态系统和高创新行业的增长将得到进一步支持。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Google 还将向该国提供 100 万个 Google for Education Workspace 帐户和 1,000 个奖学金Google 教育和 ChromeOS 副总裁约翰·所罗门 (John Solomon) 表示，Google 职业证书旨在“提高蒙古人从网络安全到数据分析等高需求技术技能”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Google 高管和蒙古官员还讨论了根据他们的声明，其他合作机会将包括 Google for Start-ups、YouTube Local 和人工智能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oyun-Erdene 在一次重要的美国之行期间签署了该协议，他还在美国会见了美国副总统卡马拉·哈里斯、其他高级政府官员和私营部门人士上周在华盛顿讨论加强双边战略伙伴关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周三的联合声明中，蒙古和美国同意加强在以下领域的合作：稀土矿产、技术和能源。两国政府还对一项新的开放天空协议表示欢迎，该协议允许两国之间有直航。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒙古在全球科技领域发挥着越来越重要的作用，因为它蕴藏着丰富的稀土和铜矿床，这对于国防设备和电动汽车等高科技产品的制造，这是许多国家应对气候变化计划的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒙古今年与美国和中国建立了伙伴关系。内陆蒙古蒙古国的大部分贸易长​​期以来一直依赖其两个巨大邻国中国和俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国人口超过 300 万，其中 65% 年龄在 35 岁以下，这使其做好了准备据政府称，要利用全球数字和技术行业发展所提供的机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉首席执行官埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 最近与 Oyun-Erdene 就电动汽车领域可能的投资和合作进行了交谈。 SpaceX 是另一家由马斯克和卫星互联网系统 Starlink 运营商领导的公司，上个月获得政府批准在蒙古提供互联网服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去两年，蒙古在美国排名上升了 18 位国家电子政务发展指数，衡量一个国家如何利用信息技术来促进其人民的获取和包容。目前排名第 74 位。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 19:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Delhi halts plan to hide street dogs for G20 summit amid intense revamp]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3230153/new-delhi-halts-plan-hide-street-dogs-g20-summit-amid-intense-beautification-drive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 19:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/3a16b9f2-7c4f-451b-8d95-ea79fbf780f7_e89c8857.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度首都已叫停之前捕捉和隐藏数千只流浪狗的计划当地官员周日表示，世界各国领导人将抵达这座大城市参加下个月的 G20 峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新德里市政府周四宣布，将在精品酒店和热门旅游热点外围捕犬类，并将它们饲养在动物收容所中。当地官员周日表示，该政策在周末突然撤销，但没有解释原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地媒体报道称，这只狗-捕捉计划引起了德里居民和动物权利活动人士的反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;通过 G20 活动，印度寻求在有争议的克什米尔地区恢复正常&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据统计，德里街头有超过 60,000 只流浪狗2012 年印度牲畜普查，这是最新的政府数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地方当局定期开展绝育活动，以控制犬类数量，尽管城市周围的公园和居民区仍然存在狗群.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德里的许多流浪狗尽管没有正式的主人，但仍受到收养社区的喜爱，有些狗穿着特殊的犬夹克，以在城市严酷的冬天保暖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但它们对人类也构成危害，当地媒体经常报道全国各地凶猛的狗群咬伤幼儿的事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度各地每年报告约 1700 万起狗咬伤事件，世界卫生组织表示，全国每年有近 2 万人死于狂犬病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自印度去年担任 G20 主席国以来，拥有约 3000 万人口的德里都市区一直在大力开展美化活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在 9 月份的峰会之前，当局已清理了峰会场地附近的非法贫民窟，并改造了该市交通堵塞的主要干道，峰会将接待世界顶级经济体的领导人。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 19:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Different candlelit dinner’: restaurant in flood-hit area of China  serves up free meals for 200 disaster workers despite no  electricity or water]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/environment/article/3230035/different-candlelit-dinner-restaurant-flood-hit-area-china-serves-free-meals-200-disaster-workers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/9210c987-6a36-4a00-9391-92c9151c04ef_0e22688e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国北方遭受严重洪灾的一家餐厅在其餐厅接待了 200 名救灾人员没有电和水的免费烛光晚餐，以表达对受害者的尊重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台风“多克苏里”造成持续数天的创纪录降雨后，河北省涿州发生了毁灭性洪水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据新华社据消息称，洪水影响了该市近13.4万人，六分之一的居民被疏散。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国各地150多个民间救援队伍抵达涿州，帮助被洪水围困的人们。一位李姓居民告诉积木新闻，水位上涨得太快，他们来不及反应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了纪念救援人员的努力，一家餐馆自愿为200人提供热食。尽管没有电、水也很少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8月1日晚，距离灾区15公里的餐厅为刚从灾区一线返回的救援人员提供烛光晚餐。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该餐厅的宋老板称，厨师们冒着酷暑准备食物，还从附近的水厂借了水，做了25公斤的馒头、几锅米饭等菜肴。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宋说：“热腾腾的饭菜是给朋友们最好的安慰。”抖音（TikTok 的大陆版）为 500 至 1,000 名洪水灾民提供食物和住所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宋的餐厅是自洪水袭击以来普通民众做出的众多好撒玛利亚人贡献之一。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;8月2日，一名40多岁的涿州男子从自家二楼公寓游过数十米深的水，打开大院大门让救援船进入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据今日中国出版报道，数百名位于涿州仓库的多家出版商和书商也在洪水中遭受重创。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中央电视台报道，2017年左右，仓库从北京搬到涿州，为图书腾出空间。数字出版公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一家广泛使用的在线书店 bookschina.com 表示，他们的仓库里有 400 万本新书，占其库存的 80%，价值 3 亿元人民币（4200 万美元） ）按照挂牌价计算，估计是被洪水损坏了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是我们25年历史上最致命的挫折”，该店的微博账号8月2日表示。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;社交媒体上数十万人聚集起来帮助这家商店购买其预售“加油包”，其中包含四本书和两种创意产品，售价为 99 元（14 美元）。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;有些人还提出购买损坏的书籍。然而，该书店拒绝出售“可能在洪水中感染细菌和病毒”的书籍。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 18:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Calm pervades Niger’s capital as deadline to reverse coup expires, no sign of intervention]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3230151/calm-pervades-nigers-capital-deadline-reverse-coup-expires-no-sign-intervention?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 18:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/7bf1f578-21be-43f1-9706-39387ec60e72_8d294861.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;尼日尔首都周日很平静，公民似乎对威胁漠不关心随着该国政变领导人恢复总统职务的最后通牒到期，西非地区集团进行军事干预。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼亚美的街道上零星出现支持军政府的迹象，军政府表示不会屈服7月26日夺权后迫于外部压力下台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西非和中非三年来第七次政变震动了西萨赫勒地区，该地区是世界上最贫穷的地区之一，具有战略意义俄罗斯、中国和西方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 100 人在尼亚美空军基地附近设立了纠察线，并承诺在必要时进行非暴力抵抗，支持新军事政府。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西非国家经济共同体的国防部长于 7 月 30 日就军事行动达成一致，其中包括如果被拘留的总统穆罕默德·巴祖姆 (Mohamed Bazoum) 未能在周日之前获释并恢复职务，则将在何时何地进行打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;西非领导人制定了对尼日尔进行军事干预的计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与西非经共体制裁相关的迫在眉睫的困难也已在断电和基本食品价格飙升中得到体现，但许多当地人似乎并没有被吓倒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我并不担心，因为我知道西非经共体对尼日尔的任何军事干预都会对该组织造成损失。这不符合领导人的利益。”周日早上，59 岁的家庭主妇 Hadjo Hadjia 在首都一条几乎空无一人的街道上说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全城各地的婚礼庆祝活动通常在周末举行，一切照常进行，周六见证了几场盛装打扮的婚礼派对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西非经共体没有回应就其下一步行动或周日截止日期何时到期发表评论的请求。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;该集团的承诺引发了人们对该地区进一步冲突的担忧，该地区已经在与致命的伊斯兰叛乱作斗争，这场叛乱已造成数千人死亡，迫使数百万人逃离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日尔政变领导人的支持邻国马里和布基纳法索的军政府可能会破坏该地区的应对措施。两国均表示将保卫尼日尔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国周六表示，将支持推翻政变的努力，但未具体说明其支持是否需要为西非经共体干预提供军事帮助，而巴祖姆总理Ouhoumoudou Mahamadou 表示，被赶下台的政权仍然相信有可能在最后一刻达成协议。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 18:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thai ex-PM Thaksin seen in video at Cambodian leader Hun Sen’s birthday party]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3230148/thai-ex-pm-thaksin-seen-video-cambodian-leader-hun-sens-birthday-party?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 17:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/7aabfc95-daf0-4fd9-a583-6259e55e020f_b20de613.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;泰国前总理他信出席为即将离任的柬埔寨首相洪森举办的生日聚会根据周日发布的视频，他信在金边表示，在多年的自我流放之后，他将推迟返回泰国的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他信在柬埔寨露面正值政治敏感时期。在邻国泰国，为泰党是一系列与他信有关联的政党中最新的一个，它正在寻求在议会赢得足够的支持，以便其一名成员在 5 月份大选近三个月后成为下一任总理。 p>;&lt;p>;他信周六在 X 平台（以前称为 Twitter）上表示，他将以医生预约为由，将下周四返回泰国的计划推迟“不超过两周”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;他的女儿 Paetongtarn Shinawatra 在最近一次选举中与为泰党一起竞选总理，近两周前曾表示，她的父亲将于 8 月 10 日返回泰国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国面临着意想不到的困难时期进步党在5月14日的民意调查中出人意料地获胜，该党寻求在多个领域进行改革，其中包括严格禁止诽谤王室的有争议的法律。前进党领导人 Pita Limjaroenrat 上个月首次要求议会提名他为新总理，但失败了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于政治僵局持续存在，前总理他信推迟返回泰国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他信2001 年当选泰国总理，并于 2005 年轻松连任，但在 2006 年因军事政变而下台。他被指控腐败、滥用权力以及不尊重该国君主制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他于 2017 年逃离泰国。 2008 年，他在几起刑事案件中逃脱了监禁，他谴责这些案件是出于政治动机，但回国后仍可能被判入狱十多年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由他的妹妹英拉·西那瓦 (Yingluck Shinawatra) 领导的政府被2014 年也因军事政变而被赶下台。她还面临刑事指控并流亡国外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他信周六关于推迟回国的消息并未提及柬埔寨之行，而是在洪森官方网站上发布了一段视频TikTok 帐户显示，在柬埔寨首都郊区的柬埔寨领导人官邸举行的生日聚会上，他信站在洪森旁边，洪森的家人也加入其中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲任职时间最长的领导人洪森转身周六71日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频中也出现了英拉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，他信和洪森关系密切，互视对方为“干兄弟”。 2009年，洪森任命他信为柬埔寨政府顾问，但他信很快就辞去职务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月26日，洪森宣布将于8月22日辞去首相职务，将权力移交给他信。长子洪马奈领导的柬埔寨人民党在 7 月 23 日的选举中取得压倒性胜利，担任该国陆军参谋长。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[University scientists in Hong Kong get rare US approval for clinical trials of new Chinese medicine-based constipation treatment]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3230150/university-scientists-hong-kong-get-rare-us-approval-clinical-trials-new-chinese-medicine-based?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 17:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/66554dba-cf0c-4e7b-976f-76ceda698779_bb0​​0cbfc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国一所大学的科学家开发的慢性便秘传统疗法的新变化香港成为第一个在美国获批进行临床试验的中药植物药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浸会大学中草药药物开发中心(CDD)周日表示，这一决定是一个重大里程碑可能会导致其CDD-2101药物打入全球市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该校副校长、中医学院临床部主任卞兆祥教授表示，美国试验，中医药管理局（FDA）批准，将于今年晚些时候开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“FDA的授权是香港中医药发展的一个里程碑，”同时也是中医药管理局局长的卞氏说。大学中草药药物开发中心周日表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国在药物审批方面拥有权威地位。在许多情况下，该药物在美国获得批准后，还会在其他国家获得批准。这将有助于该药物的国际化。”他告诉《华盛顿邮报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卞表示，希望在四到六年内将这种新药引入美国市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，没有中药已获FDA批准在美国市场销售，获批进入临床试验的中药不超过8种。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CDD-2101是由所用中药配方“麻子仁丸”研制而成治疗便秘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主要成分包括火麻仁、大黄、厚朴、苦杏子、麸炒橘子、白芍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卞氏团队2020年，在政府资助下开始改进麻子仁丸的原始配方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科学家们于3月份与芝加哥大学和澳门大学合作向 FDA 提交了试验申请，并在一个月后获得批准.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一阶段临床试验将涉及美国20名健康患者，预计2024年完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港深化中西医合作&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;第二阶段将收集慢性便秘患者的安全性和有效性信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最终研究将是一项大规模的工作，以评估该药物的有效性并寻找任何意料之外的情况。副作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卞说，研究表明，全世界大约 14% 的人患有慢性便秘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，美国大约一半的药物旨在缓解便秘。治疗便秘效果不佳，60%至70%的患者对治疗不满意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这证明临床对新药有需求。现有的药物无法满足患者的需求。”卞说。 “我们认为这对中医药来说是一个非常好的机会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卞说，麻子仁丸历来是治疗便秘最广泛使用的中药之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他解释道新配方易于服用，质量控制良好，每个处方的有效期为七至八周，与一线西药治疗效果相似。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，该药物可以通过西药处方给患者服用。 ”活性成分 – 符合 FDA 标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“药物中使用的草药的质量可能会根据其来源和收获季节而有所不同，”卞解释道。 “但是当我们用草药开发药物时，我们需要制定适当的质量标准。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的药物有六种草药，每种都含有大约一千种成分。我们如何对这六种药材进行质量控制，确保每批药品的质量相同，是最具挑战性的部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卞说，团队还咨询了前FDA评审员、内地专家的意见。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，香港的中药研发可以受益于中国内地的支持、政府的支持以及研究团队的学术经验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“我们希望中医药能够走出香港、走出中国”，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“麻子仁丸是中医药的瑰宝。怎样才能把它变成世间的瑰宝呢？”他问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们需要一个国际化的过程。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[HK$17 billion Hong Kong business boost and 4,000 new jobs trumpeted by finance secretary Paul Chan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3230147/hk17-billion-hong-kong-business-boost-and-4000-new-jobs-trumpeted-finance-secretary-paul-chan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 17:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/f08c1496-4cbf-4828-bfe9-57a1bd4ba9c2_6085f93d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;超过 25 家顶级企业已承诺投资超过 170 亿港元（2.2 美元）财政部长表示，香港将创造至少 4,000 个就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈茂波周日在他的每周博客中写道，他预计今年将有更多公司在香港扩大业务。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过聚集领先、有潜力的企业，可以带动相关产业链的发展，吸引更多的企业陈先生解释道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，这25家企业中有很多属于创新科技领域，其市场或估计价值为超过 100 亿元人民币（14 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 表示，大部分新职位将涉及研发以及高级管理人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，拥有计划在该市扩张或已经增加业务的企业包括必人科技、地平线机器人、多点和元华科技。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈表示，华为、美团和京东等科技巨头也参与其中。扩大业务并在香港开发新业务 - 并预测更多公司将效仿。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港经济增长将在第二季度逐渐放缓：Paul Chan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他补充说，更多战略企业招商办公室（OASES）已联系了超过200家企业，该办公室的成立旨在通过提供特殊奖励来吸引高潜力和代表性企业入驻该市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府早些时候推出了一系列政策在经历了三年的 Covid-19 破坏和 2019 年的反政府抗议活动后，吸引全球人才和企业来到香港，以振兴香港经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括顶尖人才通行证计划，为过去 12 个月内收入至少 250 万港元或世界排名前 100 的大学之一的毕业生并在过去五年中工作过三年的成功候选人提供两年期签证。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;香港GDP数据预示前路艰难&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;过去5年排名前100的毕业生，工作经验不足3年也可申请，但上限为10,000名&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;入境事务处表示，截至 6 月，去年 12 月启动的顶尖人才计划已成功申请 25,961 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港还预留 300 亿港元设立“联合投资基金”，旨在通过商业投资将企业引入香港。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 17:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A safety row hits a Chinese high- speed railway. How serious is the problem?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3230139/safety-row-hits-chinese-high-speed-railway-how-serious-problem?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/b601832c-aacc-4c12-96f9-c153c5d7d52c_5e80d763.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一家中国报纸指控一家知名国有建筑公司偷工减料，造成国营《经济参考报》7月20日发表的指控称，一座高铁大桥的地基支柱明显短于高铁大桥的基础支柱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;设计长度，引发人们对中国高铁安全性和可靠性的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但一些业内专家认为，需要进行更全面的调查才能确定真相。他们表示，桩长短于设计的情况在工程中很正常，丑闻可能更多的是官僚纠纷，而不是安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;争论围绕着莱荣高速的建设展开。中国东部山东省的铁路。该铁路项目是该省高速铁路网的组成部分，全长 193 公里（120 英里），列车最高时速可达 350 公里/小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约 50 公里的铁路由中国建筑集团承建第八工程部（又称八师部），于2020年11月开工建设，6月下旬完成工程初步质量验收。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国中部河南省三杰实业有限公司，一期工程该段铁路分包商举报称“贪污违法”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们声称八师克扣建筑材料，造成桩基质量问题”据《经济参考报》报道，《经济参考报》记者表示，他已核实该报道。他表示，他将施工方案与分包商的工单进行了比对，发现具体使用情况不一致，说明偷工减料的说法属实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;山东当地政府随后派出工作组前往调查，并承诺发布结果。由于中建八局总部设在上海，上海铁路监管部门也派出团队前往山东进行独立调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国当局调查高铁建设指控&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;业内一位匿名工程师表示，与桩长相关的腐败行为“几乎是标准做法”，这意味着过去其他公司在桩基工作中也曾出现过类似情况，而且这个问题并非该项目所独有.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题引起了国家的关注，因为铁路桩基承载着整个高铁系统的重量；其建设中的任何缺陷都可能造成严重后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;值得注意的是，该事件发生在中国引以自豪的行业——基础设施发展领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然官方正在进行的调查结果由于调查尚未披露，业内人士指出，媒体报道可能并未完全涵盖问题的复杂性。对安全的影响可能有限，报告背后可能存在更复杂的利益纠纷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《经济参考报》报道称：“三界的经理肖伟国表示，虽然设计要求桩长为 14.5 米或 15.5 米 [48 或 50 英尺]，实际桩大多在 10 米到 13 米之间，超过 90% 的桩长度短于[要求]。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一明显不足的消息被其他媒体转载，被视为严重违规。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，一位经验丰富的匿名承包商表示，桩长不同是正常的，称“实际施工情况可能与设计图纸有冲突”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而前桥梁设计师张伟在个人微信社交媒体账号上表示：“官方媒体报道的结果很可能是真的。很可能部分桩的长度没有达到设计长度。然而，这种潜在的违规或腐败并不一定会导致安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“建筑中使用的桩有三种类型：摩擦桩、端承桩和嵌岩桩。第一种利用土壤和桩基之间的摩擦力来提供支撑。另外两个利用地下岩层的支撑，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在选择合适的桩并设定预算之前，会聘请地质团队来检测岩层的深度。成本考虑意味着在每个桩位都钻探钻孔是不可行的。地质学家的常见指导方针是每隔一段时间钻孔，并根据经验估计之间的岩石深度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不可能准确地知道整条铁路线上数百个岩石的分布情况。公里。因此，地质团队往往会谨慎行事，而设计人员会增加额外的长度以确保安全裕度。设计图纸中还会注明“最终地质数据应以现场钻孔数据为准”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“施工队在11米深度钻孔时遇到了困难。 To avoid responsibility, they requested to continue drilling till the design depth of 14.5 metres, but the Eighth Division ordered them to start pouring concrete immediately, causing a disagreement between the two parties,” according to the official Economic Information Daily report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang said: “It is possible that the drillbit equipped could only penetrate the soil layer and encountered resistance at the rock layer at 11 metres. If the design called for end-bearing piles, which only need to reach the rock layer instead of drilling through it, there would be no need to continue drilling. That also answers why the site supervisor, a third party, did not raise any objections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the construction of end-bearing piles, if the drill reached a depth of 20 metres and hasn&#39;t reached rock layers – even if the design depth is 15 metres – the drilling must continue. The design length given by the design institute is meant to ensure contact with the rock layer, not to be adhered to rigidly.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sanjie&#39;s manager Xiao Weiguo also made further allegations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official media report said that “during the conflict, the head of the project with the China Construction Eighth Engineering Division told Xiao: &#39;Do what you can, if you can&#39;t, get out&#39;. Following that, the Sanjie company was kicked out of the construction site in the middle of the project”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;National regulations stipulate that if there is a discrepancy between on-site data and the design drawing, new data should be submitted for a redesign. The budget should be revised accordingly, but this can affect profits and the progress of the project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There&#39;s a chance that staff at the Eighth Division have concealed the actual rock depth to get extra funding. However, any embezzled funds and safety effects are likely minor,” Zhang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The China Construction Eighth Engineering Division, which has more than 50,000 employees and six major branches, is one of the most profitable and experienced companies in the sector. It earned net profits of 12.25 billion yuan (US$1.7 billion) last year, making it the second most profitable subsidiary of China State Construction Engineering Corporation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China to hasten infrastructure push to aid growth amid call to assess debt level&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;It took part in major projects such as the new Xiamen airport, Changsha airport expansion and the Hannan Yangtze River Bridge in Wuhan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official results of an investigation have not been released.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The China Construction Eighth Engineering Division has been contacted for comment and is yet to respond.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s Cross-Harbour Tunnel logs 12 per cent rise in peak traffic despite new toll fees, but start of morning rush hour pushed back]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3230144/hong-kongs-cross-harbour-tunnel-logs-12-cent-rise-peak-traffic-despite-new-toll-fees-start-morning?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 16:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/06/d0c33324-d5af-457e-94ad-6bfaddf039fe_f5bd210c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Traffic during peak periods at Hong Kong&#39;s bustling Cross-Harbour Tunnel has risen by nearly 12 per cent since new tolls took effect to help ease congestion, an official has said, but noted the policy has pushed back the start time for the morning rush hour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Commissioner for Transport Rosanna Law Shuk-pui on Sunday also expressed confidence the second phase of the overhaul, expected to launch later this year, would help alleviate traffic conditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the “6-3-3” scheme began on Wednesday, the charge for private cars travelling through the Western Harbour Tunnel decreased from HK$75 (US$9.60) to HK$60, while fees for those using the Eastern Harbour Tunnel and Cross-Harbour Tunnel rose to HK$30 from HK$25 and HK$20, respectively.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taxi drivers are only charged HK$25 when using any of the three crossings.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong drivers &#39;unfazed by cross-harbour tunnel tolls, as taxis welcome change&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The current scheme is running smoothly at the three tunnels. But it has not resulted in significant reductions in traffic,” Law told a television programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the commissioner, the hourly number of vehicles travelling through the Cross-Harbour Tunnel during peak periods reached between 2,800 to 2,900, up from 2,600 before the new tolls took effect.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The total volume of traffic had also risen from 105,000 to 107,000 each day, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But we have noticed that more taxis are using the Western Harbour Tunnel, regardless of whether its peak hours or at night,” she said. “And we also observed that unlike before, more taxis are willing to make the crossing during peak hours.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Law stopped short of providing any figures for the number of taxi drivers using the crossings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The commissioner also said the policy had contributed to smoother traffic at the busy Cross-Harbour Tunnel, pushing back the start of the 15-minute window for morning rush hour from 8.15am to 8.45am.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The current measures were purely “transitional” and coming plans to vary tolls at each tunnel based on the time of day would “greatly reduce traffic congestion”, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Law said authorities were confident the second phase would help divert traffic away from busier crossings and promote public transport, citing a government survey that showed a HK$20 toll difference could change the habits of motorists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The poll collected responses from about 90,000 Hongkongers, 12 per cent of whom were private car owners, between September and January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They have provided us with a consistent answer that they would consider changing their driving habits if there was a HK$20 price difference at tunnels, like they would go to the tunnels they seldom used before or even turn to public transport,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But that could be achieved only after the second phrase is launched.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What you need to know about Hong Kong&#39;s new tolls for its harbour tunnels&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The scheme&#39;s next stage will see private cars travelling during peak periods at 7.30am to 10.15am and 4.30pm to 7pm charged HK$60 at the Western Harbour Tunnel, while fees for the Cross-Harbour Tunnel and Eastern Harbour Tunnel will be HK$40.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All three tunnels will charge private cars HK$30 between 10.15am and 4.30pm and HK$20 between 7pm and 7.30am the next day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To deter drivers from rushing to cross before prices change, tolls will rise or fall by HK$2 every two minutes during the change over to peak-hour or non-peak-hour periods until they reach the maximum rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Commercial vehicles will be charged HK$50 at all three crossings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All three crossings will charge private cars HK$25 during the day and HK$20 at night on Sundays and public holidays.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How the Asian Youth Orchestra is marching on after co-founder Richard Pontzious’ death in 2020]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/arts-culture/article/3229948/how-asian-youth-orchestra-marching-after-co-founder-richard-pontzious-death-2020?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.06 16:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/04/624f166f-02e6-4340-93c2-d3a3f23bd99f_59651cdc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A gaping void will be apparent at next weekend&#39;s (August 12-13) homecoming for the Asian Youth Orchestra (AYO), its first concerts in Hong Kong without the larger-than-life presence of its American co-founder Richard Pontzious, who died in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He was the fundraiser. He was the writer. He was the musician. He was the whole package,” says Keith Lau, the orchestra&#39;s Hong Kong-born general manager, who has taken over the day-to-day running of the 33-year-old training platform for aspiring professional musicians.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The orchestra was entirely Pontzious&#39; idea. Back in the 1980s, he was conductor-in-residence at the prestigious Shanghai Conservatory of Music. He had already spent two decades teaching music in Taiwan and Japan, and strongly felt that young musicians in the region lacked the visibility and opportunity to take their careers further.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was a testament to his power of persuasion that he convinced the legendary violinist Yehudi Menuhin to be the AYO&#39;s founding music director in 1987, and secured long-term patronage from wealthy music lovers in Hong Kong, the city where he decided to launch the orchestra.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Each year, he would audition musicians aged 17-27 for entry to an intense summer camp of rehearsals and masterclasses, followed by high-level public performances in multiple cities. Musicians stay with the orchestra for a year, before a new cohort is recruited.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the AYO continued to take on board 100 new musicians each summer, the alumni body grew to number thousands, with many placed in professional orchestras around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why has there been an exodus of staff from the Hong Kong Arts Centre?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Pontzious showed no intention of wanting to retire. But after he turned 76, he suddenly fell ill and died from pneumonia in Hong Kong, in the middle of the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The doctor was very kind,” Lau recalls. “[Richard] was in intensive care for a long time and the doctor would let me see him once a week. It was a special arrangement because with Covid, you are not supposed to visit in a public hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And then later, when we moved him to a private hospital, I stayed with him 24 hours in the hospital.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was very difficult to have lost him, of course, after so many years,” he says quietly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lau and Pontzious were inseparable for nearly three decades. The former was working for an airline when they first met, and it was Pontzious who introduced him to the world of classical music and then made him general manager of the AYO in 1998.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I just learned from the job. He often said that I had good ears. Especially in the later years we would often look at each other during an audition and silently agree on who was good and who was a &#39;no, thank you&#39;. And now, I&#39;ve been with the orchestra for 25 years,” he says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A major reason why the AYO has kept going after Pontzious died – leaving no succession plan – is because of the continued financial support from patrons such as Jim Thompson, the billionaire founder, CEO and chairman of logistics firm Crown Worldwide, and chairman of the orchestra&#39;s board.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When Richard was still in hospital, Jim asked me what would happen if we lost him and I said I didn&#39;t know. Even before, when the board asked me what would happen if Richard decided to retire, I would say I didn&#39;t know. Richard Pontzious was AYO,” Lau says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Lau carried on, by default, with the board&#39;s encouragement. The artistic side of things is now being taken care of by principal conductor Joseph Bastian, who has been touring with the AYO for several years, and the new assistant conductor, Hong Kong-born Sophie Mok.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Conductors can never get sick, but we decided to have an assistant conductor for the first time this year,” Lau says. “Sophie has been studying in Miami and she was picked out of over 50 applicants for the position.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The orchestra regrouped in 2022 after travel restrictions were lifted, after which successful applicants from the pandemic years, plus new recruits, all got together in Bergamo, Italy for summer camp, rehearsals and concerts in Italy and Germany.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That year&#39;s intake was half the usual size of a 100-strong orchestra. This year, however, has seen it recover to the full level, with players coming from 12 different countries and territories, including Singapore, Taiwan, Macau, mainland China, Vietnam, Thailand, the Philippines and Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is the first time we have someone from Uzbekistan. Javlon Khayitov is a bassoon player currently studying in Singapore. He&#39;s a very good player,” Lau says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The orchestra has just completed its European tour after summer camp in Bergamo. It will give two public concerts in Hong Kong on August 12 and 13 before taking off again for Thailand, Taiwan and Japan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The young musicians are getting to play with well-established professionals as usual: for this tour they are violinist Ning Feng, cellist Alban Gerhardt and soprano Lydia Teuscher, who appear in two programmes that range from Rossini&#39;s rousing William Tell Overture to Mahler&#39;s contemplative Symphony No. 4.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fact that Pontzious&#39; spirit remains with the orchestra is made clear by the AYO&#39;s decision to keep his name prominently on the concert fliers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even before this year&#39;s tour is over, Lau is already agonising over next year&#39;s arrangements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One challenge is to look for space to rehearse in Hong Kong. We can&#39;t keep going to Bergamo and Hong Kong has always been a good base because every musician from Asia can get a visa to come here. We used to go to Hong Kong Academy of Performing Arts but they are getting busy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Jumping on one leg&#39;: Hong Kong&#39;s West Kowloon arts hub CEO describes money woes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In terms of Pontzious&#39; legacy, Lau is of the view that “if it ain&#39;t broke” then they might as well keep the operational model as it is.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Richard was the whole package and you can never find another one like him anywhere. What I am doing now is what I was doing before, plus a little bit more of the fundraising and writing to the sponsors to stay in touch. Fortunately, everybody&#39;s been very kind so far.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asian Youth Orchestra, Hong Kong City Hall Concert Hall, August 12-13, 7.30pm&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 06 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>