<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[World’s first mass-produced humanoid robot? China start-up Fourier Intelligence eyes two-legged robots with AI brains]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3230850/worlds-first-mass-produced-humanoid-robot-china-start-fourier-intelligence-eyes-two-legged-robots-ai?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/8945fe8e-9967-46d4-881b-bf54fdddf29d_b80c6778.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当 Fourier Intelligence 在 2020 年展会上推出其瘦长、漆黑的人形机器人 GR-1 时7 月在上海举行的世界人工智能大会 (WAIC) 立即抢尽风头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然自 11 月 OpenAI 的 ChatGPT 推出以来，全球科技界一直关注人工智能 (AI) 软件，但中国制造的GR-1——据说能够以每小时5公里的速度用两条腿行走，同时承载50公斤的负载——让人们想起了从特斯拉到小米等跨国公司正在追求的双足机器人的潜力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于上海的初创公司 Fourier 来说，GR-1 是一次不太可能的胜利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是我们一次前所未有的尝试 - 当它出现时我们几乎没有任何参考资料Fourier 创始人兼首席执行官 Alex Gu 最近在中国金融之都接受《南华早报》采访时表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fourier 的关注点并不总是在人形机器人上。该公司以 19 世纪法国数学家和物理学家约瑟夫·傅里叶 (Joseph Fourier) 的名字命名，最初于 2015 年在上海科技中心张江成立，旨在开发康复机器人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司目前的产品包括智能健身车、无线机器人手套和一系列计算机引导的装置，帮助用户恢复手臂和腿部的运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但就像他的许多同龄人一样，42 岁的顾是机械工程专业的毕业生来自上海交通大学的他一直梦想着创造自己的人形机器人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;于是在2019年，Fourier将其智能康复设备带入了10多个国家的数百家医院和医疗中心，并在全球站稳脚跟。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时，由于技术壁垒和开发成本较高，世界上很少有公司能够成功推出人形机器人。在美国，有一些项目，包括波士顿动力公司的Atlas（该公司以机器狗Spot而闻名）和Agility Robotics的Digit。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国，大多数公司选择将精力集中在轻量化上。四足机器人等产品。顾认为他可以做得更好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“康复机器人中使用的许多技术本质上也适用于人形机器人，”顾说。 “人形机器人需要非常好的电机，既强大又轻便，我们能够自己开发它们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;GR-1诞生于傅里叶总部一楼的一个小实验室，那里上个月记者走访时，一群工程师正在忙着改进和测试机器人。该团队在 2022 年（项目启动三年后）取得了重大突破，成功使这个 1.65 米高的机器人能够用双腿站立并行走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们看到它站立时第一次不受束缚地自行行走，这对我们所有的工程师来说都是一个很大的鼓励。”顾说。 “感觉就像抚养一个刚出生的婴儿。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fourier 后来在网上发布了一段 GR-1 行走的视频，得到了很多观众的称赞，但也有很多人持怀疑态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一些海外观众表示该视频是计算机生成的，”顾说。 “我知道这个领域还处于早期阶段，人们会有不同的看法，就像20年前有人争论电动汽车是否能够在道路上行驶一样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了尽管存在技术挑战，研究人员和机器人专家警告说，企业在更广泛的消费市场中将人形机器人商业化仍面临巨大困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[人形机器人]现在大多生活在实验室中，而且非常昂贵，”说张晓荣，中国神都科技研究院院长。 “一台质量相对较高的机器可能要花费数百万元。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些问题并没有阻止企业尝试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国智能手机巨头小米创始人雷军，2022 年 8 月在舞台上展示了​​该公司的第一个人形机器人 Cyber​​One，它被认为能够行走，但除此之外没有什么其他功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不到两个月后，特斯拉亿万富翁创始人埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 推出了原型机在公司的人工智能日期间展示其备受期待的 Optimus 机器人。它在舞台上现场行走和跳舞。观众还观看了一段机器人执行搬运盒子和移动金属棒等任务的视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克在上个月的 WAIC 会议上表示，Optimus 的目的并不是“拥有极高的智能”，而是为了帮助人类完成“无聊、重复或危险的任务”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;顾说他与马斯克有着相似的愿景，但补充说机器人“也可以通过提供情感价值成为人类非常好的朋友”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;虽然当前的人形机器人“在运动和认知能力方面与人类仍有很大差距”，但大型语言模型 (LLM)（支持 ChatGPT 等人工智能聊天机器人的软件类型）的开发可能会“改变时代” ”，顾说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“法学硕士将赋予机器人逻辑推理的能力，使它们变得更像人类，”顾说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然顾强调傅立叶将专注于Fourier 联合创始人兼首席战略官 Zen Koh 表示，一些人工智能公司已经在法学硕士领域寻求潜在合作，他们开发构成机器人“身体”的硬件，并让人工智能开发人员专注于“大脑”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望与所有主要企业合作，并且……作为一个系统，保持开放，”Koh 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;GR-1 机器人已经以小型形式交付。顾说，数量给一些大学和人工智能公司进行研发。他计划在年底前开始量产，并在 2024 年交付数千台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克去年还声称可以在 2023 年开始生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;顾预计傅里叶的人形机器人，他表示，在养老、教育、宾客接待等多种场景中，该机器人具有巨大的潜力，未来三到五年将比康复机器人产生更多的收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，还有很长的路要走。在人形机器人成为我们日常生活的一部分之前，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不要指望一年左右就会出现奇迹 - 即使对于特斯拉来说，我们也必须给他们时间[以实现大规模生产人形机器人]，”顾说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，不要低估这个东西可能在五年或十年内成为人们家庭生活一部分的可能性。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘The first Chinese chief in Africa’, but does he – and others like him – wield any real influence?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3230814/first-chinese-chief-africa-does-he-and-others-him-wield-any-real-influence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 07:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/f14e5c78-08bd-4385-89da-72f8e5560c4a_6b076722.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;50岁时，前英语教师胡杰国移居尼日利亚并建立了一家价值数百万美元的中式酒店，当时东亚面孔在那里并不常见。现年 70 多岁的胡生活在拉各斯，周围都是政府资助的、手持冲锋枪的警卫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡在 2001 年被授予酋长头衔时得到了这种保护，这对于非非洲人来说是一项罕见的荣誉。胡锦涛当时表示，这个头衔并没有什么特别之处，只是他现在可以“随时见到州长和总统”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十七年后，他身穿金色长袍，戴着圆顶小帽。尼日利亚西南部约鲁巴部落的胡锦涛做客中央电视台，讲述他作为“非洲第一位华人酋长”的一生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛以此身份为当地政府提供涉华建议并帮助中国公民在尼日利亚遇到问题。就连中国驻尼日利亚大使也会向胡锦涛咨询。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么硅谷的中国风险投资家的聚会结束了&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中华全国侨联出版的《国内外》杂志一位海外华人大使表示，“胡杰国像熊猫一样稀有，我们需要好好保护他。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡杰国出生于 1948 年，与母亲和兄弟姐妹在上海长大。 。他的父亲前往香港创办纺织生意。然而，二战后国际局势动荡，加上共产党在中国取得胜利，香港经济变得低迷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，跟随一位将生意迁往英国殖民地尼日利亚的朋友，胡的父亲也搬到了那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，胡老在拉各斯建造了纺织厂，与包括奥卢塞贡·奥巴桑乔（1999年至2007年担任尼日利亚总统）在内的政治家成为朋友，并成为当地海外领导人中国人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着年龄的增长，他梦想着将家族生意传给儿子，但小胡更感兴趣的是把他来之不易的教师生涯留在家乡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;胡锦涛是文革后期（1966-1976）第一批进入大学的“工农兵”学生之一。政治运动叫停了全国高考，抢走了那些被送到农村向农民学习、当农场工人的年轻人的教育机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1970年至1976年间，少数幸运的工人、农民和士兵被选入大学，不是根据学业成绩，而是根据他们的工作经验。其中就有胡，他选择了英语专业，并于1972年毕业成为一名英语教师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上课时，他在黑板上写下：“为了革命，我们必须努力学习英语。” ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化大革命期间，中国基本上对外界关闭，胡担心如果他表现出移居国外的意图，就会受到政治迫害，但这种情况在 1977 年左右发生了变化，时任中国驻尼日利亚大使冯玉九和胡父亲的一个朋友到上海看望胡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“胡老师，”冯告诉他，“华侨领袖也需要一个接班人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后，在1978年，中国改革开放之年，胡锦涛抵达拉各斯，由于担心国内政局不明朗以及未知的非洲大陆，胡锦涛最初的不情愿在冯的坚持下被克服了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;然而，胡认为，曾让他父亲受益匪浅的纺织业已经饱和。他想做自己的事情，所以他开始在一家酒店餐厅工作，很快就晋升为经理。随后前往加拿大学习酒店管理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回到拉各斯后，他于1997年投资800万美元建造了金门餐厅及酒店。该建筑采用中国风格设计，有两个房间。入口处有白色的守护狮子。政客和商人纷纷涌入，进一步扩大了胡氏家族的网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他的父亲与奥巴桑乔总统​​交往时，胡锦涛与时任拉各斯州长、尼日利亚现任总统博拉·蒂努布成为了朋友。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;甚至在胡成为部落酋长之前，他就在尼日利亚和中国政府之间轻松调动，而酋长头衔只会增加他的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 1998 年以来，胡一直帮助中国公司在尼日利亚投资。中国土木工程建设公司 (CCECC) 就是一个例子，该公司获得了一个价值 5.6 亿美元的项目，用于改造和维护一条 3,000 公里（1,860 英里）长的铁路。胡锦涛还接见了中国石油天然气集团公司代表团，并向尼日利亚石油资源部长介绍了他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛与中国各省合作，在尼日利亚举办商品交易会、开设工业园，吸引中国私营企业前来投资。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2004年，奥巴桑乔任命胡锦涛为总统顾问，负责中小企业发展。一年后，他陪同奥巴桑乔来到中国。访问期间，尼日利亚总统参观了三峡大坝等大型项目，并签署了多项经贸协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1999年，奥巴桑乔就任总统，蒂努布就任拉各斯州长时，胡锦涛想做点什么为了代表华侨华人表示支持，他决定兴建学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛历来重视教育事业，帮助兴建了四所学校，每所可容纳3000名学生，设备齐全– 与该国许多其他学校不同 – 有灯光和风扇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒂努布在另一位前中国驻尼日利亚大使梁引柱的陪同下奠基。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2001 年，承认由于胡锦涛的贡献，拉各斯约鲁巴族首领授予他酋长头衔，并经总督批准。胡锦涛穿着约鲁巴人的传统服装出席仪式，酋长向他提供了几个头衔供他选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛选择了巴巴·阿塞（Baba Ase），意思是“服务酋长”，并表示他想“服务” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自20世纪80年代以来，中国在非洲的影响力一直引人注目，国有企业大量投资，雇用了大量中国工人。据估计，截至2012年底，生活在非洲国家的中国人已超过100万，根据中国商务部2019年的数据，私营部门目前占中国对非洲直接投资的一半以上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;大英博物馆令人难以置信的中国历史展览是一个启示&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京大学非洲研究助理教授徐亮表示，继胡锦涛之后，至少有 22 名中国人获得了这一称号，大约是其中一半是国营公司员工，其余来自私营企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“将酋长授予中国人可能是一种趋势，但这不仅仅是因为越来越多的中国人（在非洲）做生意，而且他们的影响力已经越来越大。”长大了，”徐说。 “我们需要明白，西非国家正处于转型之中，他们更有动力吸引那些能够帮助他们发展的人——无论是当地人还是外国人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐，最近出版了《 《中国酋长在非洲：中非人文交流视角分析》一文估计，仅尼日利亚就有数百名外国酋长，其中华人只占一小部分。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;徐通过中国官方媒体和社交媒体对中国领导人的报道认识了胡锦涛。他将胡归类为“社区领袖”，指的是从事贸易、服务和制造业的私营商人，他们获得这些头衔主要是因为他们在中国人中的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐将他们与“基础设施建设者”区分开来。 ”，其中大多数在中国国有企业工作。中土尼日利亚公司至少有四名总经理被授予酋长头衔，中地海外的两名员工也被授予酋长头衔，这两家公司都是中国国有建筑公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一些国有企业，接受酋长头衔需要经过批准由公司。通常情况下，管理者都会获得头衔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2007年，在奥贡州帕帕兰托，Sepco III的经理方一波被授予“Baamole”的头衔，意思是“黑暗中的光明使者”。中国电力建设公司承建电站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2015年，中土集团尼日利亚经理李庆勇在拉各斯荣获“皇家道路建设者”称号，孔涛经理荣获“瓦基林·阿尤卡”称号。 2019 年在阿布贾举行的“工程总监”）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与胡锦涛不同的是，大多数中国领导人，尤其是国有企业的领导人，并没有特别积极——有些人甚至因没有履行职责而受到批评。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;有一次，当地的村长给孔打电话，询问他是否知道有一个中国公民打算在附近购买土地。当孔给出否定的回答时，总长说：“你是工程总长。你必须注意你周围的一切。土地要卖了，你不知道！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孔后来查了一下，但一般来说，中国酋长参与地方事务并不容易。许多人表示，语言障碍、对当地文化缺乏了解，再加上自己的工作已经太忙了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从某种意义上说，这些中国领导人的冷漠态度与中国的“不干涉政策”很相似。 ，从宏观层面来看，这意味着北京的投资几乎不附加任何政治条件。据中国商务部统计，截至2020年底，中国对非洲直接投资已超过474亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，西方传统上将贷款条件设定为促进民主和发展等举措。减少腐败。双方都没有取得令人满意的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国被指责为“流氓捐助者”，从长远来看会损害非洲，而西方的做法导致了发展失败，因为如果受援国不能合作，西方就会停止合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;胡锦涛总体上支持不干预，但他对所谓的无偿援助表示怀疑，并希望中国政府也能帮助打击腐败。&lt;/p>;&lt; “对于尼日利亚政府来说，完成任何事情都需要钱，”他说。 “无论是国有企业还是私营企业都无法改变这一点。只有政府才能有所作为 [...] 在我看来，我们不能仅仅提供援助。我们需要提出要求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐还指出，中国和西方对非洲的做法并不一定是对立的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它们可以相辅相成”。他说。 “不同的是，我们认为很多问题是在发展中慢慢解决的，我们不会因为他们有问题就断绝关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“同时，我们也希望非洲在非洲设定的指标上变得更强。西方国家。西方在这方面做得很好。他们在要求透明度、效率或更好的法律体系方面拥有经验[…]我们希望通过发展，非洲国家能够找到解决方案并满足这些指标。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国科技巨头如何破解食品配送2018年底，27岁的中地海外员工李曼虎获得称号时，他感到很困惑。媒体将这一荣誉归功于中地海外，因为中地海外正在建设连接尼日利亚和喀麦隆的跨境桥梁，但也有人指出，李先生由于负责公共关系，与当地人关系密切，或许更重要的是，他分散了工资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最近的一次电话中，李告诉我，他仍然不确定为什么被授予这个称号。 “也许是因为我与总酋长保持着良好的关系，”他说，并提到他经常去看望这位80岁的老人，并给他送礼物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在东南部克罗斯河加冕后李在中国的抖音上开设了一个名为“中国酋长李曼虎”的帐户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他发布了他的加冕视频，其中一位穿着红白条纹灰色长袍的主持人宣布：“根据根据传统统治者会议法令的规定，埃通地方政府区最高统治者和尼日利亚克罗斯河埃通传统统治者委员会成员，特此正式承认亚当[李曼虎]先生为恩图伊·奥法（Ntui Ofa）酋长头衔我是鄂东国的。”当地人爆发出热烈的掌声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该视频已获得超过 20,000 个点赞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管李说他对这个奖项感到困惑，但他相信酋长可能是一个重要的社交工具。与胡的父亲在国内有着广泛的人脉关系的胡不同，其他中国人常常难以融入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李记得，当他 2017 年第一次来到克罗斯河时，当地人经常找到借口骗钱。离开公司。当中国员工开车上街时，警察可能会伏击他们，直到他们提供baksheesh（小费或贿赂）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有一次，当他们计划建造一座桥梁时，当地人声称他们需要付费才能崇拜河流神。请求遭到拒绝，他们拔掉了公司发电机的插头，停止了工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在李获得称号后，情况发生了变化。没有河神可以安抚。警察看到他的金色车牌（只为酋长专用），挥舞着他的车通过检查站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李甚至鼓励在尼日利亚的中国游客下载加冕视频，并说他们是他的朋友，以避免遇到困难。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但李的个人开支却增加了。他被邀请参加当地的节日，并穿着传统服装。他的抖音记录了这些欢乐的活动：部落舞蹈；有节奏的歌曲。有时他跳舞。有时当地人会要求他向他们的手上吹气，这是一种祝福。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的水坝如何摧毁柬埔寨下游的生计&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当然，他需要给他们钱，就像所有其他酋长一样。很快，李就被邀请参加毕业典礼、婚礼和葬礼。 “我是否真的去并不重要，”他开玩笑说，“只要钱到了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年初，李被授予“Ekok Chiefdom Ntufam Ofa I”边境另一边的喀麦隆当地酋长，李也与他保持着良好的关系。在他的第二次加冕典礼上，李克强身穿白色上衣、红色长袍，戴着一顶软尖的红色帽子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他与 80 岁的尼日利亚酋长（他的喀麦隆人的密友）一起骑马穿越边境。同一民族的同行——抵达法语国家的英语区曼育。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东道主是曼育省长，他身穿白色西装，头戴鸭舌帽。李说，在喀麦隆，加冕礼需要政府许可，这就显得更加珍贵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宣布后，一位戴着彩虹色网遮住脸的传统舞者开始跳起来，伸出双手，问道两位传统统治者、总督和新登基者的空中祝福。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然李作为一个年轻人在不同国家获得两个酋长头衔而引起了中国的广泛报道，但他的喀麦隆加冕视频却获得了 30 万个赞抖音上——喀麦隆法语网站上没有他的踪迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在喀麦隆，授予外国人酋长头衔似乎一直存在争议。在西非被授予酋长头衔的24名中国人中，有21人获得了尼日利亚头衔，但只有两人获得了喀麦隆头衔，而喀麦隆头衔不被当地人认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年，来自一家中国私营公司的龙先生被授予了酋长头衔。喀麦隆法语网站报道称，这是该国有史以来第一位三级酋长。他身穿金边白袍、头​​戴头巾——就像该地区的统治者——的照片在脸书上疯传。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位当地互联网用户被引述说：“有一天，中国人将成为世界上最伟大的人。”喀麦隆总统。我们等待这种骗局迅速取消。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学者们经常谈论非洲殖民地的“间接统治”。英国非洲学家特伦斯·兰杰 (Terence Ranger) 在其 1983 年的文章《传统的发明》中解释说，由于英国和非洲的制度如此不同，英国管理者开始根据他们认为的传统来发明非洲传统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们着手编纂和传播这些传统，”兰杰写道，“从而将灵活的习俗转变为硬性规定。”这些发明的传统还被用来重新定义欧洲人发号施令、非洲人默许的分层社会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 20 世纪 60 年代的非洲独立运动中，领导人和知识分子常常认为酋长制是殖民政府对传统亲属关系的扭曲。以及殖民统治的残余。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括几内亚和坦桑尼亚在内的许多国家都禁止了这种传统制度。那些保留它的人并没有赋予它很多功能。这可能是一些喀麦隆人对外国酋长感到愤怒的部分原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当外国人获得酋长头衔时，历史记忆使他们非常敏感，”徐在有关中国酋长的论文中写道。 “很容易引起对‘新殖民主义’的担忧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但徐认为中国酋长不属于殖民叙事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一方面，”他写道，“授予决定是由非洲酋长而不是中国人做出的，这与欧洲殖民者任命酋长有本质的不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“另一方面，非洲人民的监督可以影响外国酋长的任免” ，追究他们的责任。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;一位中国艺术家让丁丁不再那么种族主义，并成为埃尔热最好的朋友之一&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;尽管对外国酋长保持警惕，但自 20 世纪 90 年代以来，大多数西非国家见证了土司制度的卷土重来。耶鲁大学教授凯特·鲍德温 (Kate Baldwin) 撰写了《民主非洲的传统酋长悖论》(2015)，她表示，大约 15% 的非洲国家在获得独立时在宪法中保护酋长权。 2010 年这一数字上升至 24%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日利亚是一个突出的例子。该国可能是英国发明最重要的试验场：利用豪萨-富拉尼族埃米尔统治北部各州的穆斯林，并为东南部各州的伊博族建立“授权酋长”，因为伊博族没有酋长传统.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐认为，殖民创造常常被认为是尼日利亚政治动荡的根源，但酋长制却蓬勃发展，在 1970 年代和 80 年代的经济危机期间对当地发展发挥了至关重要的作用.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;独立几十年后，虽然尼日利亚在1999年修订的宪法中没有赋予酋长任何实权，但也没有彻底禁止该制度。如今，酋长在伊博文化中很常见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外国酋长受到欢迎，尽管他们的头衔往往意味着荣誉而不是权力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在奥卡镇，有两级酋长， ”一位在阿南布拉州东南部的奥卡社区被授予功绩的伊博族酋长说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有一个顾问委员会。这些酋长分别代表 Awka 社区 33 个村庄。名誉酋长，授予奥卡镇为该镇发展做出贡献的人[…]外国酋长通常属于名誉酋长阶层。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;老挝农民的生计岌岌可危。中国开发商排干沼泽&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;因此，尼日利亚人并没有太在意这项授予。 “这就像获得荣誉学位一样，”来自阿南布拉、在拉各斯 CCECC 工作的维维安·奇索姆 (Vivian Chisom) 说。 “我真的不在乎中国人是否获得头衔。这是仪式性的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chisom 本人并不认识任何中国领导人，但她在社交媒体上读到过有关李曼虎的报道。 “他绝对没有任何权力决定社区中的任何事情，”她说，并补充说，李甚至可能买下了这个头衔，这并非闻所未闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheng Cheng，一家中国工厂尼日利亚老板表示，荣誉称号很容易买到，但能否解决问题取决于持有者的能力，与称号无关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李澄清自己没有买荣誉称号，胡耸耸肩对建议不予理睬，称中国领导人“献出贡献，接受感谢”。感谢越多，越好”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊博族酋长不知道有任何中国人购买图书，并声称这些图书不出售给公民或外国人，至少在奥卡不出售。另一方面，常驻中国的尼日利亚人 Samson Fashola 表示：“这是一款现有游戏，并非中国独有。我们的公民也会购买头衔。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早在 2007 年，BBC 就曾报道过“尼日利亚人为头衔而疯狂”，而当地人则担心这一荣誉会被贬低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“给予外国投资者酋长头衔可能会引发不同民族之间争夺国家权力和外部发展资源的竞争。”徐在他的论文中写道。当首长决定授予李首长职位时，当地议会的一位首长拒绝了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他总是找借口从我们公司拿走好项目，”李说。 “他担心如果我当了酋长，他就做不下去了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着房地产市场放缓，非洲对中国的出口大幅下降&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最终，随着酋长态度坚决，当地酋长也就放弃了争论。李开始获得好的项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李于 2020 年底在 Covid-19 大流行期间返回中国。那时他已经离开家人三年了，并多次感染疟疾。他还觉得自己在国有公司的潜力有限。他于 2021 年离开中地海外，开始在中国寻找商机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但非洲一直在他的脑海中挥之不去。 2022年7月，他前往喀麦隆开展贸易业务。然后在三月下旬，他回到尼日利亚。虽然他不住在克罗斯河州，但他的酋长地位仍然得到承认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他向潜在的商业伙伴和政府官员介绍自己时，他会提供自己的身份证——酋长李曼虎说。 – 他说当地人会表达他们的尊重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他从北京首都国际机场向近 49 万抖音粉丝发布了“再见”。 “虽然这里有很多东西放不下，但我觉得我的部落更需要我。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s increase in military exercises helps aid diplomacy efforts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3230733/chinas-increase-military-exercises-helps-aid-diplomacy-efforts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/b95db2ae-be83-442a-ad2b-91e7831ddb90_c19fd31d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;过去十年，中国人民解放军 (PLA) 扩大了外交范围在习近平主席推动国家军队现代化并赢得全球尊重的推动下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《南华早报》通过分析官方通讯社新华社发表的文章发现，自2013年以来，中国举行的军事演习次数外国军队数量增加了一倍多。中国海军也增加了港口访问，特别是对南半球国家的访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最高军事指挥机构中央军委的军事官员也访问了更多的外国同行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But while the PLA, which turned 96 last week, has made these efforts to put forward an image as a force for peace, it has also become more capable of deploying its troops further from its shores. It is something which has drawn suspicion from the US and some others in the West, who have accused China of wanting to reshape the international order against liberal democratic values.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The docking of the PLA&#39;s Yuan Wang 5 tracking ship in Sri Lanka in 2022 drew heavy protests from India, its first foreign base in Djibouti in the Horn of Africa caused concern, and more recently, the Ream naval base in Cambodia that China helped build drew fears that the Chinese navy could establish a presence there, despite Beijing&#39;s repeated denials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a January hearing on Chinese military diplomacy, Randall Schriver, a commissioner of the US-China Economic and Security Review Commission, said: “Under the guidance of the [Communist Party] and Central Military Commission, the PLA is engaging in military diplomacy of various kinds, is conducting bilateral and multilateral exercises with greater frequency, is creating foreign bases and access opportunities, is engaging in operational military activities with foreign partners, and is active in promoting foreign military sales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This external agenda is very robust.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reviewing Xinhua news reports since the 18th party congress in 2012, when Xi took the helm, it could be seen that as the PLA has broadened its diplomatic outreach, Russia followed by Pakistan have remained its top military partners. Ties with them both have continued to grow closer, despite disruption caused by Covid-19.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in terms of Beijing&#39;s ties with other countries that the PLA seeks to court, China still lags far behind in the substance and depth of joint military drills, experts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is also interacting less regularly with its top geopolitical rival, the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As tensions have risen with the West, military exercises between China and Russia have had the greatest range of areas being trained, with live fire drills and joint rescue missions most common, according to the Post analysis. China has taken part in at least 45 exercises that also involved Russia, with 20 of them bilateral exercises, since the 18th party congress in 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two countries also continued their exercises during the Covid-19 pandemic, including the Zapad/Interaction-2021 and Joint Sea 2021 drills. That was despite a sharp drop of diplomatic outreach from China during its three years of closed borders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) that includes China and Russia has been also holding larger combined exercises on counterterrorism.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As the US and China woo with military drills, who will Southeast Asia choose?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The bloc of Central Asian nations plus India, Pakistan and Iran identifies combating terrorism, extremism and separatism as a core tenet of its security policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 4,000 troops took part in the SCO Peace Mission 2021 drills, held in Russia – the most in the series of exercises. The focus was on combined command and “mixed formations” of personnel of different militaries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The drills with the SCO are much more substantive in scale and in the weapons and equipment sent than those that China holds with Asean [Association of Southeast Asian Nations] countries,” said Jackie Wong Siu-hei, a predoctoral fellow at George Washington University who has compiled data on China&#39;s military diplomatic outreach from 2000 to 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The only Asean member that China has held military exercises with which involved more sophisticated arms – including armoured vehicles and live-fire drills – is Laos, a country that relies heavily on Chinese infrastructural investment, Wong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But those drills still pale in comparison to SCO exercises. Wong said the size of the drills and the weaponry China sends reveal its varying military diplomatic goals with other nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compared with the US, China&#39;s drills with its Asean neighbours are smaller and less in-depth. In the 2023 Cobra Gold multilateral exercises in Thailand, China only took part in its search and rescue portion with 25 troops. The US sent its biggest contingent in a decade of more than 6,000 troops.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A reason behind the limited engagement between Asean countries and China could lie in America&#39;s long history of working with nations in the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US military outreach has included giving Asian military leaders executive education, as well as the American arms that have made their way to many Asian countries&#39; arsenals. Many aspects of US training have been embedded into the military training of Asean countries – a result of using American arms such as F-16 fighter jets and complying with the confidentiality conditions that come with using these weapons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By contrast, SCO countries use few US arms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong said that meant Asian countries are less inclined to hold in-depth combined training with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China might be thinking that it has consolidated its identity that contrasts with the US,” he said. “The US is shooting missiles and holding more live-fire drills. China is perhaps saying that its military cooperation is oriented around peace, unlike the US.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zenobia Chan, a PhD candidate at Princeton University&#39;s politics department and one of Wong&#39;s co-authors in the research, said the vast difference in the level of participation meant military exercises of Asean countries that China takes part in are largely symbolic, with a low level of participation by PLA personnel and the main activity being search and rescue exercises.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asean countries still participate in them because they wish to maintain good ties with both the US and China, she said, citing interviews with officials from Singapore, Indonesia and the Philippines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For them, China&#39;s a very important economic partner, whereas the US is more the military partner or guarantor. They don&#39;t want to make either side unhappy. So it means that they are constrained by US factors in that they can&#39;t work too closely with China, but they also don&#39;t want to offend China, if you will.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said in countries that receive a lot of arms deliveries from the US, the number of Chinese infrastructure projects correlated with the number of combined military exercises. That correlation does not exist with countries that do not use many American arms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our theory is that because a lot of countries rely a lot on trade with China and also these infrastructure projects, they want to preserve that economic relationship with China. On the other hand, those countries that actually receive lots of American arms deliveries, they also rely on the US for security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And to please both sides, they do these more symbolic exercises with China in order to placate China while still getting US arms deliveries or security guarantees in some cases,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some of those symbolic acts of diplomatic outreach also include port visits and senior level meetings, such as those between defence ministers and more senior officials including the vice-chairmen of China&#39;s Central Military Commission (CMC), the country&#39;s highest military command.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Senior-level meetings are part of the key performance indicators of military diplomacy, Chan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The upper level, they want you to do military diplomacy. And how do you show that you have done your military diplomacy, then? You visit. That&#39;s just how the incentive structure is set up within [China],” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many of the port visits were performed in Africa by fleets on missions in the Gulf of Aden to protect ships from pirates. In 2023, the fleet visited Nigeria, Congo-Brazzaville, Gabon and Ghana, and held combined exercises with their militaries, the review of Xinhua articles shows.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Peace Ark missions that provide free medical care to local residents also perform a bulk of the diplomatic outreach. This year, the hospital ship visited Kiribati and the Solomon Islands; the Pacific nations that switched diplomatic allegiance from Taiwan to Beijing in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Pacific is emerging as one of the most active theatres of the China-US geopolitical rivalry. The US with its regional allies have met with multiple countries in the Western Pacific to counter Chinese initiatives there, such as a policing pact signed with the Solomons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though the US and China once held bilateral military exercises, these stopped in 2019. The last one was a humanitarian assistance and disaster management drill in Hawaii involving more than 200 Chinese troops and as many American troops.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now, the only time Chinese and American troops would take part in drills together would be in exercises involving several countries, such as this year&#39;s Cobra Gold and those under the banner of Asean Defence Ministers&#39; Meeting Plus (ADMM-Plus) which includes the 10 Asean members as well as Australia, China, India, Japan, New Zealand, South Korea, Russia and the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s military diplomacy is becoming a more prominent component of its overall foreign policy,” said Anna Ashton, director of China corporate affairs and US-China relations at risk consultancy Eurasia Group. “With regard to security issues, China is asserting an alternative vision for maintaining international peace and security.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi&#39;s vision for world safety is encapsulated in his Global Security Initiative (GSI), which confronts some foreign policy principles of the West. It criticises sanctions that have not been authorised by the UN Security Council and supports regional groupings in the Global South, which aligns with Beijing&#39;s long-time opposition against non-Asian countries weighing in on contentious issues such as the territorial disputes in the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The GSI is China&#39;s concept for maintaining global peace and security in the 21st century,” Ashton said. “It is still fairly abstract, but it clearly supports China&#39;s vision of the ideal global architecture in contrast to the existing, US-dominated architecture.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Zelensky thanks Germany’s Olaf Scholz for additional Patriot launchers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3230913/zelensky-thanks-germanys-olaf-scholz-additional-patriot-launchers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 06:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/b8489b37-c527-4b45-a762-53e6f0ad45b9_b219e16a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky has thanked Germany and its Chancellor Olaf Scholz for two additional Patriot air defence system launchers his embattled country has received.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is very important,” Zelensky said in his evening address on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thank you. Thank you, Germany. Thank you to the people,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thank you, Olaf!”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Zelensky cites &#39;treason&#39; as he fires military enlistment chiefs in all Ukraine regions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;News of the Patriot delivery was made public a few days ago and Zelensky thanked Scholz immediately after that.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US-built Patriot systems are particularly valuable for Ukraine because, according to Kyiv, they have already intercepted Russian hypersonic missiles several times. Every strengthening of Ukraine&#39;s air defence means saving thousands of lives, Zelensky emphasised.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new German deliveries also include 10 more Bandvagn 206 multipurpose tracked vehicles, six heavy-duty articulated trucks and about 6,000 rounds of smoke ammunition for 155-millimetre calibre artillery pieces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Germany also provided machine guns, shooting glasses, binoculars and mine-clearing equipment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to air defence help, mine clearance support is particularly important at the moment, Zelensky said. Due to mines and unexploded ammunition, around 174,000 square kilometres of Ukrainian territory are currently dangerous for citizens.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rape victims, imperfect or not, are not to blame]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230657/rape-victims-imperfect-or-not-are-not-blame?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/11/02bca356-e0de-4e74-9799-b96f6d29e6e5_1d934a6c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A star-studded Chinese TV drama delving into workplace sexual harassment titled Imperfect Victim recently ended but the debate it triggered rages on. The show, which ran to 29 45-minute episodes, centres on a rape case: beautiful, young personal assistant Zhao Xun accuses her powerful and handsome boss, Cheng Gong, the company president, of raping her. But the case is complex, and so are the characters involved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Within three months, Cheng, a married man, promotes Zhao from a trainee to the position of senior assistant, multiplies her salary and showers her with gifts worth 880,000 yuan (US$122,170). She makes little attempt to stop him. Then one rainy night, the police turn up at the company&#39;s apartment suite, having received an anonymous tip-off about rape. Zhao, traumatised and confused, denies she has been violated. Five days later, she files a lawsuit against him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The popular and high-quality drama led to a heated discussion among the audience about the nature of sexual harassment, gender inequality, the unbalanced power play in the office and, interestingly, who is really the victim.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many viewers disliked Zhao, accusing her of being weak, vain and greedy. One said the character was someone “who wants to be a mistress but also wants a chastity arch” – a memorial used to mark a woman&#39;s extraordinary chastity in feudal times. Some said Zhao had hardly said “no” throughout the drama. “A girl, no matter how naive and stupid, knows how to say no. So, Zhao Xun is just a cunning woman who wants to have things without putting in the effort,” one said. Some – mostly male, I imagine – even claimed the president was the real victim.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the show&#39;s opening scene, Zhao, wrapped in a white towel, is curled up in a bathtub, crying while it rains outside and her boss sleeps in the bedroom. Her pained expression tells me clearly that she felt violated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even if she did not fight back when he forced himself upon her, her silence did not mean she was willing. As long as a person does not give consent for the sexual intercourse, it is rape. It is obvious to me that she didn&#39;t. Before entering the bedroom, it&#39;s clear she wants to leave but he picks her up and takes her to bed. It&#39;s clear to me that he committed sexual violence, a crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many in the audience have scrutinised areas where Zhao could have done better; for example, she could have refused his gifts. But the reality is that in many Chinese companies, the boss has such power over his employees that refusing his gift may mean the end of employment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am not too surprised by the criticism aimed at Zhao. The character assassination of rape victims is not an uncommon practice, and not just in China. Some 35 years ago, Hollywood produced a rather unusual film called The Accused, which focused on the victim&#39;s experience. A young woman is gang-raped in a bar by three men. She successfully sues them and the bystanders. Her character comes into question when her attackers are prosecuted. Does she have a history of drinking? Was her skirt too short?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Imperfect Victim, the president countersues Zhao for defamation. Her personal information is leaked, she is ruthlessly attacked online and her reputation is ruined. Unable to bear it all, she tries to commit suicide but survives with serious injuries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In real life, her death would have been a probable outcome. But the director decided to put a positive spin on it. Helped by her brilliant lawyer, Zhao wins the case, and Cheng is ordered to apologise to her. And she gets the 1 yuan compensation she asked for – it was never about the money but about clearing her name. For me, that was an unrealistic touch in an otherwise very realistic drama.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Xiaoxuan, a prominent face in China&#39;s #MeToo movement, was also sued for defamation after she accused Zhu Jun, a high-profile TV presenter, of sexual assault. She countersued, demanding an apology and compensation, and failed. Last year, her appeal was dismissed after a court in Beijing ruled that she lacked sufficient evidence. This was hardly a surprising result. High legal barriers and social stigma have silenced many victims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am delighted to see a TV drama like Imperfect Victim dealing with such serious social issues head on. For centuries, Confucianist ideas that women are inferior dominated Chinese society. It is partly due to the deeply rooted patriarchal culture that sexual harassment is prevalent in the workplace, so much so that on International Women&#39;s Day this year, the government issued a guidance specifically to combat the problem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But I do find the title Imperfect Victim problematic in that it might further encourage a victim-blaming culture. Let&#39;s not focus on the weaknesses of the victim but examine the perpetrator with a critical eye. A victim is a victim, whether she is perfect or not.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump swoops into Iowa Fair to scramble DeSantis’ effort to reboot campaign]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230912/trump-swoops-iowa-fair-scramble-desantis-effort-reboot-campaign?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 05:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/6430402b-ac0b-48fa-ba4f-f47d43b4f962_87fcf05e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;共和党总统竞争对手唐纳德·特朗普和罗恩·德桑蒂斯在早期提名州举行竞争活动周六，在爱荷华州，这位前总统在民意调查中占据压倒性优势，而佛罗里达州州长正忙着重新调整他陷入困境的竞选活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯在过去三周内进行了两次人事变动并在民意调查中不断下滑，长期以来一直计划参加爱荷华州博览会，这是该州有抱负的总统候选人的政治必修课，该州将在一月份开始共和党提名竞选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普周二晚间宣布，他还计划在同一天参加这次活动，因为德桑蒂斯的这次露面相当于政治上的一次失败，佛罗里达州州长希望这将启动他停滞不前的竞选活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯正在做出一个高风险的赌注，他可以通过赢得爱荷华州来阻止特朗普获得共和党总统提名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六被问及他的执政风格时，德桑蒂斯表示，他更关心保护选民而不是自己的财富。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以我们会做正确的事。我们将承担后果，并让筹码落在可能的地方，”他在博览会上接受爱荷华州共和党州长金·雷诺兹 (Kim Reynolds) 采访时说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在采访开始时，雷诺兹谴责了一群吹口哨的抗议者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后，当特朗普抵达展会时，一大群人为他欢呼。后来他在露天酒吧发表演讲，吹嘘自己目前的领先地位。特朗普表示：“我们的民调支持率大幅上升。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2024 年美国总统竞选陷入困境，德桑蒂斯更换了竞选经理&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然德桑蒂斯没有攻击特朗普，但德桑蒂斯的倒刺是公平的前总统的游戏。他告诉记者，他认为自己并没有过早地放弃佛罗里达州州长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及是否将德桑蒂斯视为主要竞争对手时，特朗普回答道：“我不认为他是他。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为共和党领先者，特朗普带来了一个由佛罗里达州共和党人组成的代表团，他们支持他而不是德桑蒂斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当其他候选人来到这里时，他们大约有六个人，”特朗普告诉支持者在展览会场的一家餐厅酒吧发表演讲。 “我们在三个不同的地方停下来，我们从来没有受到过如此好的待遇。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法官警告特朗普不要在2020年选举颠覆案中威胁证人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;爱荷华州举行了第一个1 月 15 日举行各州共和党提名竞赛。德桑蒂斯希望在中西部州的胜利将为他在新罕布什尔州和南卡罗来纳州初选之前提供对抗特朗普的宝贵动力。抢走了州长的风头，占据了头条新闻。它在州首府得梅因举行，举办时间为8月10日至8月20日。去年，它吸引了超过100万参观者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普的出现也将使共和党其他领域的努力复杂化。除了特朗普和德桑蒂斯之外，其他九位候选人也将在8月11日至8月18日期间参加竞选，但根据路透社/益普索对可能的共和党选民的最新民意调查，他们的支持率都在个位数，落后特朗普40多个百分点。 p>;&lt;p>;根据 8 月 3 日的民意调查，特朗普还领先德桑蒂斯 34 个百分点，即 47% 对 13%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普的大多数竞争对手都同意在 8 月 11 日期间接受雷诺兹的单独采访。 8 月 18 日。特朗普拒绝了她的邀请，因为她在初选中的公开中立性以及她与德桑蒂斯一起出现在爱荷华州的几场活动中，这激怒了她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在与雷诺兹的台上，德桑蒂斯避免谈论特朗普，而是瞄准拜登的经济政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从第一天起，我们就将所有拜登法规和行政命令扔进垃圾桶，”德桑蒂斯说。 “拜登经济学基本上是美国人的生活水平较低，以便他可以追求他的政治、意识形态议程，这是不可接受的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭博社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Meta confirms Lil Tay’s Instagram account was hacked in death hoax amid publicity stunt claims]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230911/meta-confirms-lil-tays-instagram-account-was-hacked-death-hoax-amid-publicity-stunt-claims?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 04:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/b0bb8c01-766f-4597-b226-45a367141c67_386bc7ed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Lil Tay 的 Instagram 帐户确实遭到黑客攻击，导致发布了一篇虚假报道亚洲人的帖子据 Meta 报道，说唱歌手本周早些时候去世。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管有人指责该骗局只是一种宣传策略，但这家拥有 Instagram 的社交媒体巨头周六向 TMZ 证实了此次黑客攻击，并指出这帮助了有争议的 14 岁女孩重新控制了她的帐户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，她的动态中发布了一份自称来自 Tay 家人的声明，声称她和 21 岁的弟弟 Jason Tian 均突然死亡.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们无法用言语来表达难以承受的损失和难以形容的痛苦，”这篇已被删除的帖子写道。 “她哥哥的去世给我们的悲痛增添了难以想象的深度。在这个巨大的悲痛时刻，我们恳请大家尊重我们的隐私，因为我们对这一巨大的损失感到悲痛，因为 [Tay] 和她兄弟去世的情况仍在调查中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们去世的消息震惊了社交媒体，然而，随着泰的母亲是中国人，一些与泰关系密切的人表示，他们无法（或不会）证实这些指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《商业内幕》报道，泰的父亲克里斯托弗·霍普，“拒绝回答他的女儿是否还活着，”而她的前经理 Harry Tsang 表示，这种情况需要“谨慎考虑”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更重要的是，洛杉矶（据报道郑居住的地方）和洛杉矶的警察部门温哥华（她长大的地方）表示，他们没有关于她死亡的报告，也没有对此案进行调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二天，Tay 向 TMZ 证实，她和她的兄弟不仅还活着，而且她的账户也还活着已“受到第三方的损害，并被用来传播令人不快的错误信息和谣言。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但有关黑客指控合法性的质疑很快就出现了，社交媒体上的许多人想知道死亡骗局是否是一场骗局宣传噱头或“无耻地呼吁关注。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Lil Tay 没有死，称她的社交媒体帐户遭到黑客攻击：新报告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在周四向福克斯新闻数字频道发表的一份声明中，Tsang表示他认为“所报道的黑客事件可能并未发生”，并暗示 Tay 的哥哥可能是罪魁祸首。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我持这种观点的理由是双重的，”他解释说，同时指出他没有两年内与泰的家人交谈过。 “首先，在 Meta/Instagram 等平台上恢复受损帐户通常不需要 24 小时的时间范围。其次，Lil Tay 的兄弟以采取极端措施而闻名，他的行为让我猜测这起事件背后还有其他动机。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsang 继续表示，金钱和重新获得名誉可能是动机。他说，这些骗局和黑客指控的幕后黑手是“试图从忠实的支持者和不知情的旁观者那里非法提取资金”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周之前，据信泰的兄弟是 2021 年帖子的来源，这些帖子指控他们的虐待之父。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 04:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Six dead after migrant boat capsizes in Channel, search continues for the missing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230910/six-dead-after-migrant-boat-capsizes-channel-search-continues-missing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 03:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/a65f38ae-eb81-40e6-bacf-7a5c1c5c4d09_7f1aa430.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周六，一艘前往英国的移民船在英吉利海峡沉没，六名阿富汗人死亡，法国官员表示，搜救工作仍在继续，寻找仍然失踪的人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这起沉船事故是一场可怕的人类悲剧，”法国海洋国务秘书埃尔维·贝尔维尔在加莱港对记者表示。救援行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他谴责将移民“送死”的“犯罪分子”，并承诺打击他们的走私网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沿海城市布洛涅的副检察官，菲利普·萨巴蒂尔 (Philippe Sabatier) 告诉法新社，所有六名遇难者都是阿富汗男子，据信年龄在 30 多岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其余乘客“几乎都是阿富汗人，还有一些苏丹人，其中大部分是成年人，还有一些未成年人”，他说贝尔维尔说，法国和英国海岸警卫队救出了 61 名幸存者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国海岸当局普雷马尔表示，最多仍有两人失踪，搜索工作将持续到夜幕降临.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的思念和祈祷与今天在英吉利海峡遭受悲惨生命损失的人们同在，”英国内政大臣苏埃拉·布拉弗曼 (Suella Braverman) 在社交媒体网站 X（以前称为 Twitter）上表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国总理伊丽莎白·博恩 (Elisabeth Borne) 发帖表示，她“对受害者表示同情”，并赞扬了救援队的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;地中海沉船事故后，包括 3 名儿童在内的 41 名移民失踪&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;“这非常艰难，他们是人类。你永远不会习惯带回尸体，”救回五名遇难者的船船长雷吉斯·霍利(Regis Holy)说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“还会有更多的悲剧......他们（移民）冒着一切风险，它永远不会停止，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌托邦56人道主义组织的发言人将这场悲剧归咎于边境“镇压”，他告诉法新社，确保合法通行的难度只会“增加过境的危险性”并促使人们冒着越来越大的风险前往英国”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;右翼共和党加莱市市长娜塔莎·布沙尔谴责法国政府“未能”阻止此类过境，并要求转移移民&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在英国，多佛海峡港口议员、执政党保守党成员娜塔莉·埃尔菲克 (Natalie Elphicke) 也呼吁法国政府采取更有效的行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天的情况悲剧凸显了为什么我们必须阻止小船以确保人们的安全并防止英吉利海峡的人员伤亡。”她在 X 上写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些过度拥挤且不适合航海的死亡陷阱显然应该由法国当局制止“首先离开法国海岸，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据检察官称，这艘船于当地时间凌晨 2 点左右在法国北部海岸附近倾覆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国通讯社-加来的新闻记者看到一些获救者从现场有紧急服务的巡逻艇上下来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国和英国之间的海峡是世界上最繁忙的航道之一，强劲的水流很常见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;被困的移民获救，但数十人在波涛汹涌的意大利海域失踪&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据当局称，大约 1,000 名移民正在法国北部海岸等待穿越英吉利海峡的机会。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;周五公布的官方数据显示，自 2018 年英国开始公开记录抵达人数以来，已有超过 10 万名移民乘坐小船从法国穿越英吉利海峡到达英格兰东南部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国当局已加强巡逻和继伦敦三月份同意每年向巴黎提供数亿欧元的支持后，英国采取了其他威慑措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近几天，在天气好转后，已经有多次尝试乘船穿越英吉利海峡的事件。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;周四晚间，Premar 报告称，三艘不同的船上有 116 名移民获救，其中包括儿童。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，在前往英格兰南部海岸的 14 艘小船上发现了约 755 名移民英国内政部统计数据显示，这是今年单日最高人数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些船只使今年迄今为止抵达的人数接近 16,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数字已经堆积如山。英国首相里希·苏纳克政府面临压力，该政府已将“拦截船只”作为明年大选前的关键优先事项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五名移民在海上死亡，四人在试图越境前往英国时失踪去年来自法国的移民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 11 月，一艘船在英吉利海峡倾覆，导致 27 名移民死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;次年，穿越英吉利海峡的移民人数达到创纪录的 45,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Afghan universities ready to readmit women but not until Taliban leader says it’s OK, official says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3230909/afghan-universities-ready-readmit-women-not-until-taliban-leader-says-its-ok-official-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 03:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/71720c73-fc24-4bcc-aa4a-80b37422aad2_fa090d9f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿富汗大学已准备好重新招收女学生，但执政的塔利班领导人拥有最终决定权周六，一名教育官员表示，如果真的发生的话，请谈谈何时会发生这种情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 12 月，塔利班禁止女性进入校园，引发了全球的愤怒。 2021 年 8 月塔利班重新掌权后不久，六年级以上的女孩就被禁止上学。阿富汗是世界上唯一一个禁止女性接受教育的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿富汗高等教育部长 Nida Mohammed Nadim，当时表示，大学禁令对于防止性别混合是必要的，因为他认为所教授的某些科目违反了伊斯兰教原则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，该禁令是由南部城市坎大哈发布的塔利班领导人希巴图拉·阿洪扎达 (Hibatullah Akhundzada) 一直就职，直至另行通知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高等教育部顾问莫尔维·阿卜杜勒·贾巴尔 (Molvi Abdul Jabbar) 表示，一旦阿洪扎达下达禁令，大学就准备重新招收女学生。被解除。他无法透露这种情况何时或是否会发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿洪扎达“下令关闭大学，所以它们就关闭了，”他告诉美联社。 “当他说营业时，他们就会在同一天营业。我们所有的领导人都赞成（重新启动女童教育），甚至我们的部长们也赞成。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贾巴尔说，他最后一次见到阿洪扎达是在七八年前。他在阿富汗的 10 年苏联战争期间与他并肩作战，对抗俄罗斯人，并加入塔利班 27 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只是因为我们（对阿洪扎达）的服从，我们才追随他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“谁将成为助产士？”：失业后，阿富汗妇女重新接受护士培训&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他的评论是阿富汗内部意见分歧的另一个迹象塔利班关于决策过程和阿洪扎达的法令，首席发言人扎比乌拉·穆贾希德迅速采取行动，否认分裂的报道。它们还显示了阿洪扎达对塔利班的权威。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳迪姆将禁令作为一项临时措施提出，同时找到了解决性别隔离、课程材料和着装规范等问题的解决方案。他说，一旦这些问题得到解决，大学将为女性重新开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塔利班对女孩进入中学做出了类似的承诺，称一旦校服和交通方面的“技术问题”得到解决，她们就会恢复上课，但女孩仍然被排除在教室之外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贾巴尔说，教育部门和以前一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一切都提前准备好了，无论是学校还是大学学习。可能是（开始）时间不同，早上有男生，下午有女生。或者早上有女孩，下午有男孩。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的评论是在塔利班重新掌权两周年纪念日前几天发表的。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div >;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shippers warned to stay away from Iranian waters over seizure threat as US-Iran tensions high]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3230908/shippers-warned-stay-away-iranian-waters-over-seizure-threat-us-iran-tensions-high?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 02:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/27ff0525-7619-4319-aa22-1bb3063b6752_5afb6b7a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;西方支持的中东海上部队周六警告穿越战略要地的托运人霍尔木兹海峡应尽可能远离伊朗领海，以避免被扣押，这是在伊朗和美国之间紧张局势加剧之际提出的严厉建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，在伊朗扣押了两艘在波斯湾狭窄的海峡附近行驶的油轮，世界上 20% 的石油都经过该海峡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然伊朗和美国现在即将达成一项明显的协议，该协议将使数十亿伊朗人受益解冻在韩国持有的资产，以换取释放被关押在德黑兰的五名伊朗裔美国人，这一警告表明海上紧张局势仍然高度紧张。美国已经在探索在海峡商船上部署武装部队的计划，以在该地区集结军队、船只和飞机的情况下威慑伊朗。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国可能在商船上部署武装部队阻止伊朗扣押&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国海军司令、驻中东第五舰队发言人蒂莫西·霍金斯承认已发出警告，但拒绝讨论相关细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;霍金斯表示，美国支持的一个名为“国际海事安全组织”的海事组织“正在通知地区海员采取适当的预防措施，以最大程度地降低因当前地区紧张局势而被扣押的风险，我们力求缓和紧张局势”。 “建议船只尽可能远离伊朗领海。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，欧盟领导的一个负责监视海峡航运的海事组织“警告称，可能会袭击伊朗领海”。私人情报公司 Ambrey 表示，“未来 12 至 72 小时内，霍尔木兹海峡将出现一艘悬挂不明旗帜的商船。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此前，在发出类似警告后，伊朗当局扣押了一艘商船。该公司警告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由欧盟领导的名为“霍尔木兹海峡欧洲海事意识”的代表团没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;伊朗将被监禁的美国公民转移至软禁，以达成互换协议&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;伊朗国营伊斯兰通讯社引用了美联社的这篇报道，但没有引用任何伊朗官员的说法。伊朗驻联合国代表团没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;霍尔木兹海峡位于伊朗和阿曼的领海内，最窄处仅 33 公里（21 英里）宽。航道双向宽度仅为 3 公里（2 英里）。任何影响它的因素都会波及全球能源市场，可能导致原油价格上涨。然后，这些费用会通过消费者购买汽油和其他石油产品的费用而流向消费者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2019 年以来，自特朗普政府单方面从伊朗撤军后，伊朗发生了一波针对伊朗船只的袭击浪潮。核协议并重新对德黑兰实施严厉制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些袭击于 4 月下旬恢复，当时伊朗于 5 月扣押了一艘为雪佛龙公司运送石油的船只和另一艘名为 Niovi 的油轮。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两艘油轮在不到一周的时间内被扣押，当时悬挂马绍尔群岛国旗的苏伊士拉詹号停泊在休斯顿附近，可能正在等待卸载显然被美国扣押的受制裁的伊朗石油。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些扣押导致美国军方发射了在该地区进行了大规模部署，其中包括巴丹号两栖攻击舰和卡特霍尔号登陆舰上的数千名海军陆战队员和水兵。海军发布的图像显示周二红海中的巴丹和卡特霍尔。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 02:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Anger as Hawaii wildfire death toll climbs to 80; residents confront devastation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230907/anger-hawaii-wildfire-death-toll-climbs-80-residents-confront-devastation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 02:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/e80f76d5-9a0d-4867-9d42-03f022602e74_ae5da74d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;夏威夷一场可怕的野火造成的死亡人数攀升至 80 人，居民面临着灾难周六，针对应急响应的批评越来越多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联邦紧急事务管理局表示，超过 2,200 座建筑物在火灾中受损或被毁，估计重建受影响社区将花费约 55 亿美元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;夏威夷当局表示，他们正在对火灾的处理方式展开调查，该州大岛的一名女议员承认，官员们低估了危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在历史悠久的度假城市夏威夷毛伊岛拉海纳居民安东尼·加西亚 (Anthony Garcia) 表示，大火烧毁了他租用的公寓，摧毁了他所有的物品和记忆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它夺走了一切，一切！这令人心碎，”这位在拉海纳生活了三十年的 80 岁加州人说道。 “有很多东西值得一看。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这座拥有 12,000 人的小镇曾经是夏威夷王室引以为傲的家园，如今已沦为废墟，热闹的酒店和餐馆化为灰烬。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一棵雄伟的榕树，150年来一直是社区的中心，虽然在大火中伤痕累累，但仍然挺立着，树枝失去了绿色，黑黑的树干变成了一副笨拙的骨架。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;“这太疯狂了”：随着对夏威夷野火反应的愤怒加剧，启动了调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;夏威夷总检察长安妮·洛佩兹表示，她的办公室将审查“火灾发生之前、期间和之后的关键决策和长期政策”本周毛伊岛和夏威夷群岛发生山火。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五晚些时候，毛伊县官员将死亡人数修正为 80 人，州长乔什·格林警告说，死亡人数肯定会进一步上升。超过 1,400 人在紧急疏散避难所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们低估了火灾的杀伤力和速度，”夏威夷国会女议员吉尔·德田 (Jill Tokuda) 周六早上告诉 CNN。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毛伊岛遭受了多次停电。危机期间的削减，导致许多居民无法通过手机接收紧急警报 - 德田说，官员们应该为此做好准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须确保做得更好，”她补充道.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年夏天北美发生了其他极端天气事件，加拿大各地仍在燃烧破纪录的野火，美国西南部也出现了严重的热浪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧洲和部分地区亚洲也经历了气温飙升、大火和洪水造成的严重破坏。科学家表示，碳排放引起的全球变暖正在导致极端天气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于一些回到拉海纳的人来说，当他们含泪与他们担心可能会发生冲突的邻居重新取得联系时，他们有一种短暂的兴奋感。没有逃脱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你成功了！”奇娜·乔 (Chyna Cho) 在废墟中拥抱安珀·兰登 (Amber Langdon) 时喊道。 “我正试图找到你。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于一些最幸运的人来说，他们感到高兴，尽管这场悲剧的规模是夏威夷州最严重的自然灾害之一，但这种喜悦却有所缓和。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我简直不敢相信，”基思·托德在发现自己的家完好无损后告诉法新社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我非常感激，但同时这也是毁灭性的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;64 岁的托德发现他的家和邻居的房子没有被破坏，他的太阳能电池板为冰箱提供电力，而冰箱仍在按需分配冰块。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;担心遭到抢劫居民们也很担心，县当局表示，任何进入拉海纳的人都必须证明他们曾经居住或住在当地的酒店，并且晚上 10 点到早上 6 点之间将实施宵禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;部分地区那些成功返回拉海纳的人在震惊的沉默中徘徊，试图了解破坏的规模。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;44 岁的安东尼·拉普恩特 (Anthony La Puente) 表示，发现自己的家被烧成灰烬时感到非常震惊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“无法找到伴随你长大的东西，或者你记得的东西，真是太糟糕了，”他向法新社讲述了他住了 16 年的房子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我唯一能说的是，这很痛苦。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;毛伊岛山火死亡人数已达 53 人，度假小镇已成为阴燃废墟&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登周三晚间在一份声明中表示他已下令“所有可用的联邦资产”来帮助夏威夷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，媒体大亨奥普拉·温弗瑞（Oprah Winfrey）向受火灾影响的毛伊岛居民伸出了援助之手。她并不是唯一一个表达担忧的名人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位亿万富翁脱口秀主持人是岛上的兼职居民，周四在怀卢库的一个避难所运送了各种物资，两个人火灾袭击历史名镇拉海纳几天后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这有点让人不知所措......但我真的很高兴有这么多人......支持，而且你知道，人们只是尽其所能”她告诉 BBC。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非盈利组织 Kāko&#39;o Haleakalā 分享的 Instagram 视频显示，温弗瑞拿着枕头，并给躺在床上的一名居民一个枕头。该帐户感谢温弗瑞“坚持到底”，还提供了婴儿床和洗漱用品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她甚至花了一些时间与这里的人们在一起。非常感谢，”标题写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;温弗瑞还告诉英国广播公司，她“去沃尔玛和好市多购物”购买用品，其中还包括洗发水、尿布、床单和枕套。近年来，这位大亨在蒙特西托的房产也面临着各种自然灾害，包括洪水和火灾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;火灾发生后，温弗瑞和她的好莱坞同行大声疾呼，以提高人们的认识和声音支持对于毛伊岛居民来说。出生于夏威夷的《Fast X》演员杰森·莫玛 (Jason Momoa) 最近分享了一组来自环保非营利组织 Āina Momona 的信息照片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们为我们的朋友和毛伊岛的‘ohana’感到震惊和心碎，他们 [受到最近野火的影响，”莫玛写道。他还分享了一个资源链接。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Instagram 上，莫玛敦促游客暂时避开毛伊岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“毛伊岛现在不是度假的地方，”莫玛写道。 “不要去毛伊岛旅行。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不要让自己相信，在一个遭受如此严重苦难的岛屿上，你的存在是必要的，”他的帖子继续说道。 “向所有在这个需要的时候向社区捐款和表达敬意的人致敬。”亚马逊创始人杰夫·贝佐斯和他的未婚妻劳伦·桑切斯表示，他们将捐赠 1 亿美元用于恢复工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚马逊创始人杰夫·贝佐斯和他的未婚妻劳伦·桑切斯表示，他们将捐赠 1 亿美元用于恢复工作。 >;&lt;p>;桑切斯在 Instagram 上发帖表示，他们对毛伊岛最近发生的事件感到“心碎”，并正在创建一个基金，以“帮助毛伊岛现在和未来几年重新站稳脚跟”。根据彭博亿万富翁指数，贝佐斯的净资产为 1630 亿美元，他在该岛南端的拉彼鲁斯湾拥有一处房产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“眼前的需求很重要，同样重要的是直升机飞行员兼 Black Ops Aviation 创始人桑切斯表示：“即使在大部分注意力已经消退之后，长期重建工作也必须进行。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;音乐家米克·弗利特伍德 (Mick Fleetwood) 也对这次破坏表示哀悼，他在星期四在 Instagram 上写道：“毛伊岛和拉海纳社区几十年来一直是我的家。”这位弗利特伍德麦克 (Fleetwood Mac) 明星拥有一家名为弗利特伍德 (Fleetwood&#39;s) 的海滨餐厅和酒吧，该餐厅和酒吧在大火中消失了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我代表我自己和我的家人向毛伊岛人民表达我衷心的思念和祈祷，”他继续。 “我们致力于在未来的几天、几个月和几年内为社区和受这场灾难影响的人们提供支持。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;演员皮尔斯·布鲁斯南 (Pierce Brosnan) 和他的妻子基利·沙耶·史密斯 (Keely Shaye Smith) – 在考艾岛有一个家– 也提高了人们对野火的认识。沙耶·史密斯 (Shaye Smith) 周四分享了一段海滩日落的视频，并鼓励追随者采取行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我为毛伊岛和夏威夷县、夏威夷社区、居民、家庭和受到影响的动物表示真诚和衷心的祈祷这些前所未有的野火，”她写道。 “如果有能力，请考虑向夏威夷/毛伊岛社区基金会捐款，以帮助有需要的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;论坛新闻服务、彭博社、商业内幕的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 02:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>