<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[In Australia, a Sri Lankan refugee’s long ‘Walk for Freedom’ spotlights plight of persecuted asylum seekers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3230800/australia-sri-lankan-refugees-long-walk-freedom-spotlights-plight-persecuted-asylum-seekers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/cf0f47c0-2d2e-4cd7-b3b0-9ce279a6b59a_2648acc5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这只是斯里兰卡难民 Neil Para 1,000 公里（620-英里）步行去见澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯（Anthony Albanese），当时他开始起可怕的水泡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，与在澳大利亚没有签证生活了 11 年（这意味着他无法工作或入境）的痛苦相比，这种不适根本算不了什么。免费医疗服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2014 年他和家人的过桥签证被无故吊销且从未更换以来，帕拉陷入了该国复杂的难民处理系统，他正在步行以提高人们对他和数千人困境的认识&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的家人是逃离 1983-2009 年斯里兰卡内战的泰米尔人，他们表示由于担心受到迫害而无法返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们感到愤怒、沮丧，抑郁并有很多心理健康问题。我们在任何一天都有如此多的感受，”帕拉告诉《亚洲周刊》，并补充说，家人甚至一度集体考虑过自杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，这位 44 岁的老人仍心怀感激。不要回到他的祖国。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;联合国批评澳大利亚对船民的“惩罚性做法”，并警告仇恨言论的增加&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“那里现在可能没有战争，但有很多种族主义和歧视，”他说。 “没有稳定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帕拉正在利用他为期 40 天的“自由步行”活动，从维多利亚州巴拉瑞特镇的家出发，前往位于新州悉尼郊区马里克维尔的阿尔巴尼斯选区办公室南威尔士，向堪培拉请愿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 8 月 1 日步行开始以来，他已收集了超过 16,000 个签名，支持者在整个旅程中与他一起举起横幅并为他加油。他的目标是获得 25,000 个签名。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;帕拉和他的家人于 2008 年逃离斯里兰卡前往马来西亚，然后于 2012 年乘坐一艘载有大约 200 名其他难民（其中包括来自伊朗的难民）的渔船抵达澳大利亚、伊拉克和阿富汗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚海军拦截了这艘船，帕拉一家首先被安置在圣诞岛的拘留中心，然后被转移到达尔文和丹德农，并最终于 2013 年持过桥签证定居在巴拉瑞特.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Para怀疑2014年他家人的签证被吊销是澳大利亚国内政治的结果。时任总理托尼·阿博特 (Tony Abbott) 的政府于 2013 年上台，此前他以“调头”为竞选纲领，导致澳大利亚目前旨在阻止海上入境的“主权边界行动”难民政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前总理此后，殖民统治者英国也采取了类似的政策，并于本月开始在一艘住宅驳船上安置难民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国谴责了推回难民船的“残忍和致命做法”，因为这种做法增加了难民的风险进一步侵犯人权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“也许难民是有权势的人，可以决定谁是政府成员，”帕拉讽刺地说。 “而且，如果政府向难民发放签证，[他们认为]他们可能会失去权力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚对难民的零容忍态度导致了数千人持有临时签证的“遗留案件”——或者根本没有——获得永久居留许可的希望渺茫。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚制作了假星座来阻止斯里兰卡寻求庇护者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在距离斯里兰卡约 3,000 公里的瑙拉 (Naura) 拘留中心悉尼卡尔多国际中心的一份简报称，澳大利亚大陆最终在 6 月被清空，但仍然屹立不倒，人道主义组织无国界医生组织将这场苦难评估为“有史以来最严重的苦难，包括酷刑受害者”。难民法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年夏天当选的阿尔巴尼斯工党政府表示，将允许 19,000 名持有临时签证的难民申请永久签证。但这不包括像帕拉一家这样根本没有签证的人。移民部长安德鲁·贾尔斯 (Andrew Giles) 的发言人表示，政府不会对个别案件发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚内政部在一份声明中表示，未被邀请申请永久签证但认为自己值得申请的难民可以请求部长干预。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而这正是帕拉一直在做的事情——在过去十年中定期多次致电内政部和移民部长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最终政府难民行动联盟发言人伊恩·林图尔 (Ian Rintoul) 表示：“希望那些在澳大利亚被拒绝并被迫过着下层阶级生活的人被迫返回自己的祖国。”他补充说，该国所有主要政党都看到“严厉的反“寻求庇护者政策”作为一种选举优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“像我们这样的人”倡导组织的法比亚·克拉里奇 (Fabia Claridge) 表示，缺乏政治领导力在许多澳大利亚人心中助长了“任何非盎格鲁人”的说法。巴士”是一名难民“他们将占据巴士座位、工作等等”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种领导力的缺乏是基于赢得选票......这也向种族主义选民传达了一个信息，即政府正在对非白人、非基督徒很严厉。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克拉里奇的非政府组织是支持帕拉及其家人的众多慈善和社区团体之一，帮助他们支付房租、食物和其他生活费用。 Para 目前是一名消防员志愿者，但希望成为一名警察，而他的妻子 Sugaa 在老年护理机构担任志愿者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自澳大利亚农村难民组织的玛格丽特·奥唐纳 (Margaret O&#39;Donnell)，该组织是巴拉瑞特 (Ballarat) 的居民帮助家庭的组织，说，在某个时候，帕拉孩子们甚至面临着必须支付“外国学生费用”上学的前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[家庭]推迟去看医生或牙医，因为我们其他人都这样做。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国敦促澳大利亚关闭离岸拘留中心&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“[有一次]我因为不得不上夜班而头发花白[抱怨]，尼尔回答说，‘至少你可以工作’，”奥唐纳补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我多次听到难民说，没有人可以站在他们的角度思考，因为这是不可能的。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s July automobile exports jump 63 per cent, helping extend the lead over Japan as the world’s biggest vehicle-exporting economy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3230935/chinas-july-automobile-exports-jump-63-cent-helping-extend-lead-over-japan-worlds-biggest-vehicle?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 15:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/8b7b6b32-cdb9-49a1-851b-1d5f8ef0a586_25e8ac9b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;7月份中国本土品牌向海外交付的汽车数量增加，占三分之二月度出口量大幅增长，扩大了中国对日本的领先地位，成为全球最大的汽车出口国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月份海外出货量同比增长 63%，达到 31 万辆，首季总销量达到 265 万辆根据中国乘用车协会（CPCA）编制的数据，一年中有七个月。 CPCA 表示，本土品牌占 7 月份出口量的 248,000 辆，占 80%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“汽车制造商保持出口增长势头，对中国汽车的需求不断增长，鼓励组装商提高产量。”高申，上海独立分析师。 “越来越多的中国汽车公司现在正在寻求加强海外市场的销售。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新数据扩大了中国对日本 15.8% 的领先优势。上半年，中国出口汽车234万辆，超过日本汽车工业协会（JJAMA）报告的日本品牌202万辆。日本2022年出口汽车350万辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可以肯定的是，中国7月份的出口增速较6月份的41万辆的出货量放缓了24.4%。尽管如此，分析师表示，随着中国制造的汽车越来越受到一些发展中国家消费者的欢迎，未来几个月的增长可能会加快。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国（左舵驾驶市场）的一些组装商正在发展右舵驾驶- 出口用手动驾驶车辆。上海合众新能源汽车和河北省保定市的长城汽车上周宣布计划向印度尼西亚发运右舵汽车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;合众已开始接受其旗舰 Neta S 电动轿车的订单，以及紧凑型运动型多功能车（SUV）Neta U-II和Neta V。中国最大的SUV制造商长城表示，将在印度尼西亚销售坦克500和哈弗H6等多款车型。&lt;/p>;&lt; CPCA没有透露7月份电动汽车出口数量，但Canalys在6月份预测，2023年中国纯电动和插电式混合动力汽车海外销量预计将达到130万辆，几乎是67.9万辆的两倍该研究公司补充道，到 2022 年，它们将有助于汽油和电池驱动汽车的出口总量从 311 万辆激增至 440 万辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;战争Canalys 表示，中国电动汽车“物有所值，产品质量高，可以击败大多数外国品牌”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是世界上最大的汽车和电动汽车市场，约有 200 家电动汽车组装商相互竞争，开发能够定义移动出行未来的绿色智能汽车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大陆的电动汽车销量将增长 35%瑞银分析师 Paul Kong 在 4 月份预测，今年汽车出口量将达到 880 万辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国汽车出口的强劲增长与今年迄今为止大宗商品出口的下降形成鲜明对比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国海关数据显示，7月份中国出口连续第三个月下降，同比下降14.5%至2817.6亿美元，创2020年2月以来最大同比跌幅。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Go back to original Kai Tak plans to fix cruise terminal transport fiasco]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230770/go-back-original-kai-tak-plans-fix-cruise-terminal-transport-fiasco?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 15:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/03203258-4836-42b1-a053-df27dd6f6529_7559a5b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“如果一张图片描绘了一千个单词......”，大卫·盖茨写道1971 年，流行乐队 Bread 发行了这张专辑。不出所料，这首歌对乐队来说很受欢迎。如此强大的意象解释了为什么大多数语言都有相似的表达和概念：无论是口头还是书面的文字，都不会产生相同的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这就是为什么最近出现的富裕游客在启德门外排队的照片邮轮码头等待出租车引发了如此强烈的反应。几天之内，政府召开了一次紧急高层会议，以确定问题所在以及可以采取的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毕竟，有多少关于洪的好故事并不重要。孔或者我们告诉他们的有多好，本地和海外媒体总是在寻找负面消息，特别是如果有一张好的图片作为支持的话。事实上，十多年来，这一直是一场公关惨败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对我来说，故事开始于 1999 年 5 月，当时——令所有人（包括我自己）大为惊讶——我被任命为出任香港首任旅游事务专员。我当时已是财政司司长办公室的主任，该办公室的日程最近已扩大，包括与华特迪士尼公司的谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一步是成立一个旅游策略小组，汇集与行业巨头进行交流并提出一些想法。早期出现的一项提议是建立一个专门建造的世界级邮轮码头，以管理大型船舶，而不是海运大厦可以处理的小型船舶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在那之前，大部分船舶营销香港作为旅游目的地的重点是我们作为“购物天堂”的声誉。尽可能长时间地保持这一势头很好，但最终竞争目的地可能会迎头赶上，迪拜和海南已经这样做了。即使我们能够保持优势，多加一根绳子也肯定没有坏处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港地理位置优越，是亚洲邮轮业的枢纽。向北前往日本的 7 天航程可以在台湾、上海或韩国中途停留，或者向南前往新加坡，可以在海南、越南或泰国停留。游轮乘客可以从香港出发，从另一端飞回家，或者从这些城市出发，在这里结束。邮轮乘客几乎从定义上来说相对富裕，这正是旅游目的地寻求吸引的休闲游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后，邮轮码头项目成为启德发展规划建议的一部分。从很多方面来说，这是一个理想的安排：海港本身就是香港的主要景点之一，因此大型游轮停靠在海港的中心将为游客带来美妙的景色。旧跑道旁边的深水区非常适合停泊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该地区的总体规划包括许多相辅相成的兼容用途。不利的一面是，对该地区部分开发的任何重新考虑或提供基础设施的延迟都会对该码头运营产生影响，这或多或少已经发生了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邮轮码头本身于 2013 年开业，但许多附近规划的道路尚未完工。单轨铁路的想法被废弃了，没有公共交通交汇处，停车位也有限。配套设施根本看不到。该码头只有一条道路——巨型游轮抵达当天发生的事故，有效地封锁了进出通道几个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;码头运营商和游轮公司都熟悉这一点。情况并推出了几种解决方案。当天，约三分之二的乘客乘坐预先安排的巴士和其他交通工具顺利离开航站楼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港交通专家 Alok Jain 告诉香港电台上周的 Backchat 计划表明，其他临时解决方案也是可行的，例如公告和预先批准特殊巴士服务，以便在船舶抵达日自动启动。 Jain也强烈支持政府规划者最初制定的一揽子交通安排。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港邮轮码头运营商拒绝商业改造，强调港口作用&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但出租车数量不足的问题遗迹。一些额外的激励措施正在出台，但这些本质上都是姑息措施。我们希望我们的旅游业蓬勃发展，而不是生存。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们应该回到原来的发展方案，看看能尽快恢复多少项目。附近有空地可供停车，相邻的一块土地可以出售用于酒店开发。如果单轨铁路无法继续建设，那么我们需要迅速做出替代方案的决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总之，我们的情况是，旅游战略家正确地预见到我们的地位将面临挑战，并且需要扩大旅游范围。旅游产品。一旦世界一流的设施到位，交通规划者对乘客需求的评估是正确的。我们现在需要改进实施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Ecuador became one of the most violent countries in Latin America]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3230933/how-ecuador-became-one-most-violent-countries-latin-america?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 14:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/6b086e15-f0f4-4bb7-b5ed-022528cfcf49_40523641.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;仅在几年前，厄瓜多尔还是夹在哥伦比亚和秘鲁之间的和平岛屿世界上最大的可卡因生产国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但自 2018 年以来，毒品缉获和凶杀案数量惊人增加，人们普遍将其归咎于跨国有组织犯罪集团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三中间派候选人费尔南多·比亚维森西奥 (Fernando Villavicencio) 被暗杀– 在 8 月 20 日总统选举前的民意调查中排名第二 – 已经从根本上动摇了该国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;六名哥伦比亚人因竞选集会外的枪击袭击被捕，第七人死亡与安全人员的枪战。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;哥伦比亚杀手在杀害厄瓜多尔总统候选人后成为人们关注的焦点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年厄瓜多尔与毒品有关的暴力导致凶杀率达到每 10 万居民 26 人，几乎是前一年水平的两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统吉列尔莫·拉索一直在与贩毒团伙作斗争，但无法遏制不断上升的暴力事件，他指责“有组织犯罪”杀害了比亚维森西奥，一名前记者曾谴责过比亚维森西奥。厄瓜多尔周六通过大规模军事和警察行动将 Los Choneros 领导人何塞·阿道夫·马西亚斯（化名“Fito”）转移到最高安全级别的监狱。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lasso 在社交媒体网站 X（以前称为 Twitter）上宣布，Fito 已被转移到 La Roca，这是一座可容纳 150 人的最高设防监狱，该监狱与黑帮老大所在的监狱是同一监狱的一部分。被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲托被指控在被杀之前威胁比亚维森西奥。比亚维森西奥早些时候告诉当地节目，菲托的一名“特使”已经联系了他，并告诉他不要再谈论该团伙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我继续......提及洛斯乔内罗斯，他们就会破裂我，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内政部长胡安·萨帕塔表示，厄瓜多尔有超过 13 个有组织犯罪集团，其中最古老、最强大的是 Los Choneros，目前与墨西哥锡那罗亚贩毒集团结盟。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但该国军事情报部门表示，已发现多达 26 个活跃的贩毒团伙，这些团伙全副武装，专家称人数可能可与厄瓜多尔 6 万名警察部队相媲美。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;分析人士表示，墨西哥和哥伦比亚的禁毒战争给这些国家的贩毒集团以及阿尔巴尼亚黑手党带来了压力，促使他们在厄瓜多尔开展业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于贩毒者来说，厄瓜多尔的港口太平洋上的港口提供了向欧洲和美国出口可卡因的有用地点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国漏洞百出的边境、美元化的经济、普遍的腐败和缺乏洗钱控制措施也吸引了这些犯罪团伙， &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;厄瓜多尔总统候选人在竞选活动中被暗杀&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;哥伦比亚 CERAC 智库主任豪尔赫·雷斯特雷波 (Jorge Restrepo) 表示，卡特尔可以“以较低的生产成本”在厄瓜多尔运作.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“厄瓜多尔制定了打击有组织犯罪的政策，但这并没有阻止政府部队和司法组织受到与毒品有关的有组织犯罪的渗透，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路易斯·科尔多瓦·阿拉尔孔 (Luis Cordova Alarcon)负责厄瓜多尔中央大学冲突与暴力项目的他将“极端犯罪暴力”的开始追溯到 2018 年 1 月发生的致命汽车爆炸事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次袭击部分摧毁了警察总部，造成人员受伤与哥伦比亚接壤的一个小镇有 23 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这起事件被归咎于哥伦比亚游击队哥伦比亚革命武装力量的一名持不同政见者，他谋杀了为基多《El Comercio》报纸工作的三名记者，并于当年被哥伦比亚保安人员杀害.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汽车炸弹袭击之后，敌对贩毒团伙之间发生了血腥的监狱大屠杀，在接下来的三年里导致 430 名囚犯死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就像在墨西哥一样，厄瓜多尔人开始看到被肢解的情况街头遗留的尸体、桥上吊死的尸体，以及绑架者砍下受害者手指或耳朵以勒索赎金的绑架。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;厄瓜多尔的暴力受害者包括市长、法官、检察官和数十名无辜平民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，可卡因缉获量稳步上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，缉获量不断增加，警方对关押许多贩毒团伙头目的监狱进行镇压。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“厄瓜多尔正变得越来越暴力，因为该国通过安全部队进行干预，抓获了头目，并缉获了更多的可卡因，”科尔多瓦·阿拉尔孔 (Cordova Alarcon) 说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，犯罪分子在捍卫自己的生意以及非法金矿开采和武器贩运等其他非法活动时变得更加暴力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有组织的犯罪已经接管了国家，”他已添加。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesian domestic helpers in Hong Kong protest against agencies ‘overcharging’ practices outside consulate]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3230936/indonesian-domestic-helpers-hong-kong-protest-against-agencies-overcharging-practices-outside?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 15:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/a88699c1-b56e-4f25-baaf-2f4b47c7d689_1ce916c2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周日上午，数十名印尼女佣在本国驻香港领事馆抗议，要求政府解决安置机构影响其自身及其雇主的“收费过高”行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次集会是在印度尼西亚人力安置机构协会（Aspataki）表示将承担额外费用之后，对于谁将承担额外费用感到困惑。执行雅加达在 2020 年和去年推出的规定，即雇主在雇用新佣工时必须支付行政费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，有关当地老板是否需要全额支付 20,000 港元（2,558 美元）的细节仍不清楚截至周五。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚领事馆和香港劳工处表示，现有政策将保持不变。周四，劳工及福利局局长孙玉涵也补充说，阿斯帕塔基并不代表印尼政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港工作 20 年的家政女佣 Leni Sumarti 也在其中。周日，50 名印尼人在铜锣湾领事馆抗议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港居民仍不确定是否必须为印尼佣工支付更多费用&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这位 43 岁的女士表示，她正在为争取印尼劳工权益而集会。工人和雇主反对机构要求更多费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们今天来这里是因为我们想要回我们的钱，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们在没有咨询我们的情况下突然实施了这一举措，但是我们是每天必须与雇主一起生活和工作的人。我们感觉自己就像商品一样被交易。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样 43 岁的抗议者同伴（只透露了自己的昵称 Bimo）声称，招聘公司将继续在工人来香港之前向他们收取费用，尽管他们收取费用” &lt;p>;“因此，在印度尼西亚，我们收费过高，雇主也被收费过高。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港人雇用印尼家庭佣工的规则没有改变：劳工部长&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;比莫呼吁印度尼西亚和香港当局确保双方不再多收费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该家庭佣工还要求雇员和雇主向中介机构支付的费用提高透明度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“多年来，没有任何细节，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我知道这一点是因为我问我的雇主：‘当你雇用我时，该机构有告诉你这笔钱的用途吗？’她告诉我他们没有说。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，当印度尼西亚机构会见香港劳工官员并表示他们将针对工人执行新的“零费用”规定时，混乱就开始了。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;香港部长会见国家官员，讨论引进更多帮工的计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这些规定意味着本地雇主需要承担全部招聘成本，而不是支付目前 7,000 至 13,000 港元的份额。与此同时，据说外佣只需支付培训费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它警告不遵守规定的雇主可能不会处理他们的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据移民局称，该市约有33.8万名外籍家庭佣工，到2022年，菲律宾籍人数将超过19万。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong to launch night bazaars, organise more conferences and exhibitions to drive economic recovery, finance chief Paul Chan says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3230931/hong-kong-launch-night-bazaars-organise-more-conferences-and-exhibitions-drive-economic-recovery?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 14:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/674521fb-2818-487b-89b1-2523fd5d6ee1_7a2ec674.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港将推出夜市及举办更多会议展览带动经济复苏，财政部长在政府缩小全年国内生产总值 (GDP) 增长预测后表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财政司司长陈茂波周日表示，香港需要提高竞争力和吸引人才的能力由于Covid-19大流行后游客改变了习惯，因此需要通过创新、优质服务和户外体验来吸引游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管游客人数正在迅速恢复，但我们必须抓住机遇，促进多元化、高价值-旅游业的增长和可持续发展，特别是大型活动、国际会议和展览对于吸引高价值游客至关重要。”他在每周博客中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港 6 月份零售额旅游业和消费拉动增长19.6%&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他强调，政府将与相关部门合作举办夜市以刺激消费，并指出私人消费和旅游业仍将是经济增长的主要推动力。政府周五将 2023 年 GDP 增长预测从之前 3.5% 至 5.5% 的目标修改为 4% 至 5%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于全球需求疲软和利率上升，第二季度 GDP 同比增长 1.5%，较第一季度 2.9% 的增幅有所放缓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 表示，更多游客 –尤其是年轻人 – 前来参加文化艺术活动以及音乐会和展览，他们指的是来自东南亚国家的游客，他们曾参加 7 月份的 Ani-com 和 Games Hong Kong 2023。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恢复情况尤其明显他表示，来自中国大陆和东南亚国家的游客表现强劲，跨境游客数量达到疫情前水平的70%左右。菲律宾等东南亚国家的入境人数已超过疫情前的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月份访港旅客约360万人次，平均每日116,000人次，增幅超过30% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财务总监宣布即将举行的重大活动，例如十月的香港美酒佳肴巡礼2023、十一月的香港冬日节和十二月的香港单车节。当局已向活动主办方旅游发展局拨款 2.5 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他重要活动包括 9 月举办的 2023 年亚洲果蔬展，以及明年 5 月回归的 Vinexpo 香港展。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;由于全球贸易疲软将造成影响，香港修订了城市经济预测&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;陈表示，通过专注于创新和技术开发，特别是人工智能，将实现更持续的增长。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;另外，香港科技大学商学院兼职教授 Ceajer Chan Ka-keung 表示，香港需要重建因冠状病毒大流行和中美紧张关系而受损的全球形象。&lt;这位前金融服务和财政部长周日在广播节目中表示：“尽管人们预计取消大流行限制将导致香港游客涌入和商业增长，但事实证明并非如此。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于大多数游客来自内地，而海外游客数量因中美关系恶化而大幅下降，香港可以投入更多资源，通过加大海外宣传力度，争取更好的旅游表现他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“应努力吸引更多长途商务旅客，包括举办大型会议和展览，将注意力转移到香港。”重要的是要确定哪些行动将改善我们的整体国际形象并重新向世界介绍香港。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登上周宣布了一项行政命令，旨在对美国风险投资和私募股权施加限制投资半导体和微电子、量子信息技术和特定人工智能系统领域的中国公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前部长表示，随着中美关系恶化，香港需要重新定义其发展和经济定位。生意更具挑战性，美国资金变得更加谨慎，导致内地资金缺乏流入香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港目前的经济模式过于狭窄。亚洲将成为全球经济发展的重要支柱，香港需要与东南亚国家合作吸引人才和投资。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指的是香港传统上对四大核心支柱产业的依赖– 金融服务、贸易和物流、旅游和专业服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位兼职教授表示，政府可以扩大从其他地区获得资金的渠道，并协助优质内地企业在香港证券交易所上市。他敦促香港交易及结算所优先完善上市机制，为候选企业提供更灵活、更快捷的选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港需要激发市场活力，可以发挥为内地企业提供选择的作用企业寻求筹集资金，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Miss Universe cuts ties with Indonesia organiser accused of sexual harassment]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3230927/miss-universe-cuts-ties-indonesia-organiser-accused-sexual-harassment?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 13:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/158a15cf-4523-4ea5-b8e4-7bcdb5175d7b_7e1c4878.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;环球小姐组织表示正在切断与其印度尼西亚特许经营商的联系并取消今年的活动马来西亚选美比赛后，参赛者指控当地组织者进行性骚扰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家总部位于美国的组织在周六晚间的一份电子邮件声明中表示，已决定终止与 PT Capella Swastika Karya 及其国家总监 Poppy Capella 的合同，她还持有马来西亚环球小姐的执照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;六名印度尼西亚环球小姐参赛者向警方提出投诉，指控组织者性骚扰，并称她们受到裸露上身的“身体检查”，她们的律师周二表示。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“It has become clear that this franchise has not lived up to our brand standards, ethics, or expectations as outlined in our franchise handbook and code of conduct,” the Miss Universe Organization said, adding that providing a safe place for women was its utmost priority.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Police probe topless &#39;body checks&#39; at Miss Universe Indonesia beauty pageant&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Jakarta police did not respond to a request for comment on Sunday. Spokesperson Trunoyudo Wisnu Andiko said on Tuesday the report would be investigated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Capella said in a statement on Instagram she does not condone any form of sexual harassment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I emphasise that I, as the national director and licence owner for Miss Universe Indonesia, was not involved at all and have never known, ordered, requested or allowed anyone who plays a role and participated in the process of organising Miss Universe Indonesia 2023 to commit sexual harassment through body checking as reported,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Jakarta contest was held to select Indonesia&#39;s entry for the annual Miss Universe competition, to be held in El Salvador late this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Miss Universe Organization said it was evaluating its policies and procedures to avoid similar occurrences in the future, adding that there are no measurement or body dimensions requirement to join its pageant worldwide.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Jailhouses rocked: China prisons spark controversy with  ‘remote visit app’ which charges US$7 for 20-minute video call with inmates]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3230621/jailhouses-rocked-china-prisons-spark-controversy-remote-visit-app-which-charges-us7-20-minute-video?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/11/08697ae3-469f-443f-94a4-deb25d8220bb_677867c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Prisons in a province of China have introduced a “remote visit app” that charges relatives of inmates 50 yuan (US$7) to conduct video call visits, triggering controversy on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On August 7, a former lawyer, surnamed Li, revealed on Weibo that prisons in the northern province of Hebei had implemented the service.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It allows inmates and their family members to have a 20-minute video conversation for which the relatives pay 50 yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, among other criticisms he had of the scheme, the ex-lawyer pointed out: “If the signal is poor and the call is disconnected, you need to pay another 50 yuan to reconnect.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li also questioned the overall legitimacy and financial transparency of the service which is provided to the prisons via a third-party company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Several family members interviewed said that even if it cost 500 yuan for each conversation, they would be willing to pay.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So, may I ask if a license has been issued to allow for charging? Do they issue invoices? Are they paying taxes? Is financial transparency maintained within the prison?” he wrote in the post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ex-lawyer tagged the official Weibo accounts of the Ministry of Justice and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate in his post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhengguan News reported that the application is available for use in a total of 14 prisons in the province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The development of the application was carried out by an outside company and was first deployed in Hebei&#39;s prison system in November 2020, according to the company&#39;s official website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to Li, a member of staff from Baoding Prison told Zhengguan News on August 8 that in-person visits at the prison are free of charge, adding that the remote video visit service is provided by a third party which collects the fees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Making money is normal, as you are using their equipment and network, which also saves you time and travel expenses,” the member of staff said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Whether the visits are by video or in-person, the inmate has to apply for them. In the case of video visits, only the inmate can initiate the request, and the interaction must take place on designated days,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following news coverage of the initiative, Li reposted on Weibo on August 9, which said: “Of all the prison directors in the country, you might be the most talkative! Not only are you unaware that video visits in other provinces are free of charge, you are also unaware that charging on the e-government platform is prohibited.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story has also sparked a robust online debate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A supporter of the scheme said “freedom of choice” was the key and argued that convicted criminals should not enjoy free services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For those who don&#39;t want to spend money, they can have face-to-face visits. Why should criminals enjoy free services?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, others countered, with one person saying: “It&#39;s ridiculous. There are plenty of free video calling apps available, why use a paid one?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another speculated: “It may not be coerced, and theoretically, they have options. But in practice, prison authorities could simply deny the approval of face-to-face visits.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A third person voiced concern about financial connections between a prison authority and a third-party company: “I fail to understand. Do the prison authorities benefit financially here? Is this legal?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another online observer quipped: “Hebei prisons, you certainly understand the market economy!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The introduction of remote visit services in mainland prisons has produced some intriguing anecdotes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May 2022, a prison in Quanzhou, in the southeastern province of Fujian even went as far as concealing the location of inmates who had not told their families they were in jail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prison arranged backdrops of cityscapes and inmates were allowed to wear everyday clothing during the calls.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Asia’s grain supply in flux as Russia-Ukraine Black Sea deal lapses: ‘very complicated, expensive’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3230841/asias-grain-supply-flux-russia-ukraine-black-sea-deal-lapses-very-complicated-expensive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/11/8040684a-968c-49e8-9d0d-87059f817569_76c1b3c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukraine has for years been called the world&#39;s breadbasket because its rolling fields have fed far-flung corners of the globe. But Russia&#39;s refusal last month to extend a Black Sea deal with Kyiv means Ukrainian grains will no longer flow to Asia so easily.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Black Sea deal, brokered by Turkey a year ago, allowed Ukraine to send agricultural goods from its seaports on Panamax-sized vessels, despite its war with Russia. After the pact lapsed in July, Ukraine has only been exporting limited quantities across the Danube River in overloaded vessels, crammed with other commodities like metals and minerals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The supply uncertainty comes at a time when El Nino conditions are threatening Southeast Asia&#39;s grain output, heavy rains have ravaged crops in China&#39;s northeast, and Indian wheat prices have surged to six-month highs amid peak demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Asia braces for more rice-price shocks as India&#39;s export ban unnerves markets&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Russia&#39;s closure of the grain corridor via Odesa has led to very complicated and expensive logistics,” said Viacheslav Chuk, commercial director of Astarta, one of Ukraine&#39;s largest agricultural firms. “Very little of Ukraine&#39;s agricultural commodities will [now] go to destinations in Asia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July, Ukraine exported 1 million tonnes of grain to Europe over land by train, another million tonnes by trucks and 2 million tonnes by the Danube river, Chuk said. “These are very expensive routes and farmers always have to pay extra,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia and Ukraine were in 2021 the world&#39;s top and fifth-largest exporters of wheat, respectively, according to the Observatory of Economic Complexity trade data website. China had always been a key export destination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine exported 32 million tonnes of grain to 45 countries in the year before the Black Sea corridor was closed, according to the United Nations. China accounted for about one-quarter of that total.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the pact ended in July, Ukraine exported 1.1 million tonnes of corn, out of which China took 10 per cent. It also exported 800,000 tonnes of wheat with none going to China, Chuk said, citing Ukrainian customs data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is because we [Ukraine] don&#39;t have the possibility of loading big vessels to China or other Asian countries, having only the Danube river route and Polish seaports which cannot serve Panamax-sized vessels,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Such ships can easily dock at Ukraine&#39;s Odesa because it is a deep water port.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We need big vessels to reach our traditional markets in Asia, and this requires Russia to unblock the grain corridor via Odesa,” Chuk said, explaining that it was not economical to send smaller vessels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine was loading up to seven Panamax vessels with up to 70,000 tonnes daily when the Black Sea route was open. It exported 2 million tonnes of wheat in October last year, out of which 40 per cent went to Indonesia, Vietnam, Tunisia and Egypt.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other Asian nations like South Korea, Bangladesh and Lebanon were also importing from Ukraine through the route, according to Ukrainian customs department statistics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An early resumption of the trade route appears unlikely, though Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan has said he aims to revive and expand the scope of the deal, calling on Western countries to help turn the initiative into a basis for peace.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two warring sides have escalated attacks on each other in the Black Sea region since the deal ended.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, Ukrainian sea drones attacked the key Russian port of Novorossiysk on the Black Sea, damaging a naval ship, according to a Ukrainian official. Moscow said it repelled the attack.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia has hammered Ukraine&#39;s ports, with its drones causing significant damage and a large fire at facilities in the Odesa region that are key to Ukrainian grain exports. Kyiv retaliated by hitting a Russian oil tanker and warned that more attacks could follow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The escalation of the conflict to the Black Sea region is bad news for the world&#39;s food supplies, as it could also affects shipments from Russia even as its ports overflow with grains after a record harvest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The blockade of the Black Sea also has longer-term implications because it will make Ukrainian farmers think twice about planting grains that can no longer be exported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The action will make it more expensive for Ukraine to ship grain, which will mean lower prices for Ukraine producers. This is likely to result in further disincentives for planting grain this autumn and next spring,” said Joe Glauber, a senior research fellow at the International Food Policy Research Institute.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russia may let Black Sea deal expire. Is a spike in global food prices looming?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian farmers are also now considering growing crops that can be stored more easily than highly perishable corn and wheat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the corridor remains closed to Black Sea exports, we [Ukrainian farmers] will go into lower [yield] per hectare crops. So, we will switch from corn and winter crops into oilseeds, sugar beets and niche products,” Chuk said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Russian occupation of Ukrainian territory and exchanges of fire have significantly reduced Ukraine&#39;s agricultural production.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ukraine&#39;s grain production has been significantly limited by the war, reducing its exportable surplus of grains,” said Paul Hughes, chief agricultural economist &amp; director of research at S&amp;P Global Commodity Insights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian exports through the Danube River remain feasible as long as there is no military destruction, he said. “However, Russia has targeted the Danube River terminals in Izmail and Reni in recent weeks.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If this mode of export is severely limited, it will have an impact on the availability of grains globally, and world wheat, corn and barley prices are likely to rise,” Hughes said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Will China-Philippines tensions make other South China Sea claimants more likely to speak up?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3230824/will-china-philippines-tensions-make-other-south-china-sea-claimants-more-likely-speak?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/11/9a018909-d8f2-4ad1-91ed-2b77716caa02_5011bd67.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A clash between China and the Philippines in the South China Sea last weekend will make Southeast Asian nations a little anxious but it may make some governments more likely to speak up against Beijing&#39;s actions if tensions escalate, observers said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese coastguard ships intercepted and fired water cannons on August 5 to warn off a Philippine vessel that was carrying supplies for Filipino troops stationed at the Second Thomas Shoal in the contested Spratly Islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Manila summoned the Chinese envoy to the Philippines over the incident and called China&#39;s actions “illegal” and “dangerous”, while its long-time ally the United States said the actions directly threatened regional peace and stability.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China said it had implemented “necessary controls” to stop the Philippine ships, and that Beijing had “indisputable” sovereignty over the Spratly Islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also claimed that the Philippine ships had “disregarded China&#39;s repeated dissuasion and warnings and attempted to transfer construction materials used for maintaining and repairing the ship, which has been grounded on the shoal illegally”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Second Thomas Shoal is controlled by Manila but also claimed by Hanoi, Taipei and Beijing, which also claims the resource-rich South China Sea waterway almost in its entirety.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Collin Koh, a senior fellow at the S Rajaratnam School of International Studies (RSIS) in Singapore, said the Philippines&#39; neighbours were likely to have watched the incident unfold with some unease against a backdrop of repeated stand-offs between Beijing and Manila.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Southeast Asian countries] will certainly view that as something quite worrisome and see it as an uptick in tensions that seem to have built up,” said Koh, who specialises in naval affairs in the Indo-Pacific. “They view that as potentially impinging upon regional peace and stability.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February, Chinese coastguard ships directed lasers at a Philippine vessel and disrupted a supply mission. More recently, vessels from the two countries nearly collided.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last weekend&#39;s incident was the first time since 2021 that China&#39;s coastguard had used a water cannon against a Philippine resupply mission to the Second Thomas Shoal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Greg Poling, director of the Southeast Asia programme at the Centre for Strategic and International Studies, said the incident and the overall “rise in Chinese coercion … makes everyone in the region nervous”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the anxiety, he suggested, would be much more immediate for other South China Sea claimants in the region, from Malaysia to Indonesia and Vietnam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These countries have in recent months appeared to be more cautious about China&#39;s actions in the disputed seas.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What next in the China-Philippines war of words over the Second Thomas Shoal?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Manila now had plans to sign a maritime cooperation pact with Hanoi, and Indonesia had undergone a major shift within its security services after the Chinese coastguard “dangerously harassed” Indonesian oil and gas operations some two years ago, according to Poling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If China continues to ratchet up pressure, and especially if it causes a threat to the lives of Filipino mariners, I expect some Southeast Asian parties – Singapore, Vietnam, Indonesia, potentially a future Thai government – could feel compelled to speak up more forcefully,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thomas Daniel, a senior fellow at the Institute of Strategic and International Studies Malaysia, said claimant states “ought to be worried”, noting that Malaysian and Vietnamese stations – like the Philippines – also relied on resupply runs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The response of Southeast Asian countries would largely rely on their interests in the South China Sea and their relationship with China, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Koh from RSIS said most, if not all, Southeast Asian countries were likely to remain silent on the incident or stick to the refrain that they were monitoring the situation, for fear of appearing to take sides and being “embroiled in what seemed to be a very unnecessary problem”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was also a fear of repercussions from China, which remains a key trading partner for many of the region&#39;s economies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Any continued silence from Southeast Asian countries, and especially claimant states that had experienced some form of aggression from China, would be “both telling and damning”, Daniel said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Perhaps this is a reflection of a real fear of escalation dominance by Beijing, which no claimant state can ever hope to counter,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Worse still, perhaps Hanoi and Putrajaya [Malaysia] have been slowly, reluctantly, but successfully conditioned by Beijing to keep their heads down, in the ultimately doomed hope of biding one&#39;s time.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beyond that, the recent stand-off could also prompt countries in the Association of Southeast Asian Nations to question whether they should still trust China in negotiating a code of conduct for the South China Sea, said Aristyo Rizka Darmawan, an international law expert at the University of Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why is a rusty old Philippine warship involved in the South China Sea dispute?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China and Asean last month completed the second reading of a much-delayed code of conduct, which would be a legally binding document to regulate behaviour in the disputed waterway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Darmawan, whose research focuses on maritime security in Southeast Asia, said it was important for claimant states to stand behind the Philippines and put pressure on China to not escalate tensions if Beijing was committed in the negotiations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Otherwise, this shows that China is not trustworthy on any mechanism and therefore there is no point in the negotiation of code of conduct if China does not commit to keeping peace in the area,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While most countries in Southeast Asia would have viewed last week&#39;s incident with some anxieties, Koh said some might see it as a “welcome development”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Not to say that they welcome tensions but I think what they saw … was a somewhat interesting phenomenon where there are more countries in Southeast Asia who are more willing to speak up against China and, in a way, hoping that at least it might have some positive impact of moderating Chinese behaviour from now on,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Sudanese start small businesses to survive war: ‘misfortune makes you creative’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3230925/sudanese-start-small-businesses-survive-war-misfortune-makes-you-creative?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 12:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/9b93fab7-c75c-4e2e-992e-7dc8a6d84fec_0559fae5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Sudan&#39;s war has left university lecturer Ali Seif without pay for months. To make ends meet, he has turned to making soap in his room at a makeshift displacement camp.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Out of work as fighting rages between the forces of rival generals, many Sudanese have been forced to find creative ways to support themselves and their families.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until April 15, when the conflict erupted between the army headed by General Abdel Fattah al-Burhan and Mohamed Hamdan Daglo&#39;s paramilitary Rapid Support Forces, Seif had worked at a Khartoum university.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;More than 1 million may flee Sudan bloodshed: UN&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Now the engineering lecturer and his family live in Wad Madani, a city where most of the nearly three million people displaced from the capital fled for safety with the few belongings they could bring.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wad Madani has been spared the violence so far, but air strikes and fighting are taking place around 150km (95 miles) to the north.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like many others, Seif said his house was “robbed” by paramilitaries, and that he has not received a salary since March with banks closed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to survive, he has started selling soap.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Misfortune makes you creative,” Seif said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I noticed there was no soap left on the market even though everyone wanted some, so I decided to make soap bars,” he recalled, surrounded by plastic pots he uses to mix soap paste before pouring it into ice cube trays to mould the bars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like Seif, Michelle Elia Moussa used to stand in front of a classroom full of students.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But since the war turned her life and country upside down, she has spent her days standing in front of a stall at Al-Hasaheisa market, halfway between Khartoum and Wad Madani.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;ve given up hope and shelved my ambitions of being a brilliant teacher,” she said, glasses on her nose and apron around her waist, as she looks over her cakes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without a job, I can&#39;t support myself,” she said, in a poverty-stricken country where the spectres of famine, epidemics and widespread war crimes now loom large.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s the first time I&#39;ve worked in a market,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m not comfortable, I&#39;m ashamed, but it&#39;s a war. I have no choice,” she added, expertly spreading a light dough on cast-iron plates to make thin wafers with holes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eshraqa Mousa, another woman who fled Khartoum, has opened a small stall to sell tea. Without it, she said, she could “only provide one meal a day” for her children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her family&#39;s hasty departure from the capital at the start of a war that has killed at least 3,900 people and displaced four million is still fresh in Mousa&#39;s memory.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We left everything behind … so I came here and bought this little stall to sell tea,” she said, draped in her long, multicoloured veil.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a conservative society where tea sellers, though numerous, are often stigmatised and harassed, the move was an act of bravery she had never imagined she would achieve.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But with the war, such taboos were shattered, and survival and resourcefulness took over.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We were forced to find alternatives,” said Mohammed Ali.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A former civil servant in the capital, he “teamed up with some colleagues to open a small mobile food stall”, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Made of white sheet metal and powered by a generator, it is “in the style of those you find in Khartoum, which don&#39;t exist in Wad Madani.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every day, he now sells mashed beans, falafel and other snacks loved by his compatriots, and he makes enough to feed his family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That is, until the next storm: the streets of Wad Madani are buzzing with speculation that the war could soon come to this city.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>