<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[South China Sea: Chinese boat scavenging scrap metal from WWII wrecks shows Malaysia’s vulnerability to maritime actions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3222756/south-china-sea-chinese-boat-scavenging-scrap-metal-wwii-wrecks-shows-malaysias-vulnerability?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/d511c398-f0f4-477a-ba77-c0abfd5c71bc_36291b44.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;多年来，马来西亚潜水员 Hazz Zain 沮丧地看着沉没的残骸两艘英国二战战舰——被指定为 842 人的战争坟墓——被非法打捞人员抢走了埋在海浪下的历史遗迹的珍贵钢材。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们从 2012 年开始，”Hazz 说，一位专业潜水员，对 68 米深的威尔士亲王号和反击号沉船地点了如指掌，这两艘船被派去保卫新加坡，但在 1941 年 12 月被日本鱼雷击沉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周展示在Asia 拍摄了反击号受损程度的视频片段，她指出了从后炮塔区域撕下的参差不齐的金属片，这些金属片在沉没时完好无损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“看看被非法打捞工作损坏的部分，”她说。 “那是2018年，当时的船还像船。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚扣押涉嫌洗劫英国二战坟墓的中国船只&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hazz对潜水的兴趣始于她年轻的时候1990年代。她被海底的美丽所吸引，在发现散落在全国各地水域的残骸后，她对两次世界大战的船只和飞机产生了兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种浓厚的兴趣让我开始潜水在马来西亚周围的水域以及其他拥有自己独特历史的地方，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凭借超过 30 年的潜水经验，Hazz 遇到了英国当时的威尔士亲王——现在的查尔斯国王– 2017 年，并向未来的君主简要介绍了沉船不断恶化的状况，这些沉船不仅是数百名水手的坟墓，也是英国称霸海洋的愿望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一艘散货船——中国-登记在册的 Chuan Hong 68 – 是罪魁祸首，专家说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，它一直在冲刷马来西亚的沿海浅滩，那里有许多二战残骸。这些“战前钢材”在第一次原子爆炸之前建造，没有核辐射，售价是现代钢材价格的三到五倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“川红 68”号于 5 月 28 日被扣押由马来西亚海事执法机构 (MMEA) 及其 32 名船员组成，其中包括 21 名中国公民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是同一艘驳船，”Hazz 说，她目睹了一艘在该地点周围盘旋的船只年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据新闻报道，这艘驳船曾在 2017 年打捞同样的沉船时被发现，但似乎已经返回继续其非法捕捞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它已注册为据马来西亚当局称，中国公司在福州。但中国表示，这艘船是由一家马来西亚公司租用的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论其运营的幕后黑手是谁，这艘驳船的历史都是神秘海上打捞贸易中金钱和机会主义的故事。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;对残骸的搜查是在离马来西亚海岸如此之近的水域进行的，以至于与中国的联系让许多人对中国船只可能潜入激烈竞争的海域——以及其愿望——感到不安。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但当“川红 68”的船员们故技重施时，他们被一种非常现代的方式绊倒了：TikTok。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名现场工作人员发布的视频显然很高兴看到炮塔正在建造中从一艘驳船上卸下的货物提醒马来西亚当局注意丹绒勿隆哥僻静的红树林覆盖的海岸线上发生的奇怪事件，该海岸线距离新加坡德光岛和马来西亚与邻近城市国家之间的国际边界不远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 21 日，他们发现了废料场散落着来自威尔士亲王号和反击号的零件——包括未爆弹药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后流传的照片显示，一名马来西亚官员在废料场，被一个笨重的锚和它的链节显得矮小，还有一些专家声称这是生锈的枪管。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这些舰只在战争开始时被日本航空鱼雷击沉——在海战开始两天后香港和入侵马来亚。造成的 800 多人死亡使其成为英国最严重的海军灾难之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在战争过程中，各方 400 多艘船只在马六甲海峡和南部的浅水区沉没今马来西亚附近的中国海。其中埋葬着约 15,000 名在冲突中丧生的水手的尸体，将沉船提升为战争坟墓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;距离马来西亚半岛关丹海岸 60 海里处，威尔士亲王颠倒地安顿在海底 68 米深，而浅水号侧卧在南海清澈湛蓝的海水下 56 米处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为“Force Z”的一部分部署到南海” 为了保护英国在该地区的财产——特别是马来亚和新加坡——在日本帝国海军空袭中击沉船只标志着当时的现代战舰首次在公海上被空中力量击沉。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;它预示着制空权时代的开始和英国海军霸权的终结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国前首相温斯顿丘吉尔在他的战后回忆录中描述说，在听到沉没事件后，他“翻身并在床上扭动着全身的恐惧”，再也没有“受到更直接的冲击”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这片广阔的水域中，日本是至高无上的，而我们到处都是软弱和赤裸的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;失去海空保护，“新加坡堡垒”仅在两个月后就倒塌了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，其历史意义并没有阻止一些人在厚重的高处看到潜在的财富-优质钢材在海底可控深度无人看管，导致许多地点被未经授权的打捞作业破坏。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚潜水教练在热水中亲吻中国游客&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;TikTok 视频，以及当地渔民看到起重驳船的情景，促使专家们对南海沉船现场可能存在的非法打捞活动敲响了警钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8,352-长 122 米乘 32 米的总吨 Chuan Hong 68 起重驳船注册于中国福州连江县的福建亚瑞海运公司，该公司在其网站上将其业务性质描述为“打沉沉船”国内外”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这艘驳船自 12 月以来一直在该地点作业，在那里停留了两个多星期，然后在 Tanjung Belungkor 的码头卸载废料并返回进行进一步的未经批准的打捞作业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;驳船及其 32 名船员——21 名中国公民、10 名孟加拉国人和一名马来西亚人——在 MMEA 的例行检查中因未能出示抛锚许可证而被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >; 致力于保护世界水下文化遗产的英国机构海事天文台表示，其卫星侦察显示，“川红 68”号运行了五个多月未被发现，并从威尔士亲王号上卸下了至少六船废料，耗费在现场停留超过 54 天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高级考古学家 Giles Richardson 声称有证据表明驳船在海上为避免被追踪而禁用了其自动识别系统转发器，并涉嫌使用允许移动一艘现代残骸作为进入威尔士亲王遗址的掩护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果属实，这表明官方对船舶运动的检查和对运入丹绒勿隆哥的废料的核实是完全不充分的， ” 理查森告诉《亚洲周刊》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，人们对目睹川红 68 号的担忧是有道理的，因为它还负责在 2017 年在沙巴清除三艘日本二战残骸。&lt;/p>; h3>;尽管紧张局势加剧，中国仍将参加印度尼西亚的多边海军演习&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然人们对川红 68 号了解甚少，但中国政府在 2017 年声称，一家名为埃森哲战略私人有限公司的马来西亚公司租用了起重驳船，之后印度尼西亚海军扣留了这艘船，原因是该船在南中国海最南端的印度尼西亚阿南巴斯群岛附近非法清理一艘瑞典超级油轮的残骸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该公司的注册信息，该公司已更名为 Amenture Strategy私人有限公司Bhd.，并报告其业务活动为填海造地、买卖废金属和“从海底疏浚废料废料”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其营业地址位于柔佛州士古来，距那里一小时车程从英国军舰上非法打捞的材料被卸下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚“川红”68 号是否仍被马来西亚公司租用。打给该公司的电话无人接听。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于英国朴次茅斯的皇家海军国家博物馆对“威尔士亲王号和浅水号的明显破坏行为表示担忧，这两艘船均被指定为根据英国 1986 年《军事遗迹保护法》，它们被列为受保护的地方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它们被指定为战争坟墓，”其总干事多米尼克·特维德尔 (Dominic Tweddle) 说。 “我们对海军遗产的流失及其对了解我们皇家海军历史的影响感到不安。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题也带来了地缘政治优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大片南中国海的争议非常激烈，中国声称在所谓的九段线下拥有大部分海域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是威尔士亲王号和浅水号的位置超过 240 海里（445 公里）在中国最西端的主张以西以及马来西亚无可争议的专属经济区内，使得川红 68 的活动更加令人震惊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当驳船继续在南中国海搜寻日本和英国的沉船时，一艘去年，中国在大约三个月的时间里对有争议的水域进行了考古扫荡，发现了五艘满载历史文物的古代商船。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一天，有关非法打捞太子号的消息传出在威尔士，中国国家文物局宣布已开始对在有争议的水道中发现的两艘沉没的百年明代商船进行测绘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于威尔士东北部的一个未指明区域中国海，该机构表示现在将评估如何保存和保护这两艘沉船，据称这两艘沉船具有“世界级的考古重要性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8 月，在广阔的海域发现了另外三艘沉船中国南部海岸与西沙群岛或西沙群岛之间的广阔水域，越南也称这些岛屿为黄沙群岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计中国将利用中国产沉船的发现来加强其主权主张几个世纪以来，它一直是一个活跃的海上强国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，由于南中国海的紧张局势、武装分子入侵苏禄海和繁忙的马六甲海峡沿线的海盗活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2011 年开始建造六艘濒海战斗舰的长期拖延丑闻让海军深受打击，首批交付预计在2019 年。然而，这些船都没有完成 50%，政府正在报废最后一艘船，还有五艘有待建造。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着 Chuan Hong 68 被扣押，要求马来西亚紧急行动的呼声越来越高保护沉船遗址。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于我们英国人来说，这些是重要的战争坟墓，”考古学家理查森说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于马来西亚人来说，它们是世界级的应该带来游客和金钱的著名潜水地点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当它们被摧毁时，没有人受益。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Hope our love will not change’: Chinese woman, 23, surprises Taiwan singer Richie Ren at concert by thanking him for saving her life 22 years ago]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3222296/hope-our-love-will-not-change-chinese-woman-23-surprises-taiwan-singer-richie-ren-concert-thanking?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/c18c0fb4-6e52-4662-b758-1002ccaf2ad9_2a503762.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个年轻女子感谢台湾歌手任贤齐捐款的感人故事22年前她的生活牵动着中国无数人的心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深受1980年代和90年代成长起来的人们喜爱的任正非在中国大陆仍然很受欢迎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“悲伤的太平洋”、“太温柔”和“嘿，女孩这样看”等歌曲为许多人留下了回忆，他慷慨和积极的社会形象也确保了庞大的粉丝群。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他22 年前，他在前往中国东北辽宁省沉阳市参加一场音乐会的途中进行了捐赠，而在他 2023 年全国巡回演唱会期间，这一历史在同一座城市重演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在特别会议期间演唱会现场，歌迷可以点歌，一位年轻女子站起来说：“我今年23岁，但认识你22年了。小时候，您还把我抱在怀里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2001年，我刚一岁多的时候，患上了先天性心脏病。由于我的家庭经济状况不佳，我的生活岌岌可危。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你们在去沈阳演唱会的路上看到了我的新闻，慷慨地捐助了 3 万元人民币（4,200 美元），使我能够手术挽救了我的生命。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女孩随后点歌《不要改变》表达她最美好的祝福。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我希望我们之间的爱永远改变，人与人之间的博爱和同情心也将保持不变，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被这个故事所吸引，任正非的粉丝们翻出了关于二十多年前捐赠的新闻报道，上面有照片和歌手的心声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要勇敢，记住我在等你，”任正非在女孩的救命手术前说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国，大约据MedSci报道，中国医学科学院阜外医院李守军教授称，每年有16万新生儿被诊断为先天性心脏病，这一数字一直在稳步上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;临床数据显示，大约如果不及时治疗，50% 的患者在三岁前死亡，60-70% 的患者活不过五岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事在大陆社交媒体上引发了大量感人的评论：“我很感动。这是善良和感恩的人之间的共同旅程，”一位说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位同意：“一方面，这是他不求回报的无私付出，另一方面，是女孩的生命得救，双双怀揣感恩之心。这是真爱。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人称赞任正非是一个真正的榜样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Richie真的是一个善良的人。我以前看过几篇关于他的类似新闻，其中一篇是他帮助父母找到了走失的孩子。帮助别人对他来说似乎是一件很自然的事情，”一位人士说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How much should Hong Kong pay for IVF treatments? Couples must weigh cost of test-tube babies as city reluctant to raise subsidies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3222767/how-much-should-hong-kong-pay-ivf-treatments-couples-must-weigh-cost-test-tube-babies-city-reluctant?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/b12b431e-c4b9-4e74-95ab-a277ddf927a1_ffb21543.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;42 岁的香港保险代理人 Flora Chan 已经数不清流产的次数自 2009 年结婚以来，她一直在怀孕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她多次自然受孕，但每次都在短至 5 周和长至 11 周内不幸结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年后2016 年，Chan 和她同样 42 岁的个体经营者丈夫在失望和沮丧中前往沙田威尔斯亲王医院寻求体外受精 (IVF) 治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了避免排长队，可能几个月后，她们选择接受私人服务的治疗，这意味着总共要支付大约 200,000 港元（25,528 美元），但流产仍在继续。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后她求助于一位私人专家，该专家进行了测试结果发现基因异常，并在试管婴儿治疗的同时给她开了药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇花了 300,000 港元，但 Chan 终于怀孕并一路分娩。他们的儿子现在是一个健康的三岁孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 说，虽然她和她的丈夫可以负担得起试管婴儿治疗，但许多其他夫妇可能无法支付 50 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“资助这些治疗可能不会在一夜之间解决出生率问题，但肯定会在一定程度上有所帮助，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;浪费了 130,000 美元，她的身体被“毁坏”以避免将卵子冷冻香港&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;体外受精是治疗不孕症最常见的辅助生殖技术 (ART) 类型之一，是指从女性卵巢中取出卵子，与精子一起受精的一系列医疗程序&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港每年出生的婴儿数量在去年下滑至 32,500 的历史最低点，许多年轻女性和已婚夫妇推迟生育&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在联合国人口基金最近的一份报告中，这座城市的总生育率或 TFR（一名妇女预计生育的孩子数量）在世界上表现最差&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其得分为 0.8，紧随其后的是韩国 0.9、新加坡 1.0 和日本 1.3。 TFR 应该是 2.1 才能让人口自我更新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了应对不断下降的出生率，一些立法者呼吁政府扩大对不孕症治疗和卵子冷冻服务的补贴。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;日本、新加坡、以色列和中国大陆已经增加了此类补贴，但尚未看到显着回报。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国研究发现，筛查技术可以提高试管婴儿活产率&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然香港当局和专家基本上认为提高补贴不会削弱出生率下降的趋势，许多人同意可以做更多工作来帮助寻求不孕症帮助的夫妇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;理事会的数据《人类生殖科技》显示，2020年有超过4,600名香港妇女接受ART手术，其中约有1,630名婴儿出生，占当年活产的3.8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年有超过6,000名婴儿出生大约有 2300 名婴儿出生，占当年活产的 4.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种治疗在 30 多岁的女性中更为常见，其次是 40 多岁及以上的女性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;全市只有三间公立医院为40岁以下需要转诊的已婚妇女提供资助试管受精服务，但资助的促排卵周期只有三个，每个周期约港币10,000元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么在香港，许多女性被剥夺了成为母亲的机会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;患者在转诊后必须等待长达 12 个月才能进行生育力低下评估，然后再等 4 到 7 个月才能开始治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;不愿轮候或不合资格接受公营试管婴儿服务的人士，可求助私营机构，每次治疗至少需支付港币 80,000 元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;需要更多资源以缩短排队时间&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;30 岁出头的香港人 Carol Chan 于 2021 年在伊利沙伯医院终止了妊娠，因为她三个月的胎儿被发现患有重型地中海贫血，这是一种严重的遗传性血液病，危及母亲的生命。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 和她的丈夫都是这种疾病的携带者，IVF 是他们唯一的解决方案，因为可以在将胚胎转移到子宫之前对胚胎进行疾病筛查——这种疾病发生的几率为 25% .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她被转介到玛丽医院接受体外受精治疗。她在公立医院等了六个月，并支付了约40,000港元，但唯一通过筛查的胚胎并没有成功怀孕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们想立即开始另一个周期，但我们不得不多排几个月的队，会进一步耽误时间紧迫的治疗。”去年他们搬到加拿大后，健康的女婴在多伦多出生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这对我们来说非常昂贵，”她说。 “以同样的价格，我本可以在公立医院多做几个周期，但我们不能再等了，因为我们即将移民。我们感谢玛丽医院的服务和照顾，但当然，需要更多资源来缩短排队时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前玛丽医院生殖医学科主任吴鸿宇教授Mary Hospital 表示，需要更多的工作人员和空间来进行咨询、胚胎孵化和咨询，以提高服务能力并缩短排队时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在公立医院增加一名医务人员可能意味着提供额外的 200 个周期的试管婴儿治疗一年，他说。但他认为，在私营部门补贴治疗的成本效益较低，因为那里的治疗费用更高，而且不能保证成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与其他程序不同，IVF 治疗可能需要多次尝试才能怀孕，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大学妇产科名誉临床副主任张丽萍医生同意公共部门需要更多资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“这是一个private pain&#39;：准妈妈流产和&#39;失去的禁忌&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“但如果政府要补贴私营部门的 IVF 服务，患者应该接受适当的评估，最好在公立医院，以确保治疗是必要的并防止滥用，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她解释说，许多夫妇直接在私营部门进行试管受精，而一些不孕症病例可以通过药物治疗和...即使有足够数量的卵子，它们的质量也很可能较低，”她说。 “这意味着在实验室中成功受精和着床的几率较低，母亲流产的几率更高。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;不能生孩子吗？先检查男人——50% 的生育问题归咎于他们&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她补充说，40 岁以上的女性有 40% 到 50% 的流产几率，她们的孩子也有更高的风险患上唐氏综合症等疾病.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020 年，超过 430 名 40 岁以上的女性接受了冻融胚胎移植，这是一种常见的体外受精过程，其中卵子受精，胚胎被冷冻和储存，直到它们解冻并植入女性的子宫.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些女性中只有 106 人怀孕，而在这组女性中，有 79 人继续分娩，几乎五分之二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 40 岁以上的女性中，在没有冷冻的情况下进行新鲜周期 IVF胚胎解冻后，只有不到 3% 的人继续怀孕，不到 2% 的人分娩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学 (HKU) 公共卫生学院院长 David Bishai 教授)，也是一名试管婴儿的父亲，表示监管保险政策是政府可以解决的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前香港的大部分保险产品并不涵盖ART程序的费用。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“不涵盖 ART 的健康保险单是有缺陷的产品，”Bishai 说。 “保险中基本福利包的规定必须来自政府，并且应包括经批准的技术，以帮助家庭应对意外的医疗困难。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;如果你想要孩子，请提前计划&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;为响应立法者关于建立集中式卵子银行和补贴更多试管受精治疗的呼吁，卫生局局长罗仲茂本月早些时候表示，大多数计划生育夫妇并不关心此类服务。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“生不生是个人的选择，政府不应该干预，但政府会努力提供家庭友好型政策，为生育营造支持性的环境，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;我的孩子还活着吗？”：夫妇在胚胎混合抚养陌生人的儿子得到 93,000 美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“在公共医疗系统中分配资源时，重要的是要在提供辅助生殖服务和其他服务之间找到平衡点挽救生命的医疗服务，尤其是私营部门无法获得或可能更昂贵的服务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;港大人口专家叶兆辉同意，ART 无法扭转局面出生趋势下降，表明新加坡和以色列的失败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“附带收益很小，与成本不成比例，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，政府&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生殖医学专家梁家康医生表示，准备结婚的夫妇和新婚夫妇应及早定期进行生育测试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;那些发现生育能力下降迹象的人可以决定是早点生孩子还是冷冻卵子和精子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说政府可以为此类检查发放代金券，并扩大计划生育协会婚前和孕前检查的服务能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“这很伤脑筋但很值得”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;立法会议员 Nixie Lam Lam，41 岁，8 岁怀有试管婴儿几个月的她说，应该做更多的工作来让女性了解自己的生殖健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在成长过程中经历过严重的痛经，但直到 2019 年，她才准备怀孕后，她发现自己的子宫受到了影响，后来导致 4 年内发生了 3 次流产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam 和她的丈夫，一位 34 岁的私人投资者，随后求助于 IVF .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很多香港女性直到30岁才关心自己的生殖健康，”她说。 “政府应该补贴 20 多岁女性的相关检查，例如子宫颈抹片检查和盆腔超声检查，以便尽早发现问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频创作者 Sona Ng So-na，33 岁，是一个两岁孩子的母亲老试管婴儿女孩，回忆起自己的怀孕是一次“伤脑筋”的经历。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;嫁给了一个32岁的商人，在经历了三次流产后，她于2020年寻求试管婴儿治疗。尽管第一次尝试就怀孕了，但在最初的几个月里，她的阴道出现了很多斑点，医生开了黄体酮激素注射剂、药丸和栓剂来维持婴儿的健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我每天醒来都希望有时间会过得更快，”她说，“每天打针，我的肚子上布满瘀伤，有时拔出针头时满是血，非常可怕。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不知道谁打过在接受试管婴儿治疗后，她努力获取信息来回答她的许多问题。她希望卫生当局可以做更多的工作来教育和提高认识，例如建立一个问答网页。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她所经历的孤独感也促使她建立了一个社交媒体社区，聚集了数百名母亲准备接受试管婴儿治疗，希望提供一个相互支持和信息交流的平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但与生育相比，整个试管婴儿过程的挑战不值一提，”她说。 “如果一个人只是受到父母的压力，或者对孩子没有感情，就不应该尝试试管受精。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，最后，有了孩子，Ng 和她的丈夫觉得这一切都是值得的，他们正在为今年晚些时候的第二个 IVF 婴儿制定计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们非常爱孩子，而且我们从未如此快乐，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UN agency warns there is no let-up in drugs trade from Asia’s Golden Triangle]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222821/un-agency-warns-there-no-let-drugs-trade-asias-golden-triangle?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/799ca103-e747-4c87-8bc1-2d62210da400_88fcb5ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;来自东南一个小角落的巨额冰毒等非法毒品交易联合国毒品和犯罪问题办公室周五警告说，亚洲没有放缓的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该地区继续生产和贩运大量甲基苯丙胺，同时生产氯胺酮和其他合成药物该机构的 2023 年报告《东亚和东南亚的合成毒品——自 Covid-19 大流行后边界重新开放以来的第一份报告》说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报告显示了犯罪集团重新建立的模式自己处于大流行前阶段，并显着改变了贩运路线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以片剂和冰毒形式存在的甲基苯丙胺的大部分来自被称为金三角的地区，该地区与缅甸、老挝和泰国相遇。鸦片和海洛因的生产曾经在那里蓬勃发展，主要是因为缅甸偏远的东部掸邦周围无法无天。该地区大部分是丛林，仍然是各种少数民族民兵的领地，其中一些是毒品交易的合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“甲基苯丙胺仍然是东亚和东南亚最常用的药物，并且使用在过去十年中有所增加，”报告说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰国寺庙在所有僧侣都未通过药检后空无一人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;工业规模生产也比劳动力更容易-鸦片的密集种植，从中提取海洛因。然后，毒品通过陆路、海上和空中在亚洲和太平洋各地分发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，主要有组织犯罪集团对领土的控制“使他们能够大规模增加和多样化供应市场扩张和支配的目的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最强大的区域贩运网络能够高度确定地运作，他们可以而且不会被阻止，并且他们能够规定条款和条件”它说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去的十年里，东亚和东南亚几乎每年都有创纪录的甲基苯丙胺缉获量，但最新数据表明，缉获的毒品总量在 2022 年有所下降根据报告，减少到 151 吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;缉获量下降通常与生产减弱有关，但报告称“其他指标——逮捕、街头供应、纯度、创纪录的低批发和街头价格，以及接受治疗的人数——表明供应量仍然很高或没有变化。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毒品和犯罪问题办公室东南亚和太平洋区域代表杰里米·道格拉斯周五在曼谷举行的新闻发布会上特别指出，缅甸掸邦的局势was “quite concerning” due to the past year&#39;s unprecedented drop in drug seizures there, despite being “the epicentre of production for Asia-Pacific,” which he said was directly related to the conflicts and instability in the area.&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;The report suggests the overall decrease in seizures was due to traffickers changing their smuggling routes from land to maritime to evade authorities, explaining that shipments are made by sea from Myanmar&#39;s coastal regions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thailand recently made two major busts of crystal meth that was expected to be transported to a third country by sea. On Tuesday, nearly a tonne of the drugs was seized off the coast in the Gulf of Thailand, which Thai authorities suspected were en route to be loaded to a bigger ship in international waters. Drugs that were seized in several recent raids were supposedly bound for Australia, Thai authorities have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Traffickers are a little more successful last year than in the previous year, and they were able to connect to market mainly using maritime routes that were not noticed by people over the course of the year,” Douglas said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The UN office also expressed concern that Cambodia has become “a key transit and to some extent production point for the regional drug trade.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It suggests that even though there has been consolidation of synthetic drug production in the Golden Triangle, that development may reflect “some diversification of production and &#39;hedging&#39; by organised crime.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Industrial-scale ketamine labs and facilities for processing and storing the substance were found across Cambodia, raising serious concern throughout the region, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Organised crime groups have adopted a supply-driven market expansion modality similar to the approach taken to expand the methamphetamine market in the region that started in 2015,” warns the report about the trade-in ketamine, which has legal use as an anaesthetic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Landlocked Laos, near both Shan State and northern Thailand, is another weak link in the fight against the drug trade, and “intelligence officials have come to the conclusion that supply is transiting the country with little resistance,” says the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report says that in addition to becoming an increasingly important route for drugs trafficked out of Myanmar, meth tablet production was also detected there in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It says that meth and other drugs produced in Shan State laboratories usually enter Laos by crossing the Mekong river from ports “under the control or influence of major non-state armed groups,” naming some of them: ethnic militias including the United Wa State Army, the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army, the National Democratic Alliance Army, “and their allies who work in partnership with transnational organised crime syndicates.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The case of Laos also illustrates the difficulties of blocking the ingredients needed to produce the drugs from reaching the illegal labs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Laos, it says, is becoming an increasingly important route for chemicals reportedly used in drug production in Myanmar, entering the country through Vietnam, Thailand, and China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Efforts to disrupt chemical flows into Myanmar&#39;s drug-producing areas also continue to be impeded by slow and bureaucratic inter-agency coordination, inadequate resources and personnel, and limited cross border cooperation,” the report says, and traffickers are finding alternatives for obtaining their supplies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The main chemicals needed to make methamphetamines are generally under tight international controls, so illicit laboratories in recent years have moved to using chemicals that are not so closely regulated. The report says that the logistics of obtaining such chemicals have also been expedited by online ordering, especially from suppliers willing to disguise the nature of the transactions.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shangri-La Dialogue: US defence chief Lloyd Austin doubles down on security alliance push]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3222826/shangri-la-dialogue-us-defence-chief-lloyd-austin-doubles-down-security-alliance-push?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/4099efc9-c881-48e0-b066-1e9e2cb6d500_ef316a92.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin underlined US resolve to shore up alliances and partnerships in the Asia-Pacific in a speech to a key security summit in Singapore on Saturday morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stressing there was no room for intimidation, bullying or coercion, he said the US was doubling down on reinforcing its security alliances and partnerships.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our shared goals are clear: to deter aggression and to deepen the rules and norms that promote prosperity and prevent conflict,” he said at the Shangri-La Dialogue, a three-day defence summit run by the International Institute for Strategic Studies think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His speech to hundreds of officials and analysts is focusing on the United States&#39; views on hotspots in the Asia-Pacific, especially on Taiwan and the South China Sea, issues on which Washington has accused Beijing of using force – and sometimes falling foul of international law – to force its geopolitical interests onto other countries in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Beijing and Washington clash on Taiwan, compete on advanced weapons development and engage in close encounters in the South China Sea and elsewhere, the United States has shifted funds to its Asian allies and partners to shore up their defensive abilities and held joint drills with armed forces in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So we&#39;re stepping up planning and coordination and training with our friends, from the East China Sea to the South China Sea to the Indian Ocean,” Austin said. “That includes staunch allies such as Australia, Japan, Republic of Korea, the Philippines and Thailand.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US had reinforced deterrence to prevent conflict and stood for rule and norms that “protect us all”, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More to follow …&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its national security strategy released in October, the US described China as the only competitor with the intent and power to reshape the international order to become more accommodating to its authoritarian political system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Pentagon&#39;s national defence strategy, also from October, said the US military would focus on efforts to deter Chinese “aggression” against American interests and to “prevail in conflict if deterrence fails”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has often criticised the framing of US-China relations as a competition and has accused the US of containment with its system of allies in the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI, post-Covid work from home culture will reverse slump in world PC sales, Acer CEO says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3222770/ai-post-covid-work-home-culture-will-reverse-slump-world-pc-sales-acer-ceo-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/b87f40ac-f85b-4272-83b3-8186f924cafd_076f668a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A post-coronavirus work from home culture and rising unit prices will stop the long slump in PC sales caused by weak consumer confidence, the head of the world&#39;s sixth-largest vendor said this week during the Computex Taipei tech show.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sales of laptops and desktops have declined over the past 12 months because inflation and interest rates combined to hurt consumer sentiment, Jason Chen, the chairman and CEO of Taiwanese hardware and electronics firm Acer, told the Post said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the surge in PC purchases during the pandemic for remote working and home study means more machines than before will need to be replaced during the next so-called refresh cycle, Chen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A refresh cycle usually refers to business replacement of hardware and software every three to five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From the macro level, inflation has triggered interest rates, and the interest rates have triggered [weaker] consumer confidence, and because of that, the end-user demand made a drastic change about four quarters ago,” said 61-year-old Chen, who was appointed CEO in 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Interest rates have risen as central banks tightened monetary policy to combat inflation, which grew in much of the world last year due to rising energy prices and shipping costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Working from home, however, shows no sign of disappearing despite the end of Covid-19 controls, Chen added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said remote working and studying at home during the pandemic meant that every family member had a PC rather than sharing one.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Wow, what a view! China&#39;s &#39;digital nomads&#39; seek paradise while on the clock&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Around a third of workers with jobs that can be conducted remotely are working from home, the Pew Research Centre said in a survey released in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When we talk about refresh cycles, the numbers required will be higher because of the bigger installation base,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fields such as accounting and human resources “people get used to that working model and it&#39;s harder to get them back,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Consumers are already buying up PC accessories, such as docking stations and different kinds of connectors, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PC shipments across vendors reached 286.2 million units last year, down by 16.2 per cent from 2021, according to market research firm Gartner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shipments of just 55.2 million units in the first three months of 2023, representing a 30 per cent decrease from the first quarter of 2022, follow what Gartner describes as an “unfavourable combination of oversupply and continued low PC demand due to economic uncertainties”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Acer sold 3.523 million units in the first quarter, according to Gartner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rising average sales prices of PCs stand to increase overall sales revenues, Chen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Consumers are often willing to pay more for PCs with strong computing power and parts made from recycled materials, he added, with the PC gaming market already “declining less”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the next few years, the demand for generative chatbots such as ChatGPT will drive purchases of late-model PCs, Chen said, as phones are not suitable due to their lack of keypads and small screens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Generative AI will become more popular and people will use it for productive purposes,” said Chen, who previously worked for 14 years at Intel and eight years at Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen said India and Indonesia are also taking increasing numbers of PCs because of their relatively large young population employed by burgeoning manufacturing sectors.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The next Bali? Taiwan city tries to lure remote workers amid talent shortage&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Market research firm IDC ranks Acer, which plans to expand sales and marketing in both countries, as the fourth-largest vendor in India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In another boost to global PC sales, Chen said Chromebooks orders are also picking up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Acer, among other brands, make the lightweight notebooks together with Google.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;School districts in the US and Europe are placing orders, Chen said, and Acer is discussing sales with India and Japan.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ticking time bomb: just how widespread are Hong Kong’s undetected illegal property renovations?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3222506/ticking-time-bomb-just-how-widespread-are-hong-kongs-undetected-illegal-property-renovations?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/01/bd639b10-6bc1-44f2-96fc-3642dbd0b6a7_19d5aa49.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A house of cards. That might have been what some Lohas Park residents in Tseung Kwan O felt they were living in when they found that a flat owner had carried out illegal modifications on a load-bearing wall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The discovery that a structural wall had been partially demolished was made by keen-eyed viewers in a video of the renovated flat. If it had not been uploaded onto a property-related channel with over 30,000 subscribers (the video has since been pulled), the illegal modification is likely to have remained hidden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This raises a point – just how many other similarly compromised flats exist in a housing market that remains one of the world&#39;s most expensive?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s flats are not only expensive, but 59 per cent of private residential buildings are more than 30 years old. A Legislative Council report found that, at the end of 2019, many of the roughly 35,700 residential buildings were approaching the end of their 50-year working life. A fifth had been built in 1969 or earlier, and another 39 per cent were 30-49 years old.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ageing flats are a concern as any permanent structural damage affects safety. Other factors such as property valuation and the determination of mortgages and insurance premiums are also affected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compromised load-bearing walls will shift the burden to other walls. Overloaded walls can fail, causing building damage. It is only a matter of time before structural failure happens – making it a ticking time bomb. The 2010 To Kwa Wan building collapse at Ma Tau Wai Road is a stern reminder that illegal modifications have serious ramifications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With such devastating consequences, the elephant in the room is the absence of a mechanism to detect such modifications. Owners are unlikely to report their own illegal work and the problem may never surface until it becomes too late to rectify. Some offenders may wrongly believe that, since the building has not collapsed, it probably never will.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most Hongkongers spend their life savings just to be able to afford a home. Often, this will be in multistorey building where owners and tenants have to depend on one other to comply with the law and deploy common sense. Like the Chinese saying, when everyone is on the same boat, we don&#39;t start drilling holes in it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But common sense is not always common. On a recent flight, while the seat belt sign was on, I counted no less than six passengers getting up to go to the toilet despite in-flight announcements to remain seated. Staying in place when the seat-belt sign is on is for the safety of all passengers. Only half were stopped while the others simply ignored the attendants and rushed into the toilets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While only a very small minority did this, the point is that it only takes one person to compromise the structural integrity of an entire building. Take the example of a recent flight in South Korea, when one person opened an emergency exit door mid-air and endangered all other passengers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If people cannot even be trusted to respect straightforward safety rules that are enforced in plain view, trusting everyone in the privacy of their own homes to respect all the building rules may be a little optimistic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Lohas Park incident, the different parties involved – at the very least, the homeowner, interior designer and renovation workers – had all failed to point out the significance of a load-bearing wall before commencing demolition work. Even after alterations, staff involved in filming the modifications did not realise the detrimental effect, despite including the original and amended floor plans in the video.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not all is lost, however. There is a legal framework to deal with the high-density nature of homes, such as providing for the formation of an incorporated owners&#39; committee for building management and a deed of mutual covenant to set out the rights and obligations of a building.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Owners planning alteration works on their flats are required to ensure they comply with the Buildings Ordinance and its subsidiary legislation. But this provides little comfort next to the question I posed at the beginning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If no one is able to detect these illegal modifications, could we all be living in a ticking time bomb? If using such strong words can raise awareness to prevent these illegal alterations from recurring, it will be worth it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden says ‘crisis averted’ as he celebrates debt ceiling deal in first Oval Office address]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222825/joe-biden-says-crisis-averted-he-celebrates-debt-ceiling-deal-first-oval-office-address?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 07:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/7b8a96b4-a1f1-47ef-999a-a0f35732bd7e_7c488b37.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;President Joe Biden celebrated a “crisis averted” in his inaugural speech to the nation from the Oval Office Friday evening, ready to sign a budget agreement that eliminates the potential for a first-ever government default that would have sent shock waves through the US and global economies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bipartisan measure was approved by the Senate late Thursday night after passing the House in yet another late session the night before. Biden is set to sign it at the White House on Saturday with just two days to spare until the Treasury Department has warned the US would not be able to meet its obligations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agreement was hashed out by Biden and House Speaker Kevin McCarthy, giving Republicans some of their demanded federal spending cuts but holding the line on major Democratic priorities. It raises the debt limit until 2025 – after the 2024 presidential election – and gives legislators budget targets for the next two years, in hopes of assuring fiscal stability as the political season heats up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“No one got everything they wanted but the American people got what they needed,” Biden said, highlighting the “compromise and consensus” in the deal. “We averted an economic crisis and an economic collapse.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re cutting spending and bringing deficits down at the same time,” Biden said. “We&#39;re protecting important priorities from Social Security to Medicare to Medicaid to veterans to our transformational investments in infrastructure and clean energy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden&#39;s remarks were the most detailed comments from the Democratic president on the compromise he and his staff negotiated. He largely remained quiet publicly during the high-stakes talks, a decision that frustrated some members of his party but was intended to give space for both sides to reach a deal and for lawmakers to vote it to his desk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Passing this budget agreement was critical,” Biden was to say. “The stakes could not have been higher.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said on Friday that Biden was using the occasion to deliver his first address to the nation from behind the Resolute Desk in the Oval Office because “he just wanted to make sure that the American people understood how important it was to get this done, how important it was to do this in a bipartisan way”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;McCarthy&#39;s moment: US debt win secures House speaker&#39;s standing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Biden praised McCarthy and his negotiators for operating in good faith, and all congressional leaders for ensuring swift passage of the legislation. “They acted responsibly, and put the good of the country ahead of politics,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overall, the 99-page bill restricts spending for the next two years and changes some policies, including imposing new work requirements for older Americans receiving food aid and greenlighting an Appalachian natural gas pipeline that many Democrats oppose. Some environmental rules were modified to help streamline approvals for infrastructure and energy projects – a move long sought by moderates in Congress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Congressional Budget Office estimates it could actually expand total eligibility for federal food assistance, with the elimination of work requirements for veterans, homeless people and young people leaving foster care.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The legislation also bolsters funds for defence and veterans, cuts back some new money for Internal Revenue Service and rejects Biden&#39;s call to roll back Trump-era tax breaks on corporations and the wealthy to help cover the nation&#39;s deficits. But the White House said the IRS&#39; plans to step up enforcement of tax laws for high-income earners and corporations would continue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agreement also imposes an automatic overall 1 per cent cut to spending programmes if Congress fails approve its annual spending bills – a measure designed to pressure lawmakers of both parties to reach consensus before the end of the financial year in September.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In both chambers, more Democrats backed the legislation than Republicans, but both parties were critical to its passage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Senate the tally was 63-36 including 46 Democrats and independents and 17 Republicans in favour, 31 Republicans along with four Democrats and one independent who caucuses with the Democrats opposed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vote in the House was 314-117.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI sector a bright spot in tough jobs market for China’s graduates, as ChatGPT frenzy spurs new employer demand]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3222811/ai-sector-bright-spot-tough-jobs-market-chinas-graduates-chatgpt-frenzy-spurs-new-employer-demand?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/7fecab30-8d11-4dac-8cd4-6d694131a28a_8827b31d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A surge in the number of job offers in China&#39;s artificial intelligence (AI) sector for college graduates has become one of the few bright spots in an otherwise bleak jobs market, according to a report by a local recruitment platform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While China&#39;s youth jobless rate has hit a new high and with conditions mostly tough for the country&#39;s 11.6 million fresh graduates, those with degrees related to large language models (LLMs), the AI technology behind the rise of Microsoft-backed OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT, are in short supply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this space, the number of related job openings has surged 172.5 per cent from a year earlier, according to Liepin&#39;s 2023 employment report for Chinese university graduates.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Province rolls out 100-day plan to help China&#39;s anxious graduates &#39;land a job&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;San Francisco-based OpenAI launched its conversational bot ChatGPT last autumn, setting off a global AI arms race, with Chinese Big Tech firms rushing to launch similar services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A local headhunter said earlier that the explosion in demand for AI jobs started a while ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since late last year, we have been getting increased inquiries from local tech firms looking for talent working in LLMs and AI-generated content, and some are willing to offer fat pay cheques,” Max Xiao Mafeng, co-founder and CEO at recruitment agency TTC Consultancy, told the Post in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roles involving algorithms, deep learning, and natural language processing (NLP) – all critical to developing ChatGPT-like services – are among the most popular jobs in the LLM area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A student who majored in NLP at the University of Electronic Science and Technology of China – located in Chengdu, capital city of Sichuan province – said in a Thursday post to career-focused social networking site Maimai that he has already landed five offers from companies including Meituan, Shein, Xiaomi, battery marker CATL and logistics giant SF Express.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apart from AI, employment opportunities in the new energy and new materials sectors saw 93.9 per cent and 30 per cent year-on-year increases respectively, making them the second- and third-fastest growing sectors for job increases among the 18 emerging areas Liepin analysed in the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s expected 11.6 million college graduates this year – a record – comes at a time when the country&#39;s youth unemployment rate for those aged between 16 and 24 has also hit a record high, reaching more than 20 per cent in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 60 per cent of students surveyed in the Liepin report have not secured a job offer yet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, despite a much tougher regulatory environment in recent years that has seen thousands of lay-offs, the country&#39;s Big Tech firms are still the top choice among elite school graduates in China. Overseas returnees had a preference for multinationals, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overall, Chinese graduates expressed an increasing preference for job security over other factors, with employment in state-owned enterprises (SOEs) and governmental agencies top choices. Nearly half, or 45 per cent of students, wanted to work at SOEs, versus almost 27 per cent for governmental agencies, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Police attack on reporter sparks rare public debate, outrage in China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3222716/police-attack-reporter-sparks-rare-public-debate-outrage-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/73514918-8d42-4787-b139-9210eaac3cba_20db83c8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The assault of a Chinese reporter by three police officers over his investigation into the deaths of two teachers has sparked a heated and rare public debate about the hostility and heavy restrictions faced by journalists in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The officers were suspended and detained for allegedly beating the reporter, surnamed Li, from the online outlet Jimu News, according to a statement issued on Thursday by the Bijie municipal government in the southern province of Guizhou.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statement failed to quell the concerns of China&#39;s online community, with more than 5 million views of the attack by Friday. A number of state media outlets have also condemned brutality against journalists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li was assaulted on May 23 in Guizhou after arriving from Hubei province to follow up his earlier reporting on the teachers, who drowned in a local river after a sudden discharge by a power station upstream. Authorities are still investigating the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a widely circulated social media posting Xu Jiangqiao, an editor for Jimu News – which is affiliated to Hubei Daily – said “we stand firm to defend the rights of reporters and demand justice [for Li]”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For the Bijie [municipal government] in Guizhou, it&#39;s important to give us reporters and the public an account [of the incident], make public the identity of the attackers and any persons who instigated the attack,” Xu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese authorities sack, detain 3 police officers after reporter beating&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;State news agency China News Service also condemned the assault, saying in a commentary that it was “a blatant violation to journalists&#39; normal duties of supervision [of officials] through public opinion”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;one Weibo user wrote: “Why did the police officers follow the reporter? Who gave the order? This is the key!” Another said: “We should support the reporter and not let reporters covering social news feel frightened and disappointed.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhan Jiang, a retired professor with Beijing Foreign Studies University who closely tracks China&#39;s media issues, said the industry had faced growing hostility in recent years, with an increase in censorship and violence against reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The media environment] is at a stage of suffocation. It&#39;s not that the supervision role of media has vanished but it is true that it has been greatly reduced,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Most investigative reporters have left the industry, especially those who specialise in &#39;hard core&#39; topics, and those who have stayed face huge difficulties in their reporting.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s already the epilogue&#39;: censorship, cost-cutting hit China&#39;s media industry&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;One challenge – highlighted by Li&#39;s case – is a ban on local media from reporting on “negative issues”, which has prompted investigative journalists to cover stories in other provinces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Reporters are basically not allowed to report on local negative news … the governments cannot control media from other places – especially from other provinces – so this kind of incident happens if local officials feel offended,” Zhan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, several journalists were beaten and barred from reporting in Henan province, central China, after travelling there from Chengdu, Beijing and Chongqing to report on the deaths of several children who were found buried in an illegal construction site.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Lethal illegal building works in China can&#39;t be torn down fast enough&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chu Chaoxin, a former reporter for Southern Weekly, was surprised that the latest incident had drawn such attention and public support for the reporter. “The media environment is not good, but it has received so much attention and that is unexpected to me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chu said there were reporters who still strove for media freedom, despite the hostility and challenges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Media control has tightened since 2016, when Chinese President Xi Jinping ordered Communist Party outlets to toe the party&#39;s line on all major issues. In a high-profile visit to newsrooms, Xi said all reporting and commentaries should follow “the right direction”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s top party mouthpieces pledge &#39;absolute loyalty&#39; as president makes rare visits to newsrooms&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to Zhan, the harassment of journalists also reflected the pressure on local governments to maintain social stability above all else. Under such a mentality, the space for media could further diminish, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi warned on Tuesday that China was facing more complex and difficult national security concerns. Chairing a meeting of the National Security Commission, he urged officials to be ready to face the challenges of “high winds and waves and even perilous storms”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China sits in 179th place on the Reporters Without Borders index – one spot above North Korea. The press freedom NGO describes China as “the world&#39;s largest prison” for journalists, with regular campaigns of repression against journalism and the right to information worldwide.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China-Australia trade: what’s the state of relations after 3 years of ups and downs?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3222743/china-australia-trade-whats-state-relations-after-3-years-ups-and-downs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 04:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/d79e27d0-733c-4312-bb6a-db3f8eae6d8f_7448c6ce.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After no in-person talks since 2019, the trade ministers from China and Australia met twice in May, highlighting how relations between Beijing and Canberra continue to thaw after years of frosty diplomatic wrangling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australian Minister for Trade and Tourism Don Farrell first travelled to Beijing for a meeting with Chinese counterpart Wang Wentao on May 12 before the pair reunited in the US city of Detroit during an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (Apec) meeting later in the month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relations between China and Australia turned sour in 2020 after the then-Morrison administration asked for a probe into the origin of the coronavirus with other world leaders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing responded with unofficial bans on Australian products, including lobsters, coal, cotton and logs, while it also imposed official import tariffs on wine and barley.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relations have since improved, starting with a meeting between President Xi Jinping and new Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in November on the sidelines of the G20 meeting in Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But what is the state of play in relations between Australia and its largest trading partner?&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China officially imposed duties of between 116.2 per cent and 218.4 per cent on Australian wines in containers of up to two litres in March 2021 after concluding anti-dumping investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The duties – higher than the preliminary tariffs – were due to be applied for five years, after the Chinese commerce ministry reiterated a decision made in November 2020 that the domestic wine industry had been hurt by the dumping of cheap Australian wine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Canberra lodged a formal complaint with the World Trade Organization (WTO) over China&#39;s imposition of anti-dumping duties on Australian wine exports in June 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is believed that Australia has asked for the tariffs on wine to be removed in full, or returned to the previous pre-sanction levels, before Australia will drop its WTO investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In October, Wine Australia said Australian wine exports to China plunged by 92 per cent to A$21 million (US$13 million) in the year ended September 30.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s commerce ministry said in mid-April that it would review the necessity of continuing to impose anti-dumping and anti-subsidy tariffs on imported Australian barley, with the survey to be completed within a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Days before, Australian foreign minister Penny Wong said Australia would suspend its WTO case after China&#39;s tariffs of 80.5 per cent on Australian barley all but wiped out imports of the grain by the world&#39;s biggest beer market. Australia submitted its formal complaint to the WTO in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the start of June, Farrell said that China&#39;s review into the tariffs was heading in the “right direction” and that the process was “close to completed”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the tariffs, trade had ranged between A$1.5 billion (US$1 billion) and A$2 billion a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Australian lobsters were caught up in the unofficial bans after Canberra called for an international inquiry into the origin of Covid-19 in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since November 2020, legal imports of live Australian rock lobsters into China have fallen to virtually zero.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, before the ban was put in place, more than 90 per cent of Australian rock lobsters were exported to China, and figures from the Australian agriculture department showed that the market was worth about A$750 million (US$517 million) a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia has diversified lobster exports to Hong Kong and Vietnam, though some have entered the Chinese market via grey channels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was reported in early 2023 that China was discussing customs clearance for Australian lobsters.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Coal was another commodity caught up in the unofficial bans after Canberra called for an international inquiry into the origin of Covid-19 in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March 2020 – before China&#39;s unofficial ban on Australian coal – imports of coking coal had reached 4.36 million tonnes, while 5.65 million tonnes of thermal coal entered the Chinese market, according to official data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s state planner, the National Development and Reform Commission, was reported to have held talks with four state-owned importers in January this year over a partial lifting of the verbal ban on Australian thermal and coking coal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, China&#39;s coking coal purchase from Australia quadrupled from the previous month, while thermal coal imports rose fourteenfold.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Once the biggest market for Australian cotton, the A$900 million (US$621 million) trade ground to a halt in late 2020 after China imposed a series of official and unofficial restrictions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China imported 20,000 tonnes of Australian cotton in 2022, compared with 400,000 in 2019, according to Chinese customs data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it was reported in February this year that Chinese buyers were buying up Australian cotton, and that it was being shipped to a bonded warehouse in Qingdao and possibly one other location.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s foreign minister to visit Australia in July for &#39;reciprocal visit&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chinese ambassador Xiao Qian said in May – days after Australian trade minister Farrell returned from a trip to Beijing – that China would resume imports of Australian timber.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The once A$600 million (US$399 million) annual timber trade with China had been largely suspended since late 2020 after Beijing said it had found pests in shipments coming from several Australian ports.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Post reported in May that China&#39;s foreign minister, Qin Gang, may visit Australia in July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The expected trip to Canberra would follow a meeting between Australian foreign minister Wong and Qin&#39;s predecessor, Wang Yi, in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang also accepted an invitation from Farrell to visit Australia, during their meeting in Beijing in May.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>