<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Mourning and anger continues after Chinese school roof collapse]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3229397/mourning-and-anger-continues-after-chinese-school-roof-collapse?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/7ce9f4e7-ea18-4ff3-9f95-0c00eabbb63b_6a56fcf1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国东北地区学校体育馆屋顶倒塌事件中遇难者的家人和朋友标志着周六是具有重要文化意义的哀悼日，全国各地的普通民众向遇难者表示哀悼，并向遇难者致以哀悼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人传统上认为，人死后的第七天是亲人灵魂安息的日子。她们最后一次重访这个世界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周日，黑龙江省齐齐哈尔市屋顶垮塌，造成10名中学女排队员和教练死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;周六早些时候，一位母亲在网上发布的消息中表示，她在女儿第二天被海葬之前，已经准备了一些化妆品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的孩子，你的书包被发现了[在废墟]昨天你的手机却不见了，只有奖牌和你攒下来的零用钱，你知道我看着这一切有多伤心吗？据湖南省长沙电视台拥有的一个在线视频帐户显示，这位母亲写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国城市因学校倒塌后未能及时通知家长而受到批评&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我知道你爱美丽，第二天早上醒来时，我会带口红、腮红和眼影去太平间和海葬。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国高度审查的互联网上，社交媒体用户与家人一起悲伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;病毒视频显示，校门外放置了数百杯珍珠奶茶、零食、酸奶和鲜花，以悼念死者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据信是全国各地的人订购的，由外卖骑手送货上门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的朋友在网上看到一些帖子，说有人付了珍珠奶茶或果汁的费用送到学校，所以“他点了一些，送货员给他拍了一张照片，可见很多人都做了同样的事情。”一位距离齐齐哈尔约 1400 公里的山西省的互联网用户在社交媒体平台微博上写道。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“我们为这些年轻人感到非常遗憾，因为他们在生命中最美好的时光经历了这样的悲剧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人在评论死者悼词时继续表达对这起事故的愤怒三十四中在线发布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“七天来，痛苦摩擦着银河，化作星星，化作明月，化作你们的脸，留在你们家人的心里。”崇拜你的老师、同学”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们只想知道是谁蹭了屋顶，蹭了人心”，一位微博用户写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “这是一场人为灾难，”另一位写道，而第三位则补充道：“请你不要打扰天地吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这起事故引发了人们的疑问：它是如何以及为何会发生的？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;初步调查显示，屋顶上非法存放建筑材料，导致屋顶倒塌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;建筑工程师付建一告诉上海新闻门户网站论文称这是一个“低级常识性错误”，本应由地方当局和监管机构制止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;悲剧发生后，中国教育部已下令全国中小学和大学加强处理&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;全国学校体育场屋顶塌陷，至少10人被困&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据澎湃新闻报道，安徽、安徽、宁夏、吉林、河北、河南等地，部分高校已发布新的安全须知。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong bringing green power to Indonesia? Mainland Chinese tech behind 2 firms’ bids to service rural areas with air travel, electricity]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3229402/hong-kong-bringing-green-power-indonesia-mainland-chinese-tech-behind-2-firms-bids-service-rural?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 15:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/e3f18a06-ee15-415b-afab-22e066e390ac_be5802d0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;两家香港企业正在利用中国内地的绿色技术提供电力和航空运输到印度尼西亚的农村社区。&lt;/​​p>;&lt;p>;香港人 Brian Chan Pak-lam 的目标是年底前在 Bangka 岛上开设一座生物质发电厂，而前银行家 Henry Hooi Hing Lee 则计划使用电池驱动的飞机提供航空服务中国大陆制造。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多周二在雅加达会见行政长官李家超时，强调绿色电力和交通是香港企业值得探索的高潜力领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚拥有 2.76 亿人口和遍布其广阔群岛的 18,000 个岛屿，是东南亚国家联盟（东盟）中面积最大、人口最多的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港与印度尼西亚签署 15 项协议李约翰宣扬东盟关系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;今年上半年，东盟获得了 452 亿美元的外国直接投资，而香港则以 35 亿美元的规模跻身三大投资者之列，仅次于新加坡和中国内地。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;商人陈，经营 PT。 Rimba Palma Sejahtera Lestari 表示，邦加的渔业社区依赖柴油发电机，需要稳定的电力供应才能繁荣发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了出口渔获，他们需要制冰，而制冰又需要电力。为了维持更大出口量的冷链和储存，他们需要稳定的电力供应。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的香港家族企业 ELL Environmental Holdings 于 15 年前开始在印度尼西亚投资。该公司于 2016 年收购了苏门答腊岛现有的一座生物质发电厂，并决定在东部的 Bangka 建造一座新发电厂，所用的专业知识和设备主要来自中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈预计新工厂和生物燃料供应链为岛民创造更多样化的就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，印尼电力市场的竞争力不如大陆，根据与当地政府的协议，他的公司可以收取更高水平的电价。&lt;/p>;&lt;他补充说，即便如此，直接供电将使邦加渔民的成本不到柴油发电机费用的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们预见到印度尼西亚的许多岛屿需要经济发展，这将需要他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但随着 2 月份印度尼西亚总统大选的临近，他的公司将所有新计划搁置至少 12 个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港，印尼领导人在雅加达会谈期间重点关注更深层次的经济联系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“只有当选总统提名内阁后，部长的选择变得明确，我们才能知道政策的变化，”他说。 “我们必须小心，因为影响可能会持续20至25年。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前银行家Hooi是马来西亚人，在香港生活了27年后，他形容自己“大部分时间是香港人”当他注意到岛上居民的交通困难时，他在印度尼西亚发现了一个机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多村民无法走出社区，因为飞行成本太高，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他正在计划使用中国辽宁通用航空学院设计的小型电池驱动飞机推出一系列新的航空服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港和印度尼西亚交易所考虑交叉上市、联合产品&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;他表示，四座 RX4E 电动飞机的运营成本将比传统飞机更便宜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它可以帮助建立交通、医疗服务和牙科服务、农业、测量、通勤飞行和生态网络-旅游业，”他说。 “村民可以有更多机会参与或做他们无法做的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三年前，他创立了初创公司 Volar Air Mobility 来营销中国电动飞机，并与多家公司签署了多项协议马来西亚和印度尼西亚的合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括 PT Bum Desa，这是一家监管印度尼西亚各地数千家农村合作社的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度尼西亚人通过 TikTok 直播销售热潮获利&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;另一个热衷于将游客飞往龙目岛的林贾尼山。火山口湖现在只能通过三天的徒步才能到达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一位负责旅游业的部长发现这个想法很棒，因为游客不用徒步三天，而是可以在两个小时内看到这个湖，并花上”Hooi 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他希望明年向客户交付第一架 RX4E，但必须首先获得中国和印度尼西亚当局的适航认证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港贸易发展局助理首席经济学家薛冠南表示，印尼正在婆罗洲南部建设新首都，并致力于成为全球经济强国，因此提供了丰富的基础设施机会。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;随着印度尼西亚对海沙出口的转变，人们担心海洋生物数量增加，岛屿消失&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“他们特别关注绿色基础设施，全世界也是如此。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;薛建议在印度尼西亚做生意的新来者确保他们有一个可靠的当地合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“必须找到一个了解当地文化和风险的合作伙伴，他知道要与哪些政府机构联系才能进入当地市场。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 15:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Back on track: Europe’s night trains make bumpy comeback]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3229394/back-track-europes-night-trains-make-bumpy-comeback?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 14:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/e352275c-0d4b-47f3-9539-ed4ae9cd37fc_fafea9c8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由于低碳足迹，夜间列车在欧洲卷土重来，但是经过多年的忽视，复兴之路坎坷不平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运营商承认火车已经过时——乘客偶尔会遇到延误、技术问题或厕所故障——而公司则在超载的网络中竞争。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;尽管面临挑战，国家铁路运营商还是给了夜间列车另一个机会，而初创企业也纷纷加入这股潮流，因为气候问题促使旅客放弃烧煤油的飞机，转而选择更清洁的交通方式。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;奥地利位于西欧和东欧的十字路口，在政府的支持下一直处于这一复兴的中心，尽管低成本航空公司威胁要让卧铺火车载入史册。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥地利铁路运营商 OeBB 是该行业的先驱，拥有欧洲最大的夜间列车车队，为 150 万名乘客提供包括床位车厢的车厢服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家国有公司一度考虑放弃其夜间服务，但它却反其道而行之，而是投资了它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的夜间列车几乎已经订满了，”OeBB 发言人 Bernhard Rieder 表示，夏季旅行在欧洲正如火如荼地进行。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;OeBB 运营 20 条路线，连接维也纳和欧洲其他城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在夜间列车服务方面拥有悠久的传统，”Rieder 说道，并指出了这个阿尔卑斯国家的山区地形如何打造高速连接困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;27 岁的顾问阿斯特丽德·雷特 (Astrid Reiter) 预订了从维也纳到苏黎世的夜间列车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这很好，因为你基本上在不同的国家醒来，”她说。 “如果一切顺利的话，这是一种非常方便的出行方式。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充道：“我确实希望除了奥地利铁路公司之外的其他公司开发更多的夜间列车，让人们更容易乘坐更快的列车夜间列车。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rieder 承认，其服务质量“目前并不总是像我们希望为客户提供的那样高”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有需求他说，“超过 25 年没有对夜间列车的需求”，导致制造业陷入停顿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年，OeBB 从德国企业集团西门子订购了 33 辆新夜间列车，以扩大其覆盖范围并取代部分其老化的车队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一批列车具有现代设计、更多隐私和更多淋浴设施，预计将于今年年底投入使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chris Engelsman，比利时-荷兰初创公司European Sleeper的联合创始人也抱怨缺乏“合适的夜间列车教练”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的公司成立于2021年，于5月开通了柏林-布鲁塞尔的线路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“火车并不总是符合现代标准，但尽管如此，还是有很多人愿意乘坐夜间火车出行，而且热情相当高，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“存在故障有时厕所坏了，或者电力不能正常工作，诸如此类的事情，”他补充道，并指责“几十年来缺乏投资”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;世界上最长的火车旅程的最佳观赏地点：新加坡飞往葡萄牙&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;低成本航班的竞争以及不同欧洲铁路运营商和公司之间缺乏协调是其他障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很难与某些航班的“不合理低价”竞争” 非政府组织绿色和平组织最近的一份报告称，航空业受益于补贴和免税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一方面，铁路运输“需要缴纳各种税费”，特别是德国智库 Agora 分析师 Philipp Kosok 表示，“运营夜间列车非常困难、复杂且昂贵”。他补充说，基础设施甚至“超载”夜间货运列车在铁轨上行驶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;也没有集中的站点来查询时刻表和比较价格，一些业内人士抱怨缺乏政治意愿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前欧洲还没有真正采用火车旅行的方式。”Engelsman 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国初创公司 Midnight Trains 联合创始人 Adrien Aumont 表示，他的公司的目标是“重新发明”夜间列车“使其成为真正有竞争力的交通工具。”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他的合作伙伴“决定不再乘坐飞机”时，奥蒙特萌生了创建这家公司的想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的初创公司正在与一家夜间列车制造商计划在 2025 年重新开通曾经广受欢迎的巴黎-米兰-威尼斯线路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我意识到[不乘坐飞机]在欧洲旅行几乎是不可能的。人们被要求下飞机，但不一定向他们提供解决方案，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他猛烈抨击这项服务随着时间的推移而“恶化”，与传奇和豪华的东方快车相去甚远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia says 3 Ukrainian drones brought down in ‘terrorist attack’ on Moscow]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3229398/russia-says-3-ukrainian-drones-brought-down-terrorist-attack-moscow?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 14:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/78870729-99a3-403f-8505-616791c2ebc7_d0ed8f88.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部表示，周日凌晨击落了三架乌克兰无人机上午，一直试图对莫斯科进行所谓的“恐怖袭击”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有人受伤，谢尔盖莫斯科市商业区两栋办公楼的外墙仅受到轻微损坏莫斯科市长索比亚宁说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该地区距离克里姆林宫几英里，以其现代化的高层塔楼而闻名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来，敌对无人机已经开始出现即使没有造成严重损害，袭击到达俄罗斯首都市中心也会让当局感到不舒服，因为他们告诉公众，俄罗斯完全控制了他们所谓的针对乌克兰的“特别军事行动”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“没有人员伤亡，”索比亚宁在有关该事件的简短声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防部表示，两架无人机在使用无线电电子设备击落后在莫斯科市区坠毁。设备。防空系统在莫斯科地区奥金佐沃地区上空再次击落一架飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“7月30日上午，基辅政权利用无人机对叙利亚境内目标发动恐怖袭击。莫斯科市的目标被挫败，”该部在声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社交媒体上出现的一段显然由路人拍摄的未经证实的视频显示，在一声巨响后，建筑物附近的空中出现火焰。就像爆炸和一个年轻女子的哭泣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我和朋友租了一间公寓来这里放松，在某个时候，我们听到爆炸声，就像波浪一样，每个人都跳了起来，”一位自称莉亚的年轻女子说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然后烟雾很大，你什么也看不见。现场的路透社记者称，一栋高层建筑的部分玻璃板被炸飞，下面的人行道上散落着玻璃和碎片。已被警察和紧急服务部门封锁。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;莫斯科称其在俄罗斯南部上空拦截了两枚乌克兰导弹&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在此事件发生之前，俄罗斯称乌克兰曾试图用两架无人机攻击莫斯科。周一凌晨。俄罗斯军方表示，在 7 月 4 日的另一次袭击中，四架无人机被莫斯科郊区的防空系统击落，第五架无人机被电子干扰。战争手段并被迫降落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对莫斯科的袭击发生在乌克兰反攻几周后，以夺回自 2022 年 2 月爆发大规模敌对行动以来被俄罗斯占领的领土。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯的外交乌克兰国防部表示，“如果没有美国及其北约盟国向基辅政权提供的帮助，此类袭击是不可能发生的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰副总理米哈伊洛·费多罗夫在周一的袭击未遂后表示，将会有更多袭击无人机袭击。基辅没有对最新事件立即做出反应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Are you OK?’: Chinese man spends US$120 buying all instant noodles from vendor after ‘you can’t afford it’ insult, becomes online joke]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3228960/are-you-ok-chinese-man-spends-us120-buying-all-instant-noodles-vendor-after-you-cant-afford-it?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/11f75ba9-bc78-4baa-93de-095b3a7dc061_498c5bf0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个中国男子的视频，他感到受到街头小贩的侮辱，并买下了所有东西他以 850 元（120 美元）的价格将一包面条扔在地上，在大陆社交媒体上疯传。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名来自中国东部山东省的身份不明的男子遭到一名在街头卖面条的摊贩的辱骂。 7 月 24 日的夜市。 据星视频报道，摊贩发表轻蔑评论的原因是该男子抱怨一碗 14 元（2 美元）的方便面太贵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他继续询问碗里的配料。然而，当摊贩回答说只有一个鸡蛋和两片菜叶时，他大吃一惊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“怎么可能卖到14块钱一个？太贵了，不是吗？”他问摊贩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;摊贩无视他的问题，挥手让他走开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你在做什么？”该男子询问摊主。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，他身边的摊贩的儿子站起来对他大喊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果你买不起，那就买吧。” ”儿子对男子说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他很生气，询问了每包面条的价格，并表示要全部购买。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他支付了850元。 ，把包裹砸在地上，并额外支付了一笔未公开的赔偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“儿子道歉了，但没有用。我自己的东西就不能摔坏吗？” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该视频在中国社交媒体上引发讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人说：“他骂你，你奖励他850元。”你还好吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个人说：“这是年轻人的轻率行为。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社交媒体上有关客户服务冲突的视频和帖子在中国经常流行。&lt;/p>;&lt; 6 月份发生的一起事件中，中国东部的一名女士在网上疯传的一篇帖子中表示，她被多收了 300 元人民币（42 美元）的费用，因为她和她的朋友在酒吧“没有营造出足够活跃的氛围”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月份，华东地区的一家中式烧烤店经理因抱怨排队太长而下跪求原谅，令不少网友震惊。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Young Indonesians secure Singapore citizenship as many lament ‘skills mismatch’ back home]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3229314/young-indonesians-secure-singapore-citizenship-many-lament-skills-mismatch-back-home?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/c1d35bc9-d0d2-4a6e-829f-9e962df8d904_0156f8bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;越来越多的印度尼西亚年轻人被慷慨的奖学金和有吸引力的就业前景所吸引，放弃公民身份成为新加坡人，这让官员们感到震惊，因为东南亚最大的经济体正寻求到 2045 年成为发达国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚移民机构本月早些时候表示，2019 年至 2022 年间，近 4,000 名印度尼西亚人获得了新加坡护照，其中大多数是这个城市国家的学生，年龄在 25 岁至 35 岁之间。去年，有 1,091 人做出了改变，而 2020 年为 811 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚移民局局长西尔米·卡里姆 (Silmy Karim) 表示，该国失去了最优秀和最聪明的人才。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对印度尼西亚来说这不是一件好事，因为我们正在失去优秀的人才，”CNN 印度尼西亚援引他的话说。他指出，新加坡制定了针对该地区年轻人才的政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡承诺支持印度尼西亚 340 亿美元的新首都 Nusantara&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这一消息的披露不同寻常，因为这是第一个印度尼西亚在其数据中挑选了一个国籍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡是一个拥有 545 万人口的城市国家，近几十年来一直试图通过主要来自其他东南亚国家的新移民来增加其人口，以及中国和印度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方数据显示，每年约有 15,000 至 20,000 名新公民被授予，同时每年约有 30,000 名公民出生。这个城市国家当局拒绝透露按原国籍划分的新公民的详细情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，新加坡护照被亨利护照指数评为世界上最强大的护照，该指数根据持有护照的人可以访问的地方的数量。新加坡护照允许免签证前往 192 个目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于雅加达的智库经济与法律研究中心执行董事 Bhima Yudhistira 表示，移民官员 Silmy 的言论旨在敲响警钟：呼吁雅加达提高工人的素质。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Silmy 本人曾在海外留学，包括在德国的乔治·马歇尔欧洲安全研究中心和北约学院学习。&lt;/p>;&lt; “这是对公务员素质的批评，包括移民部门的公务员素质，”比马说。 “人才流失确实存在，如果你放任不管，新加坡将从真正享受印度尼西亚政府支持的人那里获得很多价值。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2011 年以来，雅加达一直为顶尖学生提供奖学金根据印度尼西亚教育捐赠基金（LPDP）计划出国留学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;获奖者必须在毕业后在印度尼西亚工作几年。然而，该基金去年表示，从2013年到2022年，有413名毕业生没有返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据全球招聘咨询公司摩根麦金利的数据，2023年新加坡全职工人的平均月薪为S 5,783 美元（4,360 美元）。在印度尼西亚，统计机构的数据显示，去年毕业生的平均月薪为 430 万卢比（286 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果可以选择住在新加坡，许多印度尼西亚工人会抓住机会， “无论他们是否会成为公民”，出生于印度尼西亚的新加坡南洋理工大学 (NTU) 科学、技术与社会副教授苏尔菲卡尔·阿米尔 (Sulfikar Amir) 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这表明了他们的不满“这符合印尼的国情，也是政府为年轻人打造更好的就业生态系统的一个迹象。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;印尼移民事件曝光引发印尼民众网上热议生活在新加坡的利弊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些人承认这个城市国家拥有强大的护照、繁荣的就业市场、现代医疗保健和世界一流的公共交通，但表示印度尼西亚在自然景观方面胜过其邻国&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Septian Hartono，36 岁，于 2020 年获得新加坡公民身份。他于 2003 年获得南洋理工大学奖学金后移居新加坡，该奖学金要求他完成学业后在新加坡工作三年&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2007年他毕业时，新加坡政府给他发了一封信，称如果他在新加坡工作，将获得永久居留权。同年晚些时候，他成为了永久居民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这可能听起来很无辜，但这是一种不知不觉地[让你]在新加坡扎根的有效方法，因为你总共会在这里住七年，”医学物理学家塞普蒂安说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我曾多次认真考虑过返回印度尼西亚。但最终，出现了技能不匹配的情况，”他说，尤其是在他的生物医学领域，差距“相当明显”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“生物医学是新加坡的重点产业之一，因此从培训到产业，整个生态系统已经非常成熟。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Septian 估计，他 2007 年毕业班的印尼学生中约有三分之一也成为了新加坡公民。他与其中一位结婚，现在有两个孩子，并于 2018 年决定启动公民身份程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这更有意义，”他告诉《亚洲周刊》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这对夫妇在申请两年后成为新加坡公民，而他们的孩子仍然拥有双重国籍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚不承认成年人的双重国籍，拥有多本护照的孩子要等到 18 岁才能做出决定他们将保留哪种公民身份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了较高的收入能力之外，新加坡的生活方式（尤其是高效的公共交通）也是塞普蒂安的另一个吸引力，他说他鄙视开车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雅加达的道路堵塞是出了名的，导致通勤者每天上下班要花费多达六个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在新加坡，您可以轻松前往任何地方。我可以想象我无法在雅加达生存。”塞普蒂安说，并补充说，他对人们每天都能在这座印度尼西亚城市开车感到“惊讶”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，他指出虽然新加坡“确实很方便”，但它也“昂贵”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;可以肯定的是，并不是每个生活在这个城市国家的印度尼西亚人都迈出了全面的飞跃，包括南洋理工大学的苏菲卡尔自2008年以来一直居住在那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他没有申请永久居留权，更不用说护照了，因为他仍然享受海外人才身份带来的福利，例如子女的教育津贴和他说，是住房补贴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，他也承认使用目前的护照出行不太方便。 “我仍然使用印度尼西亚护照，这让我很难去任何地方旅行，因为我仍然需要先申请签证，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡监禁了在赌场发现的彩票的印度尼西亚游客&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据 Sulfikar 的说法，奖学金仍然是新加坡招募有前途的印度尼西亚人才最有力的工具之一，其大学在这方面一直积极主动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，例如，他的大学，每年为外国学生提供100个奖学金，包括来自印度尼西亚、中国和印度的学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡大学代表知道要针对印度尼西亚的哪些学校，经常会见顶尖学生并进行现场测试。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;表现最好的人将获得奖学金，包括全额学费和每月 3,000 新元（2,260 美元）的津贴，以及用于购买书本、住宿和回家的往返机票的资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他们只需要把行李箱带到新加坡，”Sulfikar 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡并不是唯一吸引印度尼西亚顶尖人才的地方。 LPDP 数据显示，2013 年至 2022 年间，约 15,000 名获得海外奖学金的印度尼西亚人中，有 58% 前往欧洲大学就读，而 20.7% 则在澳大利亚和新西兰学习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚奖 – 印度尼西亚是最大的奖学金获得者堪培拉提供的奖学金计划已经运行了70年。与新加坡一样，它也提供慷慨的套餐，包括全额学费、行前培训、生活津贴、机票和教育支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但即使有些人已经选择新加坡，他们对印度尼西亚的热爱依然强烈.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塞普蒂安每年访问该国两次，并表示“无法抹去”他在印度尼西亚的成长经历。尽管他是华裔，但他说，由于文化相似，他与城邦马来族人相处得比大多数华裔新加坡人更好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从某种意义上说，我不认为需要保持我作为印度尼西亚人的身份，因为这意味着这需要努力。当然，我与这里的其他人不同，”他说。 “我最怀念印度尼西亚的是食物。这可能听起来很陈词滥调，但你不能在这里复制它。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Philippines forecasts heavy rains as Khanun turns into typhoon]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3229390/philippines-forecasts-heavy-rains-khanun-turns-typhoon?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 13:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/386a86a0-0e3a-42ed-9f21-65598fc11232_7f7ec8b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;菲律宾气象局警告山区山区将出现大雨、洪水和山体滑坡强热带风暴“卡农”预计将发展成为台风。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pagasa 在早上 5 点的通报中表示，预计卡农将“在未来三天内稳步增强”。 “预计今天傍晚或明天凌晨之间将成为台风，并在周二达到峰值强度。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡努正在菲律宾海向北移动，似乎正在远离菲律宾海。气象局表示，上周袭击该国的风暴和超强台风“多克苏里”将推动西南季风，预计将出现强降雨。报告称，这将给吕宋岛西部和米沙鄢群岛带来“偶尔”的季风阵雨。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于超强台风的袭击，航班取消，菲律宾旅客滞留&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;菲律宾的水位capital region&#39;s Marikina River reached 16.1 metres (52.8 feet) on Saturday evening, nearing the 18-metre level that triggers a forced evacuation of certain parts of Marikina City, the Philippine Daily Inquirer reported, citing the local government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The Philippines is affected by an average of 20 tropical cyclones a year, making it one of the world&#39;s worst-hit countries, according to Pagasa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Doksuri, which struck last week, destroyed more than 1.3 billion pesos worth of agricultural crops and caused an estimated 2.66 billion pesos of damage to infrastructure, including bridges and roads, according to local media reports that cited the agriculture and public works departments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The super typhoon affected half a million people mostly in the northern parts of main Luzon Island and left 14 dead, according to the National Disaster Risk Reduction and Management Council. It flooded more than 258 villages in the Luzon provinces of Bulacan and Pampanga, located north of Manila.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khanun is moving at 15km (about 9 miles) an hour with maximum sustained winds of 95km an hour near the centre and gusts of up to 115km an hour, Pagasa said. It&#39;s forecast to move north northwestward before veering northwestward on Monday, according to the weather bureau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tropical storm may exit the Philippines on Monday evening or early Tuesday before turning west northwestwards and passing close to Japan&#39;s Okinawa Islands in the Ryukyu archipelago on Tuesday morning and then entering the East China Sea.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s economic growth to taper off in second quarter, fresh ideas needed to raise competitiveness amid new spending habits: Paul Chan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3229392/hong-kongs-economic-growth-taper-second-quarter-fresh-ideas-needed-raise-competitiveness-amid-new?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 13:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/30/4a2f77aa-8ebd-48ed-aa70-bf86676fe209_174142de.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s economic growth in the second quarter will taper off compared with the first three months of the year, the financial secretary has said as he called for new ideas and strategies to improve competitiveness amid changing spending patterns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po on Sunday said the city&#39;s gross domestic product (GDP) would continue to grow in the second quarter over the same period last year, but noted the path to economic recovery would not be “flat”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The increase would be lower than the 2.7 per cent year-on-year rise in the first three months of this year, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong economy driven by local spending as exports remain weak, finance chief says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Fresh challenges arose from new consumption habits among both tourists and residents, with the former preferring a focus on experiences while the latter increasingly commuted across the border to mainland China for spending on weekends.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For the second quarter GDP advance estimates due to be announced tomorrow, although the year-on-year growth may have slightly slowed down compared with last quarter, the overall economy is still on the track of improvement,” Chan said in his weekly blog. “In reality, the road to recovery is not flat, instead it is progressing under ups and downs, the most important thing is that the recovery keeps heading upwards.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He earlier forecast Hong Kong&#39;s full-year economic growth at a range between 3.5 per cent and 5.5 per cent against 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said two key growth drivers in the city had reported lacklustre performances.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, the city&#39;s merchandise exports faced “severe pressure” amid a weak external environment, and shrank for the 14th consecutive month in June. Exports dropped 13 per cent year on year in the second quarter compared with 18 per cent in the first three months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fixed asset investments, the increase seen in the first quarter of the year had recently shown signs of slowing down, the finance chief said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Affected by the interest rate hike and the external economic outlook being weak, fixed asset investments are predicted to be weaker in the second quarter,” Chan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He noted residents had reduced their nighttime outings and purchases after the Covid-19 pandemic, with Hongkongers also heading to mainland cities such as Shenzhen to spend their money.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mainland tourists in the city were also more interested in local culture instead of shopping, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;5.5 per cent growth possible for Hong Kong under current momentum&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The relative bright spot for growth was local consumption, according to Chan. The city&#39;s retail sales between April and May increased by 17 per cent compared with the same period last year, down slightly from the 24 per cent year-on-year growth in the first quarter. Restaurant receipts were also predicted to have a “significant” growth against last year&#39;s figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite this, the city needed new ideas and innovation in both offerings and marketing to raise its game in the post-pandemic spending environment, the financial secretary said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Hong Kong must bolster economy amid rising interest rates, US banking woes&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We need to develop even more special and creative marketing strategies and activities, better products and services, as well as new areas for consumption growth ... to attract residents to stay in Hong Kong and tourists to come, so they can spend happily,” he said. “We hope to discuss with the industry to come up with more novel concepts, so we can both further increase the prosperity of the market and boost the economy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government is due to reveal the advance GDP estimate for April to June on Monday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Extinct birds on the ballot for New Zealand’s avian beauty contest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3229388/extinct-birds-ballot-new-zealands-avian-beauty-contest?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 12:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/30/0d89470a-4f32-4adb-b643-477c6f0c126f_398c575c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Five extinct species have been included on the ballot to find New Zealand&#39;s most popular feathered friend as competition organisers hope to draw attention to endangered birds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New Zealand&#39;s annual avian beauty contest has proved highly contentious over the years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The kakapo, a chubby parrot resembling a green-feathered bowling ball which cannot fly, could not run in last year&#39;s Bird of the Year competition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The twice former winner was dropped from the 2022 vote by organisers to help less popular species have a shot at the title.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Feathers were also ruffled when a native bat was allowed to enter, then flew off with the 2021 title.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;New Zealand&#39;s bird of the year is a drunk and gluttonous pigeon&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;This year, competition organisers Forest &amp; Bird will celebrate their centenary by crowning New Zealand&#39;s most popular feathered friend in the last 100 years – even if the potential winner no longer exists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re searching for the bird that has captured New Zealanders&#39; hearts over the last century,” said Forest &amp; Bird chief executive Nicola Toki at Saturday&#39;s launch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The environmental group has put 75 species on the ticket for this year&#39;s Bird of the Century contest, of which a quintet are thought to be extinct in New Zealand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They include the huia – a songster, whose last confirmed sighting was in 1907.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Voters can also plump for the laughing owl – also known as the “whekau” – whose shrieks were last officially heard in 1914.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;We were wrong&#39;: US zoo apologises to New Zealand for mistreating kiwi bird&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Toki says she hopes adding extinct species will trigger conversations about endangered birds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“New Zealand&#39;s extinction record is devastating,” Toki said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The now-absent species, she said, were “a heartbreaking reminder of the incredible biodiversity we&#39;ve lost”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Eighty-two per cent of our living native bird species are threatened or at risk of extinction,” Toki added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We cannot let any more end up with the tragic fate of the laughing owl or the huia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Voting opens at the end of October, closing on November 12 with the winner announced the next day.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rumblings in the EU ranks as ‘de-risking’ plan for China gains momentum]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229218/rumblings-eu-ranks-de-risking-plan-china-gains-momentum?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/f2056dc2-5d81-4493-a371-c8b991bba8f7_425e1448.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Future historians might look back at a three-week period this June and July as a defining moment in Europe&#39;s ties with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The one-two of the European Union&#39;s economic security communique – an early-stage manifesto for de-risking – and Germany&#39;s first China strategy have the potential to cause serious ruptures in one of the world&#39;s largest trading relationships.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both seek to recalibrate how European countries and companies trade with and invest in China. They want to keep cutting-edge technologies away from the Chinese military and reduce dependencies on China for goods and minerals that it is feared could be weaponised by Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But each is also carefully vague on execution, reflecting the need to get the broad churches of Germany&#39;s coalition government and an EU membership that ranges from Lithuania, a sworn adversary of China&#39;s, to Hungary, a close ally, on board.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a meeting of EU foreign ministers in Stockholm in May, top diplomat Josep Borrell proclaimed that all 27 members had vouched support for de-risking. One diplomat responded, in a private conversation, that if they had all agreed, it was only because nobody really understood what de-risking actually was.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Berlin, an early draft of the foreign ministry&#39;s hawkish proposal was watered down by Chancellor Olaf Scholz, known to favour continued engagement with Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Brussels, meanwhile, the strategy was first announced during an infamous speech about China by European Commission president Ursula von der Leyen in March. At the time, the German said a new approach was needed to counter Beijing&#39;s pursuit of “systemic change of the international order with China at its centre”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At its launch, however, von der Leyen proclaimed the strategy to be country-agnostic, with a succession of commissioners declining to name China when asked during a day-long series of press events.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They need to have the space for pretending,” a senior EU official said about the linguistic gymnastics on display that day in Brussels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There needs to be some plausible deniability for member states so that they can tell China that this is not just about them,” a second official said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite these efforts, some see the pair of strategies as the start of a decoupling process with China in all but name. Few in Europe argue for full-on economic divorce, and the gung-ho US China policy is viewed in many capitals as over the top.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We could live with a small yard that is very small and a high fence, if it is guaranteed to be very high. But in the American context, this yard is not small,” a European business leader said on condition of anonymity, referring to the Biden administration&#39;s description of its own restrictive policies towards China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the direction of travel is familiar, even if the pace and route are not quite the same.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;To fight &#39;de-risking&#39;, China&#39;s economy must stay too attractive to resist&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We don&#39;t call it decoupling because for some people, the meaning of decoupling is too sharp. But in the end, it is a different description of the same process,” the business figure said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Viking Bohman, an analyst at the Swedish National China Centre, wrote in a recent paper that while EU bureaucrats use the term “de-risking synonymously with &#39;reducing risk&#39;”, in business circles, it usually applies to the termination of business relationships, “indiscriminately with broad categories of customers”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In other words, the Commission seems to have chosen a word that expresses precisely the scenario that the EU has been trying to avoid – a sweeping decoupling that goes beyond national governments&#39; intentions,” Bohman wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Chinese observers too, the policies are loaded with terminology that point to long-term fragmentation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The choice of the term &#39;de-risking&#39; rather than &#39;decoupling&#39; has allowed Brussels to find a suitable middle ground between pro-decoupling and pro-engagement voices in Europe. This should allow for greater unity within the EU when it comes to China,” wrote Jian Junbo, deputy director of the Centre for China-Europe Relations, Fudan University, in a recent article for The Paper, a state-run digital outlet based in Shanghai, and summarised in the Sinification newsletter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the infighting that plagued both strategies during their development and, in the case of Brussels&#39; economic security paper, after its launch, show how challenging they will be to deliver on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Brussels, the economic security strategy is seen as the handiwork of Bjoern Seibert, the cabinet chief to von der Leyen, who diplomats and officials say is close to US National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the weeks leading up to its release, Seibert presented his plans to ambassadors from the EU&#39;s 27 member states and was told in no uncertain terms that he was going “too far, too fast”, multiple diplomats said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some representing the bloc&#39;s freest trading members worried that provisions like outbound investment controls were too protectionist. Others worried about a power grab from Brussels, due to Seibert&#39;s citing of “national security” and promoting a “Europeanisation” of export controls, powers that usually sit in the 27 capitals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More still told Seibert that he was flying too close to US policy for comfort. A senior official said the “cool and cautious” feedback from some the bloc&#39;s most powerful members was: “We are Europe, not the United States.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last-minute edits to the strategy failed to assuage some members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At an event hosted with trade officials and think tank members just days after its launch, ambassadors pelted experts with questions about outbound investment restrictions, which would see companies being told they could not put their own capital into Chinese tech sectors deemed sensitive, such as robotics, artificial intelligence or semiconductors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think on some of the stuff that was pitched, especially on outbound investment, it seems like a political mistake. I think the Commission committed on paper to an instrument without being able to specify the risks. And so they really built this world the wrong way around,” said Tobias Gehrke, an expert in economic statecraft at the European Council on Foreign Relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trade officials complained that the plan was cooked up too hastily, with less than three months between von der Leyen&#39;s announcement and the communique&#39;s unveiling in June. “If all you want is an announcement, we can have it ready tomorrow,” one official said, adding that a substantive policy would take more time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But von der Leyen will have been encouraged to see unqualified support for de-risking in the German strategy announced three weeks later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Everyone benefits from competition when it is based on fair rules. It is not our intention to impede China&#39;s economic progress and development. At the same time, de-risking is urgently needed,” it read.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Berlin said outbound investment screening “could be important as a supplement to existing instruments”, but the fact that it was in there at all showed observers that Germany is unlikely to stymie any proposal at EU level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They have chosen to repeat all the buzzwords that come out of Brussels, and somewhat formulate support for that; some elements with more enthusiasm, some with less enthusiasm,” said Tim Ruehlig, an expert in EU-China geoeconomics at the German Council on Foreign Relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On outbound investment screening, it&#39;s a formula that reflects the internal divergences within the German government, but you can&#39;t read it as Germany will certainly block anything on outbound foreign investment screening.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The consensus among a dozen business figures, diplomats and officials spoken to in recent weeks is that events in Brussels and Berlin have set a process in motion. It is impossible now to put the genie back in the bottle, even if nobody is sure where exactly the de-risking agenda will end up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week in Brussels, Germany&#39;s Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock hoped to present the strategy to other EU foreign ministers. As the largest EU economy and China&#39;s biggest European trading partner, there is a sense that where Berlin leads on China, others may follow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, items on China and economic security were bumped off the agenda as the meeting focused on contentious debates about Turkey&#39;s path to EU membership and committing more arms to Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Europe&#39;s omnicrisis means non-neighbourhood issues – such as China – are often the first to be sacrificed during important meetings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These time restraints in themselves present a logistical challenge to reaching consensus on the thorniest parts of the strategy. The legislative clock is ticking towards European elections next year that will see an overhaul of commissioners – even if von der Leyen is fancied to keep the top job, offering the prospect of some continuity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This Commission has a very short window to push this economic security agenda, which makes it all the more important that the big member states engage now on this issue,” said Noah Barkin, an analyst of Europe-China relations at the Rhodium Group research house.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think we have the luxury to kick this into the long weeds. If we don&#39;t have real progress by the first quarter of next year, then you can kiss this agenda goodbye until 2025, when a new Commission is in place.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesia influencer Denise Chariesta’s pregnancy plea highlights deep stigma unwed mothers face]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3229275/indonesia-influencer-denise-chariestas-pregnancy-plea-highlights-deep-stigma-unwed-mothers-face?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.30 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/e1902ad5-cf2d-409e-b571-fb5c88eaa623_e8dd554d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;In a bombshell post that shocked, appalled and won applause all at the same time, Indonesian influencer Denise Chariesta announced she was pregnant and implored her fans to contribute the cost of her prenatal medical care, which she estimated may top 1 billion rupiah (US$67,000).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apparently short of cash, the 31-year-old, who identifies as a Christian, appealed to supporters this month to give what they could, quoting a Biblical passage from the Gospel of John that exhorts Christians to help those in need.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I need all of [my fans] to chip in, especially those who like to make nasty comments. Your generosity will make up for your rudeness,” she wrote on Instagram in early July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her forthright words aside, there was another point of contention as far as many Indonesians were concerned: Chariesta is unmarried, and getting pregnant outside of wedlock is still taboo in Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Why would you air your own dirty laundry like this, since you are unwed?” said one follower, Zeeyra Wowor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Siska Tobing, 34, a Christian resident of Surabaya, took umbrage at what she saw as Chariesta&#39;s levity with the scriptures, which she said brought shame on all in her faith.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“How dare she quote the Bible, trying to make people feel guilty if they didn&#39;t help her, when having premarital sex is obviously forbidden by the same book?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others were incredulous that Chariesta, a celebrity with multiple businesses, who parades a glamorous life to her 705,000 followers across various platforms, would beg for money.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As Asia tries to spur a baby boom, Indonesia says no thanks&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“You asked for donations so you can have your baby with the best [private] medical care, and yet those you expect to give probably use BPJS [Indonesia&#39;s state-funded healthcare system] at no cost,” said Instagram user Helena Kiran.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Chariesta&#39;s characteristic turn to social media has – unintentionally – kick-started a wider conversation over pregnancy outside marriage in a country where women often carry the burden of societal &#39;shame&#39; in secret and silence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were more than 23,000 children born out of wedlock in the Indonesia last year, according to official figures cited by Coordinating Minister for Human Development and Cultural Affairs Muhadjir Effendy – likely a fraction of the real number in a country with more than 270 million people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although unwed mothers face no legal penalty from the state and are still entitled to healthcare and other government services, ostracism by society – especially in poorer, more conservative parts of the country – is often the reality.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Susi Trisila, a Surabaya-based mother who was unmarried and pregnant in the 2010s, said she chose to hide her pregnancy from her extended family for fear of rejection and stigma.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My father&#39;s small business relied on the business connections from my other relatives, so the danger of suffering a financial catastrophe was considerable,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But privileged Indonesians like Chariesta usually fare better than most women who fall pregnant out of wedlock, Susi said. “She is a celebrity who has influence and no doubt the earning power. That makes all the difference.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Susi said her family, mortified by her pregnancy and the fact she had no husband, asked her to carry the baby to term in another town, simply to avoid gossip.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She spent the next year there lying low before daring to show her face in her hometown again. “Even then, I had to make up excuses like how my husband had died, leaving me with a child,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Susi said she tripped up when it came to registering her son&#39;s birth. “I couldn&#39;t produce proof of any marriage, so on my child&#39;s birth certificate the father&#39;s name was left blank.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Registry offices in Indonesia ask for marriage certificates but if that is not forthcoming a child is recorded as anak di luar nikah (born outside marriage). That can have social consequences later, with the illegitimate nature of the birth made plain to anyone viewing the person&#39;s birth certificate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But at least the authorities were told about Susi&#39;s little boy. Many women whose babies are born outside of wedlock do not even register the births to avoid social stigma, especially in rural areas. In 2020, the Ministry of Home Affairs estimated that there were around 5 million Indonesian children without birth certificates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not having the vital document means they are denied essential government services, including health subsidies and education.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The issue is perhaps even more keenly felt for Muslim Indonesians, who are governed by Islamic inheritance by-laws.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Islamic law does not recognise the legal rights of so-called illegitimate offspring to inherit from their biological father&#39;s side of the family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Islamic legal expert Eka Sihombing said the same principles were also embodied in Indonesia&#39;s 1974 Marriage Act, until the Constitutional Court in 2012 handed down a landmark decision affirming the legal rights of all children, of all faiths, who are born outside of wedlock – provided their paternity can be proven.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Until then [2012], Muslim men who shunned their paternal responsibilities always had the upper hand, but no longer. Now their &#39;haram&#39; [illegal] children can claim child support.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DNA tests are not common, though, as they are expensive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Susi, who is a Christian, claimed that even for non-Muslims, the stigma and “society judgment” was usually more than enough to stifle the lives of unwed mothers and their children. “It&#39;s not just neighbours and their disapproval, but you can feel it from your own relatives. It&#39;s as if your mere presence can pollute them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said that while her son was growing up, she sometimes received odd looks from teachers at his school when they found out he was illegitimate. “It&#39;s tougher on the kids in the long run. It puts them at a disadvantage early on in life.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chariesta, on the other hand, does not seem too concerned about the legal status of her unborn child.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unwed pregnancy is not the first contentious issue she has waded into since she first shot to fame as an influencer in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, she confessed online to having an affair with a married man, rumoured to be the husband of a high-profile actress and television presenter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the wife who got in the way, Chariesta claimed, prompting widespread online condemnation of her as a “homewrecker” by social media users.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the influencer has tried her best this time to present a compelling narrative underlying her cash appeal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chariesta claimed the ex-lover who is the father of her unborn child had evaded responsibility by casting doubt on the baby&#39;s paternity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I was so incensed he had the gall to distrust me. So I told him to stick it and not think of the child as his,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oki Rahadianto Sutopo, a sociologist at Yogyakarta&#39;s Gadjah Mada University, said Chariesta&#39;s campaign had everything to do with money, and nothing to do with prodding social change.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Asian-Australian&#39;s teary-eyed TikTok of Vietnam sparks &#39;slum tourism&#39; backlash&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Social media platforms enable celebrities like Denise to monetise the attention she&#39;s getting,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A week after her bombshell plea, Chariesta advertised for “corporate sponsors” with benefits including naming the baby after their brand of choice, then teaching the newborn to say it as his or her first word.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seemingly unbowed by all the criticism, she has posted screenshots from her bank account showing thousands of dollars gifted to her by fans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For those who choose not to send her anything, she has little obvious sympathy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Why have some of you left nasty comments instead of sending me money?” Chariesta ranted in one of her latest videos. “It&#39;s not my fault you haven&#39;t got the dough to give me. It&#39;s your own fault you are poor!”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 30 Jul 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>