<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com<item><title><![CDATA[Russian forces tried to blow up my men, Wagner boss Yevgeny Prigozhin says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3222824/russian-forces-tried-blow-my-men-wagner-boss-yevgeny-prigozhin-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 03:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/e0ddda5a-cc88-4381-b277-971c08d12917_d54724d7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯雇佣军老板 Yevgeny Prigozhin，几个月来一直与军方高层争论不休，上周五指责亲莫斯科的部队试图炸毁他的部下，从而加剧了争执。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin 的瓦格纳集团部队已从乌克兰东部城镇巴赫穆特大部分撤退，他们在上个月夺取了大部分城镇造成重大伤亡，并将阵地移交给俄罗斯正规部队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin 在 Telegram 上写道，他的部下在后方发现了十几个地点，国防部官员在这些地点安放了各种爆炸装置，其中包括数百个&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及为什么要设置这些装药时，官员们表示这是上级的命令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有必要在这些地方安放这些装药”为了威慑敌人，因为它[有关地区]在后方。因此，我们可以假设这些炸药是为了满足瓦格纳的推进部队，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有炸药，也没有人受伤，他说，并补充说：“我们假设这”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯的瓦格纳老板说，他的 20,000 名士兵在巴赫穆特阵亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;无法立即联系到俄罗斯国防部发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Prigozhin 经常抱怨他的手下没有得到足够的弹药来袭击 Bakhmut，他周三表示，他已要求检察官调查俄罗斯高级国防官员是否在乌克兰战争之前或期间犯下了任何“罪行”。&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Western ‘de-risking’ from China without decoupling makes little sense and only aggravates tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3222573/western-de-risking-china-without-decoupling-makes-little-sense-and-only-aggravates-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 01:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/4386beeb-7282-4bde-b98d-7c3a23b04be9_5f328a46.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Nvidia 首席执行官黄仁勋最近警告称，美国面临“巨大损失”风险如果它继续升级筹码战，那么在不脱钩的情况下“降低风险”的定义不明确的方法将再次成为人们关注的焦点。在最近的七国集团 (G7) 峰会上，领导人肯定了这种做法，但几乎没有提供任何线索来说明他们的意思。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这给政策制定者和企业留下了很多疑问。您要降低哪些风险？鉴于长期存在的相互依赖关系，您将如何做到这一点？哪种胡萝卜加大棒最有效？为了哪些目标？你什么时候开始和停止？中国政策如何影响？衡量成功的标准是什么？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种混乱加剧了世界上最大的工业化民主国家与中国之间的紧张关系。由于政府采取报复性冲突（包括北京突袭办公室和美国贸易禁令），相互利益已被搁置一旁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，公司正在告诉中国“我们回来了”，因为本周，摩根大通首席执行官杰米·戴蒙 (Jamie Dimon) 在上海举行了小组讨论会。近 3,000 名与会者参加了该活动，这凸显了跨国公司如何需要在世界第二大经济体拥有强大的基础，即使他们通过在新兴市场的友谊和扩张实现业务多元化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;企业渴望利用机会源于围绕去风险化的模糊性。星巴克就是一个例子，它大胆计划到 2025 年在中国开设 9,000 家新店。据估计，苹果公司至少 95% 的 iPhone、AirPods、Mac 和 iPad 在中国生产，同时约五分之一的收入来自中国.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种悖论——更高的利润需要更深层次的联系和更大的风险——自从这种方法成为西方对华外交的模板以来，就已经危及在不脱钩的情况下去风险。欧盟委员会主席乌尔苏拉·冯德莱恩 (Ursula von der Leyen) 是第一批在 1 月份的演讲中使用该词组的人之一。美国国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文 (Jake Sullivan) 在 4 月份的一次重要讲话中也做了同样的事情，上月底在日本广岛举行的 G7 峰会将这一原则制度化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;定义去风险是一件混乱的事情。美国财政部将其定义为“不分青红皂白地终止或限制与大类客户的业务关系”。该机构建议在决定切断哪些关系时要精确——这些建议应该影响西方与中国之间的关系进程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从广义上讲，去风险旨在减少 G7 国家对中国的经济依赖不需要向内撤退。沙利文将这种方法等同于拥有“有效的供应链”和原材料、关键部件或技术的多种来源。其推动力还与国家安全优先事项纠缠在一起。对竞争对手的极端依赖可能会诱使对手进行报复并迫使其让步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在去风险的情况下，尽管关系距离增加，西方和中国仍将从彼此做生意中受益.地缘政治紧张局势将缓和，而在一个中国政策下台湾周边的现状将保持不变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;G7 内部的分歧正在造成不一致，从三个方面威胁到去风险方法：模糊性；其实施的困难；以及——最棘手的问题——缺乏更深入的方法来减少正在扰乱国际秩序的美中关系中的敌意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;模棱两可对外交来说既是诅咒也是祝福。它提供了适应持续变化的灵活性。但是，当参与规则不明确时，各国会在国内外感到不安甚至不安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;荷兰贸易部长 Liesje Schreinemacher 最近的评论表明，模糊性正在以多快的速度发挥作用。 “在使我们的经济更具可持续性和绿色转型方面，我们需要彼此，”她说，指的是利用中国的实力推动她的国家向可再生能源的转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实施去中心化能源的挑战冒险是提高准确性和清晰度的另一个理由。这些困难可以从美国去年 10 月对公司实施限制的方式中看出，以阻止中国利用芯片加速提升其防御能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾半导体制造公司和韩国芯片制造商 SK 海力士和三星获准豁免美国对中国的贸易禁令。事实上，大约三分之二的在中国开展业务的许可申请是由美国商务部批准的。尽管他们向中国出售的芯片被美国视为低技术含量，但它们仍然可以增强防御能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国的投资银行、养老基金和其他投资者没有受到去风险化的影响，他们可能为中国的技术进步提供资金。但据报道，拜登政府正在考虑此类限制，尽管其两位特使沙利文和财政部长珍妮特耶伦对行政命令将授权的限制含糊不清。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;强制执行去风险化会破坏该学说的可信度，并且无助于解冻与中国的关系。这项政策是临时制定的，助长了 G7 希望缓解的紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最重要的是，去风险化似乎是解决无法解决的问题的方法。双方在许多紧迫问题上有着共同利益，但压倒一切的是他们对世界秩序的不同看法以及他们维护国家利益的不相容方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在零 Covid 政策被取消后证明不那么有力了。西方需要中国的市场、工厂和研究突破。利用这些共同利益是化解紧张局势的最佳方式。然后，重点应该放在寻找在边缘进行合作的方法，并在紧张局势变得根深蒂固之前化解紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 01:50:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Trains derail in India, killing at least 13 and trapping hundreds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3222823/trains-derail-india-killing-least-13-and-trapping-hundreds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 01:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/cb6cdd47-c2f4-43a9-8ec8-0d127b9ee3ce_5e4b471f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三，两列客运列车在印度脱轨，造成至少 13 人死亡，数百人被困官员说，十多辆损坏的客车内还有其他人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官员说，大约有 400 人受伤并被送往医院，事故原因正在调查中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;死亡人数尚不清楚。国家消防局局长 Sudhanshu Sarangi 证实至少有 13 人死亡。新德里电视新闻频道报道称，恐有 30 人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥里萨邦最高官员 Pradeep Jena 表示，近 500 名警察和救援人员以及 75 辆救护车和公共汽车对事故作出了反应。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;该州 Balasore 区行政长官 DB Shinde 说，救援人员正试图解救 200 名担心被困在残骸中的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;铁道部发言人 Amitabh Sharma 说，有 10 到 12 名教练一列火车脱轨，一些损坏的车厢的碎片掉到附近的轨道上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它被另一列从相反方向开来的旅客列车撞上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最多三节车厢第二列火车也出轨了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;两列希腊火车迎面相撞，造成 36 人死亡，交通部长辞职&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;印度报业托拉斯新闻社称，出轨的科罗曼德尔快车是从豪拉出发的在西孟加拉邦飞往泰米尔纳德邦南部首府钦奈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪表示，他对这起事故感到悲痛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这悲痛的时刻，我的思念与死者家属同在。愿受伤的人早日康复，”莫迪在推特上说，他已经与铁道部长进行了交谈，并表示正在提供“一切可能的帮助”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管政府努力改善铁路安全，但每年都会发生数百起事故印度铁路是世界上最大的统一管理铁路网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1995 年 8 月，两列火车在新德里附近相撞，造成 358 人死亡，这是印度历史上最严重的火车事故。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数火车事故都归咎于人为错误或信号设备过时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度每天有超过 1200 万人乘坐 14,000 列火车，行驶在 64,000 公里（40,000 英里）的轨道上。&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 01:50:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[CIA Director William Burns made secret visit to China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222822/cia-director-william-burns-made-secret-visit-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 01:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/55079637-14dd-4050-bcf0-59c997a4774e_ea4540ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中情局局长威廉伯恩斯上个月秘密访问北京，在那里他会见了中国人据一位美国官员称，情报官员的访问是在拜登政府试图稳定与其主要地缘政治对手的关系之际进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在访问期间，中央情报局局长强调了维持这位不愿透露姓名的官员表示，华盛顿和北京之间的情报渠道中的沟通渠道畅通无阻。美国政府试图重启因台湾地位问题和 2 月被美国空军飞机击落的所谓中国间谍气球等问题而紧张的双边关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近的外联取得了喜忧参半的成功。上个月，美国国家安全顾问杰克沙利文会见了中国最高外交政策官员王毅，而美国贸易代表戴凯瑟琳一周前会见了中国商务部长王文涛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;向中国军方示好领导人没那么成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京拒绝了国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀会见中国同行李尚福的请求，当时两人正在新加坡参加安全会议，部分原因是李在 2018 年受到制裁&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥斯汀和李在周五于新加坡开幕的一年一度的香格里拉对话会上握手并简短地交谈。他们在活动中坐在同一张桌子上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位美国高级国防官员说握手很好，但不能代替坐下来进行有意义的交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;作为中国, 美国国防部长抵达香格里拉论坛，会开会吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国务卿安东尼·布林肯随着气球争议的展开而推迟了计划已久的北京之行，但仍未宣布任何重新安排的行程前往中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伯恩斯在成为美国间谍局长之前是一名外交官，他曾为拜登政府执行过其他敏感任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在俄罗斯入侵乌克兰之前前往莫斯科试图说服弗拉基米尔·普京总统的政府停止攻击，但没有成功。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU set for ‘small revolution’ through enlargement, minister says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222820/eu-set-small-revolution-through-enlargement-minister-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 23:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/e08ba0be-1164-452f-9346-cab62c3f15f5_9c49dc9e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧盟将通过扩大到包括乌克兰在内来一场“小革命”法国欧洲事务部长周五表示，可能还有另外 9 个国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙周三在斯洛伐克的一次演讲中坚决支持扩大欧盟 27 个成员国的规模，这让人感到意外。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;“对我们来说，问题不是我们是否应该扩大……而是我们应该如何做，”马克龙对听众说，他曾在 2019 年否决与阿尔巴尼亚和北马其顿的欧盟成员国谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;欧洲部长劳伦斯·布恩 (Laurence Boone) 周五解释说，欧盟边界的扩大将带来“巨大冲击”，需要改变该集团的运作方式，该集团上一次经历重大扩张是在 2004 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这意味着重新审视我们的政策，对预算和机构做出改变”，她告诉 Europe 1 电台，并称这将是“未来十年的项目”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;欧盟可能同意对中国公司实施新的制裁下周，外交官们说&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;扩大意味着考虑“我们如何组织自己前进。这是一场小革命，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 2 月，俄罗斯入侵邻国，导致马克龙明确支持欧盟扩大，并支持乌克兰加入北约军事联盟.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士说，任何新的扩张都可能伴随着欧盟决策过程的重大变化，这需要其 27 个成员国在许多政策领域达成一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他的演讲中，马克龙暗示了他过去提出的所谓“多速欧洲”的想法，新国家将被接纳，但与历史成员相比具有不同的地位和权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共有 10 个国家被认为是欧盟成员国的候选人或潜在候选人，其中包括乌克兰，还有摩尔多瓦、格鲁吉亚和最具争议的土耳其。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扩大欧盟的呼声受到欧洲疑欧政党的激烈反对。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长期以来一直批评欧盟的法国极右翼领导人玛丽娜·勒庞在民意调查中处于历史高位，并计划在 2027 年接替马克龙。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shangri-La Dialogue puts focus on shifting US-China military balance]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3222668/shangri-la-dialogue-puts-focus-shifting-us-china-military-balance?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 23:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/69689843-8685-4650-8fb1-54f00ed7be55_1b207a56.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;国际日历上最重要的安全会议之一将于 20 日举行6 月 2 日在新加坡举行，国防部长、军事人员和政策观察员齐聚一堂。在 a 的决赛中，Amber Wang 比较了美国和中国的军事实力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡总理李显龙或许对大多数亚洲国家对美中竞争日益激烈的情绪进行了最好的总结，他在之前的一次香格里拉对话“大象打架，草被践踏。当大象交配时，草地也会受到影响。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于世界上两个最强大的军队的国防部长出席了今年的论坛，周末前往新加坡的地区官员和安全分析人士很可能会有 Lee 的想法&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀和中国国防部长李尚福将军是否会在论坛上会面是笼罩在此次活动中的重大问题之一。美国周一表示，中国已拒绝会面，而北京则敦促华盛顿为对话“创造条件”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论发生什么情况，他们的与会者都可能会在两个强大的一方的压力下感到压力，因为他们就有关地区内外和平的最热门问题阐明立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中美两国在一系列问题上日益紧张的气氛中，包括他们在该地区不断增加的军事存在，亚洲首屈一指的防务峰会将试图对两股力量之间的力量平衡做出冷静评估。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国表示，美国必须在国防部长会晤前纠正“错误行为”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;观察人士表示，中国和美国在亚洲的军事平衡正在向有利于北京的方向转变，中国人民解放军在高超音速武器和其他能力方面迅速赶上，以便在台湾等“关键战场”与华盛顿展开竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，解放军尚未弥合在部队整合、联合作战和实战经验方面的差距，华盛顿一直在加强其在该地区的联盟和伙伴关系，以阻止中国占据上风。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;而且，据专家称，虽然北京在台湾海峡具有地理优势，但对这个自治岛屿的攻击以及华盛顿的军事回应对任何一方来说都将付出高昂的代价。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在1996年的危机中，当华盛顿将航母部署到台湾海峡时，北京无能为力。但那些日子已经一去不复返了，只留下了痛苦的记忆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二十多年后，解放军山东舰首次出动——前往西太平洋——在一场围绕太平洋的大规模军事演习中。台湾总统蔡英文与美国众议院议长凯文麦卡锡会晤后的台湾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国在 1990 年代拥有绝对优势，可以在第一岛链内封锁中国，”周晨鸣说，北京远望军事科技智库研究员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但解放军迅速赶上来……我们制造了先进的武器并取得了优势。中国现在有能力在关键战场上与美国竞争——不是在任何地方，而是……东海、南海和台湾海峡，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在该地区的整体军事优势上，他们说毫无疑问解放军已经缩小了差距，甚至在一些新兴技术上处于领先地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国说解放军火箭军参加了关岛美军基地附近的海军演习&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;然而，根据新加坡拉惹勒南国际研究学院研究员 Collin Koh 的说法，军事力量不仅仅是硬件和软件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它还关于学说、人力资本质量、培训和整体配套基础设施，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Koh 表示，中国确实逐渐稳步地与美国建立了军事力量平衡的桥梁，尤其是在硬件方面。他补充说，在 AI 技术和高超音速武器的军事应用方面，PLA 也可以被评估为领先于美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“PLA 还拥有比美国更全面的地面防空网络许说：“中国拥有军事资产，当然它也拥有大量的弹道导弹和巡航导弹系统。”中国和俄罗斯等主要竞争对手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在印太地区，美国正在通过增加军事存在、增加投资以及与区域伙伴建立更紧密的联盟来巩固其主导地位，以明确对抗北京，专家说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该地区越来越担心两个敌对大国之间可能会在短期内发生冲突——双方都拥有核武器——这对双方来说都是一场灾难。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;东南亚在该地区寻求美国和中国之间的“平衡”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，美国国防部长奥斯汀表示，他的“整个部门”的重点是继续“超越”中国——拜登指出去年政府的国家安全战略被称为“美国最重要的地缘政治挑战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样在今年，奥斯汀宣布他的部门要求将今年的预算增加 40%，以加强其在美国的军事态势。太平洋，通过加强对夏威夷和关岛的防御，以及与那里的盟友和合作伙伴进行更深入的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在 2021 年通过两次高超音速武器试验“震惊”了美国。由于速度快、机动性强，这些导弹难以被发现或拦截，据了解主要用于对付航空母舰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为回应，五角大楼一直在加快自己的高超音速武器系统的开发，因为与中国和俄罗斯保持同步的技术重点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国也在加强人工智能和网络战等领域的研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，解放军正在执行根据美国海军印太司令部的最新评估，这是“二战以来常规和战略核领域规模最大、速度最快、最全面的军事集结”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印太司令约翰·阿奎利诺海军上将在 4 月的声明中称，解放军增加先进能力的步伐加快是“令人担忧的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，解放军海军——拥有世界上最大的舰队，约有 350战舰——到 2030 年有望交付 440 艘舰船，仅去年一年就有 17 艘主要军舰加入其作战库存。美国舰队的舰船数量不到 300 艘。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国海军老化的舰队是否为解放军攻击台湾打开了窗口？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;解放军空军第 5 代 J 的生产能力-20 战斗机的数量也翻了一番，估计其中有 150 架现在投入使用，“其中许多是去年部署的”，阿奎利诺说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在去年的一份报告中，五角大楼还指出，解放军空军武力正在“迅速赶上”其美国竞争对手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京智库分析师周表示，美国硬件“在某些领域已经失去了硬件优势，例如高超音速武器、反舰弹道导弹和隐身能力战斗机”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国科学家对美国航母群进行高超声速打击&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Drew Thompson，新加坡国立大学李光耀公共政策学院访问高级研究员，表示两国“更像是一场势均力敌的竞赛”，北京在多个方面迎头赶上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“解放军在力量投射能力方面取得了长足进步，尤其是短程、中程和洲际弹道导弹导弹、两栖能力、综合防空和电子战等关键支持能力，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在区域防御合作方面，美国可能会占据上风，因为它最近做出了努力多年来深化整个印太地区的安全联盟，包括通过与区域伙伴更频繁的联合军事演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月，美国获得了对菲律宾另外四个军事基地的使用权，其中一个接近台湾和南中国海附近的另一个。华盛顿还同意定期向韩国部署美国核潜艇，并让首尔参与其核计划行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美菲基地协议被视为对中国在南中国海行动的回应&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;美国通过双边关系和军事集团加强了同盟关系，例如 Aukus（与澳大利亚和英国签订的三边安全协定）和 Quad（包括澳大利亚、印度和日本在内的战略对话）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;分析人士表示，在从潜在冲突的角度评估中美之间的军事平衡时，也应考虑此类联盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然不能保证所有美国盟友和合作伙伴都会提供Koh 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在该地区任何潜在的武装冲突中，很难想象一个假设美国必须单独行动——其盟友和合作伙伴可能会以某种方式受到牵连，并可能在不同程度上参与支持美国的军事行动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Koh 表示，美国也享有“决定性的地位” “在力量整合、联合作战和实战经验方面”优于解放军。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“例如在海军能力方面，[PLA] 仍处于建立成熟的航母作战能力，以及进行大规模两栖攻击行动的能力，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Koh 指出，解放军地区战区正在“建设他们的力量整合和联合作战能力&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在解放军喷气式飞机被指控“咄咄逼人”的举动后，中国抨击美国的飞越行动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;前解放军教官宋忠平，现驻基地在香港表示，美军在印太地区的主导地位将持续很长时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国有 11 艘航空母舰，其中至少有 5 到 6 艘可以部署在印太地区。”太平洋地区，”他说，并补充说，美国还拥有比中国更多的第五代战斗机和更强大的远海作战能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界，”宋说。 “中国也在不断提升其军事现代化，但与美国相比仍有一定差距。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国为台湾提供核保护伞：坚固的两岸盾牌还是一厢情愿？&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;对于周来说，美国“充分利用”其亚太盟友——包括澳大利亚、日本、韩国和一些东南亚国家——的努力及其军事能力和训练水平“令人担忧”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;他表示，美方联合起来遏制中国是“一厢情愿”。 “那些盟友太弱了，不可能成为中国的对手，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在去年的共产党全国代表大会报告中，习近平主席呼吁加快国家现代化建设，目标是到 2050 年建设“世界一流”军队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平要求解放军加快信息化作战研究，“构建强大的战略威慑体系”。他还在报告中特别提到了无人化、智能化和网络化作战力量的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“强国必有强军”：习近平从苏联解体中得到的重要教训&lt;/h3>; p>;根据兰德公司 3 月份的一份报告，解放军认为自己在整体军事平衡中处于较弱的一方。它说，这主要是因为它在决定未来战争的领域——信息化和基于系统的作战——只取得了有限的进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前解放军教官宋说，中国需要克服它的缺点，特别是其信息化能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京还在努力增加其航空母舰和潜艇舰队，以及其核武器以威慑美国，宋说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国联邦科学家在其年度调查中表示，中国目前拥有大约 410 枚核弹头，而五角大楼估计，按照目前的速度，到本十年末，这一数字可能会增加到 1,000 枚，到 2035 年左右会增加到 1,500 枚。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;核弹头太快了中国的建设会让邻国感到担忧：分析人士&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国海军部长卡洛斯德尔托罗在 2 月份呼吁“更现代化的舰船”，以扭转 PLA 海军在整体舰队数量上的显着优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;周认为，美国需要五到八年的时间才能重新占据主导地位——一些老旧军舰即将退役，美国在军舰生产方面将无法跟上中国的步伐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国智库战略与国际研究中心开发的兵棋推演发现，在大多数基于北京接管台湾的情景中，美国、日本和台湾军队击败了常规的两栖入侵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，该智库发现，保卫一个自治的台湾对双方来说都付出了高昂的代价。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国重新调整的军事领导层凸显了对台湾的关注&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在宋看来，他说，尽管美国拥有硬件优势，但中国有朝一日可能会在台湾海峡赢得一场战斗，因为它“离自己的家门口很近”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周说北京有可能拥有&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国最近的战争游戏清楚地表明，事实上，如果中美之间发生战争，双方必须付出巨大代价才能取胜，而且不可能轻易取得胜利，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国担心未来几年台海会发生战争。他们希望它发生在 2035 年之后，届时美国可能会恢复其主导地位，届时与中国展开真正的战斗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但对我们来说，我们有自己的战略，不以美国的意志为转移”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈美妮补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine: As intense Russian shelling kills and maims more people, hundreds flee border region]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3222819/ukraine-intense-russian-shelling-kills-and-maims-more-people-hundreds-flee-border-region?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 23:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/4e44d711-b27d-486a-8fde-9b05db4988a4_8277c0ac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Two civilians were killed on Friday in shelling on Russia&#39;s Belgorod region on the border with Ukraine , while Moscow&#39;s forces attacked Kyiv for a sixth day in a row.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past few days hundreds of residents have fled villages near Russia&#39;s border with Ukraine as shelling intensified in the southwestern Belgorod region.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Residents from the town of Shebekino have been pouring into the region&#39;s main city, Belgorod, where the atmosphere was calm on Friday, journalists said. The sports arena – which has become the city&#39;s biggest centre for displaced people – looked packed but clean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Volunteers were distributing white bracelets allowing people to get free meals and organising their transfer to smaller dormitories. A dozen people huddled in front of a television, and some grew emotional as they watched news developments from Shebekino.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Belgorod governor Vyacheslav Gladkov said 2,500 people were being accommodated in temporary shelters, including the sports arena.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier in the day, the regional governor said two women were killed by shelling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Shrapnel hit cars passing by. Two women travelling in one of them died on the spot from their wounds,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two people were severely wounded by the shelling that hit a village in the district of Shebekino. The head of the district, Vladimir Zhdanov, said authorities were continuing to evacuate people but faced difficult conditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, the Russian defence ministry said forces had used jets and artillery to repel a Ukrainian attempt to “invade” the region of Belgorod.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The attack “involved up to 70 militants, five tanks, four armoured vehicles, seven pickup trucks and a Kamaz truck,” the army said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also on Friday, two people were killed and four others were wounded in shelling of the village of Komyshevaha in Ukraine&#39;s Zaporizhzhia region, the regional governor said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuriy Malashko said on the Telegram messaging app that Russian forces had hit a multistorey residential building in the small village close to the front line in southeastern Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following the uptick in violence on the border with Ukraine, the Kremlin has denounced the silence from the international community despite “every opportunity to see the footage describing strikes on residential buildings, social infrastructure.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United States has said it does not support attacks inside Russia and is instead providing Kyiv with equipment and training to defend itself.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine&#39;s air defence has been boosted by Western equipment, including Patriot air defence systems, seen as one of the most advanced US air defence systems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Ukrainian capital has seen almost nightly air raids in May after being relatively spared in the beginning of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, Ukraine said it had destroyed all 15 missiles and 21 drones from a new wave of overnight attacks that left two people wounded in Kyiv.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the last six days, [Russians] have already carried out six attacks on the city!” the chief of the capital&#39;s city administration, Sergiy Popko, said on Telegram.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Russian defence ministry said forces struck Ukraine&#39;s air defence systems protecting “key” military infrastructure and that “all assigned targets have been hit.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The intensified strikes on Kyiv, far from the front lines in the east and south of the Western-backed country, have raised questions about Russia&#39;s calculus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some experts say the Kremlin might be seeking to hinder Ukraine&#39;s planned counteroffensive and deplete its air defences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday three people including a nine-year-old child were killed in Kyiv as a result of falling rocket fragments when Russia pounded Kyiv with ballistic and cruise missiles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The husband of one of the victims, Yaroslav Ryabchuk, said the shelter where they routinely hid from Russian strikes was closed. Following the latest tragedy, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said that all shelters in Kyiv must be inspected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He vowed that all those responsible would be held accountable, saying “there may be a knockout,” apparently a thinly-veiled warning directed against Kyiv Mayor Vitali Klitschko, a former boxer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Klitschko said measures had been taken to ensure “round-the-clock access to shelters”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The enemy is now shelling the capital with ballistic missiles,” Klitschko told residents, saying they might only have “a few minutes” to hide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He advised residents to shelter in their homes, with two walls of protection from the outside, “if you understand that you won&#39;t reach the shelter that quickly”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s Defence Ministry said on Friday that the “Akhmat” group of Chechen special forces were waging an offensive near the town of Mariinka, in the eastern Ukrainian region of Donetsk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Together with the Wagner mercenary group led by Yevgeny Prigozhin, troops from Russia&#39;s Chechen Republic have been one of the main driving forces behind Moscow&#39;s offensive in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Akhmat commander Apti Alaudinov said on Thursday that his forces were being moved to “another area” in preparation for a counteroffensive, but did not say where the troops were or where they were going.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unlike Prigozhin, who has repeatedly lambasted Russia&#39;s military leadership, Chechen leader Ramzan Kadyrov has recently refrained from echoing criticism of the defence ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Members of the two groups have since openly sparred, with one of Kadyrov&#39;s close allies on Thursday casting Prigozhin as a blogger who yells all the time about problems.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US plans to curb investment into Chinese chips and AI are ‘harmful’, Beijing says, as country braces for reduced capital]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3222804/us-plans-curb-investment-chinese-chips-and-ai-are-harmful-beijing-says-country-braces-reduced?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/857d2626-1f2c-45d3-8543-1b35a67802f8_6adf9a73.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Washington is working on new regulations that would limit capital and information flows into sensitive technologies in China such as chips and artificial intelligence (AI), according to comments from a US Treasury official, drawing condemnation from Beijing and warnings from analysts about declining capital flows to Chinese start-ups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plans, referenced on Wednesday by Paul Rosen, the assistant secretary of the treasury for investment security, would allow Washington to exert greater control over the transfer of “US investment dollars that come with know-how and expertise” in specific sectors and sub-sectors such as advanced semiconductors, AI and quantum computing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning firmly opposed the news on Thursday, saying the US was “politicising and weaponising trade and sci-tech issues”, creating obstacles for normal technological cooperation and disrupting global supply chains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Such practice is harmful and serves no one&#39;s interests,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US citizens at Chinese chip firms caught in the middle of tech war&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;AI, quantum computing and the semiconductors responsible for providing these technologies with the necessary computational power have been a growing point of contention between the US and China due to their presumed potential to affect national security. Rosen said the purpose of the curbs is to prevent China from obtaining resources that could be used to gain enhanced military or intelligence capabilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It echoed previous reports that the Biden administration was working to finalise an executive order, slated for this summer, to restrict certain outbound investments into China&#39;s hi-tech industries. A Beijing spokeswoman acknowledged the reports in April, saying they would monitor the situation and strongly oppose such policies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a result, funding will continue to dry up for China&#39;s tech start-ups, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brock Silvers, chief investment officer with Kaiyuan Capital in Hong Kong, said “the almost certain result will be decreased US funding for China&#39;s tech companies” if the government goes ahead with such curbs and trade tensions continue to escalate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move comes as funding for Chinese tech firms has been drying up. China-focused venture capital fundraising is heading for its weakest first half in at least eight years, according to data from research firm Preqin, Reuters reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On the US side, VCs with a global presence, especially those with offices in China, have started to re-evaluate their China strategies,” said Kaidi Gao, a VC analyst with capital market research company PitchBook Data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As foreign fund flows slow from the US, some Chinese asset managers will be forced to place greater emphasis on fundraising from areas outside of the US, such as from Southeast Asia, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, both China and the US are ramping up state investments in an AI arms race. Total US Department of Defence spending on AI is expected to reach US$1.8 billion by 2024, according to a report from PitchBook, spurred on by strategic competition with geopolitical rivals like China. In 2022, the Department of Defence awarded 79 contracts to AI vendors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Beijing government has enlisted major Chinese tech firms to accelerate its own development of AI, with national investment in the industry expected to reach US$26.69 billion in 2026. The government has also cracked down on the use of third-party applications for overseas generative AI products like ChatGPT, which its American developer OpenAI has not officially made available in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to the latest capital curbs, both China and the US can be expected to address their domestic vulnerabilities, according to Silver. “Thus, China will continue its drive to develop greater chip expertise, while the US will begin reshoring its critical minerals supply chain,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 22:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Big powers must avoid ‘diplomatic deep freezes’ for stable world order: Australia’s Albanese]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3222816/big-powers-must-avoid-diplomatic-deep-freezes-stable-world-order-australias-albanese?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/5a0c2dbc-53b3-4036-8ca4-1fb5921bebc8_58b10f7e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The stability and security in the Asia-Pacific region and the world can only be secured through the collective responsibility of all countries, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said on Friday, adding that any “diplomatic deep freezes” by big powers would invite misunderstanding and arouse suspicion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Giving a keynote speech at the Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore, Albanese said peace, stability and security could not be taken for granted, and warned that no nation must think it was above multilateral rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To be collectively responsible, all countries must always engage, maintain open dialogue and diplomacy – that is, establishing guardrails and for all countries to follow the agreed-upon multilateral rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia can play &#39;stabilising role&#39; in Asia amid US-China tensions: Singapore&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;When any country thinks it is above those rules, then stability would break down, Albanese said, citing the importance of the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea to the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Australia&#39;s goal is not to prepare for war, but to prevent it through deterrence and reassurance and building resilience in the region, doing our part to fulfil the shared responsibility all of us have to preserve peace and security,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And making it crystal-clear that when it comes to any unilateral attempt to change the status quo by force, whether Taiwan, the South China Sea, the East China Sea or elsewhere, the risk of conflict will always far outweigh any potential reward.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Globally, Albanese said complacency that free trade and globalisation would support a stable world order appeared to be fading, and countries were now realising they had not paid “sufficient attention to the maintenance and effectiveness of multilateral institutions and global rules”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To do better, big powers and nations must establish the most fundamental guardrail – that is, to move away from “diplomatic deep freezes”, Albanese said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The silence of the diplomatic deep freeze only breeds suspicion, only makes it easier for nations to attribute motive to misunderstanding, to assume the worst of one another,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you don&#39;t have the pressure valve of dialogue, if you don&#39;t have the capacity – at a decision-making level – to pick up the phone, to seek some clarity or provide some context, then there is always a much greater risk of assumptions spilling over into irretrievable action and reaction.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia &#39;hopeful&#39; barley exports to China will resume soon amid warming ties&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;To that end, Australia had moved to set that example by stabilising its relationship with China, Albanese said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While there remained challenges, Albanese said Canberra had sought to recognise that “it was always better and always more effective if we deal direct”, regardless of the differences between the two governments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s extraordinary economic transformation has benefited not only its own population, it has benefited our entire region,” Albanese said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Australian leader also addressed concerns about the potential instability that could be triggered by his country&#39;s purchase of nuclear-powered submarines through the security alliance Aukus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The submarines we are acquiring – the single biggest leap in Australia&#39;s defence capability in our history – reflect our determination to live up to those expectations … [of being] a stronger partner and a more effective contributor to stability in our region,” Albanese said, adding that Aukus was about partnership, not competition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier at a press conference in Singapore after conducting the eighth Australia-Singapore Annual Leaders&#39; Meeting with the city state&#39;s Deputy Prime Minister Lawrence Wong, Albanese said his government made personal calls to more than 60 countries to provide transparency on Aukus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Besides Albanese&#39;s meeting with Singapore&#39;s Wong, Australia&#39;s defence ministers also met their counterparts from Fiji and Ukraine at the dialogue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With Singapore, Albanese agreed to support multilateral cooperation as he had indicated in his speech and to maintain Asean centrality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Albanese and Wong also launched a joint A$20 million (US$13.2 million) Go-Green Co-Innovation Program, to provide grants over a four-year period to drive co-innovation between Singapore and Australia. They also agreed to establish a Green and Digital Shipping Corridor by the end of 2025 to help decarbonise and digitalise the port and shipping industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia committed to being a reliable supplier of energy to Singapore, including gas to meet global emissions targets. The collapsed Sun Cable project to transmit solar-generated electricity from Australia&#39;s Northern Territory to Singapore was recently resuscitated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shangri-La Dialogue is in its 20th edition, and the second meeting after a two-year absence due to the pandemic. Ministers from more than 40 countries attended the meeting, including 48 ministerial-level delegates and more than 35 senior defence officials.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 22:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong trio jailed for up to 5 years, 2 months for rioting as police laid siege to PolyU at height of 2019 anti-government protests]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3222809/hong-kong-trio-jailed-5-years-2-months-rioting-police-laid-siege-polyu-height-2019-anti-government?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 21:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/a5a828ab-4a59-4618-ad0f-5a0e1d1a7d10_625ffb86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A trio of Hong Kong men have been jailed for up to five years and two months for rioting as police laid siege to a university at the height of the 2019 anti-government protests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The men were among four defendants sentenced at West Kowloon Court on Friday in connection with the large-scale disturbance that ended with police rounding up more than 200 protesters at a junction in Yau Ma Tei near Polytechnic University on November 18, 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee Wing-yin, 27, received the heaviest sentence of 62 months after the court rejected his claim that he was working as a photojournalist during the confrontation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yu Pak-hang, 24, was jailed for 57 months and Chen Zhiyuan, 23, was sentenced to 4½ years behind bars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Student Tang Miu-siu, 19, was sentenced to up to three years&#39; detention at a training centre as she was only 16 at the time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deputy District Judge Ada Yim Shun-yee accepted the teenager had displayed genuine remorse while on remand and that the vocational and character development training offered to her would help her turn the page.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Yim said the three men deserved deterrent sentences as they had been involved in serious offences that endangered public safety.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee, a Metropolitan University graduate, said at trial earlier this year he was a photojournalist and produced a press card and a reflective vest as evidence of his role.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Yim rejected his contention in her verdict last month and said Lee had failed to submit any proof that photographs he took that day had been published.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added she was also unable to find a reason why a journalist would tie the vest around his waist instead of wearing it to identify himself.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;13 jailed over &#39;mini war zone&#39; in riot near PolyU&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In a separate case, five men and two women admitted rioting during the same Yau Ma Tei protest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The seven, who appeared at the District Court, were students Wu Hoi-wai, 23, Reaf Yeun Wing-sing, 21, and Chester Wan Yuk-yin, 26; clerk Xu Pengyi, 30; decoration worker Yip Wing-san, 24; part-time waitress Cheung Tsz-ching, 23 and editor Chow Fung-yin, 30.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Judge Stanley Chan Kwong-chi remanded the defendants in custody for sentencing later this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The university was the scene of some of the worst violence of the months-long unrest as protesters occupied the university and barricaded the campus against riot police who attempted to arrest them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Supporters staged several protests in areas around the campus with the aim of giving people trapped inside university grounds a chance to escape.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;3 first aid volunteers jailed for up to 19 months over riot near Hong Kong&#39;s PolyU&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Police arrested 213 people near Yau Ma Tei MTR station during the protest on the night of November 18.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They were in custody for two days before they were taken to six Magistrates&#39; Courts across the city to face riot charges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the largest number of defendants taken to court at one time in connection with the same alleged offence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 213 were divided into 17 groups for trial. A total of 110 people have been convicted so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two were acquitted after trial and three have absconded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sentences imposed earlier ranged from 29 to 64 months in jail to a period of detention at a training centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 22:20:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[BRICS meet with ‘friends’ seeking closer ties amid push to expand bloc]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3222813/brics-meet-friends-seeking-closer-ties-amid-push-expand-bloc?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 22:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/50ecd5ca-6bb6-4d3b-92e4-20671e66f21f_471f0152.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Senior officials from over a dozen countries including Saudi Arabia and Iran were in talks on closer links with the BRICS bloc of major emerging economies on Friday as it met to deepen ties and position itself as a counterweight to the West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BRICS, which now consists of Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa, is considering expanding its membership, and a growing number of countries, mostly from the global South, have expressed interest in joining.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once viewed as a loose association of disparate emerging economies, BRICS has in recent years taken more concrete shape, driven initially by China and, since the start of Ukraine war in February 2022, with added impetus from Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In remarks opening Friday&#39;s discussions, host South Africa&#39;s Foreign Minister Naledi Pandor spoke of the bloc as a champion of the developing world, which she said was abandoned by wealthy states and global institutions during the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The world has faltered in cooperation. Developed countries have never met their commitments to the developing world and are trying to shift all responsibility to the global South,” Pandor said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Africa backtracks on quitting ICC before possible Putin visit&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Iran, Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates, Cuba, Democratic Republic of Congo, Comoros, Gabon, and Kazakhstan all sent representatives to Cape Town for so-called “Friends of BRICS” talks, an official programme showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Egypt, Argentina, Bangladesh, Guinea-Bissau and Indonesia were participating virtually.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BRICS heavyweight China said last year it wanted the bloc to launch a process to admit new members. And other members have pointed to countries they would like to see join the club.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, officials said on Thursday there was still work to be done and appeared mindful of the need to proceed carefully.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“BRICS is a history of success”, Brazilian Foreign Minister Mauro Vieira said. “The group is also a brand and an asset, so we have to take care of it”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indian Foreign Minister Subrahmanyam Jaishankar said Thursday&#39;s talks had included deliberations on the guiding principles, standards, criteria and procedures of what an expanded BRICS bloc would look like.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is still work in progress,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s foreign ministry has previously emphasised the need for a common policy for such an expansion, rather than the consideration of candidacies on an individual basis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Africa&#39;s Pandor said the foreign ministers were aiming to complete work on a framework for admitting new members before BRICS leaders meet at a summit in Johannesburg in August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Preparations for that summit are going forward under a cloud of controversy due to the possible attendance of Russian President Vladimir Putin, who is the target of a warrant issued by the International Criminal Court (ICC).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As an ICC member, South Africa would face pressure to arrest Putin were he to travel to the summit. Pretoria has said it is still considering its legal options for hosting the Russian president.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 22:20:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>