<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Pakistan’s PM Shehbaz Sharif launches US$3.5 billion Chinese-designed nuclear energy project]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3227776/pakistans-pm-sharif-launches-us35-billion-chinese-designed-nuclear-energy-project?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 21:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/39ad22df-328b-4d3b-8c53-64b10c84185d_a7ccb884.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;巴基斯坦总理谢巴兹·谢里夫周五启动了中国 1,200 兆瓦核电站的建设设计的核能项目，该项目将耗资 35 亿美元建设，作为伊斯兰国家政府努力生产更多清洁能源的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;项目启动仪式不到一个月前，巴基斯坦与中国国家核工业海外集团公司在首都伊斯兰堡签署了建造华龙一号反应堆的协议，该反应堆是第三代核反应堆，由于采用了最新的安全功能，被认为更安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴基斯坦和中国是长期盟友。巴基斯坦与北京的关系如此密切，以至于巴基斯坦领导人称中国为“铁哥们”。中国还在修建道路、桥梁、发电厂和铁路，将其遥远的西部地区与中国在印度洋上建造的瓜达尔港连接起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;巴基斯坦启动了价值 27 亿美元的中国设计的核电站&lt;/ h3>;&lt;p>;名为 Chashma-5 的核电站将建在东部旁遮普省米安瓦利地区湍急的印度河左岸的一个地点。该地点已经是近几十年来建造的四座中国供应的核电站的所在地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢里夫在米安瓦利举行的巴基斯坦和中国官员聚会上发表电视讲话时表示，Chashma-5 核电站能源项目本身就是一个“巨大的里程碑，一个巨大的成功故事，也是两个伟大朋友之间合作的美好象征。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，项目完成后，巴基斯坦将获得清洁、高效和更便宜的能源。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴基斯坦从加拿大获得了第一座核电站，目前仅 8% 的电力来自核电站，并计划到 2030 年将这一数字增加到 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴基斯坦的第一座核电站来自加拿大。近几个月来，中国向巴基斯坦提供了50亿美元贷款，帮助该国获得国际货币基金组织的救助，以应对严重的经济危机。国际货币基金组织周三批准了一项 30 亿美元的救助计划，该救助计划自去年 12 月以来一直处于搁置状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，谢里夫表示，他的国家永远不会忘记中国在他的国家面临危机时向其提供的财政援助。违约风险。他说，这是“在非常困难的时刻做出的非常有价值的贡献，国家永远不会忘记它”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢里夫的总理任期将于 8 月结束，他表示巴基斯坦不再面临默认值。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 21:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China completes first step in advanced nuclear reactor project by finishing core module]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3227777/china-completes-first-step-advanced-nuclear-reactor-project-finishing-core-module?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 21:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/d12309f8-2cd9-4297-993c-0bb64cd077de_1f2b2891.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国已建成全球首个商用陆上小型模块化反应堆核心模块。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国核动力研究院表示，这是玲龙一号反应堆建设的第一个里程碑，“标志着小型模块化压水堆制造迈出了历史性的一步”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;核行业内部人士表示，这种类型的反应堆有几个好处，包括它们可以用于多种用途，并为传统反应堆不适合的地区提供电力和淡水。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;该反应堆于 2021 年在海南岛南部的长江电厂开始建设，预计将于 2026 年完工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;建成后，它将能够生产 10 亿千瓦时的电力每年的电力足以满足526,000户家庭的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;核电已成为该国到2060年实现碳中和的目标以及使用沿海核电站（包括玲珑核反应堆）的日益重要的组成部分一是当前的国家发展五年计划中提倡的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;聚变反应堆正在造成故障——泰国科学家很高兴&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;小型模块化反应堆是先进的核反应堆，具有强大的功率单机容量高达300MW，约为传统核电堆的三分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该技术可满足发电、城市供暖和制冷、海水淡化和蒸汽等多种能源需求据国家通讯社新华社报道，目前，世界各地正在开发 70 多个商用小型模块化反应堆，其中包括阿根廷、俄罗斯&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该技术还可以在海上使用，可能在南海等有争议的水域使用。俄罗斯已建成世界上第一座浮动核电站——“罗蒙诺索夫院士号”，并于2020年5月开始商业运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国核电公司党组书记、董事长陆铁忠此前曾介绍过反应堆被认为适合人口数万的小岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两年前，卢告诉国营科技日报，它们的海水淡化能力也很重要，因为它们可以被利用为这些岛屿提供淡水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多‘一带一路’沿线国家和南海沿岸国家，如菲律宾、印度尼西亚和马来西亚，有许多小型岛屿岛屿。沙特阿拉伯等国家的偏远地区也可能对这项技术有需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的“人造太阳”打破了聚变反应堆的里程碑记录&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;核心据新华社报道，玲珑一号的模块由中国第一重工制造，是该反应堆最关键的部分，其技术和建造完全是中国的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;制造公司告诉新华社：“通过自主创新，我们突破了多项关键技术并实现了工程应用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年，玲龙一号成为世界上第一个通过安全审查的小型模块化反应堆国际原子能机构表示，该设计“能够应对极端环境条件和多次故障”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 21:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[France celebrates Bastille Day with pomp, a tribute to India and extra police to prevent new unrest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227780/france-celebrates-bastille-day-pomp-tribute-india-and-extra-police-prevent-new-unrest?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 21:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/6d60e5b9-0e75-4c6a-9758-3e7c1d3cdc43_8c1183f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;法国周五将用呼啸而过的战机和盛大的巴士底日游行来庆祝国庆节在巴黎，并在全国各地部署了超过 100,000 名警察，以防止贫困社区爆发新的骚乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，庆祝 1789 年 7 月 14 日法国大革命开始的年度活动将于一名北非裔青少年被警察开枪打死，引发了该国近 20 年来最严重的骚乱，这暴露了人们对根深蒂固的不平等和种族歧视的愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度是主宾国在今年的巴士底日游行中，总理纳伦德拉·莫迪与法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙一起在贵宾看台上观看。大约 240 名印度军队在数千名法国军队之前率领沿着香榭丽舍大街行进，法国制造的印度战机也参加了传统的飞越活动，结束了此次活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法国马克龙授予印度莫迪最高荣誉&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;法国经常在巴士底日展示国际合作伙伴，而印度选择印度之际，法国希望进一步加强在应对气候变化、军售和战略印太地区方面的合作。但尽管欧洲立法者、人权组织和其他人士提出了担忧，但广泛的议程中却缺少人权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国各地的城镇在巴士底日举行庆祝活动，旨在庆祝法国“”的理想自由、平等和博爱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但对于许多生活在被忽视的住房项目中的人来说，这句座右铭听起来很空洞，他们的根源可以追溯到前法国殖民地，并与缺乏机会和日常种族主义作斗争。上个月，警方在巴黎郊区楠泰尔的一次交通堵塞中杀害了 17 岁的纳赫尔·梅尔祖克 (Nahel Merzouk)，之后这些问题就凸显出来了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频记录了这起近距离致命枪击事件。 ，引发了与警察数天的冲突，焚烧建筑物和车辆，以及抢劫法国各地城镇的商店。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为应对巴士底日期间的更多暴力事件，每年骚乱往往都会加剧，法国部署了周四和周五有 130,000 名警察。包括 Nanterre 在内的多个城镇都禁止燃放烟花爆竹，因为烟花在最近的骚乱中被用来瞄准警察。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四至周五夜间，内政部报告称，有 97 人在城市暴力中被捕，218 辆汽车被劫持。全国各地下车。这比去年略低。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 21:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Intel CEO wraps up low-key China trip as US chip giant taps hot Chinese demand for semiconductors]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3227718/intel-ceo-wraps-low-key-china-trip-us-chip-giant-taps-hot-chinese-demand-semiconductors?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/cc258bf3-e761-4c49-ba5f-c2ea3342caef_f4b02bb0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英特尔首席执行官帕特里克·基辛格 (Patrick Gelsinger) 本周结束了低调的中国之行，这是他的第二次访问尽管美中科技战愈演愈烈，这家美国芯片巨头仍加倍进军中国市场，三个月后将前往中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，基辛格的行程包括周三访问新华三集团北京总部，清华紫光集团旗下中国领先的IT设备供应商。 H3C在一份声明中表示，基辛格会见了清华大学联盟集团董事长李斌和H3C首席执行官余英涛，并补充说该公司将在其最新服务器产品中使用英特尔Gaudi2处理器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当天据xFusion的一份声明称，基辛格拜访了算力基础设施和服务提供商xFusion Technologies，并与该公司董事长刘宏云就“绿色数据中心创新和人工智能算力”方面的合作进行了会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;“扎实创新”：随着美国加大科技战力度，中国习近平再次呼吁自力更生&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;基辛格周一开始了他的行程，参观了英特尔位于西南部省会成都的芯片封装和测试工厂四川省举行了庆祝英特尔在该市运营 20 周年的庆祝活动。据当地媒体报道，英特尔负责人受到了四川省省长黄强和成都市市委书记石晓林的接见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基辛格表示，成都在该公司的全球供应链中发挥着关键作用，并且根据成都市政府的一份声明，成都政府指出，其“有利”的商业环境为英特尔的“稳定增长”铺平了道路，并为该公司在该地区的扩张“增强了信心”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英特尔没有透露基辛格的中国行程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此行恰逢该公司在中国推出专为人工智能 (AI) 深度学习应用而设计的 Gaudi 2 处理器。该处理器不受美国出口限制，是广泛用于训练人工智能系统的 Nvidia A100 GPU 的替代品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国顶级人工智能服务器制造商浪潮也将使用该处理器。该公司周二宣布其新的 NF5698G7 AI 服务器将基于 Gaudi 2。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gelsinger 上次访问中国是在 4 月份，当时他表示中国仍然是英特尔的一个关键市场，并指出该公司已经自 1986 年以来一直在该国开展业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管拜登政府不断努力限制向中国公司出口先进芯片技术，但该国仍然是美国芯片制造商的主要市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;超过四分之一收入来自中国的英特尔面临着改善财务业绩的压力。最新财报显示，今年第一季度，其营收同比下降36%至117亿美元，净亏损28亿美元，而上年同期净利润为81亿美元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，中国监管机构尚未批准英特尔收购以色列晶圆代工厂Tower Semiconductor 的交易。分析人士认为，涉及美国公司的并购交易进展缓慢是北京方面抵制华盛顿制裁的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有报道称基辛格在此次访问期间会见了中国反垄断监管机构国家市场监督管理总局。过去一周。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 21:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s top diplomat backs Hong Kong membership of world’s biggest trading bloc at Jakarta summit for regional foreign ministers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3227723/chinas-top-diplomat-backs-hong-kong-membership-worlds-biggest-trading-bloc-jakarta-summit-regional?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/a6603eb7-1dc9-4d7e-b886-63aafecc907c_1558656a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京最高外交官全力支持香港加入全球最大贸易区在印度尼西亚举行的东南亚外交部长会议上，分析人士表示，此举将推动该市领导人李约翰本月晚些时候访问该地区三个国家时进行的商务谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅，中国外交政策负责人周五表示，他支持香港加入由 15 个亚太国家组成的区域全面经济伙伴关系协定 (RCEP)，其中包括 10 个东盟国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还向该协会发出呼吁在印度尼西亚首都雅加达举行的东盟10+3（APT）外长会议上，东南亚国家、日本和韩国坚持“开放合作”，加速区域一体化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“全面加入东盟10+3”以RCEP的力量为契机，我们支持香港作为首批成员之一加入RCEP。”中央外办主任王在会上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “中国支持建设稳定、畅通、基于比较优势的区域生产供应链体系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅对与会代表的讲话强调了中国对RCEP经济技术合作的支持以及对东盟的援助”东亚共同体”，指的是为指导未来五年区域合作而制定的《10+3合作工作计划》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年1月1日生效的RCEP包括占世界人口的三分之一和全球国内生产总值的约30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它被视为美国主导的全面进步跨太平洋伙伴关系协定的替代方案。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中文大学经济学家庄大良教授表示，公开表达支持香港加入RCEP的时机为行政长官李家超访港“铺平了道路”三个东盟国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最高外交官的支持可以为东盟国家注入信心，促进李氏代表团与其同行之间潜在的商业谈判，”该大学刘佐德全球研究所执行董事张&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李显龙率领的高级贸易代表团将于本月晚些时候访问新加坡、马来西亚和印度尼西亚，以与东盟成员国建立密切联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;洪由于出口持续低迷，香港李约翰为东盟贸易之旅做好准备&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;张表示，如果一些需要先进技术的关键部分转移到香港，香港的专业服务和技术行业将受益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他补充说，香港可以把握机遇，发展成为区域数据中心，为高增长的东盟地区对中国市场感兴趣的企业提供服务，并为内地企业在该地区的发展提供便利。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;城市大学公共政策系政治学家Linda Li Chelan教授预测，在与美国持续紧张的情况下，香港加入贸易集团可以支持国家的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经济利益加强区域合作带来的成果预计将有助于北京缓解风险，特别是在中国经济发展明显陷入危机的情况下。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近前往雅加达进行研究工作的李说。东盟国家政府官员和企业普遍欢迎香港资金，认为是符合其政策蓝图的“优质投资”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她呼吁香港企业抓住机遇开拓新兴市场，拥有年轻、精通技术的人口以及对商品和服务不断增长的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港李家强“率领代表团”访问新加坡、马来西亚和印度尼西亚&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;王还强调了“共同点”峰会上提出了“安全”的主题，并呼吁该地区不断提高危机应对的有效性，更好地维护粮食供应链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，该地区还应加强创新，挖掘可持续发展潜力， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王还要求日本在将失事福岛核电站的核污染废水倒入海洋之前“三思而后行”，他说这对日本的安全产生影响。海洋环境和人类健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港申请加入RCEP也必须获得成员国的批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;RCEP协议涵盖文莱、柬埔寨、印度尼西亚、老挝、马来西亚、缅甸、菲律宾、新加坡、泰国和越南，以及东盟五个主要贸易伙伴中国、日本、韩国、澳大利亚和新西兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东盟是香港第二大贸易伙伴2022 年商品合作伙伴金额达 1.29 万亿港元（1,660 亿美元）。香港仍然是东盟成员国与内地之间的重要纽带。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两个经济体之间通过香港的转口贸易去年达 6,170 亿港元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 21:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s local governments to play bigger role in protecting citizens abroad under new regulation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227774/chinas-local-governments-play-bigger-role-protecting-citizens-abroad-under-new-regulation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 21:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/6f43ffd1-c824-4ab8-8258-62ce3d300fa0_b8901a94.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国将调动更多国内资源保护海外中国公民，包括发挥更大作用&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着越来越多的中国公民和企业走出国门，在“严峻复杂的形势下”为领事保护设定了“更高的门槛”，这一做法是必要的。中国外交部副部长邓励周五表示，“安全形势更加复杂，风险更加多元化。”他在新闻发布会上就周四公布的 27 项监管规定发表了上述言论。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新规定填补了长期以来的立法空白，将中央各部门、驻外外交机构和地方的职责分工以及海外的自我保护职责制度化中国公民和组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“领事保护和协助……不是外交部一个人完成的，而是各部门、各地方、驻外使领馆乃至企业、组织和个人共同完成的。” &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国使馆官员探视在日本商业秘密案中被拘留的男子&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新规定要求中国地方当局完善工作机制，加大人员和财力“动态”加强对境外人员和机构的监控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各地要制定应急预案，共同应对涉及境外中国公民和组织的突发事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着北京在世界各地的政治和经济影响力不断扩大，越来越多的中国公民出国留学、旅游、投资和就业。涉及中国公民的安全事件也呈上升趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，中国组织撤侨行动近20次，办理领事保护案件超过50万起，涉及数百万中国公民。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，中国驻外外交机构和国内相关机构却遇到了职责不清、资源不足、能做什么、不能做什么缺乏法律明确等挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在两周前批准新规定的会议上，中国国务院呼吁“努力增强海外安全保障能力，加快建立海外安全防护体系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;更多中国受害者在缅甸遭受跨境网络诈骗&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国在四月份部署海军在苏丹爆发内战时救援公民，之后出台了开创性的领事保护法规。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;新规定规定，其他国家发生战争、严重自然灾害、严重传染病疫情、恐怖袭击等重大突发事件时，我国地方政府及其他有关部门应当履行职责，提供在有条件的情况下向中国公民提供帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邓表示，中国还将加强对中国公民和境外机构的统计，以便根据新规定提供“及时”支持。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 21:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Whale met again! Hong Kong’s second sighting in 2 days as experts tell public to leave animals in peace]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227775/whale-met-again-hong-kongs-second-sighting-2-days-experts-tell-public-leave-animals-peace?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 21:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/aa5de443-a216-45fa-baa1-789e504d184c_ba707034.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;两天内第二次在香港水域发现鲸鱼，市政府表示，在这种罕见的情况下，警告居民不要外出搜寻海洋哺乳动物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海警周五下午表示，他们在万宜岛（也称为良船湾）附近发现了一头鲸鱼。一天前，同一岛上的百万富翁海滩附近发生了类似的目击事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚西贡地区的这两次目击事件是否是同一头鲸鱼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;渔农自然护理署表示：“署方呼吁市民不要出海搜寻鲸鱼，以免对人类造成滋扰。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;围观者惊叹不已&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;专家表示，周四发现的海洋哺乳动物根据其体型和体型，相信是布氏鲸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部门没有具体说明该鲸鱼的具体情况。周五看到的鲸鱼品种。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最初的目击事件引起了香港人在网上的大量关注，引发了人们可能涌入该地区一睹风采的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A早报记者在百万富翁海滩附近海域观察到，除了水警、海事处和渔农自然护理署的六艘船只外，还有不到十几艘私人船只。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚是否有私人船只专门在那里观看鲸鱼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们对大量船只的到来感到紧张，”Hebe Haven 游艇俱乐部的高级教练莉莉·里德 (Lily Reid) 说，她是最先发现鲸鱼的人之一周四的鲸鱼。 “我们希望一直这样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港海豚保育会副主席麦熙文表示，鲸鱼等海洋哺乳动物通常会在同一区域进食一天以上然后继续前进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她警告居民不要为了罕见的目击而进入水域，因为这可能会导致鲸鱼的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“简单来说，这会打扰麦解释说：“这会影响鲸鱼的进食活动，并可能威胁其健康。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“纯粹的混乱”：马尔代夫的鲸鲨旅游业如何使动物的生命面临危险&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最后的目击事件2021 年 6 月至 8 月期间，在深圳大鹏湾大鹏半岛附近以及西贡附近的香港或附近水域记录到一头布氏鲸的尸体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一具属于同一物种的尸体8 月在深圳附近海域发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布氏鲸是须鲸的一种，体长可达 15 米（49 英尺），体重可达 25 公吨（27 吨）。它们通常全年都出现在热带水域，并以张开嘴时使用鲸须板过滤食物而闻名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家指出，虽然布氏鲸在香港水域出现并不常见， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主题公园海洋公园总馆长黄永康表示，虽然海洋哺乳动物经常出现在菲律宾海和南中国海，但香港仍然属于&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还否认了之前关于这种海洋哺乳动物可能与同伴分离并迷路的说法，因为众所周知，布赖德鲸在进食时会单独游泳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港大学鲸类研究所所长 Leszek Karczmarski 建议船上居民与发现的鲸鱼保持 150 至 200 米的距离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还应该突然避开他补充说，改变船的方向，并在生物接近船只时避免故意阻碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它们是好奇的生物，”Karczmarski 说。 “享受难得的荣幸，能够看到如此壮丽的景象。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Ong Beng Seng, the ‘prince of a thousand deals’ who charmed Singapore, got caught up in Iswaran corruption probe]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3227768/how-ong-beng-seng-prince-thousand-deals-who-charmed-singapore-got-caught-iswaran-corruption-probe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 20:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/25d5513c-8bdb-4750-a52d-1b93bfc8a248_3cba2e83.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;亿万富翁王明成 (Ong Beng Seng) 卷入新加坡四年来最引人注目的腐败调查几十年来，他并不缺乏最高级的：他是这个城邦最富有的大亨之一，一级方程式特许经营权所有者俱乐部的大人物，并且四十多年来一直是东南亚的重要人物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年来，他一直避免成为聚光灯下的焦点，尽管有关 Ong 丰富多彩、有时傲慢的性格的细节——尤其是他作为一名积极进取的交易撮合者的技能——是众所周知的，这要归功于一个关系密切但口无遮拦的地区富有阶层。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 20 世纪 90 年代，国家媒体和时尚商业杂志对 Ong 的描述范围从“远东酋长”到“千笔交易王子”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至少有一次提到 Ong 和他的妻子 Christina Ong（她自己认为是一位非常成功的女商人），称其为新加坡房地产和酒店界的“时髦和小贝”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的酒店地产有限公司 (HPL) 1995 年，该岛共和国长期执政的人民行动党 (PAP) 曾短暂地感到恼火，当时该党以折扣价向高层政客出售豪宅，引发了对官方不当行为的质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;已故独立领袖李光耀和他的儿子、现任总理李显龙通过独立调查被证明没有不当行为，但 HPL 因不遵守证券交易所规则而受到谴责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我会“我宁愿每天和他一起吃饭，也不愿和单调的童子军一起吃饭，”一位亲密的同事周五告诉《亚洲周刊》。 “新加坡的活力和兴奋很大程度上归功于他。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位来自 Ong 出生国马来西亚的商人指出，虽然这位酒店经营者保留了马来西亚公民身份，但他也“成功地在新加坡站稳了脚跟”一位与这位大亨同处一个圈子的新加坡商人说，他的招牌风格“在一英里之外”就可以看出。 ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他的做事方式就是一路撒糖，一不小心就会被诱惑。这位人士表示，阿谀奉承会让你头脑发热。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位来自一级方程式业务的人士形容 Ong 在做生意时“无情”。 “如果他想要什么，没有什么可以阻挡他，”这位驻伦敦的消息人士说。 “你这样交不到很多朋友。看看会发生什么将会很有趣。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ong 出生于 1946 年，在新加坡和英国接受教育，在 1975 年加入岳父的石油贸易业务之前，他从事航运保险业务。 Ong 和他的妻子的日常商业利益遍布国内外的房地产、酒店和生活方式领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡 F1 最高领导人 Ong Beng Seng 在 Iswaran 调查中发出“逮捕通知”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;在新加坡，周五公众正在消化这样的消息：这名以名字缩写“OBS”而广为人知的男子被捕，并协助可怕的腐败行为调查局（CPIB）调查涉及交通部长 S. Iswaran 的案件。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;李周三命令伊斯瓦兰无限期休假。李和该机构（直接向总理报告）没有具体说明调查的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地媒体称，周三有人看到翁进出 CPIB 总部。中文《联合早报》刊登了这位亿万富翁的照片，他穿着 T 恤、休闲裤和拖鞋，戴着围巾，似乎进入了反腐机构大楼外的一辆丰田 Vellfire。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公司周五提交的文件称，Ong 正在全力配合 CPIB。声明称，他从周五开始旅行，并缴纳了 10 万新元（75,710 美元）的保释金，并将返回新加坡接受进一步审讯。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在社交媒体、Reddit 和以激烈的政治八卦而闻名的论坛页面，“我告诉过你”似乎是 Ong 被捕后的主导主题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然还没有涉及 Iswaran 的调查细节，但律师警告称，他必须被视为无辜until proven otherwise – the chatter before Friday had been that Ong could be questioned too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Iswaran, 66, and Ong, are widely seen as twin engines behind Singapore&#39;s successful pitch in the mid-2000s to bring the F1 race to the city state. Iswaran, as then junior trade minister, and Ong as the money man, convinced the then F1 global head honcho Bernie Ecclestone to make Singapore the venue for the sport&#39;s first night race, starting in 2008.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Iswaran reportedly knew Ong from his previous career as a high-flying bureaucrat and top executive at the state investor Temasek Holdings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Singapore race has since been entrenched as one of the highlights of the F1 calendar, with the three-day event attracting the super wealthy from around the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The event&#39;s rise in status, despite the sprouting up of five other night races including in Qatar and Las Vegas, has mirrored Singapore&#39;s meteoric progress in the 2010s as the go-to Asian playground for the rich and famous.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore&#39;s DPM Wong pledges transparency as ruling PAP reels from graft probe&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;After a Covid-induced interruption in 2020 and 2021, the race returned in grand fashion last year, attracting a record crowd. The Singapore government, along with Ong&#39;s Singapore GP, in January announced that the contract to host the race in the republic would be extended for a further seven years – the fourth and longest contract extension with the owners of F1.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are no indications that the CPIB probe has anything to do with F1, but public speculation – and even talk among associates – has gone in that direction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prime Minister Lee&#39;s No. 2 and designated successor, Lawrence Wong, earlier urged the public not to speculate on the investigation into Iswaran, saying only that it was initiated by the CPIB and was originally pertaining to a separate matter. It was brought to Prime Minister Lee&#39;s attention in May, and on July 5 the agency asked for his assent to interview the transport minister. Lee greenlit the request the next day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Singapore-based businessman who spoke to This Week in Asia, who has close ties to Ong and his wife, said of Iswaran: “As the minister in charge of F1, should you be so buddy-buddy with the FI franchise owner? This is something we need to ask.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Also circulating online were remarks by the late Lee Kuan Yew on the probity of political leaders and their relationship with tycoons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The founding prime minister remains widely revered for force-marching Singapore from third- to first-world status, and for entrenching a culture within the bureaucracy and the public that deeply eschews corruption practices – seen as key to the city state&#39;s status as one of the world&#39;s least corrupt places.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a speech to parliament in May 1996, as the PAP-dominated legislature debated the concluded investigations into the Lees&#39; purchase of HPL properties, the political patriarch said interacting with the country&#39;s tycoons, including Ong, was important to help Singapore&#39;s economic interests “go regional”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I can eat with Ong Beng Seng and Koh Beng Seng and I would still be the same person. No difference,” Lee said. “And that is again back to character and a code of honour.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China urged to push Russia to renew Black Sea Grain Initiative to avoid ‘blow to global food market’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3227756/china-urged-push-russia-renew-black-sea-grain-initiative-avoid-blow-global-food-market?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 20:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/99e62dee-8613-495e-9fe5-5b83dba6ff76_adf150d0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China has been urged to persuade Russia to renew a United Nations-brokered deal that is set to expire on Monday, a breakdown that could threaten grain shipments from Ukraine and also add to Beijing&#39;s growing pressure to diversify its food imports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has placed a greater emphasis on food self-sufficiency in recent years, but still relies on Ukraine for nearly 30 per cent of its corn imports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has been the top destination for grain shipments from the war-ridden country under the Black Sea Grain Initiative, which was introduced to help alleviate a global food crisis after Russia&#39;s invasion blockaded Ukrainian ports, according to an association of agricultural companies in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Russia&#39;s refusal to renew the Black Sea Grain Initiative will result in a blow to the global food market, lead to rising prices and further aggravate the global food crisis,” Patricia Flor, the German ambassador to China, told the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We appeal to China to support the extension of the deal and talk to Russia. China, which is also a food importer and recipient of Ukrainian grain, can contribute to stabilise the global food market.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Failure to renew the deal, which was brokered by the UN and Turkey in July last year, will force China to turn to more expensive sources to fill the gap in corn – an important food for its citizens and one that is used to make cooking oil and animal feed – warned a Beijing-based analyst.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ukraine has been the cheapest source as we have mature infrastructure there, mainly developed by state-owned food giant Cofco over the past decade,” said Ma Wenfeng, a senior analyst with Beijing Orient Agribusiness Consultant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without imports from Ukraine, prices in the domestic market will rise. And China needs to get more from Brazil and other traditional partners such as the US, Canada and Australia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the grain initiative set to expire, ships arriving in Ukraine to export grain “have been rare”, said Roman Slaston, director general of the Ukrainian Agribusiness Club.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most recent shipments were agreed on June 28, but they were still waiting to be inspected in Istanbul, he added last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Millions of tonnes of grain may be spoiled in silos if we do not have the possibility of sea exports in sufficient volumes,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grain shipments from the Black Sea port of Pivdennyi have been suspended since May, Slaston added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have additional 3 to 5 million tonnes of grain to be exported from the previous harvest and will have at least 40 million tonnes of grain and oilseed to be exported from the new harvest this year,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine and Russia are major food suppliers in the global market, with the war pushing up global food prices and threatening supplies, especially to countries in the Middle East and Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turning from a net exporter of corn to a net importer in 2010, China bought over 20 million tonnes of the grain last year, with the US the largest source ahead of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has been seeking new agricultural partners since the start of the Ukraine war in February 2022, with Beijing adding Brazil, Myanmar and South Africa to its approved list of corn suppliers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Critical grains cut back China&#39;s copious cotton yields amid food-security push&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Brazil overtook Ukraine as China&#39;s second-largest source of corn in the first quarter, representing 28.8 per cent and 27.7 per cent of imports, respectively, according to Chinese customs figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Black Sea Grain Initiative, which helped decrease global prices, is intended to be extended for 120 days at a time, but in March and May, Russia agreed to only 60 days in an attempt to pressure the West to relax its sanctions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russian President Vladimir Putin said on Thursday that Russia would withdraw from the deal completely unless its demands to export more food and fertiliser were met.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin told Russian state television that the UN had so far failed to provide a satisfactory solution, according to Reuters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine grain exports were an important topic of discussion during two days of talks between the UN and the European Union, according to a UN press release on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen urged Russia to extend the deal as “the world needs it”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Otherwise, global food insecurity will be the consequence. So now the ball is in President Putin&#39;s court, and the world is watching,” she said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Partner, not a rival’: China urges Germany to take ‘rational’ view after it reveals de-risking strategy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227754/partner-not-rival-china-urges-germany-take-rational-view-after-it-reveals-de-risking-strategy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 20:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/c43c4d2f-acc9-4b87-8fcd-c393e6f9b293_8de7ae38.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing has called on Berlin to take a “rational” view of China&#39;s development and regard it as a “cooperative partner” instead of a “systematic rival”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The call follows Germany&#39;s release of a blueprint highlighting Beijing&#39;s risks on various fronts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is a partner, not a rival, to Germany&#39;s challenges. The perception of China as a &#39;competitor and systemic rival&#39; does not correspond to objective facts and is not in the common interest of the two countries,” the Chinese embassy in Berlin said in a statement on Thursday, adding that many of Germany&#39;s challenges and problems were “not caused by China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China and Germany have many common interests in promoting global multipolarity, safeguarding free trade and addressing climate change. We hope that the two sides will work together … inject more stability and positive energy into the turbulent world,” the statement said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;EU aims to project united approach towards China ahead of Brussels meetings&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Germany launched a sweeping 61-page strategy paper on Thursday, outlining Berlin&#39;s comprehensive, risk-reducing approach towards Beijing, which has shifted from a more moderate stance under former chancellor Angela Merkel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China has changed. As a result of this and China&#39;s political decisions, we need to change our approach to China,” read the document, which has been considered a top foreign policy priority for German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Anyone who listens to China knows that it will assertively shape the course of this century. With the China strategy we set up a compass to guide our relations,” Baerbock tweeted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Acknowledging China as a “partner, competitor, and systemic rival”, the document stated that Berlin wished to maintain a close and wide-ranging dialogue with Beijing on issues of mutual interest but would “become less dependent in critical sectors in order to reduce the risks they entail”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The document also stated that to avoid long-term security risks to Germany, the European Union and its allies, Berlin would adjust its export control lists, especially in key technologies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Germany&#39;s biggest trading partner, China&#39;s dependence on Europe had decreased, while Germany&#39;s dependence on China had grown in recent years, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, trade volume between China and Germany increased by a surprising 21 per cent year on year to €191 billion (US$214.5 billion). The value of Germany&#39;s imports from China increased by around 30 per cent, but the value of its exports to China increased by only 3.1 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The much-anticipated blueprint signalled that Berlin had thrown its support behind the EU&#39;s de-risking policy, at least on the economic front, despite Chinese Premier Li Qiang&#39;s pleas to Chancellor Olaf Scholz during his trip last month for a moderate attitude towards China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The goal of the document was not to disconnect Germany and China, Scholz stressed, adding that Berlin wanted to avoid critical dependencies in the future. With the new strategy, Germany was responding to a China that was changing and taking a more offensive stance, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, Chinese foreign ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin said de-risking and cutting reliance would only be counterproductive and create risk, adding that Germany was drawing ideological lines between competitors.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;EU leaders agree to &#39;de-risk&#39; the bloc&#39;s trade dealings with China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Forced &#39;de-risking&#39; on the basis of ideological bias will ... exacerbate risks,” the ministry said, adding that the greatest risk to the global economy and security was the “promotion of divisive confrontation and decoupling”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to economic factors, the German strategy document highlighted China&#39;s relationship with Russia during its invasion of Ukraine as a “security concern”, and said Berlin saw direct risks in the Taiwan issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong health minister encourages disapproving stares from public to discourage smokers from lighting up in restricted areas]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227760/hong-kong-health-minister-encourages-disapproving-stares-public-discourage-smokers-lighting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 19:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/cdd47b2e-e31d-4efb-9642-9a8717ad224c_3f026410.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong public should give the evil eye to people who light up in non-smoking areas to underline opposition to breaches of anti-tobacco laws, the health minister has said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Health Lo Chung-mau on Friday also warned that authorities would take into consideration surveillance footage or video clips provided by members of the public, which could be used as evidence to crack down on illegal smoking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cigarettes can harm the health of all of us,” Lo told a meeting of the Legislative Council&#39;s health service panel after the launch earlier in the week of a public consultation exercise on tougher anti-smoking rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added: “When the members of the public see people smoking in non-smoking areas, even if no law enforcement officers can show up immediately, we can stare at the smokers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When someone takes out a cigarette at a restaurant, everyone in the premises can stare at that person. I do not believe that person would dare to hit back at everyone at the restaurant as they are simply staring.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lo promised to improve law enforcement, but suggested members of the public could work together to create a culture that discouraged smoking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We understand that law enforcement officers cannot always take actions at the scene of the crime. When they arrive at the scene, the crime may have already stopped,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Take queuing at a bus stop as an example. No one will say it requires law to compel people to queue. Our society is able to create a culture that people will comply with this rule of queuing when waiting for buses. I hope the whole of society can build a non-smoking culture.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lo was speaking after health authorities on Wednesday unveiled new anti-smoking strategies such as banning people born after a certain date from buying cigarettes and whether to increase the tax on tobacco to 75 per cent of the package price in a rapid or gradual way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The news was reported on the same day that diners were seen smoking inside restaurants, despite the ban.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Raising Hong Kong&#39;s tobacco tax annually will discourage smoking: health secretary&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Staff at the premises said it was difficult to force customers to stop smoking and, even if they complained to the authorities, offenders would have finished their cigarettes before officers arrived.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Statutory no smoking areas cover indoor areas of restaurants, workplaces, indoor public places and some outdoor public places, with penalties of HK$1,500 for breaches.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Enforcement of tobacco control regulations have been criticised in the past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A report by the ombudsman in 2018 found that the Tobacco and Alcohol Control Office had staffing problems and that there was a lack of patrols at night.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lo dismissed fears that a get tough approach to smoking would damage Hong Kong&#39;s international image and affect the experience of tourists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lo said: “Tobacco-free Hong Kong has a healthy image. I do not think tourists visit Hong Kong because they would like to buy or smoke cigarettes.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ban on cigarettes for Hongkongers born after certain date proposed&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He added information on the city&#39;s anti-smoking rules had been passed to airlines so they could tell arrivals and that announcements on tobacco policies were made at the airport.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawmaker Chan Kin-por said he supported an increase in the legal age to buy cigarettes, but disagreed that those born after a certain year should be banned from buying them altogether.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Very few countries around the world have implemented similar measures. Smoking or not should be a personal choice,” Chan said. “Tobacco control measures should be gradual. One-size-fit-all policies may backfire.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fellow legislator Chan Hoi-yan said she was disappointed with the content of the public consultation paper and accused it of being “too basic” and “void of concrete solutions”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For example, we can do a study on whether parents of schoolchildren have smoking habits, then we can formulate measures to focus on these children,” Chan said. “The government should suggest solutions to prevent smoking while walking instead of asking the public whether they agree to ban such behaviour or not.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kitson Yang Wing-kit, the panel&#39;s deputy chairman, said the government should boost promotion of tobacco control and smoking cessation so that the public could be better-educated on the risks or “even hate smoking”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 20:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>