<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Victoria’s Secret’s first Malay-Muslim model Nia Atasha Rosli divides fans, conservatives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3227008/victorias-secrets-first-malay-muslim-model-nia-atasha-rosli-divides-fans-conservatives?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 12:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/0660824c-09dd-4abc-8d74-8cbecb39aeb5_f5638ad3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;马来西亚模特兼女演员 Nia Atasha Rosli 本周在社交媒体上掀起了波澜作为全球内衣品牌维多利亚的秘密的第一位马来穆斯林模特。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚维多利亚的秘密周一推出的 T 恤文胸系列中，这位 27 岁的模特与 2018 年马来西亚环球小姐 Jane Teoh 一起亮相以及泰国女演员兼模特 Janie Tienphosuwan。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该活动标志着该标志性品牌的许多第一，包括首位马来西亚模特在当地活动中担任主角、首位马来穆斯林模特以及首位全马来西亚模特。女性制作团队 – 与马来西亚女性摄影师 (WPM) 社区合作组建。它还将出现在全球维多利亚的秘密商店中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在发布会上接受生活方式杂志 Eh Malaysia 采访时，Nia 表示：“自从我开始模特生涯以来，我一直有一个梦想，成为代言人周二，她还在自己的 Instagram 帐户上发布了发布会的视频汇编，感谢当地的马来西亚人和她曾与美国团队合作过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“老实说，我仍在处理所有事情，目前处于捏我模式，”她补充道。 “十几岁的妮娅不会相信这一点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;奥斯卡奖得主杨紫琼将她的全球视野归功于马来西亚血统&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;过去一周，粉丝和网民对她的帖子进行了大量评论获得了压倒性的支持，并宣称他们为这位年轻模特感到“自豪和高兴”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 Instagram 用户在提到现已停办的维多利亚的秘密时装秀上顶级模特佩戴的奢华翅膀时说道：“迫不及待地想看到有一天你带着[一对]翅膀行走！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;演员尤娜·拉希姆 (Yuna Rahim) 和艾丽西亚·阿明 (Alicia Amin) 等马来西亚名人、主持人阿祖拉·扎纳尔 (Azura Zainal) 和模特梅丽莎·腾 (Melissa Th&#39;ng) 也纷纷插话。恭喜 Nia。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我可以说我现在认识了一位 VS（维多利亚的秘密）模特，”马来西亚嘻哈艺术家 SYA 写道，他的真名是 Nur Batrisya Mohammad Nazri。 “Slayyy mama。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该活动也被称赞为多元化的胜利，Teoh 在 Instagram 帖子中评论说，这“对我们东南亚人来说是一个值得注意的里程碑”，因为来自该地区的模特已经历来在该行业中的代表性不足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很高兴看到我从小观看的品牌......已经采取了更可持续的品牌形象，更具包容性并拥抱多样性，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚维多利亚的秘密以#BeAuthenticBeYou 标签宣传该活动，庆祝“在日常生活的各个方面无畏地拥抱自己个性的女性​​，使她们能够对自己的生活感到自信和舒适” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在预告片中，该品牌将这些模特称为“来自不同背景的三位杰出人才”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但并非所有人都同意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 WPM 在 Instagram 上发布的宣传视频中，最上面的评论讽刺地写道：“所谓‘拥抱个性’，就意味着拥抱他们（三位模特）浅肤色和瘦骨嶙峋的身材，是吗？这就是你所代表的，对吧？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你不代表有色人种，也不代表任何与你外表不同的人。恭喜你达成交易，你的个性得到认可一定很高兴，我相信你很努力才达到这个目标。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样，其他 Instagram 用户也呼吁更多地展示“深色皮肤的[东南部]”亚洲]女性”以及更广泛的“现实体型”，例如大号女性和有“木乃伊肚子”或剖腹产疤痕的女性。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚国会议员因说护士制服也受到猛烈抨击紧身、暴露体型&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;另一个阵营表达了他们对 Nia 作为一名马来穆斯林女性的不满，认为她的形象“太暴露”，违反了伊斯兰教义，伊斯兰教义规定女性身体的某些部位应该被覆盖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 Twitter 用户用英语和马来语混合写道：“她是如此华丽和美丽......但作为一名穆斯林女性本身，她在选择品牌活动时应该更加挑剔。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然有些人同意，但穆斯林同胞也对批评者进行了反击，问道：“当事情发生在她和全能者之间时，为什么你的观点很重要？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了维多利亚的秘密，Nia还曾为Calvin Klein、Louis Vuitton、Dior、Gucci等国际知名品牌做过模特。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文首发于&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Visit by Russian navy chief to submarine academy and Chinese shipyard deemed a sign of military ties getting stronger]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3226932/visit-russian-navy-chief-submarine-academy-and-chinese-shipyard-deemed-sign-military-ties-getting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/a680f833-2295-4751-9c42-27972ef63ad5_f6c1713b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯海军司令尼古拉·叶夫梅诺夫本周高调访华分析人士称，这是“全面战略伙伴”之间军事合作的又一次展示，承诺相互支持彼此的核心利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科国防部称，周一，他会见了中国海军司令，并参观了上海的一家大型造船厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年成为俄罗斯最高海军军官的潜艇专家叶夫梅诺夫参观了中国海军的最新舰艇叶夫梅诺夫此行的部分目的是展示两国之间的伙伴关系，但参观军事设施也表明了更实际的方面符拉迪沃斯托克远东联邦大学区域和国际研究学院研究副主任 Artyom Lukin 表示，两国的军事合作仍然仅限于定期联合演习和战略讨论，与美国及其盟国在亚太地区上演的情况相去甚远，不应被忽视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“自俄罗斯上台以来，俄中军事合作的有形部分并没有增加。”在乌克兰的军事行动，”他说。 “但在幕后、雷达下可能正在发生一些事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，在访问前一周，俄罗斯护卫舰“格罗姆基”号和“索维申尼”号于 6 月 27 日至 29 日沿着台湾东海岸向北然后向南航行。到日本防卫省，显然是在从印度尼西亚科莫多多国军事演习回国的路上。俄罗斯军舰很少驶近台湾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京没有就外国军舰靠近​​其声称拥有领土的岛屿发表声明。相反，中国船员周三在上海举行仪式欢迎俄罗斯军舰，俄罗斯军舰在上海停靠，参加舰队编队、通信和海上救援联合训练。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肖斌中国社会科学院俄罗斯东欧中亚研究所驳斥了俄罗斯可以帮助北京控制台湾的观点，因为北京一再表示可以解决这个问题，不需要外国势力干预。&lt;/ “更有可能的是，俄罗斯舰艇是主动行动，想向中国展示政治支持，或者赢得中国对俄罗斯的支持，”他说。 “它利用军事行动来表达政治立场。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将这个自治岛屿视为一个与大陆统一的分离省份，必要时可以使用武力。大多数国家不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但许多国家反对任何武力夺取台湾的企图。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢金表示，俄罗斯目前不会代表北京就台湾问题发动战争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢金表示，俄罗斯目前不会代表北京就台湾问题发动战争。 >;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯开设习近平意识形态研究中心，这是中国以外的第一个研究中心&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“如果中国甚至不承认克里米亚是俄罗斯主权领土的一部分，[俄罗斯]怎么能这样做呢？”他说。 “即使是俄罗斯与中国结盟的最激进的支持者也不会支持俄罗斯在台湾的军事介入。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于克里米亚和俄罗斯吞并的其他四个乌克兰地区——顿涅茨克、赫尔松、卢甘斯克和俄罗斯是否吞并，中国一直保持沉默。扎波罗热——属于俄罗斯，当被问及其立场时，一再表示尊重所有国家的主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但卢金表示，他不排除莫斯科在外交上支持北京、分享侦察数据或向北京提供帮助&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肖表示，允许叶夫梅诺夫参观沪东中华造船厂及其新舰艇和潜艇，体现了中俄两军之间的高度信任。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;扩建后的造船厂已为中国人民解放军生产了054型护卫舰、075型两栖攻击舰和071型两栖运输船坞舰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肖说，两国之间的军事外交旨在遵循中国国家主席习近平和俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京三月份的会谈引起了人们的关注，当时他们宣布将深化“全面战略协作伙伴关系”——这一称号将俄罗斯置于中国所有其他外交关系之上。&lt;/p>;&lt; “军事合作始终以联演联训为中心，”他说。 “我们可以看到新的训练项目，但中国和俄罗斯长期以来一直在这样做。只是这些联合行动在日韩美亚太联合军演中更加引人注目。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“圣彼得堡清凉一夏”：俄罗斯来了但中国会动摇吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国国防部在一份声明中表示，周一，北京国防部长李克强告诉叶夫梅诺夫，他希望中俄能够定期组织联合演习、巡逻和竞赛，并改善各个层面的沟通。声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当附近举行联合演习时，日本将中国和俄罗斯军队之间不断加强的合作视为对其国家安全的威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本和韩国此前曾紧急升空喷气机作为回应卢金表示，中俄演习仍可发展一些基本的互操作性并实现情报共享。中国有兴趣从俄罗斯获取有关无人机等北约武器在黑海的表现以及北约行动模式的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;访问期间，叶夫梅诺夫还会见了董军海军上将， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月，中国最高军事决策机构中央军委联合参谋部部长刘振立上将与俄罗斯国防部长瓦列里·格拉西莫夫举行视频会议.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt; br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Happy Hong Kong Shopping Festival: from free hamburgers and coffee to grab-all-you-can races, here are some gems worth checking out]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3227004/happy-hong-kong-shopping-festival-free-hamburgers-and-coffee-grab-all-you-can-races-here-are-some?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/9ba580c3-faf3-4be3-8772-387843149db7_9f1af9a0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港各地的零售商正在进行一场吸引顾客的购物活动 - 包括本地人和游客 – 多消费，开心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由香港零售管理协会（HKRMA）牵头的“欢乐香港购物节”已于7月1日正式拉开帷幕，精彩纷呈。 8月31日结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国庆节恰逢财政司司长陈茂波将于7月16日起向居民发放最新一批消费券。预计将为本地经济带来130亿港元的提振，相当于占 5 月份 345 亿港元零售额的近五分之二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从免费咖啡到一分钟疯狂购物和水疗中心折扣，以下是节日的一些亮点。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;财政部长表示，由于出口仍然疲弱，香港经济由本地支出推动&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;食品和饮料&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;“我讨厌我无法选择”：香港人对 7 月 1 日杂货店态度冷淡折扣&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;商店&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;为期两个月的购物节会提振香港零售餐饮业吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;香港零售商推出1.5亿港元折扣，让人们微笑的优惠&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;赢得 PlayStation 5&lt;/h3>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A year after Shinzo Abe’s death, Japan still grappling with how to protect politicians amid ‘lone wolf’ attack fears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3226864/year-after-shinzo-abes-death-japan-still-grappling-how-protect-politicians-amid-lone-wolf-attack?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/fb784cb1-b519-48f5-a637-302b286ba09b_b49bc420.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在日本纪念前首相安倍晋三遇刺一周年之际，政治负责保护高层政治人物的政党和警察仍在努力平衡提供保护和使选民能够与其当选代表互动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安倍晋三在奈良县的一次竞选活动中发表讲话时被枪杀。去年7月8日。继这次袭击之后，今年早些时候又发生了一起事件，4 月 15 日，在日本西部和歌山的一场政治演讲中，现任首相岸田文雄被投掷了一枚管状炸弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岸田没有受伤，但弹片刺穿了墙壁。距装置引爆地点约 60m 的仓库。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安倍的死引发了对政界人士安全的审查，但有迹象表明，岸田正盯上一位急躁的将军，寻找确保他们安全的方法变得更加紧迫今年年底或 2024 年初的选举。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在日本，安倍晋三后安全改革后，人们对“警察权力过大”的担忧加剧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“基本上，保护政客非常困难”，京都龙谷大学犯罪学研究中心主任石冢真一说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“日本是一个政治开放的国家，政治家一直认为有必要自由走动并与选民见面，特别是在他们自己的选区和选举时间，”他说。 “但我担心这种情况现在正在改变。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在战后的几十年里，警察不得不应对来自共产主义组织的政治暴力，这些组织通常与工会、民族主义和黑帮组织有关，Ishizuka &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1960 年 10 月，日本社会党主席浅沼稻二郎在东京的一场电视辩论中遇刺，震惊全国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;山口乙哉，17 岁岁的极端民族主义者，用短剑刺伤了浅沼。他在候审期间自杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1960 年代和 1970 年代的政治暴力主要由极左团体主导，例如在特拉维夫罗德机场屠杀 26 人的日本红军和中华民国组织（中核心派）因为革命性不够而与日本共产党决裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而石冢指出，警察和安全机构在很大程度上能够保护政客和商界领袖，因为他们能够保护政客和商界领袖。监视他们的行动和通讯，并定期接收来自如此大群体内线人的情报泄露。他说，随着“独狼”袭击者的出现，这种情况已经发生了变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在安倍事件和岸田事件中，袭击者都没有犯罪记录，也不是与国家利益相关的人。”之前有警察，”他说。 “他们不是具有政治目的的团体成员，而是心怀不满的独来独往者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这使得警方很难提前了解他们并监控他们在网上的行踪。 ”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本首相会在 G7 成功、改善韩国关系的情况下宣布提前选举吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;安倍被谋杀后，国家警察厅实施了一系列程序上的变化，包括为参加活动的官员和政界人士制定和共享安全计划。看守安倍晋三的警察因在他讲话时未能监控他的背部而受到严厉批评，导致 41 岁失业者山神哲也（Tetsuya Yamagami）靠得足够近，用自制枪向他开枪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; NPA 还扩大了网络巡逻部门，该部门最初是为了监控非法在线毒品交易和儿童色情制品而设立的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他建议包括在室内发表演讲并与公众保持至少 20m 的距离，尽管当岸田遭到袭击时，这些建议都没有被遵循。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，当袭击发生一周后首相出现在同一地点时，旁观者通过金属探测器进行筛查，并检查了他们的行李。警犬也在现场，他在演讲后并没有留下来握手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但有人担心，强化措施仍不足以抵御坚定的“独狼”袭击者，促使NPA 加大行动力度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构将于 8 月开始测试一项试点计划，收集引起当地部队注意或有政治抗议记录的个人信息并共享这些数据设有中央调查总部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我感觉到政治正在成为一种越来越危险的职业，令我惊讶的是攻击安倍晋三和岸田的人都是年轻的孤独者，”教授村上弘美说天普大学东京校区的政治学教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“显然，他们都对国家领导人怀有一种挫败感，但令人担忧的是，警察对他们的不满和他们构成的威胁一无所知，直到他们意识到这一点。”太晚了，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Popular users known for spreading hate and misinformation flock to Threads, testing its ‘positive’ vibe]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227006/popular-users-known-spreading-hate-misinformation-flock-threads-testing-its-positive-vibe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 11:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/14954b36-1033-45f1-868c-7e70f6ee9275_af881596.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;自 Meta Platforms Inc. 于周三推出 Threads 以来，数百万用户已加入新的线程承诺“积极、富有成效的对话”的社交平台——这显然是对 Twitter 和其他网站上常见的分裂言论的猛烈抨击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着该应用程序越来越受欢迎，这一承诺将变得更加难以兑现——它是如此远远吸引了7000万用户。根据彭博社的调查，独立研究人员证实，早期采用者名单中包括一些与其他网站上传播错误信息、虚假信息和仇恨言论有关的用户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中一些用户已经在测试该技术的极限。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们已经看到大量知名账户传播有害信息和信息战略对话研究所美国分部的研究主管 Melanie Smith 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Threads 上的新用户帐户包括极右翼记者 Jack Posobiec，他支持反犹太主义和反犹太主义。白人至上主义观点； YouTube 评论员蒂姆·普尔 (Tim Pool) 被指控传播右翼错误信息； &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着竞争对手 Threads 的崛起，Twitter 威胁要起诉 Meta&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Threads 已开始与一些内置的-针对有害内容的防御机制，因为其用户政策与 Instagram 相同。例如，当人们点击关注过去被标记为传播错误信息的帐户时，Threads 会显示一条警告，询问他们是否确定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta，最大的社交媒体公司，还拥有 Facebook 和Instagram 没有立即回应置评请求，询问其是否知道在其他平台上传播虚假信息或仇恨言论的用户的 Thread 帐户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Posobiec 就是其中之一，已经发布了侮辱性言论Threads 上的变性人并错误地声称，“2020 年的选举被操纵了，每个人都知道。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Raichik，以 Libs of TikTok 用户名，也在新应用程序上针对变性人进行了攻击，并喜欢她的帖子可能会引起争议。 “我喜欢这样一个事实：我在这个应用程序上的存在如此强烈地触发了左派，”她在注册后不久写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至少有一名成员是“虚假信息十二人”（Disinformation Dozen）的成员，该术语用于指代一些关于 Covid-19 及其疫苗的虚假声明的最有影响力的传播者也创建了账户。尽管自 Threads 推出以来，Joseph Mercola 博士尚未发布任何有关疫苗的内容，但他在 Threads 上的帐户已聚集了近 7,000 名关注者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多极右翼新闻媒体也加入了这一行列。应用程序，其中包括 Breitbart News 和 The Gateway Pundit 的经过验证的帐户，但尚未发布太多内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;War Room 的 Threads 帐户，这是由前唐纳德·特朗普顾问在 Real America 的 Voice TV 上运行的节目周四，史蒂夫·班农 (Steve Bannon) 在 Threads 上分享了一段由 Naomi Wolf 主演的视频，后者指控一家著名制药公司在为其 Covid-19 疫苗寻求紧急授权时犯有欺诈行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Meta 瞄准 Twitter，推出了竞争对手应用 Threads&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国营新闻媒体 Sputnik 的几个经过验证的帐户也建立了 Threads 帐户，但大多数尚未发布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta 于周三正式推出 Threads。该平台目前限制用户发现内容的方式。与 Twitter 不同，Threads 上的用户无法搜索特定短语，并且被迫查看由 Meta 算法决定的提要。这意味着受欢迎的用户可能会通过该算法得到广泛的推广。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于 Threads，ISD US 的 Smith 敦促用户谨慎行事。 “这是一款由 Meta 拥有的社交媒体应用程序，Meta 在管理和调节他们拥有的其他平台方面一直失败，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[PM hopeful Pita Limjaroenrat, a Swiftie, welcomes Taylor Swift to Thailand to make up for 2014 cancellation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3227005/thai-pm-hopeful-pita-limjaroenrat-swiftie-welcomes-taylor-swift-kingdom-make-2014-cancellation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 10:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/5378d8b4-7b78-4165-a4b7-3ddb77b37517_7aafc63f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;成为泰国下一任总理的领跑者宣称自己是“Swiftie， ”，并要求泰勒·斯威夫特 (Taylor Swift) 将她的巡演带到该国，距这位美国巨星在军事政变后取消了一场演唱会近十年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯威夫特于 2014 年取消了曼谷演出，当时军政府夺取政权后不久– 在她的泰国粉丝中仍然是一个令人不快的话题，其中许多人居住在泰国首都，Pita Limjaroenrat 的前进党在 5 月 14 日的全国大选中赢得了几乎所有众议院席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“泰国又回到了正轨”这位 42 岁的哈佛大学毕业生表示：“在上次因政变而不得不取消选举后，我们希望走完全民主的道路。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“泰国人民已经通过选举发声了，我们都期待着欢迎您来到我们这个美丽的国家！”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡雨燕在“过山车”般的门票争夺后流下了喜悦的泪水&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但皮塔竞选总理面临着获得冠军的重大障碍参议员们获得了足够的支持——所有参议员都是在 2019 年由军方领导的政府任命的，并且有权在 2024 年初之前与民选下议院一起挑选下一任总理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;皮塔向斯威夫特发出的信息是在加拿大总理贾斯汀·特鲁多和世界各地的其他政治家呼吁这位畅销歌手兼作曲家将在自己国家的音乐会加入到 Eras 巡演中，该巡演有望成为音乐史上票房最高的巡演。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;对于所有泰国“斯威夫特”（斯威夫特歌迷的绰号）来说，这也是关键的一周，他们竞相抢夺当前 Eras 巡回赛的门票，目前新加坡是东南亚唯一一站。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;周三大华银行有限公司预售的六场新加坡演出门票很快被抢购一空，周五一般预售中剩余座位的需求量很大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;结束在过去的九年里，斯威夫特取消的红色巡演演出经常被开玩笑地引用，特别是在民主活动人士和皮塔新兴政党的支持者中，这是现任总理巴育·占奥差(Prayuth Chan-ocha)军事支持的政府最显着的失败之一。领导了 2014 年的政变。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰勒·斯威夫特 (Taylor Swift) 的新加坡演出让马来西亚、泰国和菲律宾粉丝感到沮丧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;皮塔 (Pita) 对斯威夫特的呼吁被转发超过 136,000 次。皮塔表示，如果斯威夫特接受邀请，他将有兴趣与她一起演唱《薰衣草雾霾》，因为这是他七岁女儿最喜欢的歌曲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;皮塔的推文也被视为维持现状的举措。下周将召开议会联席会议并对下一任国家领导人进行投票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议将包括新当选的代表和先前任命的参议员。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 11:20:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘I am amazing’: woman in China with rare condition that blocks movement jubilant after walking 400m against all odds in viral video]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226646/i-am-amazing-woman-china-rare-condition-blocks-movement-jubilant-after-walking-400m-against-all-odds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/2660863d-991f-47a9-a894-b103791214e3_82ffae2a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;步行400米对于大多数人来说可能是小菜一碟，但对于中国女人来说沉琳，重新学习走路是一段漫长而痛苦的旅程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;六年前，沉琳被诊断出患有脊髓小脑性共济失调（SCA），这是一种影响神经系统的罕见疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;据《浙江日报》报道，该病的症状包括跛行、失去平衡、身体运动控制能力差、言语困难以及饮酒时将水吸入呼吸道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的坚持和康复故事已影响数百万人在中国东部浙江省的家附近，她借助助行器试探性迈出一步的视频在大陆社交媒体上引起了关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该视频已获得 40 万个点赞和 3 万条评论，其中大多数人对她的勇气表示赞赏和坚持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我步行回家了。从我的小区门口到我家有400米长的路程。我很了不起！”上月底发布在网上的视频中，沉女士对着镜头自豪地说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在母亲的支持下，沉女士于2020年认真开始康复治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的康复因SCA导致身体失去控制，扭伤了脚踝，接受手术后不得不使用轮椅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，仅仅两个月后，沉女士就可以站立和行走一点了。助行器的帮助和她的康复练习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去的几年里，她每天都在做专门的练习来增强她的肌肉和核心力量平衡训练。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还坚持定期练习英语，以锻炼口腔和舌头肌肉的灵活性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管她说话速度不快，日常言语流畅，但沉女士经常在社交媒体上分享自己练习的视频和解释。媒体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我制作视频是因为我想让别人听到我的声音，并帮助别人了解我过去的经历，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沉说，她觉得自己已经当被告知自己患有这种罕见疾病时，她掉进了又黑又深的水中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我在这深水里游泳了大约两年，但无论我如何努力都无法逃脱，”沉告诉记者浙江日报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的母亲是第一个伸出援手帮助我逃离这个陷阱的人。然后我开始感受到周围人的爱。谢谢你们。你们的爱让我意识到这个世界值得努力停留。”沉说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次是400米。下次是 4000 米，下一次是 40000 米。过不了多久，你就会在街上蹦蹦跳跳了。”一位网友在视频评论区鼓励道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位网友则表示：“姑娘，加油！你会走得更远。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就连官方媒体中央电视台也对沉林表示鼓励，在社交媒体上发帖称：“加油，沉林，你真是太棒了！”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 11:20:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In Australia, a looming mortgage crunch hints at wider economic woes to come: ‘it’s never been this bad’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3226950/australia-looming-mortgage-crunch-hints-wider-economic-woes-come-its-never-been-bad?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/97307384-28d1-4320-9dea-5182d113c9a4_42deea83.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当 49 岁的三个孩子的父亲 Chris* 为他的房子存了押金时2018 年，他的家人在新兴的悉尼郊区埃德蒙森公园 (Edmondson Park) 建造了自己的梦想之家，当时他的抵押贷款利率略高于 3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这套价值 80 万澳元（534,000 美元）的两层房子是按照澳大利亚最昂贵的城市的标准（这里的房价中位数经常超过 100 万澳元）来说，这个城市的房价并不高，而且他发现抵押贷款还款是可以管理的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，快进五年了，抵押贷款也变得可以承受。现在，利率已翻倍，达到 6%，克里斯已经打了两份工作，其中包括兼职物业清洁工，他正在寻找第三份工作，这样他就可以每月额外支付 600 澳元（400 美元）。但即使他找到了，他也表示，除了较高的生活成本之外，这也不足以支付费用，他将被迫动用自己的积蓄。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我主要是对政府感到愤怒，因为他们知道这个问题的根本原因：量化宽松、印钞……这给所有资产类别造成了泡沫，”克里斯说。 “以前利率相对较低，普通人买房时会承担更多债务……但当利率上升时，好时光就结束了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一切都涨价了。这显然影响到了工作人员，而不是已经拥有房屋的百万富翁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有抵押贷款的澳大利亚人现在不得不忍受过去 14 个月内 12 次加息，在他们辛辛苦苦工作的过程中耗尽了他们的财务储备。在新冠疫情之后重建他们的生活和生计，同时还要应对大流行后的通货膨胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生活成本危机在澳大利亚储备银行 (RBA) 周二开会以制定政策时引发了一场抗议。 latest rate decision, and a petition calling for the country&#39;s “Big 4” banks – who have posted record profits this year – to stop passing the interest-rate increases onto ordinary families who are “struggling to afford mortgages or pay rents”, which had garnered nearly 8,000 signatures as of Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;RBA ultimately held off on a 13th rate increase at its Tuesday meeting, on the premise that inflation in Australia has already passed its peak. But the central bank, which has faced criticism for blindsiding the public by reneging on an earlier promise not to put up rates until 2024, did deliver a hawkish warning.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;A property bust in Australia and a boom in Singapore? Look closer&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Some further tightening of monetary policy may be required to ensure that inflation returns to target in a reasonable time frame,” RBA governor Philip Lowe said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the bank began its rate increases in May last year, mortgage rates have shot up from as low as 2 per cent to 6 per cent or more – marking the fastest rise in three decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But like many central banks, the RBA finds itself stuck between a rock and a hard place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his statement, Lowe acknowledged the “painful squeeze” many Australians were feeling on their finances, but emphasised that the bank “remains resolute in its determination to return inflation to target and will do what is necessary to achieve that” using the only real tool at its disposal – interest rates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prime Minister Anthony Albanese&#39;s government has offered childcare subsidies and cheaper medical fees to help out unhappy voters, but from a macroeconomic perspective such handouts can do more harm than good as they act as a stimulus, further contributing to inflation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, after the RBA held rates steady, Albanese faced the public&#39;s wrath in a series of television interviews where he was repeatedly told of the torrent of emails being sent to the networks by ordinary Australians struggling to cope.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Such mortgage stress – the technical term for when homeowners are having difficulties making repayments, or devote more than 30 per cent of their income to servicing the debt – is not unique to Australia, and it sheds light on a wider global economic shift that&#39;s already in motion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This began with the pandemic and the structural changes to supply chains that it triggered, which in turn fuelled inflation and forced up interest rates – causing consumers to tighten their spending and cutting into businesses&#39; bottom lines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Decreased earnings then translated into slower economic activity, leading to downturns, job losses and the possibility of recession – giving rise to added mortgage stress and creating a vicious cycle.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The stress is mounting, but Australia isn&#39;t awash with desperate for-sale signs littering front lawns as was seen in the United States when a subprime mortgage crisis swept the nation, prefiguring the global financial meltdown of 2007-2008.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instead, property listings have tumbled, market data shows, as homeowners hold onto their houses to avoid selling at a time when soft demand is deflating prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unlike in the US, “financial hardship arrangements”, in which banks help out homeowners by providing payment plans, are common in Australia, meaning few get – or want – to walk away from their mortgages by simply handing over the keys.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But this means that behind the scenes, many homeowners are having to scrimp and save, with those like Chris in Australia&#39;s biggest housing market of Sydney telling This Week in Asia that they were dialling back on holidays and dining out. Some even said they&#39;d had to cut back on their children&#39;s education expenses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For those who cannot face the pressure, selling their homes at a loss may be the only option. Such “short-term selling” – offloading a property within two years of taking ownership, despite falling profits – is on the rise, according to property analytics firm CoreLogic Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly one-third of Australian mortgage holders, or about 1.43 million people, are currently facing mortgage stress, market research company Roy Morgan said on Tuesday – the highest level in a decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This was backed up by the latest consumer survey from property comparison website Finder&#39;s, with about 41 per cent of respondents admitting that they struggled to repay their home loan in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Higher interest rates will cause pain in Asian property but no crisis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Homeowners elsewhere in the world don&#39;t have it much better, either, against a backdrop of persistent inflation and rapid rate increases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the US, mortgage applications have been falling, leading Federal Reserve chief Jerome Powell to say last month that the central bank now sees “housing putting in a bottom”, adding: “We&#39;re watching that situation carefully”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Borrowers in Britain, like those in Australia, are nearing what&#39;s been termed a “mortgage cliff”, as fixed-rate mortgages taken out for limited terms reach renewal, lumping homeowners with new repayment schedules and rates that are double or triple what they were only a couple of years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The Japanese housing bubble that isn&#39;t&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Much of Asia has yet to feel the pain of skyrocketing mortgage payments, particularly in places like Japan where inflation is hovering around a relatively modest 3 per cent and the benchmark interest rate has been held at -0.1 per cent since the central bank first took it below zero in 2016. Homeowners in the region are also more likely than those in the West to make larger down payments on their houses or pay for them outright.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Australia, many people own property as an investment, due to mortgages being available to borrowers for an upfront deposit of as little as 5 per cent of the unit&#39;s value, and investor-friendly policies such as “negative gearing” – or using borrowed money to buy an income-producing but ultimately loss-making asset, such as a rental property, to claim tax deductions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Household debt in Australia stood at 211 per cent of net disposable income in 2021, according to OECD data, making it the highest in the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On the surface, low rates of defaults and delinquencies – or the nonpayment of debts – paint a picture of relative calm in Australia&#39;s housing market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prime home loans – those with the lowest rates offered by banks to their lowest-risk customers – that were 30 days in arrears rose to 1.26 per cent in March from 1.05 per cent in December, according to a Moody&#39;s Investors Service report released on Wednesday, while arrears for nonconforming mortgages – loans to borrowers with adverse credit histories – rose to 4.04 per cent from 3.35 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These number may be “small” but that&#39;s how the banks designed it, so that they don&#39;t have large arrears devaluing their loan books, according to Martin North, founding principal of Australian market researcher Digital Finance Analytics (DFA), who said that about 65 per cent of banks&#39; balance sheets in Australia were tied up in mortgages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So while people are staring at low default rates, in fact there is a fair amount of stress, and that stress doesn&#39;t have to be in the shape of absolute destitution but rather cutting back, changing spending habits,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Delinquencies will follow, but for now the banks are &#39;extending and pretending&#39; by offering longer-term refinancing, interest-only [mortgages] and other measures.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anecdotally, one professional couple who did not want to be named told This Week in Asia that they were about to cut a deal with their bank to only pay the interest on the mortgage they took out for a A$1.4 million (US$935,000) beachside town house in the Maroubra suburb of Sydney last year – easing the current strain on their wallets at the cost of a longer, more expensive repayment schedule.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;North said delinquency rates were not necessarily the best gauge of looming market troubles, with his firm&#39;s own tracker of household debt versus income in a rolling sample of 52,000 households revealing a leap in the proportion of mortgage-stressed households to about 50 percent today from just over 30 per cent in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It has never been this bad. Rates will rise further, more people will decide to sell, but the rental sector is so tight, that I think many will try to hunker down and spend less – and the main impact will be on retail spending which is 60 per cent of the economy,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mortgage broker Dion Villiers said he was most worried about the impact that high interest rates would have on jobs, the availability of affordable housing and the economy as a whole.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It&#39;s particularly acute for small employers like one of his clients, a truck driver in Sydney&#39;s Bankstown suburb, who is struggling with mortgage payments on two houses after his earnings retreated on the back of rising fuel costs, insurance expenses and fewer customers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He&#39;s calling two to three times a day,” Villiers said. “Small business owners will have to start laying people off.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spike in unemployment poses the biggest threat, according to Louis Christopher, managing director of property analytics firm SQM Research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In this country, it&#39;s very much the case that people&#39;s houses are the very last thing to go … all the discretionary activity generally goes before the house goes,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But that&#39;s what creates the recession, because you have a slowdown in spending … and that&#39;s where you start to see a rise in unemployment [followed by home foreclosures].”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the tightrope that the RBA has to walk, and governor Lowe, in his statement on Tuesday, alluded to an “uncertainty surrounding the economic outlook”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The impact on spending is already being felt at Michael&#39;s* Asian-fusion restaurant Goji in the west of Sydney.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turnover has fallen by A$20,000 (US$13,350) a week for the past few months, he said, while his own mortgage payments have risen by A$5,000 a month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To remain open and keep all his 70 employees, Michael said he had to cut back on having “nice things”. He said his dinner service was doing well but the number of lunch patrons had dropped, as This Week in Asia saw on a tour of the restaurant on a recent quiet Friday afternoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many are making sandwiches at home,” he said, adding that some neighbouring restaurants were now considering selling up and moving on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is one silver lining, according to Villiers, who said many homeowners had saved up over the pandemic and would be able to sustain themselves until interest rates go back down.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its Financial Stability Review in April, the RBA itself said it was confident that “continued strength in the labour market and sizeable savings buffers” would protect Australians from the worst effects of higher interest rates – although it acknowledged “this resilience is unevenly spread”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s savings glut is no guarantee of recovery via &#39;revenge spending&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But for Diana Mousina, a senior economist at financial services company AMP, the central bank is being too optimistic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recent borrowers, those who took out loans between 2020 and mid-2022, have had precious little time or opportunity to save, she said in a March note.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These households have not had time to build prepayment buffers, have faced large declines in home prices, have had a very fast repricing of mortgage rates, are more likely to have taken out larger loans and were probably not stress-tested for the current increase in interest rates,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We think that the downside risks to the household sector are greater than the Reserve Bank is estimating.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;*Full name withheld at interviewee&#39;s request&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Grow old in Hong Kong’: global movie icon Chow Yun-fat tells of love for home city and its ‘charming and arrogant’ Cantonese dialect, thrills fans]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3226645/grow-old-hong-kong-global-movie-icon-chow-yun-fat-tells-love-home-city-and-its-charming-and-arrogant?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/07/7aef98f8-540a-4cae-9217-2521ffa259d6_c1bcb45a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;World-renowned Hong Kong superstar Chow Yun-fat has voiced his deep affection for his home city and its distinct “charming and arrogant” Cantonese dialect in an interview on YouTube.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Media outlet HK01 reported that the film legend made the remarks in a new episode of the YouTube programme Shu Shu De Ai (Uncle&#39;s Love).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chow&#39;s iconic status and illustrious career extends far beyond Hong Kong, with his notable performance in Ang Lee&#39;s Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon resonating internationally. The film made history in 2001 as the first Chinese-language film to win an Oscar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His collaboration with Johnny Depp in Pirates of the Caribbean: At World&#39;s End amassed more than US$963 million worldwide, crowning it the box office winner of 2007.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chow is also admired beyond the silver screen, for his philanthropic endeavours and approachable demeanour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a 2018 interview with Hong Kong film website JayneStars, Chow shared his plans to donate his entire wealth – a staggering HK$5.6 billion (US$716 million) – to charity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He is also known as the “King of Selfies” because of his willing embrace of selfie requests from fans, something he describes as a personal “social responsibility” in the YouTube show.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hongkongers feel that since Chow Yun-fat enjoys taking selfies with people, not taking a selfie with him when you see him would seem to be a loss of face. This has somehow become a social responsibility for me,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The YouTube interview also covered the recent trend among Hong Kong residents to migrate elsewhere, with Chow reaffirming his deep affection for the city and its distinctive language.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many people have forgotten the beautiful scenery in Hong Kong. I grew up on Lamma Island and have a deep affection for the local culture. I don&#39;t see the need to live anywhere else. It&#39;s great to grow old in Hong Kong,” Chow said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cantonese has a feeling of intimacy. Nowadays, many children start learning English from kindergarten and don&#39;t know how to speak Cantonese, which I find a bit pitiful. Cantonese has a rhythmic charm, which is tricky and arrogant,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The interview has delighted many of Chow&#39;s fans worldwide, with a number taking to social media to echo his views.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Comments such as “Hong Kong&#39;s scenery is uniquely beautiful” and “Cantonese sounds really pleasant” were left by numerous people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is not the first time Chow has expressed his love for Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2021, he recalled his decades-long career and credited the city for his achievements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking at Hong Kong Baptist University, where he was accepting an honorary Humanities doctorate, Chow said that “every movie role is challenging”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I was forced to learn and make an effort as I needed to earn a living. So I thank Hong Kong people for their encouragement, tolerance and love,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thank you Hong Kong for giving me so much knowledge, patience and love.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A ‘happy’ Hong Kong campaign is not enough to tackle increasing rates of depression among residents, experts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3226976/happy-hong-kong-campaign-not-enough-tackle-increasing-rates-depression-among-residents-experts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/07/f961e611-4b1a-4b11-a62f-cdcc0f639265_73240b27.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong needs more than a “happy” campaign to tackle the increasing rates of depression among residents, experts have said, as official data showed a 20 per cent increase in patients with the disorder at public hospitals over the past five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The risks of the illness were starkly underlined by the death of pop star Coco Lee on Wednesday following her suicide attempt on Sunday. Her family confirmed she was diagnosed with depression years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the same day Lee died, a 42-year-old woman was placed on probation after the court found she had killed her 16-day-old baby under the influence of post-partum depression.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong diva Coco Lee dies; &#39;her rays of light will last forever,&#39; sisters say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“How can the government make the overall atmosphere in Hong Kong better?” asked Professor Paul Yip Siu-fai, director of the University of Hong Kong&#39;s Centre for Suicide Research and Prevention, on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The Happy Hong Kong campaign] is of course better than nothing … But these are all temporary … in the long run, the government should take note of how to make Hong Kong a happy place.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government launched the campaign in April in a bid to raise the spirits of residents after three years of disruptions to daily life caused by the Covid-19 pandemic. But Yip said the perks and activities of the campaign would not tackle the root of the problem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu said progress had been made on most of the key performance indicators he set for his first year in office, many of them aimed at improving the lives of residents, but Yip questioned whether the policies had already addressed basic needs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If there are still so many problems after completing 10 tasks, that means that the strategies are not addressing public concerns,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official data released in May showed the number of patients diagnosed with depression and receiving treatment at facilities under the Hospital Authority had increased by 19 per cent in the past five years, rising from 56,100 to 66,800 in 2022-23.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Psychiatrist Dr Chan Chung-mau, chairman of the Association for the Promotion of Mental Health, said the social unrest of 2019, together with Covid-19, had worsened the mental health of residents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“All emotional issues are linked with stress,” Chan said “When your stress is larger and lasts for a longer time, your chance of developing depression or anxiety will be higher.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dr May Lam Mei-ling, founder and president of the Hong Kong Mental Wellness Association, said she had witnessed a roughly 20 per cent increase in the number of people with depression or anxiety coming to her clinic in the past two to three years, compared with before the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Coco Lee tragedy a cry to fight cruellest of illnesses&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The situation in Hong Kong was in line with a global prediction by the World Health Organization that depression would be the leading disease burden in high-income countries by 2030. Globally, an estimated 5 per cent of adults suffer from depression.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Everyone has feelings of being happy, unhappy or anxious,” Lam said. “But if the symptoms become serious and persistently affect us, it could be clinical depression.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A wide range of symptoms could be a sign of depression, from being upset, crying constantly, experiencing difficulty sleeping and entertaining suicidal thoughts, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam added that people with these symptoms could first try reaching out to friends and family, or adopt a healthier lifestyle by ensuring they slept enough, ate a balanced diet and exercised.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If [the signs and symptoms] persist for more than two weeks, you should consider taking professional help – talking to a counsellor, social worker, psychologist or psychiatrist – so that you have a comprehensive assessment and a proper intervention,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Cycle of pain&#39;: plight of Hong Kong&#39;s ethnic minority women in focus after tragedy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On a personal level, psychiatrist Chan said a range of positive habits could help prevent depression, such as exercising at least three times a week, maintaining social activities, and avoiding cigarettes, alcohol, drugs and junk food.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Getting enough sunlight was also important, as it encouraged the production of endorphins, a hormone linked to happiness, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you have suicidal thoughts, or you know someone who is, help is available.对于香港，请拨打 +852 2896 0000 联系撒玛利亚人，或拨打 +852 2382 0000 联系预防自杀服务。 In the US, call the 988 Suicide &amp; Crisis Lifeline at 988 or +1 800 273 8255. For a list of other nations&#39; helplines, see this .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Huawei taps into computing power shortage in China, touts self-developed AI tech amid ChatGPT craze]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226981/huawei-taps-computing-power-shortage-china-touts-self-developed-ai-tech-amid-chatgpt-craze?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/07/f7d643d7-2134-41b7-8da5-0902b29a6f33_2f0ecccf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese tech giant Huawei Technologies has launched a new version of its artificial intelligence (AI) model, powered by in-house processors that it hopes will provide much-needed computing power in a country struggling to get hold of advanced American AI chips to satisfy its hunger for ChatGPT-style services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At its cloud developer conference in southern China&#39;s Dongguan city on Friday, Huawei unveiled the 3.0 version of its Pangu AI model, with a sharpened focus on industrial uses in various sectors including coal mines, finance and government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shenzhen-based company said it wants to help clients build and train their own AI models with its self-developed Ascend AI processors and AI framework MindSpore – the underlying technology supporting Pangu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The computing power in China can hardly keep up with the surging demand, as many companies are paying high prices to get Nvidia graphics processing units, with a long lead time,” Zhang Pingan, CEO of Huawei Cloud, said at a media briefing after the launch. “We hope to offer an alternative in terms of AI computing power.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington imposed new export restrictions last August that block Chinese companies from buying the most advanced AI chips from US semiconductor suppliers Advanced Micro Devices and Nvidia. The latter holds a near monopoly on GPUs used to train AI systems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s AI ambitions are facing a fresh blow as the US government looks into curbing Chinese companies&#39; access to American cloud computing services, which would bar mainland clients from using the power of advanced AI chips offered by the likes of Amazon Web Services and Microsoft, according to a The Wall Street Journal report earlier this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huawei itself is currently on a US trade blacklist that bans the company from buying technology from American businesses without government approval. Zhang said Huawei will have to survive on its self-developed technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While others can use the most mature GPUs and software in the industry, Huawei will need to rely on our own fundamental AI technology,” he said at the conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huawei said its Ascend AI cluster can achieve training efficiency that is 1.1 times higher than mainstream GPUs in the industry. It did not elaborate on the benchmark used for comparing its technology against rivals&#39;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest version of Huawei&#39;s Pangu model is set to heat up the AI race among China&#39;s Big Tech firms, which have launched around 80 models so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese internet search giant Baidu in March became the first major Chinese tech firm to launch a ChatGPT challenger, called Ernie Bot, with plans to integrate its AI model in cloud and other enterprise services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Group Holding, owner of the South China Morning Post, in April introduced the Tongyi Qianwen chatbot, which it aims to merge with all of the company&#39;s product offerings, CEO Daniel Zhang Yong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In contrast to other Chinese tech giants, Huawei has played down any comparison between Pangu and ChatGPT, stressing that it only targets enterprise clients.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our Pangu AI model will not write poems; we only do business. We will take root in industries and bring value to them,” Huawei Cloud CEO Zhang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huawei has been doubling down on its enterprise business as it seeks new revenue streams after US trade sanctions hobbled its once lucrative smartphone business.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huawei launched the first version of Pangu in 2021 and has been applying it to various industries, such as helping detect abnormalities in underground mines and identifying faults in railways and freight cars. Huawei Cloud said its AI technology has been implemented in more than 1,000 projects in different industries, including eight coal mines.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 08:20:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>