<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s old Kai Tak Airport closes: ‘We’ll miss you’ - from the SCMP archive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3226610/hong-kongs-old-kai-tak-airport-closes-well-miss-you-scmp-archive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/2832c93b-a8e2-4fe6-ba03-9c4dfc9e4b90_3420aa47.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;作者：Rachel Clarke&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凯的灯光熄灭了今天早上 1 点 16 分，启德机场 73 年的历史就此结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“再见启德，谢谢你”，民航总监理查德·西格尔 (Richard Siegel) 在按下开关之前说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;灯光熄灭后，数百人通宵达旦地进行了 13 个小时的紧张作业，将最后一批设备运至 35 公里外的赤鱲角新机场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后一位从启德起飞的飞行员是 51 岁的 Kim Sharman，这是他退休前的最后一次飞行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“几天前我最后一次来这里，所有的怀旧和回忆沙曼先生说，他乘坐 CX251 航班飞往伦敦，于午夜过后两分钟起飞。他已在启德降落约 4,000 次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为最后一位离开启德的飞行员将使我载入史册，这对我的职业生涯来说是一个美好的结局。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政务司司长行政部门陈方安生和财政司司长曾荫权看着跑道变黑。他们将于今早抵达赤鱲角，迎接首日使用机场的 7 万名乘客中的第一批乘客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从重庆起飞的港龙航空 KA841 是最后一架完成惊人 47 度翻转的飞机九龙城将于晚上 11 点 38 分降落在 13 号跑道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这架飞机和其他 30 架通常会停放过夜的飞机随后短途飞往赤鱲角，赤鱲角原定于上午 6 点 30 分开放。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首架预计将由国泰航空从纽约出发的破纪录直达航班抵达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他设备将通过卡车和驳船以军事方式运输让新机场按时开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一整天，人们的情绪高涨，数百名最后一次漫步在启德客运大楼的人们，其中包括许多过去的工人，庆祝中夹杂着悲伤。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“收到，启德，我们会想念你的”，一位澳大利亚机长是最后一批飞出机场的机长之一，他通过无线电向塔台报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;太古集团主席 Peter Sutch 表示，他于 1970 年 1 月 2 日开始了自己的国泰航空职业生涯，当时是出发大厅的实习值机职员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“启德是这样一个地方，因为它基本上设施不足，鼓励在这里工作的员工更加努力地提供优质服务，并营造出一种家庭氛围。”他说。 “赤鱲角的规模和空间都需要人情味，我希望在这里工作的人能够接受这一点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管国泰航空制定了将香港发展成为“超级枢纽”的宏伟计划在赤鱲角，萨奇先生承认，看到旧机场被拆除，他感到很难过。当被问及一周前最后一次飞来时，他是否感到喉咙有肿块或眼睛里有泪水，他回答说：“这听起来很感伤，但确实如此。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警察在出发大厅游行中午12.30左右，催促游客最后一次离开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出乎意料的晴朗天气吸引了大量人群涌上九龙城的天台，居民和游客希望最后一次近距离观看低空俯冲的客机。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;整个搬迁工作还需要 30 天才能完成，即便如此，启德周围的许多建筑物仍将使用，包括国泰航空总部，员工将在那里呆到 9 月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;整个搬迁工作还需要 30 天才能完成。 p>;&lt;p>;今天早上，对于生活在旧航线下的数千人来说，这是第一次没有喷气式飞机的轰鸣声，他们的心情很复杂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我一开始就讨厌这种噪音，但现在我要错过飞机了。”与家人在打鼓岭路启德对面居住了 10 年的吴丽华 (Ng Lai-wah) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当最后一趟航班从启德起飞后，国泰航空的 31 号和 32 号登机口最后一次关闭，国泰航空员工欢呼雀跃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共有 385 名乘客和 21 名机组人员登上 CX251 飞往伦敦 - 首批飞往伦敦的城市之一。从启德出发，也是最后一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于船上的一些人来说，这是最后一次离开启德 - 其他人只是期待成为历史的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;太古集团主席苏奇及经济局局长叶澍琨到场祝愿乘客旅途愉快，而民航处处长理查德·西格尔则派发纪念镇纸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿德莱德与妻子金 (Kim) 和女儿凯特 (Kate) 一起旅行，他说他选择这趟航班只是因为这是凯特学校假期开始后最方便的出发航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们尝试登机的话这个航班，这可能是不可能的，但我们在二月份预订时并不知道会发生这种情况，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但这很棒，我们会喝点饮料庆祝。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位更悲伤的旅客是前香港居民西蒙·洛吉(Simon Logie)，他转乘较早的航班以获得靠过道的座位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我知道的话，我会留在飞机上。如果能得到一个镇纸并成为历史的一部分，那就太好了。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乘客格雷厄姆·罗伯茨 (Graham Roberts) 说：“47 度转弯有一些特别之处，但我想是时候继续前进了。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧阳莎金娜对所有的兴奋感到困惑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[启德]是一个非常普通的机场。我只是期待着进入新的飞机。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首席乘务长关国云承诺，整个飞行过程中都会有香槟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这很令人兴奋放在最后一班航班上。我会想念启德。我在这里工作了 32 年，但我仍然喜欢这个着陆点。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Final Ariane 5 rocket blasts off amid Europe rocket crisis]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226705/final-ariane-5-rocket-blasts-amid-europe-rocket-crisis?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 07:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/06/efe44e93-6305-40e0-a441-42bc1227d928_28253bfb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧洲主力阿丽亚娜 5 号火箭周三最后一次发射，告别经过 27 年的发射，欧洲航天事业正处于困难时期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;面对日益激烈的全球竞争，欧洲大陆出人意料地发现，由于发射延误，自己无法独立向太空发射重型任务。下一代阿丽亚娜 6 号和俄罗斯撤回火箭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿丽亚娜 5 号火箭的第 117 次也是最后一次飞行于周三晚上 7 点左右从法属圭亚那库鲁的欧洲航天港进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;发射已被推迟两次。原定于 6 月 16 日发射，但由于火箭助推器中的烟火线出现问题而被取消，此后烟火线已被更换。计划于周二进行的另一次发射由于恶劣天气而推迟了一天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿丽亚娜 5 号的最终有效载荷是一颗法国军用通信卫星和一颗德国通信卫星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marie-圭亚那航天中心主任安妮·克莱尔 (Anne Clair) 表示，阿丽亚娜 5 号的最后一次飞行对库鲁的团队来说“充满了情感”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 尽管阿丽亚娜 5 号将成为一枚可靠的火箭，但它的起步并不顺利。 1996 年，它的首次飞行在升空后不久就发生了爆炸。它唯一的一次此类失败发生在 2002 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时在阿丽亚娜 5 号上工作的工程师埃尔维·吉利伯特 (Herve Gilibert) 表示，2002 年的爆炸是“ “痛苦的经历”“给我们留下了深刻的印象”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但火箭最终将进行一连串的成功发射。吉利伯特说，最初的失误“产生了积极的影响，让我们保持绝对警惕”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;木星上有生命吗？欧洲探测器出发检查行星及其卫星&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;阿丽亚娜 5 号因其可靠性而享有盛誉，美国宇航局相信它会在 2021 年底发射价值 100 亿美元的詹姆斯·韦伯太空望远镜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该火箭的倒数第二次发射是在今年 4 月，对欧洲航天局的 Juice 航天器进行了爆炸，该航天器正在探索木星的冰冷卫星是否可以容纳外星生命。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧洲航天局太空运输负责人丹尼尔·诺伊恩施万德 (Daniel Neuenschwander)表示，从商业角度来说，阿丽亚娜 5 号一直是“欧洲太空活动的先锋”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该火箭能够承载比其前身阿丽亚娜 4 号大得多的载荷，为欧洲带来竞争优势，并允许&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在等待阿丽亚娜 6 号（其首次发射最初计划于 2020 年）期间，欧洲一直依靠俄罗斯的联盟号火箭将重型任务送入太空。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但俄罗斯取消了与欧洲的太空合作，以回应莫斯科于 2022 年 2 月入侵乌克兰而实施的制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;库鲁的发射次数从 2021 年的 15 次减少到去年的 6 次&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;12月，又一次打击到来，下一代Vega C轻型发射器的首次商业飞行失败。上周，Vega C 的发动机发现了另一个问题，可能会进一步推迟其重返太空的时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Vega-C 火箭故障后，欧洲进入太空的机会处于危险之中&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;发射器亿万富翁埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 的美国公司 SpaceX 日益占据市场主导地位，该公司的火箭现在每周发射一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于缺乏其他选择，欧空局被迫转向竞争对手 SpaceX 的猎鹰 9 号火箭来成功发射火箭。周六将发射欧几里得太空望远镜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧空局还将使用 SpaceX 火箭发射地球保护观测任务的卫星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚该机构将如何发射下一轮卫星欧盟伽利略全球导航系统的卫星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在本月早些时候的巴黎航展上，欧空局局长约瑟夫·阿施巴赫承认这是“困难时期”，并补充说每个人都在“加紧工作”以获取阿丽亚娜6 和 Vega-C 已准备就绪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿丽亚娜 6 本月早些时候在库鲁的发射台上亮相，随后对其 Vulcain 2.1 火箭发动机进行点火测试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因为新火箭需要更少的人员配备和维护，库鲁航天港 1,600 个职位中的 190 个将被裁减。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China to speed up infrastructure projects to shore up growth, amid call to ‘determine scale’ of debt]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3226660/china-speed-infrastructure-projects-shore-growth-amid-call-determine-scale-debt?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/bc6b2456-f2a5-4024-aa7c-d7d1eca5a537_d4f8c57a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在国家立法机关的号召下，中国将加快新债发行以支撑经济增长财政部表示，根据2022年预算，将监督并加快地方政府债券发行财政部长刘昆向最高立法机关提交的报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据上周的报告副本，刘昆表示，截至 5 月底，已发行了 2.25 万亿元人民币（3,110 亿美元）的新债券周二发表的讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“充分发挥政府投资的引导作用，适当扩大地方政府专项债券投资范围和项目资本金范围刘说：“做好项目准备，提高项目储备质量，优先支持成熟项目和在建项目。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在中国地方政府偿还债务困难的情况下，北京是否应该出手相助？ ？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他补充说，将努力防止“盲目”扩张投资，并吸引更多民间资本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘还承诺“严格”地方政府监管财政部将“曝光”违反债务规则的当局，以“警告”和“阻止”此类行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该声明发布之际，人们对地方政府债务可持续性的担忧日益加剧。升至历史新高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国人大财经委员会对预算报告作出回应，呼吁采取措施“科学确定国家中长期经济发展规模”。长期负债。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;从GDP到人民币：7月中国经济值得关注的4件事&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国经济复苏慢于预期，房地产市场低迷，也给地方政府财政带来了压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年第二季度，100个城市的土地出让额仅为2019年水平的65%，而一季度为84%，麦格理集团表示，地方政府面临压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，据民生证券周二称，2020 年至 2022 年间，地方政府债务平均每年增加 10 万亿元人民币（1.38 万亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;到2022年底，债务总额已比2015年增长2.6倍，超过90万亿元，券商补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;是否会有更多中国陷入困境的国有企业寻求长期融资？定期债务重组？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京已要求地方政府遏制所谓的隐性债务，这些债务主要来自地方政府金融平台（LGFV）的表外借款，但带有隐性政府担保。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;北京于 2015 年推出了特殊用途债券，以鼓励预算内贷款，尽管它们只占基础设施支出所需借款的一小部分，这意味着地方政府融资平台仍然是首选平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有关于中国隐性债务规模的官方数据，但分析师估计可能在 30 万亿元至 50 万亿元之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但中国国家审计署上周报告称，去年，数十个地区和地方政府夸大了财政收入，增加了隐性债务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国评级机构穆迪周一表示，调查结果反映出地方政府，特别是下级政府面临的财政压力越来越大。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国如何化解债务泡沫，前景如何？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;内蒙古自治区北部城市乌兰察布是最新一个公开表示正在消除债务泡沫的地方政府。实现未来10年减债目标面临困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市政府上周在其微信公众号上表示，“仅依靠财政措施来守住底线是不可持续的”，并且实现债务抑制目标的“渠道越来越少”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，地方官员并没有做出太多努力来寻找解决问题的方法，尽管中国最大的社交平台上的帖子已经&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国人大财经委员会副主任石耀斌表示，隐性债务仍然堆积如山，地方政府财政纪律执行不严格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“结合对经济发展趋势和地区财政收支的跟踪研判，科学确定我国中长期地方政府债务规模和分地区债务限额水平。”周回应财政部预算报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“进一步加强市场化、法治化的债务违约机制建设。推动地方政府向全国人大报告债务。”时任全国人大常委会预算工作委员会主任的石补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时也有人呼吁中央政府分配财政资源来偿还债务。光大证券首席宏观经济学家高瑞东认为，部分地方政府融资平台债务并发行政府债券来偿还或置换地方政府融资平台债务，可能性很小。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“首先，实施的紧迫性债券大规模置换的力度不强。其次，从中央政府的表态来看，提供援助的意愿不高，这项措施的推出也遇到了相当大的阻力，”高先生周二表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前很难通过财政资金、处置国有资产、各地降息等方式彻底消除隐性债务。地方政府融资平台的市场化转型是减少债务的最终出路。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前财政部长楼继伟3月表示，认为隐性债务问题源于北京推动耗资巨大的基础设施项目的观点并不准确。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“地方政府的负担确实很大，但通过大规模的中央转移支付，地方财力是充足的。”楼在知名人士主编的《笔教》杂志上写道。中国经济学家吴敬琏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;楼继伟表示，一些地方政府希望通过过度举债来争取更高的增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经济已经转向实现高速增长。” ——高质量增长，这种模式弊大于利。除了有效遏制地方政府隐性债务上升、积极化解现存债务问题外，还需要在事权划分和支出责任上进行根本性改革。”楼继伟补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong golf course vs housing debate is really about fair use of land]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3226541/hong-kong-golf-course-vs-housing-debate-really-about-fair-use-land?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/7a83643e-c8a6-4cca-b674-b46625257869_c363a102.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;讨论亚洲第二古老的高尔夫球场所在的 32 公顷精心修剪的土地的命运建于 1911 年的香港高尔夫球会已变得炙手可热，政府批给香港高尔夫球会的租约将于 8 月底到期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这个人口稠密、土地稀缺的城市，对经济适用房的需求日益旺盛。从未如此紧迫，政府决定更好地利用土地，而不是让特权精英独享，这是正确的决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将收回的粉岭老球场，涉及 18 座球场中的 8 座。公共住房指定面积约 9 公顷，位于北部地区，总体平坦，生态问题最不敏感，无需进行大规模场地平整。香港高尔夫球会目前在该地区经营三个18洞球场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府的决定符合其提供公共房屋的策略目标。但正如最近结束的城市规划听证会所指出的，绝大多数提交的公众意见不同意粉岭住房计划，理由是担心随之而来的高尔夫球场和锦标赛场地的丧失，以及对保护和环境的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;为了更准确地了解粉岭住房计划，丹拿山工作室发起了一项社交媒体情绪研究。这项使用关键词的研究由分析机构Datago于5月1日至6月12日进行。它返回了40个帖子和2,257条相关评论，其中70%来自Facebook，18%和8%分别来自Lihkg和HK论坛讨论。分析显示，超过一半的人支持政府的决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，在过去两周里，我对来自不同行业的人士进行了 20 次非正式但结构化的面对面采访。一半人对土地是否应该用于住房持中立态度，六人支持这一提议。总体而言，人们普遍认为当前的安排是历史遗产，其基础是不平等地获得公共土地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任何公共资助的场所都应该开放供公众享用，例如我们的维多利亚公园，而私人会所使用场地时应支付市场租金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据我们所知，香港农田的租金每平方英尺可达1至10港元，视乎地点而定。这意味着香港高尔夫球会的公平市场租金应从每年3,840万港元起，而不是目前每年支付的地租和差饷8至900万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们相信政府应恢复对 32 公顷高尔夫球场的控制，以优化土地利用并解决社会真实或想象的看法。政府完全有权利不续签租约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，这个问题并不需要被如此有争议地看待。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该地区的独特品质源于其高尔夫遗产和其南部地区的生态价值，其保护已列入宪报规划。当该地区恢复政府完全控制时，有两个选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是坚持12,000套公共住房的计划。或者，保留高尔夫球场的八个洞并向公众开放打高尔夫球。不建造住房，而是建造训练设施和小食亭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在后一种情况下，政府可以与香港高尔夫球会或其他有资格的机构合作或委派管理合同，以确保旧球场的使用大部分时间对公众开放，并在必要时关闭国际高尔夫赛事。这样，粉岭高尔夫球场就可以继续参加香港公开赛和其他亚洲巡回赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;兴建公屋或保留粉岭高尔夫球场并非二选一&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;已添加到我们的选择乡议局最近提出在平岗村占地8.5公顷的土地上兴建超过12,000个单位的建议。库克强调，该提案并不是要替代政府的计划。应研究以研究为基础的建议，以补充（如果不是取代）原有的政府公共住房计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在政府土地上提供经济适用房的政策目标值得赞扬。让善意找到最好的落实路径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，要加大承办香港有优势的国际体育赛事力度。对于我们的专业人才来说，利用现有资源为国际锦标赛重新配置 18 洞比赛球场不应该是一项艰巨的任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;让我们齐心协力，找出基于证据的可行解决方案研究改善香港的土地利用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Meta takes aim at Twitter with the launch of rival app Threads]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226704/meta-takes-aim-twitter-launch-rival-app-threads?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 07:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/06/6cef84b7-7790-4abc-841c-f8fb96eab9ee_bcacfae1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Meta 于周四推出了一款与 Twitter 竞争的应用程序，目标似乎是寻找搜索引擎的用户埃隆·马斯克拥有且经常更换的社交媒体平台的替代品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新产品名为 Threads，被宣传为 Meta 的照片共享应用程序 Instagram 的基于文本的版本，该公司称该应用程序提供“一个用于实时更新和公共对话的新的独立空间”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该应用程序于周三午夜过后在英国的 Apple 和 Google Android 应用程序商店中上线，该应用程序遍布美国、英国等 100 多个国家/地区、澳大利亚、加拿大和日本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据向媒体提供的截图，用户将获得类似 Twitter 的微博体验，这表明在马斯克的所有权混乱导致 Meta Platforms 一直在准备直接挑战该平台一系列不受欢迎的变化使用户和广告商失去了兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有一些按钮可以点赞、转发或引用“帖子”，还有计数器显示帖子收到的点赞和回复数量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司表示：“我们的愿景是，Threads 将成为一款更加专注于文本和对话的新应用程序，效仿 Instagram 在照片和视频方面所做的工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帖子是限制为 500 个字符，超过 Twitter 的 280 个字符阈值，并且可以包含最长五分钟的链接、照片和视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instagram 用户将能够使用现有用户名登录并关注新应用程序上的相同帐户。新用户必须建立一个 Instagram 帐户。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚，Meta 致力于从 Facebook、Instagram 上删除“不良内容”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meta 强调了确保用户安全的措施，包括强制执行Instagram 的社区准则并提供工具来控制谁可以提及或回复用户。然而，该公司的新产品引发了数据隐私问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;线程可以收集广泛的个人信息，包括健康、财务、联系人、浏览和搜索历史记录、位置数据、购买和“敏感信息” ”，根据其在 App Store 上的数据隐私披露。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Twitter 联合创始人 Jack Dorsey 在一条尖刻的推文中指出，“你所有的话题都属于我们”，其中还包括一张截图披露。马斯克回答“是的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟不会推出 Threads，该地区有严格的数据隐私规则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta 已告知爱尔兰数据隐私委员会，它委员会发言人格雷厄姆·多伊尔 (Graham Doyle) 表示，尚未计划在 27 个国家推出 Threads。爱尔兰监管机构是 Meta 在欧盟的主要隐私监管机构，因为该公司的地区总部位于都柏林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然 Meta 本周早些时候在苹果英国应用商店上架了该产品的发布，但不可能存在于法语、德语或荷兰语版本中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师表示，它的成功远未得到保证，并引用了 Meta 推出独立应用程序的记录，但这些应用程序后来被关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外问题在于，这对于 Meta 来说是否是正确的举措，在过去一年中，随着科技行业的放缓，Meta 已宣布裁员数万人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“粉碎了中国的锅”？中国官方媒体猛烈抨击Meta的扎克伯格&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;首席执行官马克·扎克伯格也一直关注元宇宙，在虚拟现实概念上投资了数百亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;元风险“自行蔓延”太薄了，”全球市场研究公司 Forrester 的研究总监迈克·普鲁克斯 (Mike Proulx) 说。 “Meta 寄希望于 Twitter 遭遇挫败感最严重的时刻。然而，这个机会之窗已经充斥着 Twitter 的替代品，包括 Bluesky、Mastodon、Spill、Post.News 和 Hive，它们都在争夺 Twitter 的市场份额。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即便如此，Threads 仍可能是一个新鲜事物。让马斯克头疼的是，他去年以 440 亿美元收购了 Twitter。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他做出了一系列引发强烈反对的改变，最新的一项是限制人们每天可以查看的推文数量，以试图阻止这种行为。未经授权抓取潜在有价值的数据。他现在还要求用户进行付费验证才能访问在线仪表板 TweetDeck。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克与扎克伯格的竞争最终可能会蔓延到现实生活中。在一次在线交流中，这两位科技亿万富翁似乎同意进行笼式比赛对决，但目前还不清楚他们是否真的能上擂台。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba and NetEase bet future on AI despite looming US restrictions, as home province Zhejiang vows to support Big Tech]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3226672/alibaba-and-netease-bet-future-ai-despite-looming-us-restrictions-home-province-zhejiang-vows?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/90b96747-fd3b-4b1a-95d8-7be6900a38ef_4a7c71eb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴集团控股公司和网易公司是中国东部浙江省的两家大型科技公司据官方的《浙江日报》报道，他们正在将自己的未来押在人工智能 (AI) 上，因为他们对华盛顿现有的芯片贸易限制和对云计算服务的潜在限制表现出勇敢的态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丹尼尔将于9月卸任阿里巴巴董事长兼首席执行官的张勇表示，云计算是大语言模型（LLM）训练的基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“顶尖的互联网公司都在加速发展他们的[法学硕士]，”他说。 “新技术与平台经济模式的新共振，开辟了新的发展空间和前景。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;网易创始人兼首席执行官丁磊表示，网易公司将至少预算100亿元人民币每年（13.8亿美元）用于解决人工智能的“瓶颈”，包括大型模型的算法和芯片。他表示，网易将努力打造“100%自主研发”的最先进的人工智能系统，与国际竞争对手持平甚至更好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，省政府召开会议，鼓励网易和阿里巴巴（《南华早报》的所有者）等互联网平台的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浙江成为中国第一个推出本地互联网平台的省份。专门为帮助大型科技公司而设计的政策指南。该省政府已与国家市场监督管理总局签署协议，以支持浙江互联网平台。两年前，国家市场监督管理总局因垄断行为对阿里巴巴处以创纪录的 182 亿元人民币罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国已在近两年的打压打击了该国最强大的科技公司之后，该公司开始支撑平台经济。中国科技龙头企业的市值一度与美国同行并驾齐驱，但如今在西方竞争对手面前显得相形见绌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国科技公司也面临着新的挑战。据《华尔街日报》周二援引匿名消息人士的话报道，拜登政府正在研究新规则，限制中国客户访问使用先进人工智能芯片的美国云计算服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴和网易均表示他们相信北京和浙江当局会协助他们实现人工智能雄心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“去年以来，中央政府和浙江政府多次释放明确信号鼓励平台经济发展，这增强了平台经济的发展潜力。”丁说，这与张表达的类似观点相呼应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的言论呼应了张表达的类似观点，阿里巴巴执行副主席蔡崇信将继任董事长，以及淘宝和天猫集团董事长吴永明担任首席执行官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于浙江省会杭州的阿里巴巴表示，在激烈的全球竞争中，公司将充分利用浙江省的优势，继续加大对电子商务、物流和云计算的投资。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丁说，中国企业过去依靠产品和营销进行海外扩张，并在成本和上市时间上进行竞争，但它们的传统优势正在消失。 “我们现在必须在技术和生态系统上竞争，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore singles desperate to see Taylor Swift are offering themselves as dates to UOB cardholders]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3226681/singapore-singles-desperate-see-taylor-swift-are-offering-themselves-dates-uob-cardholders?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/25932f88-8a34-48e2-a153-10d5f67b9c10_35920d3c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Eligible bachelors want to score tickets to Taylor Swift&#39;s Singapore concert so badly, they&#39;re posting their profiles on Twitter, hoping to land a date who checks one key criterion: they must own a United Overeas Bank (UOB) credit card.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UOB cardholders on Wednesday began having exclusive access to a presale for tickets to Swift&#39;s concerts, which will be held next year in the city state from March 2 to March 9.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The general public will not have access until two days later.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why is Hong Kong missing out on Taylor Swift and other stars? Industry blames venues&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Keen to beat the rush for tickets, enterprising Swifties jokingly started to tweet out their dating profiles in search of romantic partners who also happened to be cardholders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a tweet on June 23 that&#39;s been viewed over 2.3 million times, @jameswindborne, a self-professed Swift-fan, described himself as a 30-year-old pilot and architect who “can afford to live in this economy”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His criteria for a partner: a “male/female” who lives in Singapore or Japan and is a “UOB Credit/Debit cardholder.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dozens of other Taylor Swift fans are racking up thousands of likes with tweets in the same format.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hazim Azman, a Malaysian fan who tweeted two selfies and a list of reasons to date him, told Insider on Wednesday that he considered his tweet successful, as he befriended a few people who were UOB cardholders and promised to help him secure tickets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Fingers crossed, let&#39;s hope we secure the tickets today,” he said, planning to travel down to Singapore to catch the show if he gets tickets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were already over 1 million fans in the presale queue on Wednesday, local media newspaper The Straits Times reported. More than 300,000 fans are expected to attend the concert&#39;s Singapore dates, per the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taylor Swift crashes Spotify with new album&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The allure of potential early concert tickets has also spiked credit card sign-ups in Southeast Asia by 45 per cent in the week after the promotion was announced, UOB said in a Tuesday statement. Most of the approved sign-ups were for those between 20 and 40 years old, the bank said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only cardholders in Singapore, Malaysia, Indonesia, Thailand and Vietnam are eligible for the presale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Eras Tour could become the first-ever concert to earn more than US$1 billion from tickets, merchandise, and sponsorships, according to a June 26 report by The Wall Street Journal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the original article on &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US-based scientists of Chinese origin still feel ‘chilling effects’ of Trump’s China Initiative]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3226688/us-based-scientists-chinese-origin-still-feel-chilling-effects-trumps-china-initiative?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/b0af1a3c-61fa-4c1a-892d-3497e1dd494e_08e3761d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Over a third of Chinese-origin scientists in the US do not feel welcome in the country, and close to three-quarters do not feel safe as academic researchers, a survey published in a renowned international science journal has revealed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The online poll, carried out after three years of the Trump-era China Initiative, also highlighted widespread fear among scientists of Chinese descent living the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Launched by the US Justice Department in late 2018 to probe scientists&#39; and academics&#39; potential links with the Chinese state, the initiative sparked concerns of racial bias and creating a culture of fear, and also triggered an exodus of Chinese-origin scholars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was dropped in February last year, with US national security officials declaring a more “threat-driven” approach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are questions, however, regarding the extent to which the formal dropping of the &#39;China Initiative&#39; name has been accompanied by substantive changes in the [US] government&#39;s practices that address the chilling effects experienced by scientists of Chinese descent,” the report published in renowned international journal Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS) last week said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least 150 scientists had been investigated so far, with criminal charges laid against two dozen of them under the initiative, and “many more investigated in secret”, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The study was carried out by five Chinese-origin researchers in the United States – a Harvard biostatistics scientist, a nuclear engineer at the Massachusetts Institute of Technlogy (MIT), and three “contemporary China” experts from Princeton.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 1,300 “tenured or tenure-track” academics at US universities were surveyed for the poll, carried out between December 2021 and March last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The findings come as the US-China rivalry spills over from the geopolitical arena to science and technology, with both seeking to win over the brightest scientific minds and Washington leading its allies in efforts to curb Beijing&#39;s access to advanced technology, including semiconductors and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Researchers in the fields of engineering, and computer and life sciences, all of key concern in the escalating US-China tech war, experienced the most fear and sense of unease amid intensifying hostility between the rival powers, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There had also been a steady increase in scientists in these fields choosing to return to China, with the trend more notable since 2018, the study found.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around 70 per cent of the respondents said they were fearful of “US government investigations into Chinese-origin researchers” and some 65 per cent were worried about joint research with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A study published by the science journal Nature in May last year said dual affiliations and US-China collaborations had fallen sharply by 2021 due to fears over drawing US government suspicions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US &#39;China Initiative&#39; stymied scientific innovation, study says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;About 65 per cent of respondents in the PNAS report attributed the fear to anti-Chinese sentiments sweeping the US with the arrival of the coronavirus pandemic, and more than 80 per cent reported having experienced insults in an non-professional setting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two-fifths also expressed unease over frequent attacks by US government officials on the “Chinese government or Chinese policies” and a similar number worried that their co-researchers, family members or friends might be targeted by the Chinese government in retaliation for something they did or said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, despite the overall fearful sentiment, an overwhelming 89 per cent of respondents “indicated their desire to contribute to the US leadership in science and technology”, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some high-profile cases under the initiative saw US-based academics&#39; careers and reputations ruined overnight by their suspected Chinese links.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2021, Chinese-born professor Gang Chen, former head of mechanical engineering at MIT and a member of the US National Academy of Engineering, was accused of lying about China ties in funding papers. He was arrested, his lab was closed and his research group was disbanded. But all charges were dropped a year later, with the Justice Department admitting it could not prove its case.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China-born scientist targeted by US &#39;discovers world&#39;s best semiconductor&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Non-Chinese academics were also caught up in the campaign. In April, retired Harvard professor Charles Lieber was placed under house arrest for six months and fined hundreds of thousands of dollars after being convicted in 2021 of trying to deny his ties to China and participation in Beijing&#39;s Thousand Talents Programme, a project to recruit scientists and strengthen research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The five scientists behind the PNAS report said they carried out the poll on behalf of the Asian American Scholar Forum, a non-profit organisation set up in response to Gang&#39;s case “to promote academic belonging, openness, freedom, and equality for all”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US suspicion of Chinese scientists actually predates the launch of the China Initiative. Sherry Chen, a National Weather Service hydrologist, was accused of spying for China a decade ago. Last November, she received US$550,000, and an additional US$1.25 million over 10 years, as settlement for the wrongful prosecution.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A number of Chinese scientists have given up their US citizenship since the launch of the China Initiative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest to do so was biophysical chemist Xie Xiaoliang, who returned to China last month. The former Harvard professor is best known for helping to invent the single-cell DNA amplification method in 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu Songchun, an accomplished computer scientist, gave up a professorship at the University of California, Los Angeles to become dean of the Institute for AI at Peking University in 2020.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thailand’s Pita Limjaroenrat confident of being named PM as parliament sets July 13 vote]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3226671/thailands-pita-limjaroenrat-confident-being-named-pm-parliament-sets-july-13-vote?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 06:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/2ff007bf-1b54-4f27-8a72-8934490d1a30_665ff0b6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Thailand will hold a joint session of its parliament on July 13 to elect a prime minister, taking a key step toward government formation almost two months after a group of pro-democracy parties swept the May election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 750-member National Assembly will convene for the vote at 9:30am next Thursday, Wan Muhamad Noor Matha, newly-elected speaker of the House of Representatives, told reporters on Wednesday. The session may not be immediately conclusive and may be only the first of many, as a successful premier candidate needs to gain the support of most lawmakers, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The eight-party coalition that has staked a claim to form Thailand&#39;s next government will solely nominate Pita Limjaroenrat, the 42-year-old leader of the progressive Move Forward Party that won the most seats in the May 14 election. It is not yet clear if other parties will nominate someone to challenge Pita&#39;s bid.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Thai parliament to convene session on July 3 enabling vote for new PM&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The coalition Pita&#39;s cobbled together after the election currently commands 312 lawmakers, a clear majority in the 500-member House of Representatives. But he needs the support of over a fourth of the 250-member Senate – a body appointed by the royalist military establishment following a 2014 coup that will vote alongside the lower chamber.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many senators oppose his Move Forward Party&#39;s proposal to amend the lese-majesty law, or Article 112 of the Thai criminal code, which penalises criticisms against the king and other royals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the house speaker usually abstains from taking sides with any group, the coalition is likely to be down one vote in support for Pita, leaving him still short of about 65 votes to reach the 376-vote marker to secure the premiership.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Pita has ruled out alliances with conservative parties, there is little alternative but to win as many Senate votes as possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the uphill battle, Pita has said that he is confident he will secure the top job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A long drawn-out government formation may further spook investors in the Thai financial markets. While the nation&#39;s benchmark stock index is the worst performer in Asia this year, the baht is the second-biggest loser in Southeast Asia since the May 14 vote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is no deadline for when the next leader has to be elected by, and the parliament may need to convene more than once to vote until a clear winner emerges, Wan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked how many times such a vote may take place, the 79-year-old speaker said: “We cannot anticipate in advance.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Agence France-Presse&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In Nepal’s male-dominated society, forests and trees thrive under ‘honest, transparent’ women bosses]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3226687/nepals-male-dominated-society-forests-and-trees-thrive-under-honest-transparent-women-bosses?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/f8ad4db7-9699-43aa-a2c5-49fb2ec06592_b2640c85.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Put women in charge of cultivating forests and the trees grow stronger. That is the takeaway from a pioneering 30-year scheme that has elevated women to the top of Nepal&#39;s community forests – and paved their way into local and national politics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three decades of picking women for leadership roles has produced healthier forests and happier workers, according to Nabaraj Pudasaini, joint secretary of the government&#39;s Department of Forest and Soil Conservation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In comparison to other community forests in the country, the ones managed by women are doing exceptionally well,” said Pudasaini.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Women spend more time in the forest than men, so they naturally have a deeper love and understanding of it. They are honest, transparent and have good relations with villagers, so they became a success,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;New Indonesia capital is &#39;massive ecological disaster&#39;, environmentalists say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Apsara Chapagain is typical of this trend for top female foresters, as the first women to chair the Federation of Community Forestry Users Nepal (Fecofun), a national body that promotes community rights over local land.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With tropical and temperate forests covering about 40 per cent of the Himalayan nation, the health of its trees is key to Nepal&#39;s prosperity and its roughly 29 million people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Having run Fecofun from 2010 to 2015, Chapagain is now deputy speaker of the assembly in Bagmati province, one of seven in the landlocked nation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 51-year-old credits her rise in local politics to her pioneering work with protecting trees and championing women.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have worked to show the way for the state,” said Chapagain, whose time with the forest movement taught her how to run teams, chair meetings and take decisions for the benefit of the community at large.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Any institution of the state cannot ignore Fecofun&#39;s contribution,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nepal&#39;s community forests were set up in 1995 to use land more sustainably and help reduce local poverty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country&#39;s forested area has since increased to about 44 per cent from 29 per cent, according to the Ministry of Forest and Environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fecofun now represents 3 million Nepalis working the forests in about 22,415 groups. Of those, 1,000 groups are female-led, and the rest are split equally by gender.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Popular Gentle, an expert in community forestry, said Fecofun was a pioneer in Nepal in ensuring the equal representation of women, ethnic groups and every caste.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the Nepali government had watched its success and followed suit, incorporating Fecofun&#39;s policy to ensure that women take a third of roles running all aspects of the state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fecofun was still more ambitious, safeguarding half of its jobs for women in a groundbreaking provision that began in 1996 and propelled many women into mainstream politics today.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bharati Pathak, who stood down as chair of Fecofun last month, said the programme “has enabled female participation and empowerment for women who could not come out from home”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nepali society is male dominated, with women largely confined to caring for family and home. Nearly 29 per cent of women are economically active – compared with about 53 per cent of men – and female workers are much more likely than their male counterparts to be in precarious employment, according to World Bank data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pathak – who has spent 15 years on Fecofun&#39;s central committee – has been treasurer, general secretary and president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now serving as a member of the Bagmati assembly, she is one of a group of forestry trailblazers turned politicians.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In last November&#39;s election, more than 40 community forest campaigners – 30 of them women – won seats in the House of Representatives and the seven provincial assemblies in Nepal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overall, female representation in state and national politics stands at 33 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Milestone&#39;: LGBTQ Nepalis welcome top court&#39;s marriage decision&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Women are vital to the cultivation and preservation of Nepal&#39;s forests – and also key to fostering greater inclusion across state institutions, said Sindhu Dhungana, joint secretary of the Ministry of Forest and Environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nepal&#39;s community forestry programme can serve as a model for the world,” said Dhungana, whose ministry oversees the Department of Forest and Soil Conservation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He praised women&#39;s role in conservation efforts, saying they had planted trees, stopped grazing, fenced forests and educated villagers about land preservation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One such woman, Nanda Kuwar, has chaired the Madhumalati community forest in Kailali in western Nepal since 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the 50-year-old took over, the forest was sparse, and the land was under direct threat from construction, cattle-grazing and farming.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kuwar&#39;s first task was to launch a campaign to get the community planting more vegetation in the forest – an initiative that opened her to attack by a developer armed with a sickle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Blood was flowing from my hand, and I immediately went to the hospital,” she recalled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now there is greenery and big trees. Seeing the trees of my community forest makes me forget my pain.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the Buddha Mangal Tal Women Community Forest in Nawalparasi district in the country&#39;s midwest has been hailed as a beacon of environmental rescue led by women.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Encroachment by villagers who cultivated paddy and reared cows had been a blight on the forest – and when local men failed to stop it, the women stepped up and took charge, said Kamal Pariyar, chairperson of Fecofun in Nawalparasi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A committee was established – managed by women – which fenced off the area and planted trees. Visitors to the forest must buy tickets, with the proceeds going towards poorer families, prioritising female-led households.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When the women took over leadership 15 years ago, they put a stop to encroachment,” said Pariyar. “They made sure that every household understood the importance of the forest.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[TikTok emerges as Southeast Asian threat to Amazon with US$20 billion shopping pilot]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3226692/tiktok-emerges-southeast-asian-threat-amazon-us20-billion-shopping-pilot?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.06 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/0666fc2e-5bcb-4209-834b-c8847a8a3cc1_3288db14.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Inside a &#39;shophouse&#39; in northeast Jakarta, dozens of salespeople take turns peddling cosmetics, contact lenses and hair accessories. A woman helps a potential customer choose the right shade of lipstick for her skin tone, while a man yells out the latest markdown on vitamin tablets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is no raucous flea market. It is a livestreamed marketplace within TikTok, and a gold rush for entrepreneurs seeking fortunes on the world&#39;s most popular short-video app. For the company, best known for viral dance challenges and owned by China&#39;s ByteDance, TikTok Shop is its fastest-growing feature with a burgeoning fan base in Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its success in the region is crucial for TikTok as it faces a possible ban in the US on national security concerns. It also provides the company a template to take on Amazon in a way that no social media company has attempted before, provided it&#39;s allowed to keep operating in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia was the first market for TikTok Shop and is still its biggest, helped by a young, mobile-savvy population that has embraced the combination of short videos and in-app shopping since its 2021 launch. TikTok Shop is expected to hit US$20 billion in gross merchandise value by the end of this year, quadrupling from a year earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If it can sustain that momentum, analysts say, it could revamp a company whose mainstay video platform is already luring consumers and advertisers away from Meta and Google.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hank Wang, who manages a cast of around 50 live streaming hosts at the bustling Jakarta shophouse, believes TikTok Shop has the power to transform the retail industry and turn entrepreneurs like him into the next e-commerce barons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I want to become the next Forrest Li,” said the 33-year-old former venture investor, referring to the China-born founder of Sea Ltd, the largest internet company in Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang directs his team to sell products on behalf of cosmetics and consumer goods makers like L&#39;Oreal, earning a cut and sharing the profits with the live streaming hosts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He moved from Shanghai to Jakarta seven months ago and started his company, Flame Media, despite not speaking the local language. “TikTok and social commerce will give rise to the next generation of tech unicorns in this region,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June, TikTok&#39;s Chief Executive Officer Chew Shou Zi visited Jakarta and promised to invest billions of dollars in Southeast Asia over the next three to five years. Wearing a traditional batik shirt, he shook hands with a key Indonesian minister and visited local shops with TikTok accounts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That was a marked contrast to his experience earlier this year in Washington, where he underwent a hostile, five-hour hearing in Congress. Politicians grilled him on Chinese influence over the business as well as its videos&#39; impact on children&#39;s mental health, and the company faces a possible ban ahead of the presidential elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TikTok Shop&#39;s start in Indonesia, Southeast Asia&#39;s biggest economy, came as ByteDance was seeking to expand outside China, where it faces regulatory and economic challenges.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In its early days, the global e-commerce project was given the code name “Magellan XYZ” after Ferdinand Magellan, the 16th-century explorer who circumnavigated the globe as he sought a route to the Spice Islands, part of what&#39;s now Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company initially presented it as an underground feature for younger, in-the-know consumers in Indonesia. Through agents, it gathered hundreds of livestreamers, some of them just out of school.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The presenters recorded themselves with their own mobile phones to sell items such as Tupperware and sunscreen. Launched during the month of Ramadan while Covid was still keeping many people at home, it was an immediate hit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The operations have since grown more sophisticated as agencies like Wang&#39;s Flame Media connect brands with live streaming hosts and set up studios.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some businesses are assigned a TikTok account manager who offer advice on content and promotions, while others are sent trained performers, or influencers, to help brands reach millennials and Gen Z-ers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet the videos have retained a somewhat amateur and improvised touch compared with the carefully staged accounts on Instagram, and that is considered a big reason for its popularity: shoppers feel a closer, authentic connection with the seller.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suanto, who goes by Kohcun online, is one of the most prominent Indonesian influencers on TikTok Shop, with his improvised, casual style attracting over a million followers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 36-year-old was previously known for his gadget reviews on YouTube, but he now livestreams on TikTok Shop for six hours each day, peddling Samsung phones and Louis Vuitton bags. The money he earns from commissions and brand deals is around three times what he got through YouTube, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“TikTok has the big advantage using their creators because it&#39;s more entertaining, it&#39;s more natural,” said David Nugroho, CEO of Jakarta-based DCT Agency, which manages 600 TikTok personalities and is one of the biggest TikTok Shop partners in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today, TikTok says it has more than 100 million monthly users in Indonesia, who on average spend more than 100 minutes on the app every day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That is a key reason ByteDance became the world&#39;s most valuable start-up – worth more than US$200 billion – in a single decade, disrupting social media and internet incumbents such as Meta and Tencent Holdings on both shores of the Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US social networking sites have tried to launch similar services, but users there have never taken to live shopping in the way people in China and Southeast Asia have.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instagram, owned by Meta, stopped allowing users to tag products while live streaming since March. YouTube and Amazon have flirted with offering shopping from live videos, without making much headway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Indonesia, TikTok Shop entered a market where consumers were already accustomed to scrolling online catalogues, spending hours on their smartphones for both entertainment and shopping.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local e-commerce pioneers GoTo&#39;s Tokopedia and Alibaba&#39;s Lazada, competing for users, spent billions of dollars helping to set up delivery networks across the country. TikTok swooped in and took advantage of all that.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TikTok has also benefited from expertise gained through its sibling app Douyin, ByteDance&#39;s China-only video platform that&#39;s become a US$200 billion shopping destination after expanding its range of services to include food delivery and hotel booking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is years ahead of the rest of the world in terms of live shopping, helped by lengthy Covid lockdowns that forced people to spend time on their phones, and platforms like Douyin and Alibaba&#39;s Taobao.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An important part of that expertise is algorithms. On both Douyin and TikTok, algorithms help serve up the right video clip in front of users to keep them scrolling, and figuring out what kind of merchandise they&#39;re most likely to buy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Key executives of TikTok Shop are from China. Bob Kang, a senior ByteDance executive who travels frequently between Shanghai, Singapore and the US, oversees thousands of employees for both Douyin and TikTok&#39;s e-commerce operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yu Weiqi, a former assistant to the company&#39;s billionaire co-founder Zhang Yiming, runs TikTok Shop&#39;s operation in Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While many of the entrepreneurs working with TikTok Shop are Indonesian like DCT&#39;s Nugroho and Pasar Kreatif Digital founder Daniel Tjandra, with strong networks of local influencers as well as businesses, some are from China, bringing with them Chinese capital as well as prior experience with live shopping.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Richard Ma, a 31-year-old marketing specialist in Beijing, is a TikTok Shop seller who coaches a small team of Indonesian livestreamers to market things like US$40 air fryers and US$8 Bluetooth earbuds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, his company has been buying goods from Alibaba&#39;s wholesaling site 1688.com and shipping them to a warehouse near Jakarta. Many of those products are bestsellers on Douyin&#39;s burgeoning e-commerce marketplace.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We can replicate the China model and adapt it to different markets,” he said, while acknowledging his operation was still in the red given the upfront investment and low price tags. With the growing scale of the site, Ma said, he is convinced he will soon turn a profit.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While TikTok&#39;s success in Indonesia helps shelter the business from the impact of a possible US ban, there are still uncertainties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even with the growing purchasing power of Indonesia&#39;s middle class, many of its users are earning far less than US consumers. TikTok&#39;s customers in Indonesia spend around US$6-US$7 on average, according to research firm Cube Asia. That is why, despite facing multiple bills in Congress that could ban the app, the US is still so important for TikTok&#39;s e-commerce business.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TikTok in November launched a US in-app shopping feature, with a constellation of mini-stores linked to the profiles of influencers and creators. It was opened more broadly to American brands earlier this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company&#39;s next plan is to roll out a marketplace, more akin to a traditional shopping site, in the coming months. Instead of stumbling across individual stores through their feeds, consumers will be able to search, compare, and buy products, all in one place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese manufacturers and exporters, in recent meetings with ByteDance sales managers, have been offered free listings, shipping, and zero commissions to eventually sell into the US market. The company is setting up its own American warehouses and fulfilment operations and is actively pitching brands on the idea, two people familiar with the matter said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is a strategy that sets the company apart from US-based social platforms like Instagram and YouTube, which have avoided management of actual goods even as they tried expanding into e-commerce. It also puts it in direct competition with Amazon on its home turf.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a move that is also more e-commerce than social media, TikTok is hiring former fashion and lifestyle brand employees to oversee retail categories like fashion, home and beauty. The roles are expected to be key in recruiting merchants and educating them on what makes the right kind of video and how to successfully work with creators.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If TikTok can make the whole live streaming purchasing process frictionless for users, brands and creators in the US, “that&#39;s the tipping point” said Ryan Detert, CEO of marketing company Influential. “And then all of a sudden, massive amounts of money that was going toward paid media and video content also applies to live.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jianggan Li, founder and CEO of Singapore-based consultancy firm Momentum Works, said TikTok&#39;s e-commerce expansion in the US market is not just about capturing consumers with greater spending power but also about gaining “tremendous advantages in negotiation power for its supply chain and fulfilment systems”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It will not be easy, although TikTok is already used by 150 million people in the US and has become a massively influential sales driver for everything from books to films in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Competing in the US retail market would mean taking on other Chinese players such as Shein and PDD Holding&#39;s Temu as well as Amazon.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;TikTok COO, who defended firm against China fears, quits after 5 years&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Even within Southeast Asia, there are concerns about whether it can keep growing once it scales back its aggressive marketing and subsidies for influencers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Vietnam, for instance, TikTok spends thousands of dollars per month in gift vouchers to influencers, according to local executives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gift vouchers are usually distributed to fans during live-shopping events to bolster sales. This strategy has made some brands question TikTok&#39;s ability to sustain its growth once it stops burning cash.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Samsung Electronics, for its part, has reduced its spending on TikTok Shop in Southeast Asia after realising that users who added products to their carts did not always follow through to checkout, according to another person with knowledge of the matter. Samsung declined to comment for this story.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And while Indonesia&#39;s government has so far been supportive, there are fears it may eventually step up its regulatory oversight of TikTok Shop.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government recently issued a censure over “online begging” on TikTok, or videos showing women begging for virtual gifts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some are also starting to question the social impact of the impulse purchases they say the app encourages, epitomised by the popular hashtag #Tiktokmademebuyit. Relations between Indonesia&#39;s Muslim majority and the wealthier minority of ethnic Chinese also remain a sensitive issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;TikTok owner ByteDance is testing AI chatbot to challenge ChatGPT&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Vietnam&#39;s government has said it will review whether TikTok poses a threat to its youth and culture, while India banned it in 2020 over national security concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For now, though, entrepreneurs like Wang see only growth ahead for TikTok Shop. As his firm is approaching US$1 million in monthly merchandise sales, he plans to soon move into a newly renovated office building in Menteng, an upmarket neighbourhood in the Indonesian capital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also plans to hire 500 livestreamers by the end of this year. After that, he said, he might move on to other growth markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The first thing is to become the number one in Indonesia,” he said. “Then we can try another region, another continent. It&#39;s one step at a time.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 06 Jul 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>