<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Bhutan cuts daily tourist fee by half to lure more visitors in struggle to recover from Covid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3232404/bhutan-cuts-daily-tourist-fee-half-lure-more-visitors-struggle-recover-covid?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 17:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/26/c65cbfab-cde7-41c1-a2e1-32ee711934d0_8ae5b7b1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;喜马拉雅山王国不丹将把每天向游客收取的 200 美元费用减半努力推动在 Covid-19 限制结束一年后仍在努力复苏的行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不丹将其“可持续发展费”从每位游客每晚 65 美元提高到 200 美元，当时它是去年 9 月结束了两年的新冠限制，称这笔钱将用于抵消游客产生的碳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每晚 100 美元的新价格将从 9 月开始生效，持续四年政府表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是考虑到旅游业在创造就业、赚取外汇……以及促进整体经济增长方面的重要作用，”它说。&lt;/p>;&lt;几代人与世隔绝的不丹于 1974 年向游客开放，当时接待了 300 名游客。官方数据显示，2019 年这一数字飙升至 315,600 人，同比增长 15.1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;不丹选美皇后在同性恋长期非法的土地上开辟了 LGBT 道路&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;不丹一直对大众旅游的影响保持警惕，并禁止登山以保护山峰的神圣性。游客收费限制了大手笔游客的数量，而这些人只占到邻近尼泊尔旅游人数的一小部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，不丹希望将旅游业对其 30 亿美元经济的贡献提高 20%，从约 5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅游部总干事 Dorji Dhradhul 表示，费用减半可能会增加 9 月至 12 月旅游高峰期的入境人数，该高峰期包括许多宗教和文化活动主要是佛教国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月，政府放宽了对游客停留时间和费用的规定，但游客数量并未如预期回升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dhradhul 表示，已有超过 56,000 名游客参观过自一月份以来，不丹约有 42,000 名印度国民，他们每天只需支付 1,200 印度卢比（14.5 美元）的费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约有 50,000 名不丹人从事旅游业，每年赚取约 8,400 万美元疫情发生前三年的外汇情况。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Be alert: China enlists the public in push back at US spying efforts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3232392/be-alert-china-enlists-public-push-back-us-spying-efforts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/26/0f40f7d0-7e47-46e6-a01c-e6b37e8752f7_fa888bd9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当中国国家安全部的微信帐号上个月末上线时，它似乎有两个使命：反击西方对其国家安全努力的批评，并动员公众参与反情报活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;指责美国双重标准并渲染中国威胁，以弥合国内矛盾为了应对政治分歧，国防部采取了罕见的举措，两次点名指责中央情报局试图招募中国线人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还呼吁中国公众警惕间谍并举报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“12339。你是一个英雄。国家安全——每个人都有责任，”该部的一张网上海报写道，敦促人们拨打国家热线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公共宣传工作与《反间谍法》的扩大相吻合。上个月生效，并且随着与西方的关系恶化而出现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但观察人士质疑模糊立法和公众推动的价值，称它们给在华外国企业增加了更多不确定性，并模糊了界限国家安全部长表示，中国需要“积极防御”间谍&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据报道，中国当局拘留或杀害了至少十几名美国线人，十年来，中央情报局局长威廉·伯恩斯表示，美国在重建其在中国的间谍网络方面取得了进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们已经取得了进展，近年来我们正在非常努力地工作，以确保我们伯恩斯在阿斯彭安全论坛上表示：“强大的人类情报能力可以补充我们通过其他方法获得的情报。”他还表示，中央情报局正在努力确保能够对任何攻击台湾的计划提供早期预警。如果那一天到来的话”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国现代国际关系研究院（CICIR）退休国家安全研究员李伟表示，国防部的宣传犯罪部分是由伯恩斯的言论引发的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“以美国为首的一些国家针对中国的间谍活动越来越猖獗，”李说，他的智库与国家安全部有联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种间谍活动对中国的国家安全利益也构成了巨大威胁，因此为了最大限度地挫败一些国家针对我们进行的情报间谍活动，中国必须让公众参与进来。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了应对这种威胁，中国的反间谍法扩大了间谍活动的定义，将“与国家安全和利益相关”的任何文件、数据和信息包括在内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还表示，国家安全部在推动反情报工作时需要管理负责媒体和互联网的机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥斯陆和平研究所高级研究员伊拉里亚·卡罗扎(Ilaria Carrozza)表示，非常令人担忧的是“几乎任何东西都可以被解释为情报”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，在我看来，这有助于解释为什么公众也参与其中，因为现在它不再只是国家机密，而是卡罗扎说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她表示，随着美中关系变得紧张，情报收集变得更加重要，导致中国更加明确地指责美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还表示，外交部的信息不仅针对国内受众和大量使用微信的华人侨民，还针对中国以外的人们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交部并不是唯一一个这样做的人。当地警察部门也一直在利用社交网络告诉年轻人留意间谍，并向公安部国家安全热线举报可疑活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;呼吁人们发现间谍的呼吁也催生了“步行”的流行语。 50万元人民币”，相当于6.9万美元，是北京市国家安全局自2017年以来开出的最高悬赏金额。这句话已成为间谍的代名词，被网红和警方广泛传播。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在南部城市佛山，铁路警察在抖音（抖音的中国版）上部署了表情包，警告该部队的 190 万粉丝，间谍可能无处不在，携带相机对军事设施进行拍照和录像。声明称，在网上发布“不当言论”的人也可能是间谍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;河南省桐柏县公安局上传的另一则抖音视频显示，一名女警察试图通过询问行人来识别间谍。素描中的台词表明，只有中国人 - 而不是外国人 - 会知道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡罗扎表示，微信和其他社交媒体平台的这种使用可能会吸引年轻人，但对抓获更多间谍没有什么帮助.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我无法想象一个外行如何能够以更复杂的方式做某事，或者能够比实际的情报部门更多地发现间谍，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “这更多的是一种宣传工作。我们应该在提高国内公众意识的背景下看待这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为这与我们过去几年在习近平[国家主席]统治下看到的媒体攻势相匹配[ ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她表示，对间谍活动进行更广泛的法律定义以及公众更多地参与发现可疑间谍活动将产生一个重大影响——这将模糊中国非法情报工作的界限，从而使外国企业面临更大的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，当局突袭了美国咨询公司贝恩公司和尽职调查公司Mintz Group的中国办事处，这在外国商界敲响了警钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;中国欧盟商会表示，商务部呼吁公众举报间谍活动增加了欧洲企业面临的不确定性，并“迫使外国企业质疑中国希望与他们建立什么样的关系”，正如他们所寻求的那样北京方面采取了更明确的迹象和切实步骤来恢复外国企业的信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新法律和商务部的反间谍活动“无助于减少商业政治化并带来潜在的合规挑战”， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;商会还表示，如果不澄清法律中的“关键条款”，欧洲企业未来可能会对在中国投资更加犹豫不决。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In Japan, residents of Fukushima cautious after start of water release from wrecked nuclear plant]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3232400/japan-residents-fukushima-cautious-after-start-water-release-wrecked-nuclear-plant?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/26/2f2a4d7c-a60a-4efb-bcea-5c4e12db4467_67e8193d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本福岛第一核电站以南港口的鱼类拍卖价格周五下跌由于不确定海鲜消费者将如何应对经过处理和稀释的放射性废水排入海洋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该工厂在 2011 年地震和海啸中受损，开始将处理后的水排入太平洋周四，国内和周边国家的抗议活动给经济担忧增添了政治和外交压力。沼之内渔港的中间人 Hideaki Igari 表示，比目鱼的价格上涨，比目鱼是福岛的标志性鱼类，被称为“比目鱼”。周五上午的拍卖中，Joban-mono 的价格下跌了 10% 以上，这是放水开始以来的第一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长达数十年的放水遭到了渔业组织的强烈反对，并受到邻国的批评。作为回应，中国立即禁止从日本进口海鲜，这加剧了渔业界和相关企业的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一家公民辐射检测中心表示正在收到询问，更多人可以携带食物、水和其他样本，因为辐射数据现在是决定吃什么的关键晴雨表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本渔业组织担心释放会对福岛地区海鲜的声誉造成更大损害。他们仍在努力修复地震和海啸后发电厂熔毁对其业务造成的损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经过这些年的奋斗，当鱼市价格终于恢复正常时，我们现在有了这些水。”变得稳定，”五十里在周五的拍卖后说道。 “渔业人士担心他们为生而捕捞的鱼的价格可能会再次暴跌，并担心他们未来的生活。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本政府和该工厂的运营商东京电力公司控股公司（Tepco），表示必须将水排出，以便为该设施的退役腾出空间，并防止未经充分处理的水意外泄漏。大部分罐装水中的放射性物质仍超出可释放水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工厂的部分废水经过处理后被回收作为冷却剂，其余的储存在大约 1,000 个罐中，这些罐的注水量为 98 立方米。其 137 万吨产能的 10%。官员们表示，这些水箱覆盖了建筑群的大部分区域，必须清理干净，以便为退役过程所需的新设施腾出空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局表示，经过处理和稀释的废水比国际标准要求的更安全，并且其对环境的影响可以忽略不计。电力公司表示，周五，排放后收集到的第一批海水样本明显低于法定排放水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在早些时候，该厂遭受了一系列意外和有意排放的污染水。灾难、怨恨以及对政府和东电的不信任在福岛根深蒂固，尤其是在渔业社区。&lt;/​​p>;&lt;p>;有人担心释放，东电称释放将需要 30 年时间或直到核电站结束退役，对于这个渔镇的年轻人来说可能意味着艰难的未来，这里的许多企业都是家族经营的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于渔获量下降，福岛目前的渔获量已经仅为灾前水平的五分之一左右。渔民数量和捕捞量下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府已拨款 800 亿日元（5.5 亿美元）支持渔业和海鲜加工，并通过赞助推广福岛常磐物和加工品的活动来应对潜在的声誉损害。海鲜。东京电力已承诺“妥善”处理声誉受损索赔以及因中国出口禁令而受到伤害的人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福岛县渔业合作社负责人 Tetsu Nozaki 在周四的一份声明中表示，对捕捞活动的担忧只要水被释放，社区就会继续存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们唯一的愿望是继续在家乡世代捕鱼，就像事故发生前一样，”野崎说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;鱼价在很大程度上取决于东京地区批发商和消费者的情绪，福岛渔获物的大部分都运往东京地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在沼之内港周五的拍卖会上，比目鱼的价格低于其预期价格。中间人 Igari 表示，通常的价格约为每公斤 3,500 日元（2.2 磅）至 3,000 日元左右。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我怀疑这一结果是由于福岛第一核电站开始排放处理过的水和担心其影响，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Igari 表示，排放令人沮丧，但希望仔细的测试能够证明他们的鱼的安全性。 “从消费者对家庭食品安全的角度来看，我认为最好的晴雨表是数据，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在位于磐城市的福岛母亲辐射实验室，这是一个名为 Tarachine 的公民测试中心，实验室正在对水样进行测试，其中包括实验室在释放前从福岛第一核电站附近收集的海水中的氚含量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实验室主任木村爱表示，任何人都可以携带食物、水甚至是海水。尽管由于测试需要时间，实验室积压了大量工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她加入了实验室，因为她后悔由于灾难早期缺乏信息和知识而未能充分保护她的女儿们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她加入了实验室。 >;&lt;p>;她说，拥有独立的测试结果很重要，不是因为对政府数据的不信任，而是因为“在过去的 12 年里，我们了解到测试以获得数据的重要性”，了解母亲们想知道什么，以便为安全和服务提供服务。为孩子和家人提供健康食品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;木村说，人们对安全有不同的看法 - 有些人对政府标准感到满意，另一些人则希望这些标准尽可能接近于零。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “让每个人都感到安全是非常困难的。 ...这就是为什么我们进行测试，以便我们可以可视化来自不同地方的食物数据，并帮助人们有更多选择来做出决定，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;木村说，实验室的测试表明福岛鱼是安全的在过去的几年里，她很高兴地吃着当地的鱼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“吃不含辐射的鱼完全没问题，”她说，但她补充说，经过处理的水的排放会带来新的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;Aeon 是一家大型连锁超市，一直在测试鱼中的铯和碘含量，并宣布计划也测试氚，这是一种与水不可分离的放射性核素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Katsumasa Okawa，一家鱼店和周四在他的四家商店之一的餐馆经营者表示，工厂于下午 1 点开始释放处理后的水的最后步骤，并且媒体报道了这一进展，之后顾客稀少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在周五，他说，他位于磐城火车总站旁边的 Yamako 海鲜餐厅似乎照常营业，午餐时间顾客进进出出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他个人一直期待着废水排放能成为一个大项目。大川说，这是朝着核电站退役迈出的一步。 “想到这些坦克最终会消失，我感到更加安心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大川说，灾难发生后他对自己的产品进行了多年的自愿测试，他担心回到过去的日子。辐射测试和数据作为吃什么的基准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为太多的测试数据只会引发担忧，”他说。 “我对自己销售的产品充满信心，我会继续努力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India tightens rice exports in threat to global food prices]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3232398/india-tightens-rice-exports-threat-global-food-prices?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 15:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/26/9a2ffeea-7f5a-4c98-a5cb-bc85fd522477_84d5e7ec.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度对大米运输实施更多限制，以确保其粮食安全最大出口国的关税可能会进一步挤压全球粮食供应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据财政部周五晚间发布的通知，政府对蒸谷米征收 20% 的出口税，立即生效，证实了彭博新闻社早些时候的报道。印度现已限制所有非印度香米品种的海外销售，这些品种约占印度大米总出货量的 80%。它在全球大米贸易中所占份额约为 40%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，亚洲大米价格飙升至近 15 年来的最高水平，并且可能进一步攀升，导致菲律宾和一些国家等进口国的成本上升。非洲国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度最近采取的保护主义措施与其在明年初大选前冷却当地食品价格的积极努力相一致，届时总理纳伦德拉·莫迪将寻求第三个任期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“通过这一举措，国内价格将会下降，这将有助于政府控制食品通胀，”大米出口商协会主席 BV Krishna Rao 表示。 “但是，全球价格将会上涨，买家将不得不承受上涨的影响。买家和卖家之间还将就某些合同进行重新谈判。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大米是世界上约一半人口的主食。印度实施限制措施之际，由于俄罗斯在乌克兰的战争，以及全球不稳定的天气威胁着谷物和油籽的供应，食品成本仍然居高不下。人们担心印度确保国内粮食安全的举措将打击几个仍在努力从新冠病毒导致的经济衰退中复苏的较贫穷国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡敦促印度免除非巴斯马蒂大米出口禁令&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;蒸谷米约占印度大米总出货量的三分之一。该国已经禁止出口碎米和非印度香米，限制小麦和糖的运输，并限制一些农作物的储存。印度还在考虑取消对小麦征收 40% 的进口税，并出售国家储备的西红柿、洋葱和谷物，以改善当地供应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预煮是一种在碾磨之前对稻谷进行部分煮沸的过程。提高其营养价值并改变米饭的质地。一些餐馆使用蒸谷米，因为它已经干净且易于烹饪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然对蒸谷米的关税于周五生效，但在政府命令之前持有有效信用证的出口商将被允许运输谷物，根据通知。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 15:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Koreans push back against businesses asking for tips: ‘I hope this never settles’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3232396/south-koreans-push-back-against-businesses-asking-tips-i-hope-never-settles?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 14:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/26/9c43a41f-5e60-4783-a4d3-0ba6f074c035_6b16dcfd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;小费文化似乎突然在韩国兴起，一些餐馆、咖啡馆甚至打车平台都会向顾客索要小费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于韩国一直是一个无小费的社会，许多人对小费文化的明显出现表现出了压倒性的负面反应.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近一篇题为“我们希望永远不要在韩国定居的外国文化”的在线帖子最近在网上疯传，其中展示了首尔一家受欢迎的面包店收银台上的一个玻璃罐的照片，里面装满了现金，上面贴着“ Tip Jar”英文。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首尔面包店的 Instagram 账户上充斥着 200 多条负面评论，其中许多人要求店主删除它，称这种习俗荒谬且非法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该帖子促使其他韩国人分享类似的经历。一名用户称，首尔麻浦区一家咖啡店的一名员工要求她给小费，并展示了一款平板电脑，上面提供了高达账单 10% 的小费选项，而其他用户则表示，他们看到一些餐馆在桌子上贴了标牌，要求顾客给员工小费.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小费文化甚至已经超越了咖啡馆和餐馆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;占据国内网约车市场90%以上份额的Kakao T应用程序推出了小费试点&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在行程结束时，在司机将服务评价为五星级后，乘客可以选择向司机支付最多 2,000 韩元（1.5 美元）的小费。这是可选的，平台运营商兼 Kakao 子公司 Kakao Mobility 表示不会从小费中收取佣金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不明白为什么他们向我们索要小费，而我们却没有接受过任何值得小费的服务。与国外不同，顾客下单后自行取货，为什么要给小费呢？”一位 30 岁的郑姓顾客拿着小费箱在面包店排队等候了一个多小时，他告诉《韩国时报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位姓金的顾客说：“在韩国，最终费用已经涵盖了服务人员，而且服务人员的工资至少达到了最低工资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我讨厌其他国家的小费文化，在这些国家，服务人员的工资不够，而顾客则以‘善意’为借口承受负担。 &#39;。我希望这种文化永远不会在韩国扎根。”她补充道，她怀疑小费箱里的钱是否​​会流向员工，而不是企业主。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据科技公司 SK 最近对 12,106 人进行的一项调查通讯方面，超过十分之七的韩国人认为给小费是“不可接受的”。只有 19% 的受访者表示给小费是个人选择，而 5% 的受访者表示支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据现行《食品卫生法》，韩国食品服务企业应在菜单上列出最终价格，其中包括税费和服务费，客户支付的费用不得超过此金额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了应对日益增长的投诉，企业主正在退缩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至周三下午，《韩国时报》观察到有争议的面包店的小费盒被从柜台上移走了。店主解释说，这“更多的是一种装饰”，增添异域风情，让游客感觉自己在旅行，没有顾客被迫给小费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，Kakao Mobility 表示，有超过 2,000 名乘客给了小费。他们的司机在推出该服务后的第一周内进行了测试，并相信这可以促使司机改善服务。例如，为孩子晕车而平稳驾驶或向乘客归还丢失物品的司机会得到小费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;食品药品安全部周四向《韩国时报》证实，强迫顾客付费的行为所列指控违反《食品卫生法》的情况比所列指控还要多，地方政府定期对食品服务企业进行打击，以监督此类违规行为以及卫生和安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文首次发表于 。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Did anyone call the police?’: actions of parents in China who tied ‘naughty’ son to pillar in food court while eating divides online opinion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3231937/did-anyone-call-police-actions-parents-china-who-tied-naughty-son-pillar-food-court-while-eating?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/23/d36a5bdc-f512-4f99-89e0-d8108b584619_e1793b50.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国的一则新闻报道，讲述了一对夫妇将行为不端的儿子绑在柱子上的故事他们吃饭时的美食广场引发了一场关于严厉育儿的新的公众辩论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对来自中国东部浙江省的身份不明的夫妇被拍摄到惩罚他们的小儿子，因为他们在一家烧烤餐厅吃饭时跑来跑去并发出噪音。据月牛新闻报道，另一位张姓食客于8月19日拍摄了这段视频，视频中可以看到父亲用胶带将儿子绑在柱子上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这对夫妇随后用智能手机拍摄了儿子与录像带搏斗并试图挣脱的过程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张说，晚间高峰期间，美食广场挤满了人，其中许多人笑着说：拍摄了这个无助男孩的视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张告诉月牛新闻：“我觉得这很有趣。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，该视频在大陆社交媒体上引起了不同的评论，抖音上的评论超过12000条。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多网上评论者批评这对夫妇的育儿方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人问：“有人报警了吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个人说：“我想知道这对他们的儿子造成了怎样的伤害。我觉得这一点都不好笑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，有些人站在这对夫妇一边。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我也是一位年轻的父母。我支持他们的教养方式。”一位说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位补充道：“儿子会吸取教训，以后会表现得端正。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于严厉教养的故事经常成为人们关注的话题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月，一位对儿子严格控制饮食的母亲因新闻媒体报道她强迫儿子吐出在同学生日聚会上吃的一块蛋糕而走红。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;4月，中国东南部一名男子要求孙子向同学报仇，结果对另一名孩子进行人身攻击，引起公愤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年年底，一名八岁的男子华中地区一岁男孩因看电视太多而被父母强迫看整夜电视的事件在网上引起热议。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fukushima water release: why China’s ban on Japanese seafood could backfire]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3232340/fukushima-water-release-why-chinas-ban-japanese-seafood-could-backfire?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/f7e4780b-1856-4edb-a755-c0d0376b1a2a_1246c8c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;继日本排放福岛核废料引发争议之后，中国决定禁止日本水产品分析人士表示，周四的水可能会适得其反，并指出对中国自己的海鲜行业的潜在影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们表示，此举还进一步给两国本已恶化的双边贸易蒙上阴影，因为这表明他们如何尽管水产养殖在中日贸易中并不那么重要，但两国之间的依赖可能会减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本将福岛核电站处理后的核废水排放到太平洋的决定激怒了北京，导致立即封锁所有日本海鲜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“显然，北京对这项禁令的不满非常明显，即使目前还不知道或不知道该禁令对日本的影响。中国的一些反应似乎与他们对日本现有的怀疑有关，”新加坡国立大学政治学副教授 Chong Jia Ian 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;福岛的放水计划：视觉解释器&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他还指出，北京似乎并不承认废水排放已得到国际原子能机构的认证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“贸易关系，尤其是货物贸易，仍然很重要，但出于商业和风险管理原因，日本正在从中国市场转向多元化，尽管中国更注重国内生产和消费，”他表示。 “随着时间的推移，中国和日本对彼此的重要性可能会降低。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，中国禁止海鲜进口并不被视为对日本有深远影响的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在目前，我不确定水产养殖在中日贸易中的突出地位。”庄说。 “如果北京方面认真反对，它可能会通过减少或限制从日本进口机械、电路和汽车来发出代价更高的信号。这将给日本带来更大的伤害，并给中国经济和消费者带来更大的损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，尽管中国是日本海鲜的最大目的地，但大多数水产品来自厄瓜多尔，其次是俄罗斯、越南和印度根据中国政府数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据海关数据，去年中日贸易总额下降 3.7%，至 3574 亿美元。 1-7月进口额同比下降12%，至1833亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本是中国第五大贸易伙伴，但考虑到其庞大的海产品进口总额，仅占其海鲜进口总额的一小部分。需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国业内人士担心废水排放和禁令对海鲜消费来说不是一个好兆头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管中国尚未采取任何行动来评估是否中国水产加工与营销联盟的一位工作人员表示，“从科学角度来看”废水是安全的，此举可能会对更广泛的海鲜消费造成打击。由于敏感，该工作人员拒绝透露姓名。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这肯定会对渔业和水产养殖业产生影响。”一些国内企业也会受到影响。”他说。 “据我所知……很多人不会吃海鲜，至少在短期内是这样。如果这种心态普遍存在，对于该行业来说是一个危险的信号。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于上海西部苏州的咨询公司金砖四国农业信息技术公司预测，这将对中国的渔业和渔业产生深远的影响。水产养殖业，在周四的一份研究报告中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“公众对水产品的消费意愿可能会受到影响，沿海城市海鲜市场的客流量可能会下降，而此类产品的销量也会下降，同时价格也会下降&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港日本人表示，尽管存在放射性排放，但该国的海鲜是安全的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国从 1 月至 1 月期间从日本接收了价值 19.37 亿元人民币（2.67 亿美元）的水产品7月，根据中国海关数据。由于对食品安全的担忧，7月份来自日本的出口额为2.35亿元人民币，环比下降三分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港等地的消费者一直在囤积食盐。地方当局响应日本的决定，禁止从 10 个县进口水产品。该禁令涵盖活的、冷藏的、冷冻的、干制的和腌制的商品，以及海盐和海藻制品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;山东大学海洋学院王亚民教授表示，废水可能会在一定程度上到达中国海域，但由于北太平洋的洋流方向，影响应该不大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“福岛附近的[循环洋流]顺时针方向移动，水流向东北方向，北美洲的方向走去。短期内不会有太大影响。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea urged to ban sale of whale meat disguised as ‘lotto in the sea’ bycatch]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/health-environment/article/3232345/south-korea-urged-ban-sale-whale-meat-disguised-lotto-sea-bycatch?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/83404580-7cd6-4d01-8bd8-5f1037cdf8f7_a6115125.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国活动人士正在寻求阻止渔民出售鲸鱼肉的漏洞accidentally caught in their fishing nets, as the country&#39;s cetacean bycatch remains suspiciously high in numbers, they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A new bill introduced earlier this year by 15 lawmakers marks the first step towards a sweeping ban on the consumption of whale meat in the country, the campaigners said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“South Korea is the only country in the world that protects cetacea with laws, while allowing the consumption of their meat at the same time,” Jo Yak-gol , head of the protectionist group Hot Pink Dolphins, told This Week in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea banned whale poaching in 1986 after it joined the International Whaling Commission&#39;s moratorium on commercial whaling.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39; Non-starter&#39;: will Japan &#39;walk away&#39; from Indo-Pacific trade pact over whaling?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Under existing law, a fisherman must immediately release a whale if it gets accidentally netted alive.如果发现鲸鱼死亡，他们必须迅速向海岸警卫队报告副渔获物，海岸警卫队将检查尸体以确保它没有鱼叉痕迹。 If checks show there are no such marks, a permit is issued that will enable the fisherman to auction the bycatch off as fair game.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netting a whale this way is known locally as a “lotto in the sea”, because a full-grown minke whale, for example, fetches as much as 200 million won (US$150,000).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On August 3, prosecutors in the southeastern city of Pohang arrested five people, including a skipper, for poaching nine minke whales between January and June this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To cover up evidence, they used untraceable illegal mobile phones for communication and dismantling whales at sea right after poaching them, prosecutors said. Dismantling refers to the removal of whale meat from other parts of its body.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Activists said poaching and smuggling were believed to make up for the gap between the supply and the demand, as whale meat supplied through bycatch was not enough to meet the demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But illegal netting of whales disguised as fair bycatch is no less serious, said Lee Yong-ki, a leader at the Korea Federation of Environment Movement (KFEM), as the number of such accidental catches is significantly higher than in other countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Government statistics show 822 cetacea – including whales, porpoises and dolphins – were reported as bycatch last year alone, although overall cetacean bycatch has been declining from 2,014 cases in 2019 to 1,350 in 2020 and 1,066 in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have firm rules and systems under which all whales and dolphins entangled in nets accidentally must be immediately reported to government authorities ... That&#39;s why the cases of bycatch in this country appear so high”, an official of the fisheries ministry told This Week in Asia on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Against this backdrop, independent lawmaker Yoon Mi-hyang and 14 other politicians in January introduced an amendment to an existing law on the protection of maritime environment, with a view of prohibiting “intentional bycatch” and punishing offenders up to three years in jail or 30 million won in fines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new amendment also calls for Coast Guard inspections rather than cursory checks with naked eyes of netted whales, but activists want more drastic measures, including the formation of a database to prevent fishermen from repeating an illegal bycatch disguised as accidental.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We welcome this amendment bill, but chances of it being passed at parliament remain unclear due to the lack of interest in it among the two major political parties [the Democratic Party of Korea and the People Power Party]” and fears of a backlash from fishermen and whale meat restaurants, Lee of KFEM said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The southeastern city of Ulsan, South Korea&#39;s industrial hub, was traditionally known as one of the region&#39;s whaling hubs until the country joined a global moratorium on whaling in 1986.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dismantling of whale carcasses happened at its southern port Jangsaengpo, where local authorities now seek to bolster tourism with a focus on whales and dolphins, ranging from a whale museum, an aquarium with four dolphins, to whale-watching boat trips after the 1986 whaling ban.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, six whale meat speciality restaurants still operate at Jangsaengpo, as people who have never forgotten the taste of whale meat continue to visit the city, which was once designated as “whale meat district”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nationwide, there are some 120 whale meat restaurants, in southeastern port cities such as Ulsan, Pohang and Busan in 2021, according to local news reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Whale meat used to be Ulsan&#39;s most famous delicacy, but whale meat restaurants are now in decline” because of rising whale meat bidding prices and growing public resentment, said Yoon Kyung-tae, 56, who operates one of the six whale meat restaurants at Jangsaengpo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If fishermen follow the existing rules and release the whale alive from nets, they would be left only with destroyed nets and fishing gear without any compensation, causing them to wait for the whale to die and report it as an accidental catch, said Jo .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The cause of the illegal bycatch comes from the paradox that maritime animals are legally protected while whale meat consumption is being allowed,” Jo added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Meta accused of endangering lives over Canada news block as wildfires rage]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3232394/meta-accused-endangering-lives-over-canada-news-block-wildfires-rage?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 13:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/26/f467680b-773f-4057-bb99-826e47f82616_7dd8d4aa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Meta is being accused of endangering lives by blocking news links in Canada at a crucial moment, when thousands have fled their homes and are desperate for wildfire updates that once would have been shared widely on Facebook.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The situation “is dangerous”, said Kelsey Worth, 35, one of nearly 20,000 residents of Yellowknife and thousands more in small towns ordered to evacuate the Northwest Territories as wildfires advanced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She described to AFP how “insanely difficult” it had been for herself and other evacuees to find verifiable information about the fires blazing across the near-Arctic territory and other parts of Canada.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nobody&#39;s able to know what&#39;s true or not,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And when you&#39;re in an emergency situation, time is of the essence,” she said, explaining that many Canadians until now had relied on social media for news.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta on August 1 started blocking the distribution of news links and articles on its Facebook and Instagram platforms in response to a recent law requiring digital giants to pay publishers for news content.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company has been in a virtual showdown with Ottawa over the bill passed in June, but which only takes effect next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Building on similar legislation introduced in Australia, the bill aims to support a struggling Canadian news sector that has seen a flight of advertising dollars and hundreds of publications closed in the last decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It requires companies like Meta and Google to make fair commercial deals with Canadian outlets for the news and information – estimated in a report to parliament to be worth C$330 million (US$250 million) per year – that is shared on their platforms, or face binding arbitration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Meta has said the bill is flawed and insisted that news outlets share content on its Facebook and Instagram platforms to attract readers, benefiting them and not the Silicon Valley firm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau this week assailed Meta, telling reporters it was “inconceivable that a company like Facebook is choosing to put corporate profits ahead of [safety] … and keeping Canadians informed about things like wildfires”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Almost 80 per cent of all online advertising revenues in Canada go to Meta and Google, which has expressed its own reservations about the new law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ollie Williams, director of Cabin Radio in the far north, called Meta&#39;s move to block news sharing “stupid and dangerous”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He suggested in an interview with AFP that “Meta could lift the ban temporarily in the interests of preservation of life and suffer no financial penalty because the legislation has not taken effect yet”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nicolas Servel, over at Radio Taiga, a French-language station in Yellowknife, noted that some had found ways of circumventing Meta&#39;s block.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They “found other ways to share” information, he said, such as taking screenshots of news articles and sharing them from personal – rather than corporate – social media accounts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several large newspapers in Canada such as The Globe and Mail and the Toronto Star have launched campaigns to try to attract readers directly to their sites.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for many smaller news outlets, workarounds have proved challenging as social media platforms have become entrenched.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trudeau slams Meta for blocking news as wildfires rage in Canada&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Public broadcaster CBC in a letter this week pressed Meta to reverse course.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Time is of the essence,” wrote CBC president Catherine Tait. “I urge you to consider taking the much-needed humanitarian action and immediately lift your ban on vital Canadian news and information to communities dealing with this wildfire emergency.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As more than 1,000 wildfires burn across Canada, she said, “The need for reliable, trusted, and up-to-date information can literally be the difference between life and death.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta – which did not respond to AFP requests for comment – rejected CBC&#39;s suggestion. Instead, it urged Canadians to use the “Safety Check” function on Facebook to let others know if they are safe or not.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Patrick White, a professor at the University of Quebec in Montreal, said Meta had shown itself to be a “bad corporate citizen”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s a matter of public safety,” he said, adding that he remained optimistic Ottawa would eventually reach a deal with Meta and other digital giants that addressed their concerns.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s former Winter Olympics delegation chief Ni Huizhong under investigation for corruption]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3232393/chinas-former-winter-olympics-delegation-chief-ni-huizhong-under-investigation-corruption?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 12:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/26/8efc92de-67b0-42ea-9179-bf3a700ff0c2_9cae81c8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The former chief of China&#39;s Winter Olympic delegation is under investigation for suspected corruption, authorities said on Saturday amid a government crackdown on graft in the sport sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ni Huizhong, who most recently headed the country&#39;s winter sports management office, “is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law”, the General Administration of Sport said, using a common byword for alleged corruption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ni, 54, previously served as secretary general of the Chinese delegation for last year&#39;s Winter Olympics, which were held in Beijing in a Covid-secure bubble.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He is one of a string of sport officials to come under scrutiny in recent months as the ruling Communist Party wages an industry-wide anti-corruption drive.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Leading Chinese sports official faces corruption probe&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s top public prosecutor said this month that former national football coach Li Tie had been charged with corruption offences including bribery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li, a one-time Premier League player, is one of several top football association officials to fall under graft probes since November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And in June, China&#39;s national snooker body issued lifetime bans to two players involved in a match-fixing scandal that sent global shock waves through the sport.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese President Xi Jinping has led an unrelenting clampdown on corruption since coming to power a decade ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Proponents say the campaign helps to ensure honest governance, but critics say it serves partly as an excuse for Xi to purge political rivals.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In Beijing, new counterterror regulations give authorities more power over tech sector]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3232275/beijing-new-counterterror-regulations-give-authorities-more-power-over-tech-sector?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.26 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/25/5bb9771e-6dc2-4029-92e7-e7e24c38f3d8_12d3933f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The city of Beijing has introduced new regulations under the country&#39;s counterterrorism law that give municipal authorities more power over the technology sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They were published on August 15 after being passed by the municipal legislature on July 28. The regulations take effect in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing is the latest municipal or provincial government to introduce its own regulations under the anti-terrorism law – which took effect in 2016 – but the clauses covering the tech sector have not been seen elsewhere in China so far. The national law includes a provision requiring tech companies to share access with security agencies to prevent and investigate terrorist acts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many tech giants have headquarters or key branches in Beijing, including internet companies ByteDance and Baidu, and artificial intelligence firm Megvii, which has been sanctioned by the US over alleged human rights abuses in the far western Xinjiang region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new regulations emphasise that internet companies must immediately remove and keep records of any content deemed to be terrorism-related or extremist and report it to the police, in line with the national law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They state that city authorities will also inspect and strengthen risk monitoring of “new technologies” and “new industries”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These new industries were identified as including AI, blockchain and autonomous driving in a draft of the regulations released for public comment in April, but this does not appear in the final version.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It comes as the Chinese government is increasingly focused on political security and tightening control of the tech industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the full text of the new regulations were published, official newspaper Beijing Daily said they were aimed at “maintaining political security and social stability in the capital”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Raffaello Pantucci, a senior fellow at the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies in Singapore, said the emphasis on “new industries” and “new technology” suggested that “this was something the public security bodies thought was a gap in their coverage”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This expands public security organs&#39; ability to prosecute and demand information from citizens by invoking this set of rules,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Angela Huyue Zhang, associate professor of law at the University of Hong Kong, the new regulations are an example of how key the internet is to the Chinese government&#39;s security vision.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Online content regulation is an important component of China&#39;s security framework, so it is not surprising that internet service providers, such as technology companies, are also subject to regulation under the anti-terrorism law,” said Zhang, who is also director of HKU&#39;s Philip KH Wong Centre for Chinese Law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But she said the move did not indicate there would be more scrutiny of the tech industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China sets out new rules for generative AI with an emphasis on &#39;core socialist values&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to the regulations, Beijing&#39;s public security and state security units will set up a “grass-roots intelligence network”, with residents to be trained so they can better identify “suspicious situations involving terrorism”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing will also be required to strengthen cooperation on counterterrorism with neighbouring Tianjin and Hebei province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The regulations also call for increased terrorism prevention efforts in the “core area of the capital” – where the top offices of the Communist Party, State Council, National People&#39;s Congress and various ministries and commissions are located.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s counterterrorism division will also establish a coordination mechanism with state ministries and state-owned enterprises that are headquartered in Beijing, as well as the People&#39;s Liberation Army in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new regulations also reaffirm the municipal government&#39;s authority to tighten traffic management during state-level “major events” – such as National Day celebrations, military parades and diplomatic conferences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Municipal and provincial legislatures in China can enact local legislation to define how they implement national laws.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Xinjiang Uygur autonomous region was the first to introduce its own regulations after the anti-terrorism law took effect. They prioritise “extremism” in the fight against terrorism, give some courts the power to designate terrorist organisations, and require the population to take part in counterterrorism efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has drawn international criticism for its treatment of Uygurs and other Muslim minorities in Xinjiang. But Beijing has denied allegations of human rights violations, saying its security policies in Xinjiang are needed to fight terrorism and the region has not seen any terror attacks since 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai as well as Hunan, Fujian and Zhejiang provinces have also introduced regulations under the anti-terrorism law in the past three years.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 26 Aug 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>