<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com<item><title><![CDATA[Indonesia’s ‘Amish of Asia’ Indigenous group wants internet blackout]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223598/indonesias-amish-asia-indigenous-group-wants-internet-blackout?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 20:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/2036b798-57dd-4077-88af-5b5053a1c174_98991253.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚的一个原住民社区要求在他们的地区中断互联网，以尽量减少“官方周五表示，“网络世界的负面影响”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爪哇岛万丹省的 Baduy 社区有 26,000 人，他们将自己分为部分采用技术的外部群体和神圣的内部群体&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据法新社看到的一封信，内部组织要求当局关闭互联网接收或转移附近的电信塔，这样信号就不会到达他们。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“这一请求是我们努力尽量减少智能手机对我们人民的负面影响的一部分，”Baduy 代表写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们认为，在他们所在地区附近建造的电信塔可能会威胁到他们的生活方式&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lebak 地区的官员告诉法新社，他们周一收到了这封信，并同意与印度尼西亚信息部交谈，以尝试遵守&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lebak 官员布迪·桑托索 (Budi Santoso) 周五告诉法新社：“基本上，我们希望始终满足巴杜伊人的需求，并需要保持他们的传统和当地智慧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;他说外来的巴杜伊人需要互联网，他们开始了在线业务，但官员们也担心访客或游客可以访问网络并向巴杜伊人展示他们认为不合适的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;我们的新地狱：土著印度尼西亚人在绿色运动中面临新的风险&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在保守的、穆斯林占多数的印度尼西亚，互联网自由是一个有争议的问题。政府已禁止赌博和色情内容，并要求互联网提供商过滤掉他们认为不合适的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管有审查制度，但托管此类内容的非法网站依然猖獗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;隐居的巴杜伊内城– 被西方媒体称为亚洲阿米什人 – 选择住在森林里，拒绝技术、金钱和传统教育。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们住在三个村庄，占地 4,000 公顷（9,900 英亩）距首都雅加达数小时车程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府于 1990 年宣布该地区为文化保护区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚是一个多元化的国家，有 1,300 多个民族分布在群岛。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan passes controversial ‘life and death’ bill to revise immigration law for refugees]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3223578/japan-passes-controversial-life-and-death-bill-revise-immigration-law-refugees?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 18:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/d116f4b6-ce3b-4d08-984b-47e70d25d0d6_15d8eb1e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本议会周五通过了一项修订移民和难民法的法案，使当局能够不顾一些反对党的反对，驱逐反复申请庇护身份的个人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该立法的反对者在雨中聚集在东京国会大楼前，要求废除该法案，而反对派立法者批评执政阵营“推翻”了该法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参议院或上议院在首相岸田文雄领导的执政自民党的支持下制定了该法律，其小联盟伙伴公明党以及其他相对保守的反对派力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然日本目前无法将正在处理难民身份申请的外国人送回本国，但移民当局怀疑许多人滥用职权&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据修订后的法律，政府将致力于减少在移民设施中的长期拘留，并鼓励驱逐不遵守驱逐出境规定的外国人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对者争辩说，修订后的立法可能会导致那些在本国面临迫害风险、危及生命的人被遣返，并导致被驱逐出境的儿童在日本出生和长大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据日本移民服务局的数据，截至去年年底，有 4,233 名外国人不顾被命令返回家园而拒绝回国。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;法律将允许政府驱逐那些在第三次请求后未能提出合理理由获得难民身份的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，批评者提出反驳，指出一些庇护寻求者过去曾在提出三个或更多申请后获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为向来自受冲突影响地区的外国人提供帮助，修订后的法律提供了“准难民”身份，使他们能够留在日本，即使他们不符合被承认为完全授权难民的标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为防止长期拘留的努力的一部分，政府将允许申请难民身份的个人在移民局之外居住设施在家人或支持者的监督下，以避免逃跑的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但反对者对该系统的有效性表示怀疑，称这给那些监视寻求庇护者的人带来了沉重的负担。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p&lt;p>;与此同时，主要在野党立宪民主党呼吁成立第三方机构来审查目前由移民当局执行的难民承认程序，以确保程序的公正性。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;执政集团拒绝了该请求，仅对该法案进行了微小的修改，例如培训移民官员如何筛查寻求庇护者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最后一刻试图阻止在修改法案后，在野党对负责立法的法务大臣齐藤健提出了谴责动议，最终于周三在参议院被否决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五在国会大厦外，持不同政见者举行集会，一些人举起标语牌，上面写着“保护难民”等英文短语。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在参议院全体会议投票前，石川大河日本立宪民主党抨击这项立法，称“这对许多人来说是生死攸关的问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ishikawa 还表示，修订后的法律可能会让寻求庇护者被遣返，即使他们面临监禁或酷刑在他们的祖国。该法案最终获得通过，反对党议员嘲笑参议院议长大辻秀久。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;三省党：新的极右翼政党希望“让日本再次伟大”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;日本远远落后于美国和几个通常每年接受超过 10,000 名寻求庇护者的欧洲国家。 2022 年，这个亚洲国家给予 202 人难民身份，其中 147 人来自阿富汗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年，由于 33 岁的斯里同年，一名兰卡妇女在被关押在日本中部名古屋的移民设施时死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几个月来，她一直抱怨胃痛和其他症状，最终因缺乏必要的医疗服务而死亡&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，岸田政府向议会提交了最新版本的法案，其中大部分保留了之前被撤回的法案的内容。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China offers South Africa help with BRICS summit security while arrest warrant out for possible attendee Putin]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223571/china-offers-south-africa-help-boost-brics-summit-security-while-arrest-warrant-out-possible?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/aea21664-9344-42aa-b005-b18f5133b861_c62acaac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国最高警官向南非承诺，北京将帮助加强金砖国家的安全俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京 (Vladimir Putin) 是否可能出席峰会引发争议，而国际逮捕令尚未出台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公安部长王晓红周四在北京会见南非警察部长 Bheki Cele 时说中国愿与南非一道，为将于 8 月 22 日至 24 日在约翰内斯堡举行的金砖国家峰会“加强安全保障”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金砖国家由中国、印度、俄罗斯、巴西和南非。普京可能会出席 - 他是国际刑事法院的战争罪逮捕令的对象 - 使南非处理逮捕令和峰会安全成为人们关注的焦点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际刑事法院发布逮捕令普京在 3 月指控他非法驱逐儿童并将人员从乌克兰领土非法转移到俄​​罗斯联邦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为国际刑事法院的签署国，南非将有义务执行逮捕令如果普京访问该国参加峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，南非在 5 月下旬授予与会者外交豁免权。其外交部表示，这是南非对在该国举行的国际会议和首脑会议授予豁免权的“标准”，“豁免权是针对会议的，而不是针对特定个人的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;金砖国家会见“朋友” &#39; 在推动扩大集团的过程中寻求更紧密的联系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;南非已向普京发出邀请，但南非和俄罗斯均未确认他将出席。不过，克里姆林宫发言人德米特里·佩斯科夫 5 月 30 日表示，“俄罗斯将以适当级别参加金砖国家峰会”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京周三与南非总统西里尔·拉马福萨通电话，就金砖国家峰会的筹备情况进行了交谈。克里姆林宫表示，约翰内斯堡峰会以及圣彼得堡俄罗斯-非洲峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南非拒绝执行国际刑事法院逮捕苏丹独裁者奥马尔·巴希尔期间访问南非的逮捕令。 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国尚未宣布习近平主席是否会出席峰会，但在周二中国外交部长秦刚与南非外长纳莱迪·潘多龙通电话时，秦表示北京愿意“支持南非成功举办领导人会议，加强金砖国家的团结与合作”，根据该部的一份声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周四的会议上，警察局长王还承诺与南非洲确保中国“一带一路”倡议的安全，打击跨国犯罪并提高执法能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南非是中国与大约 40 个非洲国家签署公共安全和执法协议的国家之一，根据华盛顿国防大学非洲战略研究中心 5 月发表的中非安全专家保罗·南图利亚 (Paul Nantulya) 的报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在普京可能访问之前，南非放弃退出国际刑事法院&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;近年来，中国与所罗门群岛等国家的执法合作备受关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而在5月王晓红与古巴内政部长拉萨罗·阿尔贝托·阿尔瓦雷斯·卡萨斯的会晤中，王毅表示，双方应加强合作，防止“颜色革命”，加强执法能力建设。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s anti-corruption body expels ex-central bank deputy Fan Yifei from Communist Party for ‘serious violations’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3223572/chinas-anti-corruption-body-expels-ex-central-bank-deputy-fan-yifei-communist-party-serious?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/eb960b47-7e69-4e40-a3f4-9a80729f3bed_a302ae34.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国央行原副行长被开除党籍撤职中国最高反腐机构周五表示，因“严重违纪违法”被免职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现年 59 岁的范一飞去年 11 月被党纪检察机关立案调查。中国人民银行 (PBOC) 副行长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着北京在过去两年加强对金融部门腐败的打击力度，他是被调查的最高级别的央行行长。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中纪委称，范某“无视”党的精神和原则，违规接受宴会、旅游、高尔夫、私人会所的邀请，同时还拿&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被查出有“迷信活动”的范某还利用职权为他人谋取利益，让亲属不干活就拿工资，中纪委说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反腐机构说，他还“以权谋私”，干涉执法活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他依靠金融，但也以金融为食，”它补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明称范是“鲁莽”的人，是一个没有纪律和法律“底线”的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国驱逐前高级官员经济数据“造假”，收受“金钱、礼物”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;范某还被指控利用金融业职务为他人取得贷款，“非法收受大额财物”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“范一飞严重违反党的政治纪律、组织纪律、廉政纪律、工作纪律、生活纪律，构成严重违纪违法行为，涉嫌受贿罪，应当严肃处理，”中纪委表示。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，范的“非法”所得将被没收，并将“依法”受到起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的反腐行动使中国人民银行高级官员孙国锋陷入困境&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;范是一位资深银行家，在 2015 年成为中央银行副行长之前，他职业生涯的大部分时间都在中国建设银行度过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还是中国经济发展的关键推动者&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，中国人民银行货币政策司司长孙国峰被免职，目前正以涉嫌“严重违纪违法、违纪违法”接受纪律审查和监察调查。法律”——腐败的常见委婉说法。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s era? Top finance officials flex city’s offshore yuan hub muscles at Caixin summit, Shanghai’s Lujiazui Forum]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3223582/hong-kongs-era-top-finance-officials-flex-citys-offshore-yuan-hub-muscles-caixin-summit-shanghais?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 19:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/11fd6585-d45f-4e74-ae37-36581b6c942a_4ace5bcc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;陈茂波、梁凤仪、余伟文香港高级财政官员和克里斯托弗·许正宇重申了香港作为中国离岸金融中心的独特作用，称在北京和华盛顿之间的紧张局势没有缓和迹象之际，香港可以促进人民币国际化。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;香港准备在未来推出更多吸收离岸人民币的金融产品，加上即将推出的股票双币种交易柜台模式和掉期连接机制，Chan, Hong香港财政司司长周五在香港举行的 2023 年财新夏季峰会上说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管世界经济已经摆脱了 Covid-19 的阴影，但全球环境仍然复杂，”Chan 说. “正是在这样的时代，香港才能发挥对内对外合作平台的重要作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将继续改革和优化香港金融市场，深化与香港的互动内地金融市场，并在中国与世界各国首都之间建立联系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国挑战美元作为主导全球贸易和商品贸易的世界主要储备货币地位的雄心为香港提供了前所未有的重塑机会在 Covid-19 大流行期间与世界其他地区隔离三年后，它作为金融中心的形象发生了变化。包括巴西和沙特阿拉伯在内的30多个国家现已同意使用人民币进行贸易结算，对离岸市场的更多投资渠道产生巨大需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港已经是全球最大的离岸市场人民币，处理全球约 75% 的涉及该货币的结算。根据央行数据，截至 2022 年底，香港的离岸人民币存款为 1 万亿元人民币（1400 亿美元），而 2020 年为 7183 亿元人民币。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;双柜台提升香港的人民币中心地位, 改善流动性&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“人民币国际化的主要问题是美元不断加息，而人民币正在降息，”香港证券及期货事务监察委员会行政总裁梁振英（证监会），在财新峰会上表示。 “多年来，人民币的融资成本首次低于美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“硬币的另一面是地缘政治，各国开始尝试在商品中使用本币和人民币支付&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港金融管理局首席执行官 Yue 在同一场会议上表示，下一个可供选择的产品可能是满足对冲需求的中国政府债券离岸期货。与此同时，香港财经事务及库务局局长许在上海陆家嘴论坛上表示，人民币是资产配置的“必然选择”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“包括亚洲在内的更多地区正在考虑资产多元化分配，当美国利率大幅波动或飙升影响汇率时，”Hui 说。 “人民币是必然的选择。随着人民币成为多元资产配置的一部分，香港可以在很多方面做很多工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 表示，目前人民币在国际跨境支付和储备中的份额仅为 3%货币，这一地位与中国在对外贸易和经济中的规模不匹配。 SFC 的 Leung 表示，由于人民币相对于美元的融资成本优势，中国的低利率环境可能会促使更多公司通过出售人民币债券来更多地开拓离岸市场，从而为人民币国际化提供一个新窗口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;香港将于 6 月 19 日推出双币种股票交易柜台，本地和海外投资者可以在人民币和港元之间自由兑换选定的股票。该计划旨在促进离岸人民币的使用，已批准 21 只股票进行交易，例如中国科技巨头阿里巴巴集团控股（本报的母公司）和腾讯控股的股票。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;香港准备推动人民币国际化和技术创新：香港交易所&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港和中国内地监管机构也在讨论让境内投资者参与双币交易，此举可以挽救这些投资者汇率SFC 的 Leung 表示，成本并扩大人民币存入该市的资金池。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双货币交易柜台模式是在该市推出允许外国投资者参与的 Swap Connect 一个月后推出的在内地银行间金融衍生品市场尚属首次。香港也已经与内地建立了跨境联系计划，涵盖股票、债券和理财产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈说，香港将更多地转向亚洲市场，特别是东南亚和中东国家，因为贸易自由化和投资机会，因为它们的经济表现出比西方国家更强的弹性，而西方国家正面临更高的借贷成本和衰退威胁。证监会的梁说，与此同时，交易所运营商香港交易及结算所将进一步探索这两个地区的上市资源，许多公司有兴趣在香港上市。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;投资者关注香港随着 6 月倒计时的开始，股票没有货币焦虑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们希望与其他离岸人民币中心一起成长，并共同抓住这些机会，”香港金管局的 Yuen 在财新峰会上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望我们可以共同利用好香港市场的基础设施，促进跨境和离岸业务的创新和增长，打造更好的人民币生态系统，进一步推动其国际化进程。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea summons Beijing’s envoy Xing Haiming over US-China rivalry remarks]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3223584/south-korea-summons-beijings-envoy-xing-haiming-over-us-china-rivalry-remarks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 19:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/27365016-f9ab-4556-81bd-59843a267e57_aac0d9a3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国召见中国最高特使，讨论可能的“干涉内政”他警告首尔不要押注北京在两个超级大国的竞争中输给华盛顿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大使邢海明在中国大使馆举行的半小时会议上发表了上述评论，该国反对派领导人出席了会议 - 并与几位记者在场——在北京烤鸭闭门晚宴之前，滔滔不绝地讲了 13 分钟的布道，这引发了一场外交争端。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望韩国在处理与韩国的关系时能够避开外部干涉中国，”邢在宣读准备好的声明时说。在他旁边的是自由派反对党领袖李在明——保守派总统尹锡烈的宿敌——他在周四晚上的会议上在中国大使面前发表了讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在美国制造在全力扼杀中国的情况下，有人赌美国赢，中国输。但我可以肯定地说，那些打赌中国会输给美国的人肯定会后悔的，”邢说，当李大使用流利的韩语继续讲话时，他面无表情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;会议由李的民主党录制并上传到 YouTube。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邢显然是在呼应美国总统拜登的言论。那些希望美国生病的人应该知道，他在 2 月份的国情咨文演讲中说，“做空美国从来都不是一个好赌注”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邢的评论周四被当地媒体视为对尹政府的猛烈抨击，作为志同道合的国家联盟的一部分，以应对日益强硬的中国，尹政府正在与美国和日本拉近距离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chang Ho-jin韩国外交部第一副部长，周五召见中国大使，对他的“无理挑衅”言论表示“强烈遗憾”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Yoon 引导韩国远离中国、俄罗斯，转向美国、日本&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他“严正警告”邢的言论违反外交礼节，可能构成“干涉内政”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交部长朴振也批评了邢，称他“走得太远了”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有外交准则，大使的作用是增进友谊，而不是传播误解，”朴槿惠在首尔对记者说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统尹的人民力量党 (PPP) 也对一位议员所说的邢的“极端傲慢”表示愤怒，指责大使的行为就像中国在 1880 年代派往首尔的清朝特使袁世凯，成为一个具有巨大影响力的人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周四晚上的会议上，李明博表达了对首尔与其最大贸易伙伴北京日益增长的贸易逆差的担忧。韩国在 5 月份公布了 17.4 亿美元的贸易逆差，自 10 月以来连续亏损八个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee 还呼吁中国在应对朝鲜核威胁方面进行合作，并向 Xing 表达了他对不断恶化的担忧自一年前尹上任以来，中韩关系一直很紧张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邢说，恶化关系的责任不在北京，指责首尔未能遵守一个中国政策，这是一项承诺两国政府于 1992 年建立外交关系时作出的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还将韩国对中国不断增长的贸易逆差归咎于首尔寻求削减与北京的​​关系并与其他伙伴开展更多贸易的政策。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果韩国坚定对华合作的信念，适应中国市场和产业结构的变化，妥善制定对华投资战略，韩国将继续从中国经济增长中受益，”邢&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还建议韩国和中国共同努力，防止日本将遭受破坏的福岛核电站的放射性水排放到海洋中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了自身的经济利益，日本正在把太平洋变成污水库。这是一种极不负责任的行为，”邢说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的言论以及他与李在镕的会面激起了尹总统执政的人民力量党 (PPP) 的愤怒反应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;议员申元- sik 周五告诉党内官员，邢“发表了粗鲁的言论”，就好像他是 19 世纪的袁世凯一样。 “他不仅谴责我们的政府，还嘲笑它。这是极度傲慢的表现，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人民党发言人 Kang Min-kuk 进一步追溯过去，在一份声明中说，李与邢的会面提醒人们韩国人屈辱的投降1630 年代的国王，他不得不将头撞在地上，直到他在入侵的清朝皇帝脚下流血。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PPP 议会领袖 Yun Jae-ok 说李的反对党应该敦促北京处理中国东部沿海的 55 座核电站释放出具有放射性的氚。他说，这些工厂释放的氚比福岛的释放量高 50 倍。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Rich second generation’: Chinese woman conned out of nearly US$3 million by ‘lover’ who claimed to come from wealthy family]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3223138/rich-second-generation-chinese-woman-conned-out-nearly-us3-million-lover-who-claimed-come-wealthy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/f17f4857-72d0-43f0-9953-b94a3d66afb0_078520db.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一场爱情骗局，一名中国女性骗取了 2000 万元人民币（美国280 万美元）一名冒充富家子弟的男子在大陆社交媒体上引发了讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 12 月，这名姓江的女子在网上认识了一名男子，该男子告诉她他的名字是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位准情人说他来自一个显赫的富裕家庭，拥有一家私募股权基金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;起初持怀疑态度，蒋利用她的个人关系进行了严格的背景调查。她收集到的所有信息似乎都证实了这个男人的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着她对孙某的信任加强，他们建立了坚定的关系，并计划去见对方的父母。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙某甚至告诉她：“这段时间我会赚更多的钱，然后我们就可以实现财务自由。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还吹嘘自己的投资技巧，以及他如何获得可靠的内幕消息，说服江注册了一个应用程序&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在两次成功交易后，又收到了孙某慷慨的99万美元，江心安心投入了2000万元，这次是用自己的现金&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1 月，也就是他们第一次在网上认识一个月后，一位朋友揭露了 Sun 故事中的不一致之处，当她无法再通过货币交易应用程序取钱时，Jiang 意识到&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她立即报了警。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经调查，一名同伙姓李，是一名兼职在线软件开发人员，同时也在开发货币交易应用程序。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李告诉警方，他只是遵从了孙的要求，改进了应用程序的功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了为自己辩护，李说：“我只是一名员工。如果我不做，别人会做。我无法阻止欺诈的发生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据了解，李从该计划中获利超过 80,000 元人民币（11,000 美元），他被判处一年零 10 个月的监禁，试用期两年零六个月，并处一万元罚款。如果雇主不雇用我，他会雇用其他人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，如果没有您的贡献，犯罪活动就不会进行得如此顺利。你的行为实际上助长了犯罪，”一位人士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人对蒋的损失感到悲痛，也有人对她的巨额财富表示惊讶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位观察者说：“她怎么可能智商这么低，就积累了2000万元？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;网络爱情骗局，俗称“杀猪盘”，在中国猖獗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年12月，一名上海女子在长达 12 年的诈骗中被一位冒充知名电视新闻主播的老朋友骗走近 200 万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年，北京警方破获了一名 18-缅甸人团伙骗取中国各地50余名受害人近千万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球反诈骗组织对240名受骗者的调查显示，此类骗局平均损失金额案件价值 98,000 美元，70% 的受害者是女性。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba Cloud wins deal with Chinese coal giant in push to woo more state-owned clients]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3223546/alibaba-cloud-wins-deal-chinese-coal-giant-push-woo-more-state-owned-clients?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/21db04ed-eef9-4141-9c27-2f8dea7acf3c_184c1a11.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴集团控股的数字技术部门阿里云智能宣布了一项新的作为云计算服务提供商，与中国矿业巨头陕煤化工集团建立合作伙伴关系，加大力度赢得国有企业客户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由阿里云支持的西部能源云平台旨在根据周四在阿里云微信公众号上发布的一篇文章，加快中国西部能源行业的数字化——总部位于西安的陕西煤炭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该战略举措标志着朝着加强运营迈出的重要一步文章称，该行业的效率和驱动可持续增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望与陕西煤炭密切合作，探索大[语言]模型时代的新能源平台，”曾振宇说，阿里云副总裁。 “By integrating industry-specific large models with business systems and processes, we aim to drive innovation in business intelligence.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The launch event was also attended by Huang Xiaolong, deputy director of the National Industrial Information Security Development Research Centre, and Huang Xinbo, deputy director of Shaanxi&#39;s provincial industry and information technology department.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Alibaba Cloud is the largest cloud service provider in China, it lags Huawei Cloud in the government cloud service market, according to a recent report by research firm IDC. Huawei Cloud is also working with Shaanxi Coal in a variety of projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite its leading position in the overall market, Alibaba Cloud saw its sales fall 2 per cent year on year to 18.6 billion yuan (US$2.6 billion) in the first quarter of this year, contributing 9 per cent of Alibaba Group&#39;s total revenue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Group chairman and CEO Daniel Zhang Yong, who took direct control of Alibaba Cloud in December, attributed the decline partly to “external changes” in “customer composition”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As part of Alibaba Group&#39;s largest-ever corporate restructuring, which was announced in March, Alibaba Cloud will be spun off into an independently-run entity along with five other units, each potentially seeking their own fundraising avenues, such as through initial public offerings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under a plan unveiled last month, Alibaba will spin off its cloud business within a year through a “stock dividend distribution to shareholders” and turn the unit into an “independent publicly-listed company”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba is the owner of the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The question marks over China’s next big Mideast peacemaking efforts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223557/question-marks-over-chinas-next-big-mideast-peacemaking-efforts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 17:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/92d7c390-35b2-4b17-a1b3-9fa4bff5976c_e0145d97.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing will need to make more political and security commitments if it is serious about deeper engagement with the Middle East and solving some of the region&#39;s long-standing problems, according to observers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an online discussion organised by the think tank the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace on Thursday, analysts said that while countries in the region had responded positively to China&#39;s recent engagement, there was still a question mark about how big a role Beijing could play.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, China helped broker a landmark peace deal between regional rivals Saudi Arabia and Iran, with Tehran and Riyadh restoring diplomatic relations for the first time in seven years. President Xi Jinping was reportedly directly involved in realising the agreement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A month later, Chinese Foreign Minister Qin Gang said Beijing was ready to help with peace talks between Israel and the Palestinians.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The engagement came after Xi attended two inaugural summits with Arab states and the Gulf Cooperation Council in Saudi Arabia late last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For many, the agreement was a clear sign of China&#39;s growing influence in a region where the United States has been the main external player.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But analysts on the Carnegie forum&#39;s panel said it was still unclear how committed Beijing was to handling security issues, and whether it had the resources needed for the Middle East.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yu Jie, a senior research fellow in the Asia-Pacific programme at Chatham House, said China&#39;s pool of Middle East expertise was smaller than its reserves of US foreign policy or European studies specialists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So even though China has the intention of playing a much bigger role, you still need the capability and capacity to sustain that level of ambition,” Yu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The panel also questioned how committed China was to enforcing the terms of the Saudi-Iran deal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the main terms was that all parties agreed in principle to non-interference in each other&#39;s affairs. But Saudi Arabia and Iran have used proxy forces against each other, such as the civil war in Yemen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Should either party renege … what China will do is not very clear,” said Maha Yahya, the director of the Malcolm H. Kerr Carnegie Middle East Centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t see China at this point moving in for security [purposes].&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That&#39;s not its usual MO, and despite the shift in its foreign policy it doesn&#39;t have the hardware in the region to do this.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How China&#39;s Saudi-Iran deal shows Beijing&#39;s Mideast influence&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Participants also raised doubts about how effective China could be in brokering an acceptable peace solution between the Israelis and the Palestinians.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yahya said that unlike the rivalry between Saudi Arabia and Iran, the balance of power between the Israelis and Palestinians was “asymmetrical”, and would require China to deploy “significant political capital” to force the two sides to negotiate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have not seen any moves by China to move in that direction,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But China does benefit from a lack of “historical baggage” in the Middle East, according to panellist Benjamin Ho, an assistant professor at the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies&#39; China programme in Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ho said China did not have any disagreements such as territorial disputes in the region, giving it a “neutral slate” for engagement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[But] they recognise the Middle East is a far more complicated region, with history that spans thousands of years,” Ho said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So I don&#39;t think the Chinese are under any illusions that they&#39;re going there in a big way and to sort of change the regional architecture or the situation.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Healthcare voucher sharing scheme for elderly will be policed to prevent fraud, Legco told]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3223558/healthcare-voucher-sharing-scheme-elderly-will-be-policed-prevent-fraud-legco-told?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 17:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/78d2be67-1d95-442a-8d9f-bc4ba8b147e5_86623b50.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A review system is to be set up to stop Hong Kong elderly people abusing a new scheme to allow spouses to share healthcare vouchers, legislators have heard.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The news came at a meeting of the Legislative Council, the city&#39;s key decision-making body, on Friday after lawmakers questioned whether the vouchers could be misused.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Are there any mechanisms to prevent issues such as using the same identity to register for several accounts? Or if your identity was registered by someone else unknowingly?” Chan Hoi-yan asked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Dr Libby Lee Ha-yun, the acting health secretary, said that steps would be taken to prevent fraud.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If an elderly person is using the balance of their spouse&#39;s account, they would also need to present a copy of the spouse&#39;s identity card,” Lee explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that after each use of the spouse&#39;s voucher, an SMS would be texted to the user as well as their partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Department of Health would also monitor a series of data, especially any abnormal circumstances. For example, an elderly person might have registered [a spouse&#39;s account] two to three times … or change a few [spouses] in a year,” Lee said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The revamped healthcare voucher programme, which will be launched next month, was designed to let spouses share each others allocations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government said it would encourage elderly people to “make better use of each other&#39;s voucher entitlement” to access private primary healthcare services.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong couples to be allowed to share elderly healthcare vouchers from July&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Couples will be required to declare their marital status when they register for the sharing arrangement and present their identity cards, but do not need to show a marriage certificate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When someone has used up the HK$2,000 (US$255) in their own account, he or she can start to use their partner&#39;s credit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Lee warned couples would be subject to legal liability after they made the declaration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Department of Health will also conduct reviews,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The voucher accounts will be linked until one of a couple submits a written application to end the arrangement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A three-year pilot reward scheme will also be introduced later this year where users who spend at least HK$1,000 from their voucher account on designated services, such as specific health assessments and chronic disease screening, would be credited with an extra HK$500 for the same purpose.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong primary healthcare reforms, greater elderly subsidies &#39;a right step&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;More than 11,600 healthcare providers had registered for the programme by May and about 1.56 million elderly people had used the vouchers – 97 per cent of the total eligible population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The amount of vouchers claimed last year was HK$2.5 billion, a decrease from the HK$2.8 billion recorded in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawmakers also used the Legco panel meeting to ask the authorities whether the healthcare vouchers could be used to cover premiums for medical insurance in mainland China, a popular retirement destination for Hongkongers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The mainland has a clear system on medical insurance. Is it necessary to study [the system] for that long?” Kingsley Wong Kwok asked. “How should we connect with the policies in the mainland? It seems that the mainland is in the fast lane and Hong Kong is in the slow lane.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee told him the healthcare voucher scheme was created to allow elderly people to receive primary care services, but mainland medical insurance was designed more for inpatient care costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eddie Lee Lik-kong, the deputy health secretary, explained that the authorities were still collecting information on the coverage offered by medical insurance schemes in a variety of mainland provinces.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Turkey’s Erdogan names ex-Wall Street banker as head of central bank]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3223561/turkeys-erdogan-names-ex-wall-street-banker-head-central-bank?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 17:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/54aa7bc1-cae3-4fc0-ab8e-dfb1bcb68c8e_99ace2c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan appointed former Wall Street executive Hafize Gaye Erkan as central bank governor on Friday, signalling a possible shift from his unconventional policies to fight soaring inflation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erkan – a former chief executive of US real estate finance firm Greystone, co-CEO of First Republic Bank and managing director at Goldman Sachs – will be the first woman to head the central bank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She takes over from Sahap Kavcioglu, who lowered rates even though central banks worldwide have done the opposite to fight inflation. Her appointment was published in the official gazette on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Saudi Arabia deposits US$5 billion in Turkish central bank&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Under Kavcioglu&#39;s watch, the bank&#39;s policy rate was decreased to 8.5 per cent. It had been at 19 per cent in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turkey&#39;s inflation rate dropped below 40 per cent in May for the first time in 16 months. Independent economists believe it is much higher, above 100 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan, who was re-elected to a third term in office last month, already signalled a shift on Saturday when he unveiled a new cabinet with Mehmet Simsek, a former Merrill Lynch economist, as finance minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Simsek – who worked as finance minister and deputy prime minister in the past ruling AKP governments – is known to oppose Erdogan&#39;s unconventional policies of lowering interest rates to fight inflation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts say investors are less interested in how talented the new economic team is than in their ability to resist pressure from Erdogan, who once called high rates “the mother and father of all evil”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Simsek &amp; Erkan will be judged on monetary policy moves, inflation and lira,” emerging markets economist Timothy Ash said on Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Turkish lira was down 1.6 per cent against the dollar on Friday, after falling to a new low on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of Erkan&#39;s main challenges this year will be to repair the working atmosphere at the central bank, according to Erik Meyersson, chief emerging markets strategist.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Too many bright economists and bureaucrats were purged, reassigned, demoted, ostracised, and there&#39;s a talent reserve that she should look to tap into. But would they want to return?” he tweeted.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Despite lira woes, Turkey may be right to cut interest rates&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Erdogan in the past sacked central bank governors after disagreements over interest rate policy, in a move that unsettled investors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After taking office, Simsek said Turkey had “no choice but to return to rational ground” – a sign of turning away from the low-rate policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As we navigate through domestic and international challenges, we affirm our commitment to rules based policymaking to enhance predictability,” Simsek said on Twitter after the lira fell this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While there are no short cuts or quick fixes, rest assured that our experience, knowledge &amp; dedication will help us overcome potential impediments ahead,” he tweeted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our immediate priority is to strengthen our team and design a credible programme.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erkan was born in Turkey and graduated from Istanbul&#39;s top Bogazici University. She earned a PhD scholarship to Princeton.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She joined Goldman Sachs in 2005 as an associate and was named managing director in 2011.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She later worked at First Republic Bank in 2014 where she earned the titles of senior vice-president, chief investment officer and co-chief risk officer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was seen as the heir apparent to the bank&#39;s founder and long-time CEO, Jim Herbert, but abruptly resigned in December 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was time for a change and for a new challenge,” Erkan told Bloomberg Television last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bank was embroiled in the US banking crisis in March this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US regulators seize First Republic Bank and sell it to JPMorgan Chase&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;US financial authorities seized First Republic in May and sold it to JPMorgan Chase, hoping to bring an end to turmoil that brought down three other regional banks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erkan was appointed chief executive of Greystone in June 2022, but she resigned in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The firm said at the time that her departure was “amicable” and “related to her decision to focus on new opportunities in the financial sector”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>