<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[US voice actors warn of rampant AI threat at Comic-Con cultural event]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228607/us-voice-actors-warn-rampant-ai-threat-comic-con-cultural-event?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 23:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/4cd87f8f-7766-433f-90e5-3963f3540 b89_990c6c1a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;谈到人工智能，世界上一些最受欢迎的动画和视频游戏的配音演员在本周的动漫展上发出警告，“潘多拉魔盒已打开”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界上最大的流行文化聚会之一正在好莱坞大罢工期间举行，部分原因是演员和作家对人工智能侵蚀艺术的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vo配音演员处于争论的最前沿，现在的技术允许用户克隆某人的声音并让它读取新的对话 - 通常无需他们的许可或付费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国配音演员协会的创始人蒂姆·弗里德兰德（Tim Friedlander）分享了一个最近的例子，一名配音演员在一家公司工作了三年，但突然失去了工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们说‘我们有你三年的声音 – 我们只是要根据我们已有的声音创建一个人工智能合成声音，’”弗里德兰德在周六的小组讨论之前告诉媒体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;危险不仅仅来自工作室。在过去的几年里，使用人工智能“deepfake mods”来克隆著名声音并让他们阅读新材料（通常是色情内容）的粉丝急剧增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我有孩子。有些事情我不想让我的声音说出，让我的孩子们听到并质疑这是否是我真正说过的话。”动画电视连续剧《猫头鹰之家》的西西·琼斯 (Cissy Jones) 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;好莱坞因演员与编剧一起进行历史性罢工而关闭&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;泽克·奥尔顿 (Zeke Alton) 的声音最近出现在视频游戏《卡利斯托协议》中，他表示配音演员并没有试图完全禁止人工智能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“让我们明确一点 - 潘多拉星球盒子是打开的”，他说。 “如果你要复制我或任何其他表演者，我们应该同意这一点，然后我们应该因为使用我们赚钱的东西而得到补偿。”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人工智能是好莱坞电影公司和美国演员工会 (SAG-AFTRA) 之间谈判陷入僵局的一个关键症结所在，该协会本月加入了编剧罢工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;演员们指责电影公司未能认真对待这些担忧，这些担忧将使他们“很容易被数字化取代”复制品。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工作室周五表示，当表演者或其声音制作“数字复制品”时，他们已提出知情同意和公平补偿，但工会没有回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SAG-AFTRA 首席谈判代表邓肯·克拉布特里-爱尔兰 (Duncan Crabtree-Ireland) 在动漫展上告诉记者，工作室希望“在 12 页合同中间的某个句子中“埋葬”人工智能同意条款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V他警告说，配音演员处于人工智能辩论的“最前沿”，“配音表演的变化比任何其他领域都更快。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，工作室正在探索人工智能将对话配音成外语，这将使世界各地的配音演员失去对当地市场有价值的工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个担忧是工作室可以使用融合多个人类声音的“合成”声音，而不向任何原始演员支付报酬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此令人愤怒的是，目前并非所有配音工作都受到罢工的影响，因为有些配音工作是根据单独的工会合同进行谈判的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;禁止为动画中的角色配音、宣布预告片或为电影或电视场景中的背景演员添加对话，这是一种非常常见的做法，称为“循环”或 ADR（自动对话替换）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但视频游戏的配音工作受到“互动”媒体的单独工会合同的约束，该合同的谈判仍在进行中，因此仍然可以在没有罢工的情况下进行。打破罢工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，奥尔顿警告说，“这次罢工所发生的事情不仅会影响演艺界，而且会影响每个职业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“演员就是演员就是演员。因此，如果我们在本次罢工结束时没有受到本合同的保护，那么我们就不会受到任何合同的保护。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong junior ice hockey team to be punished over brawl with Thai players at Bangkok match, sports body says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3228603/hong-kong-junior-ice-hockey-team-be-punished-over-brawl-thai-players-bangkok-match-sports-body-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 22:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/6847e2a6-66a8-4882-9121-1a7c7e88 8460_be59b956.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港体育协会表示，香港18岁以下男子冰球队的队员在海外比赛中与泰国队员发生冲突后将面临“惩罚和警告”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一段在推特上疯传的视频显示，尽管裁判尽了最大努力，但在曼谷举行的一场邀请赛结束后，两支球队的约30名球员仍互相斗殴。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港冰球总会一向重视运动员纪律，目前正与赛事主办方调查此事。”泰国以3-0战胜香港两天后，香港冰球总会周六表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“双方涉及事件的运动员都会受到处罚和警告。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港最高体育机构向冰球总会发出书面谴责&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该协会表示，在这场混战中没有人受伤，但补充说，涉事球员必须“培养情绪管理能力”，以避免今后再次发生类似事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;体育联合会和奥委会发言人表示，在协会发表声明后，他们已经意识到这一事件，并正在与冰球机构保持联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合会要求协会在8月20日之前提交一份情况报告，其中应包括对涉事运动员的处罚以及概述如何防止事件再次发生的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;男子冰球队成员瑞安·朱泽海 (Ryan Chu Chak-hay) 在接受《华盛顿邮报》采访时表示，某些职业联赛有时会允许打架，主要是北美的联赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但没有参加曼谷比赛的朱泽海表示，视频中看到的赛后斗殴行为很少见。他说，他看到一段视频，显示两名球员在排队握手时发生扭打，该视频是由一名参与打斗的运动员发布的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[通常]他们会给予停赛处罚，”他说。 “传统上，在曲棍球比赛中，职业联赛中的战斗是一对一的，摘下头盔，摘下手套。但在这次事件中，每个人都戴着头盔。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在网上发布的 43 秒视频中，双方球员都穿着球衣和头盔，在冰场上互相殴打，还有一些人拿着棍子。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;部长警告说，结束香港国歌惨败的争吵并改进&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港冰球管理机构在 3 月份成为头条新闻，当时一首与2019年的一场世界冠军赛中，没有播放中国国歌《义勇军进行曲》，而是播放了2019年的反政府抗议活动。香港冰球总会与该市最高体育总会就这一错误的责任问题发生争执。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;体育总会表示，目前还不清楚冰球队是否向赛事组织者提供了国歌的硬拷贝，此举本可以避免混淆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据联合会去年11月发布的指导方针，如果国家体育协会被发现对滥用冰球协会负责，他们可能会失去其委员会成员资格或政府资助。国际比赛期间奏国歌或市旗。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Quantum entanglement: how US-led sanctions are turning Russia’s genius scientists to China for collaboration]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3228292/quantum-entanglement-how-us-led-sanctions-are-turning-russias-genius-scientists-china-collaboration?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/df7c5861-7dc0-4965-8845-8b6cda50dd9 1_5ded6645.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Maxim Ostras 的量子传感器能够以创纪录的高灵敏度检测大脑信号。在俄罗斯最大银行的支持下，他计划将传感器投入商业化生产并进入中国市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alexey Akimov 对元素周期表中的一些异常现象很感兴趣，他认为这些异常现象可能会导致新材料的发现。他去年放弃了美国的终身教职，回到俄罗斯追求量子模拟器的梦想，其中一些关键部件来自中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年前，阿列克谢·费多罗夫（Alexey Fedorov）受委托在俄罗斯建立新一代量子实验室，当时他还是一名大学四年级学生。现在，作为莫斯科物理技术学院历史上最年轻的正教授，费多罗夫正在与一些中国研究人员在量子算法和密码学方面密切合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说：“世界将因这些技术而改变。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月，数百名俄罗斯科学家在莫斯科未来技术论坛上与国际同行会面，分享量子研究的最新突破，这三人是其中之一。让许多与会者惊讶的是，俄罗斯总统普京甚至出现在7月13日莫斯科世界贸易中心的一场小组讨论中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是我第一次在量子会议上见到国家元首。人们排起了长队进入会议室，想亲自见到他。”一位参加活动的中国量子科学家说道，但与其他中国研究人员一样，由于北京的媒体政策，他要求不透露姓名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京在向来自俄罗斯和印度、澳大利亚、法国和德国等其他国家的科学家发表讲话时，宣布了一项雄心勃勃的计划，即到 2030 年将俄罗斯转变为数据驱动型经济，其中量子驱动的计算机、通信网络、传感器和卫星将在该国的数字基础设施中发挥重要作用。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在一些国家的当局和统治精英宣布对俄罗斯实施实际封锁的情况下发展国际科技合作，”普京说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们确实面临着限制我们获得技术的压力和企图，这些技术旨在迫使我们放弃主权和自己选择历史道路的权利。我们的对手希望我们撤退和投降，但正如我们在这种情况下经常说的那样，这是不会发生的。俄罗斯只会继续前进，走自己的路，但不会同时孤立任何人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说：“我们打算与其他国家建立和扩大互利的技术和科学联盟，让每个人都享有平等的权利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯提议通过金砖国家共同开发量子和其他未来技术。金砖国家是由巴西、俄罗斯、印度、中国和南非组成的新兴国家集团，由2009年组成。普京表示，这些国家的人口合计占世界人口的近一半，而且比七国集团发达国家的经济影响力更大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我想指出的是，随着俄罗斯明年担任金砖国家主席国，我们预计将与我们的合作伙伴在几个重要领域讨论此类具体项目，包括尖端计算技术以及数据处理、存储和传输技术。”普京表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国科学家推出第一台实用计算机，实现巨大飞跃&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;制裁以美国为首的科学家在俄罗斯和中国科学家之间建立了新的联系。但就像物理学中的量子纠缠一样，俄罗斯与其他国家，特别是中国之间的量子合作可能是复杂的、具有挑战性的，有时会因为外部干扰而变得脆弱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一方面，俄罗斯和乌克兰之间的战区离莫斯科并不远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我实际上觉得这里很安全，”一位中国参与者说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的一些同事很想来，但最终出于安全考虑而取消了行程。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是量子技术合作的好处球体使科学家面临的挑战变得值得。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;量子技术是在原子水平上控制单个粒子的能力。它可以用来制造具有前所未有的性能的超高速计算机、超安全通信和侦探仪器，可以给经济、社会和军事行动带来颠覆性变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是量子科学家需要大量尖端设备来进行实验。没有哪个实验室能够独自建造所有必要的设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对于在俄罗斯工作的科学家来说尤其具有挑战性，因为俄罗斯几乎受到西方国家的全面制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去，俄罗斯量子实验室的设备主要从西方采购。但近年来，他们转向了中国——据阿基莫夫称，他们几乎没有兴趣回头看。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果中国组件能以一小部分价格做同样甚至更好的工作，我为什么要这么做呢？”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国声称的量子密码破译算法引发了美国的怀疑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国在量子技术方面取得了一些巨大成就，包括世界上第一颗量子卫星、最长的陆地量子通信网络以及一些可用的最强大的量子计算机。同样面临美国制裁的中国科学家在国内已经建立了或多或少完整的量子技术供应链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们花了很多年测试来自许多不同供应商的产品。这不是一件容易的事。中国有很多供应商，你不知道哪一家能做得最好，”一位中国量子物理学家说道。 “我们已向俄罗斯同事介绍了我们最好的供应商。这为他们省去了很多麻烦。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这些合作的细节不能透露，因为与俄罗斯合作的科学家或公司可能成为美国政府的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们来之前，中国当局向我们通报了要守口如瓶的情况。我什至拒绝了俄罗斯媒体的采访请求。”这位中国科学家说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国正在与美国争夺量子竞赛的头把交椅，但它有一个重大劣势。目前使用的大多数量子算法都是在美国开发的，如果北京和华盛顿之间的紧张局势进一步恶化，这可能会成为一个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯科学家自苏联时期以来一直在研究量子物理学的理论问题。他们因解决该领域一些最基本的问题而获得了六项诺贝尔奖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Federov 的团队一直遵循传统，开发了一些用于量子计算和通信的独特算法。他们已经在俄罗斯的16量子位量子计算机上测试了这些算法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但中国的量子计算机规模比俄罗斯大得多。 Federov 的团队访问了中国北京、上海、武汉和成都等城市的量子设施，以建立联合研究项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Federov 说：“合作非常重要，因为我们一起可以做出单独很难完成的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Federov 的团队成员希望在中国更大的机器上测试他们的算法。他们还参观了印度的一些量子研究设施，印度政府最近宣布了一项雄心勃勃的计划，要建造一台 1,000 量子位的量子计算机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们与科学家进行了多次会议，我们看到了很大的合作潜力。从我的角度来看，答案非常非常实用。我们需要创建金砖国家量子实验室。我们需要继续提高复杂性，并在金砖国家量子实验室等通用组织中开展工作，以协调量子通信的标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ostras 看到了中国的量子传感器的潜在市场，这种传感器可以检测大脑产生的极微弱的磁信号。超灵敏磁性探测器通常需要冷却到极低的温度才能正常工作，但它们的传感器利用稀土元素钇的一些独特特性，在室温下也能表现良好。这为许多潜在应用打开了大门，例如脑部疾病的早期检测和监测。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;得益于俄罗斯科学家在这项技术上超过 25 年的持续研究，Ostras 表示，“我们的传感器的潜在价格比竞争对手低 100 倍”，但灵敏度却高出 300 倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯量子中心的联合创始人鲁斯兰·尤努索夫 (Ruslan Yunusov) 表示，俄罗斯量子中心是一家引领俄罗斯量子研究发展的非营利性研究组织。俄罗斯科学家在量子科学领域的实力被低估了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有多少人知道，但俄罗斯的量子物理学派非常非常成功，非常强大。我认为这就是这些合作的基础。”尤努索夫说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在我们在俄罗斯和中国之间开展了一些共同项目……也许距离今年不远，中国和俄罗斯之间将会就如何建立这样一个平台进行一些部级层面的讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“科学界并不是那么庞大；人们彼此认识。中国和俄罗斯的科学家已经开始合作。因此，我们需要高层的支持。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金砖国家量子联盟预计将面临其自身的挑战。据俄罗斯一些科学家估计，中国在这一领域领先俄罗斯10年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度没有量子计算机，其第一个量子网络刚刚建成并运行几个月。巴西和南非的研究也处于早期阶段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不平等的地位可能会产生一些政治问题，例如维护欠发达国家的技术主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位中国科学家表示，也存在一些阻碍合作的制度障碍。例如在中国，研究人员可以自行订购设备，只要在研究预算之内。但俄罗斯科学家需要获得政府的批准，这可能需要一年或更长时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我在莫斯科的一位同事已经等待设备三年了。这与制裁无关。”这位中国科学家表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;也可能存在一些政治挑战。中国和印度几十年来一直存在边界争端。一些参加莫斯科会议的印度科学家表示，目前中印之间在量子研究方面没有合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但两国科学家之间的交流日益增多，他们表示，如果新德里和北京之间的紧张局势缓和，人们会抓住任何合作的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有人担心金砖国家量子联盟会加剧与西方的对抗，从而分裂世界，这对科学没有好处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但俄罗斯科学院院长根纳季·克拉斯尼科夫(Gennady Krasnikov)科学部部长表示，中国、印度和其他国家之间的合作不是为了战斗，而是为了团结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不知道有哪个科学联盟是在反对某事。任何科学联盟的成立主要是为了解决某项科学任务。”克拉斯尼科夫说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;制裁可以减缓某项科学研究或计划的进展。然而，他说：“基础科学根本没有国界。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Massive angry protests across India over women paraded naked and assaulted in Manipur state]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3228600/massive-angry-protests-india-over-women-paraded-naked-and-assaulted-manipur-state?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 21:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/f4010b26-75cc-4509-b4d7-03d88ec46aba _25e20367.j​​pg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周六，数千人（其中大部分是女性）在印度东北部饱受暴力蹂躏的曼尼普尔邦举行大规模静坐，要求立即逮捕那些参与暴徒袭击两名裸体妇女的惨案的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宗教和妇女组织领导人向近 15,000 名抗议者发表讲话，他们还呼吁解雇最高领导人比伦·辛格 (Biren Singh)。自 5 月初两个主要民族之间爆发暴力以来，该州已有 130 多人被杀。抗议活动在距离该州首府因帕尔以南 65 公里处的丘拉昌德普尔 (Churachandpur) 小镇举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一段显示妇女遭受袭击的视频引发了巨大的愤怒，并在周三晚间在社交媒体上广泛传播，尽管互联网基本上被封锁，记者也被禁止进入这个偏远的州。视频显示，两名裸体妇女被数十名年轻男子包围，他们摸索她们的生殖器，并将她们拖到田野上。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在观看裸体游行视频后，愤怒的印度妇女烧毁了两名嫌疑人的房屋&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方表示，袭击发生在 5 月 4 日，即暴力事件开始的第二天。根据警方 5 月 18 日提交的起诉书，这两名妇女所在的家庭遭到暴徒袭击，两名男性成员被杀害。投诉指控“身份不明的歹徒”强奸和谋杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;州政府周六宣布逮捕第五名嫌疑人。该邦警察局长拉吉夫·辛格表示，警方正在开展突袭行动，逮捕其他嫌疑人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曼尼普尔邦一直是一场近乎内战的现场，这场战争的起因是克里斯蒂安·库基斯 (Christian Kukis) 抗议以印度教徒为主的迈泰人 (Meiteis) 要求获得特殊地位，让他们在库基斯和其他部落群体居住的山区购买土地，并保证获得政府工作份额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管有军队，但冲突仍然持续存在。曼尼普尔邦是一个拥有 320 万人口的邦，位于印度与缅甸边境的山区，现已分为两个民族区。超过6万人逃往拥挤的救援营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近400名男女也在印度首都举行抗议活动，提出类似要求。他们举着标语牌，上面写着“我们要求对肇事者采取行动”和“比伦·辛格辞职”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在曼尼普尔邦，抗议者聚集在库基部落据点 Churachandpur 空地上的纪念墙，他们在那里安放了在暴力事件中丧生的少数民族社区成员的假棺材。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;库基妇女人权组织主席 Ngaineikim 指责辛属于梅蒂族多数群体的 h 策划了暴行，然后对受害者表示同情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辛格没有立即发表评论，但周四表示，正在进行调查，以确保“对所有肇事者采取严厉行动，包括考虑死刑的可能性。”让大家知道，我们的社会绝对不允许这种令人发指的行为。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China urges resumption of grain, fertiliser exports from Ukraine and Russia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228596/china-urges-resumption-grain-fertiliser-exports-ukraine-and-russia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/9a9d30fc-29c6-494c-9068-c27a5ce64 95f_a76af0fb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在确保黑海船舶安全的贸易协定破裂后，中国呼吁尽快恢复乌克兰和俄罗斯的粮食和化肥出口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国常驻联合国副代表耿爽周五在联合国安理会讨论中表示，所有相关国家需要共同努力，化解僵局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[各国需要]据中国代表团网站上的文字记录显示，耿爽表示，“共同努力……加快对话协商，平衡解决各方合理关切，早日恢复粮食和化肥出口”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，此举“有利于维护国际粮食安全，特别是有利于缓解发展中国家粮食危机”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耿爽还指出，“近期发生了针对重大民用基础设施的袭击事件”，并呼吁各方保持冷静，防止冲突进一步蔓延。进一步升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰粮食协议的破裂目前不会对全球粮食供应造成太大影响&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在莫斯科周一决定退出一年前由联合国和土耳其斡旋的黑海协议后，他提出了上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议允许乌克兰粮食通过其黑海港口安全地运往中国等客户，而中国的大部分玉米来自乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但当乌克兰袭击了关键的刻赤大桥时，情况发生了变化。连接克里米亚半岛和俄罗斯大陆的俄罗斯供应线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后，俄罗斯多次对乌克兰黑海港口发动导弹袭击，扰乱了运往中国的农产品出口，并损坏了中国驻敖德萨领事馆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四的袭击中没有领事馆工作人员受伤，北京当时表示正在密切关注事态发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰的港口是世界上小麦、玉米和葵花籽油出口的最重要路线之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰是谷物和油籽的生产大国，俄罗斯和乌克兰都是小麦的主要出口国，根据基辅的数据，战前它们的产量合计约占所有小麦出口的 30%，约占所有玉米出口的 18%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国并未谴责俄罗斯的入侵，但最近表示有兴趣扩大与乌克兰的贸易关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周在北京，商务部副部长凌吉告诉乌克兰副总理塔拉斯·卡奇卡 (Taras Kachka)。经济部长表示，北京愿与基辅“积极”发展双边经贸合作。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong plan for public housing at luxury golf course may be delayed for years if court accepts legal challenge, experts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3228598/hong-kong-plan-public-housing-luxury-golf-course-may-be-delayed-years-if-court-accepts-legal?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 21:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/41d57897-f2c8-44a7-bdb1-176f3ca78c 9d_730b9a54.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港领导人的一位高级顾问和一位环境保护专家警告说，如果法院批准对环境影响评估报告进行司法审查的申请，香港高尔夫球会可能会迫使其最古老的球场的公共住房开发项目推迟数年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，一位资深政治评论员还表示，这场长期斗争的最新转折表明，政府经常难以说服强大的利益相关者支持其一些最紧迫的政策举措.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府关键决策行政会议成员、俱乐部会员、高级大律师唐嘉华告诉《华盛顿邮报》，法律质疑可能会集中在编写报告所涉及的程序是否导致批准不合法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，如果司法复核申请获得批准，法庭诉讼可能需要“至少一到两年”，并敦促政府考虑其他地点建屋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个项目涉及的单位不多。” s。我很难相信政府不能使用争议较少的其他用地。”他说，并强调该建议引起了对交通、环境和体育赛事中断的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐还指出，该计划是在政府决定推进两个将建造110万个新住宅的大型项目之前提出的，这两个项目分别是沿中国大陆边境的北都新城发展和要求建造三座人工岛的“明日大屿愿景”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俱​​乐部周五透露，它将求助于法院试图阻止政府在 9.5 公顷土地上建造公寓的计划，其余 32 公顷保留用于保护和娱乐用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港高尔夫球俱乐部向法院提起诉讼，试图阻止在最古老的球场建造住房计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该俱乐部拥有该市一些最有权势的政界人士和商界领袖，表示将对评估过程中的“错误”和“违规”提出质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;当局最初打算在该地点建造12,000套房屋，但在环保局局长在批准影响评估报告时呼吁保护一小片林地后，这一数字将被修改。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府对合法投标的消息采取了挑衅的语气，称城市规划委员会将在周一的预定会议上继续处理该提案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位不愿透露姓名的熟悉法院诉讼程序的人士表示，法院通常需要一周的时间来决定是否允许专家表示，如果获得司法审查申请，法官可以要求举行听证会，然后再做出裁决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果获得许可，但一方试图质疑该决定，则可能需要 12 至 18 个月的时间来解决上诉并发布最终裁决，但如果事情紧急，案件可能会更快处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长青会竞选官员 Roy Ng Hei-man 指出，如果俱乐部根据决定提出另一次司法审查，该项目可能会进一步推迟。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港粉岭高尔夫球场应成为公共设施：前高级官员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“俱乐部稍后也可以就城规会的决定提出另一项司法复核，”吴说。 “粗略来说，如果算上法庭审理的时间，以及俱乐部获胜后重做评估及通过城规会的时间，可能需要五年或更长的时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴补充说，环保人士很少能赢得类似的司法复核案件，因为法庭不会评论评估报告的专业内容，而是评论政府是否遵循法定程序和遵守法律精神。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;资深政治评论员卢绍兴表示，高尔夫俱乐部的最新举动凸显了政府在游说强大利益集团方面的短板。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在当前我们强调和谐和建设性对话的政治和社会氛围下，对话似乎还不够，”他说。 “似乎可以以一种更好的方式进行沟通。” &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;香港高尔夫球场摊牌摊牌：支持者，反对住房计划辩论&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>; 2029年建造公寓的最初目标预计将返回到2031年，鉴于八月的求职者，将其置于八月的范围。有关该地区生物多样性的信息。但八个月后，议员仍未被要求再次投票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府早些时候表示，粉岭公寓将超出未来十年的预计住房需求，但由于其他预定项目可能需要更多时间，政府决定继续推进。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India rejects China BYD’s US$1 billion EV factory proposal, cites security concerns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3228597/india-rejects-china-byds-us1-billion-ev-factory-proposal-cites-security-concerns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 20:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/c799014d-fe8a-4e1e-8c06-6919ce9da3be_f11880de.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;India has rejected Chinese automaker BYD&#39;s proposal to set up a US$1 billion factory in India in partnership with Hyderabad-based Megha Engineering and Infrastructure, India&#39;s Economic Times reported on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Security concerns with respect to Chinese investments in India were flagged during the deliberations,” the report quoted an Indian official as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month it was reported that BYD had submitted a US$1 billion investment proposal to build electric cars and batteries in India in partnership with a local company.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will frosty India-China ties thaw as Modi, Xi look set to meet at summits?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;BYD said it was seeking to capture 40 per cent of India&#39;s electric vehicle (EV) market by 2030, but its investment proposal comes at a time when India is increasing scrutiny of Chinese firms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Great Wall Motor, which also planned to invest US$1 billion in India, failed in an attempt to buy a mothballed General Motors plant after it did not get government approval to close the deal. The government is also probing MG Motor India, a unit of Chinese carmaker SAIC Motor, over alleged financial irregularities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s Department of Commerce, Department for Promotion of Industry and Internal Trade (DPIIT) had sought opinions from other departments on the BYD proposed venture, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s switch to electric vehicles is lagging behind other countries such as China and the US, hampered by high upfront costs and a lack of charging infrastructure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Bloomberg.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong DSE 2023: police arrest teacher over social media leak of marking scheme for Chinese writing exam]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3228595/hong-kong-dse-2023-police-arrest-teacher-over-social-media-leak-marking-scheme-chinese-writing-exam?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 19:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/643f7060-b304-496b-91b2-224540dc6387_ac18bb9f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong police have arrested a teacher on suspicion of leaking the marking scheme for a university entrance exam paper on a popular Chinese social media platform to drum up business for his private tutoring lessons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The force on Saturday said the 38-year-old secondary school teacher surnamed Wong had allegedly breached the Hong Kong Examinations and Assessment Authority (HKEAA) Ordinance and claimed to be a marker for the Diploma of Secondary Education (DSE) exams.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While police did not elaborate on how Wong obtained the confidential document, they said the educator was believed to have uploaded the marking scheme for the Chinese writing exam onto Xiaohongshu in two posts in May and July.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong principal arrested on suspicion of corruption over exam paper leak&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We suspect that the person wanted to attract students for private tutorial classes by posting the confidential document from the examinations body, and subsequently profit from it,” said Chan King-lok, a senior inspector with the Wan Chai district crime squad.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“According to our investigation, that person has never been a staff member or a marker of the HKEAA … So one of the major focuses of our investigation will be the source of the document, and we do not rule out more arrests.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two posts on Xiaohongshu sparked widespread discussion among social media users a week before education authorities released students&#39; results for this year&#39;s DSE exams on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The user behind the posts, named “DSE Chinese 5** Teacher Wong” and later renamed to “DSE Miss huang 5**, claimed to have 10 and 14 years of teaching and tutoring experience, respectively. The content and the account behind were subsequently deleted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police on Saturday said they were investigating the document&#39;s source and whether the suspect had profited from leaking its contents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officers arrested Wong at his residence in Sham Shui Po on Friday after the examinations body filed a police report in mid-July. Investigators also seized his smartphone, tablet and laptop in connection with the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The suspect would be detained overnight as part of the investigation, the force said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The internet is not a lawless place, if anyone attempts to exploit the anonymity of the internet to commit illegal acts, the police will strictly enforce the law,” Chan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ricardo Mak King-sang, director of the examinations body, on Tuesday said the incident represented a severe breach of the service agreement between markers and the organisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also stressed the leak was an isolated incident as most of the markers strictly adhered to the organisation&#39;s instructions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong tutor jailed for leaking public exam questions granted bail&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Education Bureau declined to comment but said it was policy to assess whether professional misconduct was involved in such cases and review the relevant teacher&#39;s registration, with possibility of their license being revoked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The HKEAA also refused to comment further on the case after Wong&#39;s arrest, but said it attached great importance to the confidentiality and fairness of public examinations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also noted that markers were required to keep their identities confidential under the Hong Kong Examinations and Assessment Authority Ordinance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ordinance states that impersonating members of the body with intent to procure any advantage or reward can lead to a fine of HK$25,000 (US$3,198) and six months in jail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police warned that anyone appointed or hired by the authority should uphold the confidentiality of the materials they handled, including marking schemes, which constituted a separate offence punishable by a HK$25,000 fine and six months&#39; imprisonment.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s top overseas students face ‘glass ceiling’, hard choices amid fraught US ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3228533/chinas-top-overseas-students-face-glass-ceiling-hard-choices-amid-fraught-us-ties?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/02931205-f758-4873-8877-6e797d23653f_55432601.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After months of struggle, Jackie Lee, a final-year PhD student specialising in computational and applied mathematics at the University of Texas at Austin, decided to work at a research centre in Beijing after graduation this year. Lee, who prefers scientific research over working in the financial industry, had turned down an earlier job offer from US investment banker Goldman Sachs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When faced with the prospect of working as a Chinese scientist in the United States, Lee, 27, said he felt such a position was not safe or secure given growing political uncertainties between China and the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The advantage of working in the US is that I can earn more. But there&#39;s a glass ceiling for Asians here, and the trend is getting worse because of geopolitics,” said Lee, a native of Shanxi province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Uncertainty over US-China relations and a more research-favourable environment at home are luring more Chinese PhD graduates in science, technology, engineering and mechanics (STEM) disciplines to return to China for work or research, despite concerns about the intense competition at home in their respective fields.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since 2018, when then-US president Donald Trump launched the China Initiative to combat suspected Chinese theft of American scientific research secrets and technologies, the US has lost much of the best Chinese talent to its Asian competitor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hard data on the exodus is difficult to obtain, but statistics published by the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development in April showed that the US lost 896 scientific authors in 2021 while China gained 3,108 in the same period.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The long-term stay rate of Chinese STEM PhD graduates in the US has also decreased since the Trump administration. 2017年之前，超过80%的毕业生表示他们计划在获得博士学位后留在美国。 By 2021, the figure fell to 74 per cent, according to the Survey of Earned Doctorates, which collects samples of around 50,000 new research doctorate graduates annually from American universities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, meanwhile, aims to attract more STEM talent to achieve its goal of technological self-reliance. Beijing is particularly focused on developing critical industries, such as supercomputing, which Lee specialises in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One good reason for me to return to Beijing is that I can better develop my expertise in computer-assisted engineering with the research position,” Lee said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With China planning to build a supercomputing internet by the end of 2025, top computer experts are in demand, and local governments are eager to lure them. In Beijing, talent like Lee, who return from overseas, enjoy generous benefits in addition to big bonuses, such as subsidised housing, free children&#39;s school enrolment, and infrastructure and loan support if they start their own businesse&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like Lee, Noah Tsui, a second-year PhD student majoring in computer science at the University of New Hampshire, is also considering returning home as the US seeks to de-risk from China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For me, the biggest impact of the deterioration of Sino-US relations is the decoupling of personnel. It&#39;s extremely difficult for people to move between the two countries, given visa and flight restrictions,” said the 28-year-old from Shandong province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The denial rates for F-1 visas increased from a low of 15 per cent in 2014 to a record high of 35 per cent in 2022, according to a report published by the CATO Institute in May. F1 visas allow foreign students to study at American universities and schools.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsui said some of his friends, whose majors are not directly related to the military, could only obtain a one-year F-1 student visa instead of the preferred five-year document.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One-year student visas mean that during most of a six-year doctoral study, students are not able to leave the US, even to visit relatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Tsui is still hesitant about whether to leave the US. He said a major concern is that he would need to build his connections in China from scratch if he gives up his research career in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why did I abandon my Chinese name? asks New York student in moving podcast&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“PhD [graduates] returning to China are still considered outsiders in the [domestic scientific research] market. I think domestically cultivated talent will outcompete us in terms of connections,” Tsui said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Returning to China&#39;s hi-tech talent market is not easy, according to Kun Dai, assistant professor of educational administration and policy at Chinese University of Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local governments have set higher bars for incentives as competition among high quality talent has intensified. “Some cities now restrict doctoral graduate schools to be among the top 50 in the world to be eligible for rewards and subsidies,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has become “cautious” about recruiting returned PhD graduates, according to Dai. “今年中国的就业形势并不理想，高端人才市场需要时间来消化供过于求的情况。 Meanwhile, Beijing has become low key about promoting the return of high-end talent after it quietly scrapped the Thousand Talents programme.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2008, China began efforts to entice foreign scientists and researchers to relocate to China through its Thousand Talents programme, aimed at strengthening the nation&#39;s scientific capabilities.但在 2018 年，随着对间谍活动的怀疑越来越多，该计划受到了美国政府的审查。 The highly publicised programme has since been muted in China&#39;s state media.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Lockdowns prompt Chinese studying overseas to think twice about returning home&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“In the foreseeable five to 10 years, as long as there is no serious conflict between the two countries, the US will still be the priority for Chinese students to study for STEM PhDs, given the reputation of the Ivy League,” Dai said. “But the key to the return of talent lies in the implementation of talent policies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The point is whether the high-end talent can really enjoy the benefits and feel they are respected,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s MTR Corp opens new shopping centre in Tai Wai station as post-Covid retail activity picks up]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3228591/hong-kongs-mtr-corp-opens-new-shopping-centre-tai-wai-station-post-covid-retail-activity-picks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/f4f27a25-8cb8-4a31-891d-e97ff3fcbb5a_107e02fc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong transit operator and property developer MTR Corp on Saturday began a soft launch of a new shopping centre atop Tai Wai station, its first since 2020, as the company looks to tap into the city&#39;s post-Covid retail recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Wai, the 15th shopping centre developed by the firm, occupies four stories and a total floor area of 650,000 square feet. It currently houses about 150 merchants ranging from dining to retail and lifestyle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Located at the interchange between the East Rail line and Tuen Ma line, the mall will officially open in the fourth quarter with a new footbridge connecting to Tai Wai station, the company said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s not just a shopping centre. It&#39;s more of a community facility for local residents,” said David Tang Chi-fai, director of MTR&#39;s property and international business.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Wai, which sits below The Pavilia Farm residential complex co-developed by the company and New World Development, will mainly cater to the daily needs of local residents, he said. Buyers of the first phase of that home project collected their keys in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around 97 per cent of the floor space in The Wai has already been leased out, while the remaining 3 per cent will be held until later this year after MTR solicits customers&#39; feedback on the types of businesses they wish to see in the shopping centre, Tang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The opening of the mall comes as consumers return to restaurants and shops after three years of pandemic. Total retail sales rose 21 per cent in the first five months of the year from the same period a year ago, according to provisional data released by the Census and Statistics Department earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leasing momentum has picked up quickly, according to JLL.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“About 4 million sq ft of new retail supply is scheduled for completion by the end of the year, and all of these projects are located in noncore shopping areas,” said Oliver Tong, head of retail at JLL.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leasing activities will continue to be dominated by the mid-to-mass-end segments rather than luxury and high-end brands, with demand coming mostly from food and beverage, grocery, mass fashion and lifestyle businesses in the near term, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MTR is still grappling with the impact of the pandemic, which dealt a heavy blow to its recurrent business that includes transport operations, as well as station commercial and property rental businesses. That segment saw a 91.3 per cent plunge in profit to HK$157 million (US$20 million) in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s only rail operator has seen its share price fall 13.7 per cent to a nine-month low this year, compared with a 3.6 per cent retreat of the broader Hong Kong stock market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts expect the company to post a net income of HK$9.8 billion this year, down from HK$10.6 billion in 2019 – the year before the pandemic hit, according to Bloomberg data.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[At least 26 killed as Indian landslide death toll rises, dozens more trapped]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3228594/least-26-killed-indian-landslide-death-toll-rises-dozens-more-trapped?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.22 19:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/22/447dd487-2e87-4971-b3cb-6b0acb1a0f39_2e307f58.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The death toll from a landslide in India&#39;s Western state of Maharashtra rose to 26 on Saturday, a disaster relief official said, with dozens still feared trapped under layers of mud and slush two days after the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The landslide occurred on Thursday night in the remote mountain hamlet of Irshalwadi, about 60 kilometres from Mumbai, flattening several houses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The hamlet is estimated to have been home to at least 225 people, more than 80 of whom managed to escape.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Times of India newspaper reported on Saturday that around 80 people were still missing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;At least 22 die as extra-heavy monsoon rains lash northern India&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We are working on our technical equipment, our rescue techniques,” SB Singh, an official with the National Disaster Response Force (NDRF), said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We cannot judge as of now how many people are still stuck,” Singh said, adding that four more bodies were pulled out from underneath the mud on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Visuals from news channels showed rescue teams, wearing bright orange raincoats and carrying digging tools, trekking up the mountain to the site of the landslide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rescue operations are being hindered by incessant rainfall, poor visibility, and the hilly terrain, Singh added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were about 16 houses affected by the landslide and many families have been relocated, the official added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>