<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong to set up new subdivision of prosecutors to handle cybercrimes, says deputy justice minister]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3227087/hong-kong-set-new-subdivision-prosecutors-handle-cybercrimes-says-deputy-justice-minister?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 21:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/c8cee69a-a327-4ea2-bfe5-9807d3c8fdb2_77f9e2a3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港司法部副部长提供了今年计划的新细节，以创建一个检方团队将专注于处理网络犯罪，因为官方数据显示过去六年中基于技术的犯罪增加了四倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Horace Cheung Kwok-kwan 周日还强调了全球诈骗的增加警方数据显示，去年举报的科技犯罪数量为22,797 起，较 2017 年的 5,567 起增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于互联网犯罪中跨境犯罪活动的复杂性，检控部门必须及时了解技术发展和潜在的科技犯罪趋势，以便有效执法， ”他在每周博客中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;今年首 3 个月，香港网络诈骗受害者损失了 8.3 亿港元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然张没有给出启动该计划的具体日期，他表示，立法会已批准聘请一名新的首席政府律师来领导该团队的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 5 月份向立法会提交的一份简报中，该部门表示司法部表示，该部门的职权范围将涵盖基于技术的犯罪，包括联合网络欺诈、网络攻击、人肉搜索、涉及加密货币的洗钱以及煽动他人犯罪的在线消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部门还将提供有关以下方面的法律指导：根据该文件，数字证据的使用并对现行法律提出建议的修改。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张周日还表示，该部门将跟进法律改革委员会关于该市是否需要针对网络犯罪的立法的研究以及是否应具有域外管辖权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市目前没有专门的立法来监管网络犯罪，《犯罪和电信条例》涵盖了涉及互联网、数据和信息技术的犯罪行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;去年七月，该委员会发布了一份咨询文件，其中提出了新法律的建议。公众咨询期也在十月结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;资深刑事律师洪万顺表示，新部门的成立有助于集中打击科技犯罪的检控工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;根据立法会简报，刑事检控科目前将网络犯罪案件分派给来自不同部门的不同团队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;身兼委员会成员的洪先生表示，内部变革也将允许部门聘请资讯科技专家协助刑事调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同日，律政司司长林定国强调，未来立法的重要性，允许检方对法院裁定的无罪释放提出上诉&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《刑事诉讼程序（修订）条例草案》将涵盖有陪审团的刑事审判中的裁决，以及没有陪审团的国家安全程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林郑月娥在 Facebook 上写道拟议的修改旨在刑事审判中“增强程序正义”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;敲诈勒索案中，11岁的香港男孩在视频聊天中被诱骗脱衣服&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在现行制度下，检察官可以仅当一审法院法官作出错误的无案裁决并指示陪审团宣判被告无罪时，才将案件提交上诉法院澄清。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，被告不能被重审，即使法官的决定后来被认为是错误的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，被告可以在上诉法院对法官的定罪或判决提出异议，而检察官则不能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拟议的立法定于周三进行二读。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局辩称，检察官无法对无罪释放提出上诉，可能会导致法律异常。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林郑月娥表示，拟议的修改与为检察官和辩护律师提供了上诉渠道，体现了“法治精神”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 21:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong customs arrest 8 and seize HK$82 million worth of contraband cigarettes during raid on cargo vessel]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3227088/hong-kong-customs-arrest-8-and-seize-hk82-million-worth-contraband-cigarettes-during-raid-cargo?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 21:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/ca3e3fdf-b0ae-4450-97ae-da266954c0f5_104d3d5a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港海关逮捕八名男子，并没收 8,200 万港元（1,040 万美元）周六，香港海关在突袭货船时发现了价值相当于黑市香烟的货船。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，香港海关在周日发现了一艘停泊在葵涌货柜码头附近的可疑船只，该船似乎隐藏在其他船只之中&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关税务罪案调查科高级督察林伟杰表示，该船在接近位于货柜码头南路的码头时被拦截并登上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关海关在两个 40 英尺（12 米长）的集装箱内发现了 2,200 万支走私香烟，此外，船上的机舱和客舱内还藏有 40,000 支走私香烟。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港海关查获了价值 9.05 亿港元的走私香烟。自一月起开始查获非法香烟&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;海关估计，这批走私香烟的总市值为8,200万港元，如果合法进口，可为政府带来约5,500万港元的税收。&lt;/p>;&lt;这八名嫌疑人年龄在25岁至60岁之间，来自缅甸和中国大陆，其中包括该船的船长。他们都因涉嫌进口未列舱货物而被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林表示，这批货物的 70% 是运往当地市场的，而其余的则将出口，因为后者的品牌在当地市场不太受欢迎。 - 在该市众所周知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，由于海关仍在调查香烟的来源及其预期目的地，因此可能会进一步逮捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港海关在预算后走私香烟&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;今年至今，海关已检获超过4.3亿支走私香烟，价值逾14亿港元，可为政府带来10亿港元的收入。这一数字占海关去年缉获量的 60%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关表示，香港 2 月份将烟草税提高 31% 后，预计通过海运走私黑市卷烟的情况将会增加。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;增加征税后，每包20支香烟的平均成本已超过70港元，额外增加了12港元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 21:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese universities vow to target fake graduate job data as employment outlook worsens]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3227074/chinese-universities-vow-target-fake-graduate-job-data-employment-outlook-worsen?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/d6e3a9ee-bf4c-4b3f-873f-2053b24996ba_0a279697.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由于担心某些机构可能会影响毕业生就业率，中国的大学已被告知要核实毕业生就业率提交虚假数据以美化自己的声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些命令是在毕业季期间发出的，而且世界第二大经济体的青年失业率创下历史新高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中南大学中部省份湖南省周五表示，将进行检查以确保大学数据的“真实性和可信性”，以确定“真实就业情况”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;响应教育部和根据省教育厅的要求，该大学表示，工作人员必须证实属于自营职业、自由职业、咨询或海外工作的学生提交的材料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖南长沙科技大学和安徽师范大学皖江学院也已继教育部发出类似通知，严禁误报就业数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“全国高校毕业生就业统计专项检查将覆盖各省高校，对问题严肃问责该学院于 5 月 29 日表示：“今年有创纪录的 1160 万高校毕业生进入劳动力市场，但该国受疫情打击的经济，尤其是其支柱产业的中小型私营企业 - 正在努力为其创造足够的就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;青年失业率正在上升，5 月份 16 至 24 岁人群的失业率增至 20.8%，高于 20.8%。 4 月份创下 20.4% 的历史新高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，在维持高就业率的压力下，一些大学一直迫使学生在就业机会上撒谎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国媒体也报道一些大学威胁说，如果某些毕业班的学生不提交就业证明，将扣留毕业证书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教育部在近几个月发给高等院校的通知中表示，学校不得强迫或引诱学生不能以扣留毕业证书为手段强迫学生签订就业合同或劳动合同，也不能让学生签署虚假就业证明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士预计，未来青年失业率将进一步恶化。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于五月通常不是一个与季节模式上青年失业率高相关的月份，因此我们认为，随着夏季的临近，每年毕业季的到来，这个数字可能会进一步上升。”野村证券上个月在一份报告中评论了中国5月份的关键经济数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国人民大学6月份发布的研究，中国的青年失业不仅是“一个周期性问题，而且是一个系统性问题” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们判断，青年失业问题可能还会持续10年，并且短期内将继续加剧。”研究人员表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果处理不当，会引发经济领域之外的其他社会问题，甚至成为政治问题的导火索。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As global temperatures rise, can cities withstand extreme heat?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3227085/global-temperatures-rise-can-cities-withstand-extreme-heat?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 20:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/05ce7d8e-79bd-4aa1-83ec-6d86e3d32d96_1e2f5b0b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;自然灾害可能非常严重 - 飓风肆虐、建筑物倒塌的龙卷风 - 但高温却是最可怕的&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;芝加哥在 1995 年经历了惨痛的教训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那年 7 月，一场持续一周的热浪袭击了 106 华氏度（41 摄氏度），导致 700 多人死亡。大多数死亡发生在贫困和黑人占多数的社区，那里许多老年人或孤立的人缺乏适当的通风或空调。不堪重负的电网造成的停电使情况变得更糟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;芝加哥最初反应缓慢，但此后制定了紧急热响应计划，其中包括大力推动向公众发出警报，然后为最脆弱的群体提供帮助。可能需要。洛杉矶、迈阿密和菲尼克斯等其他城市现在都有“首席高温官”来协调危险高温的规划和应对。世界各地的城市和国家都采取了类似的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但专家警告说，在高温记录不断被打破以及最脆弱人群持续不平等的世界中，这些措施可能还不够。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约大学社会科学教授埃里克·克林伯格 (Eric Klinenberg) 写了一本关于气候变化的书，他说：“我不知道哪个城市真正为一些气候科学家担心的最坏情况做好了准备。”芝加哥热浪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，随着预报变得更加准确，并且气象学家、记者和政府官员集中精力传播即将到来的危险，防暑准备工作普遍得到改善。例如，芝加哥扩大了其紧急短信和电子邮件通知系统，并确定了最脆弱的居民进行外展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是在一个城市有效的方法在另一个城市可能并不那么有效。加州大学洛杉矶分校热实验室副教授巴拉特·文卡特 (Bharat Venkat) 表示，这是因为每个城市都有自己独特的建筑、交通、布局和不平等，该实验室旨在解决他所说的“热不平等”问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;越南农民通过在黑暗中种植水稻来抵御 37 度的高温&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Venkat 认为城市应该通过投资劳工权利、可持续发展等来解决不平等问题。这听起来可能很昂贵——例如，当一个城市试图改善食品卡车上工人的工作条件时，谁来买单？ – 但 Venkat 认为什么都不做最终会花费更多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现状实际上代价高昂，”他说。 “我们只是不做数学计算。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2003 年的一场持续热浪估计导致 15,000 人死亡，其中许多是居住在城市公寓和没有空调的房屋中的老年人，之后法国启动了热浪监视预警系统。空调。该系统包括敦促人们补充水分的公告。就在上个月，德国发起了一项新的防止热浪死亡的运动，据称该运动是受到法国经验的启发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在印度，2010 年的一场强烈热浪导致气温超过 118 华氏度（48 摄氏度）。艾哈迈达巴德市有 1,300 多人死亡。市政府官员现在制定了一项高温行动计划，以提高当地居民和医护人员的认识。另一个简单的举措：将屋顶漆成白色以反射炽热的阳光。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚利桑那大学助理教授 Ladd Keith 引用了巴尔的摩的红色极热警报作为精心设计的警报系统的一个例子。当天气预报要求高温指数达到 105 华氏度或更高时，警报就会发出，并在最容易受到高温风险的社区启动更多社会服务等措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他赞扬了像这样的城市的高温官员。洛杉矶、迈阿密和菲尼克斯，但表示“仍有超过 19,000 个城镇没有这些设施。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;费城天普大学环境健康科学家 Inkyu Han 指出，城市仍在努力获得这些设施。为贫困社区提供冷却中心和空调补贴等援助。他说，通过简单且可持续的解决方案，例如改善树冠，还可以做更多的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“值得注意的是，费城的低收入社区和有色人种社区通常缺乏行道树和绿地，”Han &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在罗德岛州的普罗维登斯，大西洋通常会调节气温，但该地区仍然会遭遇热浪。急诊室医生凯特·莫雷蒂 (Kate Moretti) 表示，炎热来袭时，该市的医院会收治更多患者，心脏病、肾衰竭和心理健康问题等可能与炎热没有明显关系的疾病也会增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;“人们害怕冒险”：印度北部酷热席卷数十人，导致数十人死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们确实注意到这给系统带来了压力，”莫雷蒂说。她说，老年人、户外工作人员、残疾人和无家可归者在入院人数中占很大比例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迈阿密——由于其脆弱性，被认为是气候变化威胁的零地带。应对海平面上升、洪水、飓风和极端高温 - 两年前任命了其高温官员，以制定确保人们免受高温侵害的策略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗宾·巴钦 (Robin Bachin)，该校公民和社区参与副教授迈阿密大学指出，联邦政府有法律保护寒冷气候下的人们免于在危险条件下关闭暖气，但没有类似的冷却措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于住在公寓里的人们来说，巴钦说：“由于没有公共补贴，因此不需要房东提供空调。” “这对我们当地的低收入人群来说是极其危险的，更不用说那些无家可归或户外工作者的人了。”克林伯格说，到目前为止，美国在大多数热浪持续时间上都很幸运，但是，某些地区的电网容易受到高需求的影响，加上持续存在的社会不平等，可能会在未来几十年带来严重的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;部分原因是导致高温事件如此致命的潜在社会问题正在变得越来越严重。更糟糕的是，克林伯格说。芝加哥 1995 年的死亡不仅集中在贫困和种族隔离的社区，而且还特别集中在他所说的“贫乏”社区，在这些地方，人们很难聚集在一起，社会联系也被削弱。空地、废弃的餐馆和维护不善的公园意味着人们不太可能互相检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专门研究极端天气事件的芝加哥大学大气科学教授 Noboru Nakamura 说他认为芝加哥通过实施高温应急计划、例行健康检查和降温中心做出了很多明智的改变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他也将不平等视为一项艰巨的挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一个系统性问题资源不平等的问题不可能一夜之间真正消除。我们今天仍然面临着同样的问题，”中村说。 “所以这方面仍然是一个很大很大的未解决问题。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How deep is the snow on Mt Everest? A Chinese team says it’s deeper than previously thought]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3227084/how-deep-snow-mt-everest-chinese-team-says-its-deeper-previously-thought?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 20:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/a7bcfec9-59fd-4bc8-8756-87b1b6a9760f_83d45da2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;世界最高峰顶部的积雪比之前想象的要深得多一组中国科学家表示，这一发现可能会影响对气候变化的理解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，在非营利性国际科学期刊《冰冻圈》上发表的一份报告中，中国科学院的研究人员青藏高原研究所表示，珠穆朗玛峰山顶积雪的平均深度约为 9.5 米（31.1 英尺）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;之前的估计深度在 0.92-3.5 米之间，研究人员表示，并补充说，这些测量结果不一致，并且具有“很大的不确定性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的测量显示……山顶的平均积雪深度惊人，约为 9.5 米，比之前的估计深得多， ”该研究所的杨伟教授在冰冻圈网站上的一段视频中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员的这一发现是基于去年四月和五月珠穆朗玛峰北坡探险的结果。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;他们使用探地雷达沿着海拔 7,000 米以上的山脊获取了数十个读数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;读数显示雪和岩石表面之间存在很大差异，从而允许团队确定了两种材料之间的边界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，总共集中在山顶的 26 个测量点显示积雪平均深度约为 9.5 米，并补充说结果范围在正负1.2米之内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种均匀性不仅表明了在这个有限区域内重复雷达测量的可靠性，而且还提供了对珠穆朗玛峰山脊相对平坦地形的深入了解， ”他们在论文中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨表示，之前的测量工作受到“积雪密度、[测量]桩长和高海拔挑战”等因素的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在论文中，研究人员表示，比较不同时期的积雪深度可能有助于了解人类引起的气候变化对喜马拉雅山极高海拔地区的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“珠穆朗玛峰上的积雪和冰川是他们说：“我们是气候变化的哨兵，因此为了解如此极高的海拔地区正在发生的气候变化及其对亚洲水塔可能产生的广泛影响提供了一个潜在的自然平台。”他们说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们说雪芯钻探等等需要对珠穆朗玛峰进行探地雷达测量，以了解积雪的变化情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于雪位、重力偏差和光折射的变化，人们对珠穆朗玛峰的确切海拔存在分歧。其他因素。这一新发现意味着珠穆朗玛峰的真实高度可能会发生变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员表示，珠穆朗玛峰是喜马拉雅山脉的最高峰，但顶峰的高度一直不一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;2020年，北京和加德满都联合公布的最新测量值为8850米，略高于尼泊尔此前的测量值，比中国当时的评估值高出约4米。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong customs arrests man for allegedly arriving in city with cocaine worth HK$6.9 million hidden in biscuit tins]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3227082/hong-kong-customs-arrests-man-allegedly-arriving-city-cocaine-worth-hk69-million-hidden-biscuit-tins?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 19:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/7e0fc6d8-1c07-4deb-a73c-088d12752520_c8ae4354.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港海关拘捕一名从澳门抵港的26岁外籍男子从他的行李中检获约 6.3 公斤（14 磅）怀疑可卡因，价值约 690 万港元（868,720 美元），藏在四个饼干罐内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是两天内第二起涉及入境旅客在饼干中走私毒品的逮捕行动当局表示，他们发现涉嫌贩运的游客有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新案件中的男子于周六在上环港澳客轮码头进入香港时被捕。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“我们用X光机检查他的行李时，发现其中一个塑料袋的X光图像可疑。”毒品调查科督察方子扬说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;他补充说，调查显示该男子的四个饼干容器有被打开的迹象。里面发现了可卡因，嫌疑人因涉嫌贩毒被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关称，嫌疑人当时正在帮助将饼干罐运往市区，并采取了“极其曲折”的路线前往香港。 Fong补充说，该男子从巴林前往土耳其，然后前往埃塞俄比亚和马尼拉，最后抵达澳门，乘船抵达香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港因持有CBD产品而入狱第一人&lt;/h3>;&lt;方说：“随着香港恢复与内地和世界的联系，到访香港的游客也会相应增加。” “海关注意到近期利用游客走私毒品的案件有所增加，因此我们将相应调整执法策略。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局表示，将重点打击来自高风险地区的游客， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一起涉及游客的案件中，海关在三罐饼干和三罐饼干中发现可疑可卡因，逮捕了一名 62 岁的妇女。她拥有一个塑料袋，里面装着几盒薯片。她从丹麦哥本哈根飞来。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方查获价值 1.23 亿港元的冰毒，为今年最大一起缉获量&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周四案件中的毒品重约 6.5 公斤，具有估计价值700万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据香港《危险药物条例》，贩运毒品属严重罪行。最高刑罚为罚款港币500万元及终身监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China on alert for crop and power grid damage as heat and flood risks rise]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3227078/china-alert-crop-and-power-grid-damage-heat-and-flood-risks-rise?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/4e824e62-c89a-4353-8157-4f0bd1123c13_b052d405.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由于持续的热浪和威胁，中国当局在周末发布了一系列天气警告严重洪涝增加了农作物和电网受损的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;农业农村部和中国气象局周日警告称，持续炎热天气可能会损害水稻生产，有关部门应确保田间安全有足够的水来降低气温并防止过早成熟，特别是在南方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计未来 10 天内，中国南方大部分地区的气温将保持在 35 摄氏度（95 华氏度）以上，并且还会上升湖南、江西、浙江、福建等省份部分地区最高气温达40摄氏度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国气象局周日上午还单独发布了三级高温黄色警报，警告人们河北、河南、山西、浙江、福建、内蒙古等地预计气温将突破40摄氏度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;建议受影响地区人员避免户外活动，以及必须在室内工作的人员&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于电力需求给电网带来压力，它还提醒当局警惕火灾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自那以后，严重的热浪席卷了中国大部分地区。 6月，预报员称极端天气可能比去年持续两个多月的热浪更严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，水利部对内蒙古九个省份的洪水发出警报、辽宁、吉林、黑龙江、安徽、江苏、湖北、重庆、贵州。仅江苏省就有约6000名堤防检查人员在执勤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称，周四以来的强降雨导致江苏、江西、辽宁、贵州和内蒙古北部的12条河流水位超过警戒水位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;根据中国气象局周六发布的《中国气候变化蓝皮书（2023）》，气候变化对中国的影响日趋严重，去年夏季平均气温、沿海海平面和冰川退缩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海新闻媒体澎湃新闻援引国家气候中心副主任袁家双的话说，中国气温上升速度明显高于全球平均水平气候系统持续变暖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蓝皮书称，1901年至2022年，中国年平均气温每10年上升0.16摄氏度，高于全球平均水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国气象局气象服务部首席专家周冰告诉澎湃新闻，高温天气也可能是厄尔尼诺现象造成的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;厄尔尼诺现象是由于气候变暖而自然发生的气候模式。热带太平洋中部和东部的海洋表面温度。它通常每两到七年发生一次，持续九到十二个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界气象组织周二表示，热带太平洋地区七年来首次出现厄尔尼诺现象，设定了周表示，厄尔尼诺现象预计将在夏季给中国北部、中部、东部和西北地区的部分地区带来极高的气温，并使中国的气温升高。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家气候中心气候变化影响与适应办公室首席专家徐红梅表示，中国亟需加大对气候变化适应能力的投入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“特别是要加强全球变暖对我国典型脆弱地区影响的监测。”澎湃新闻援引徐的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Towngas, Citybus parent Bravo Transport sign agreement for Hong Kong Island hydrogen refuelling station]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3227080/towngas-citybus-parent-bravo-transport-sign-agreement-hong-kong-island-hydrogen-refuelling-station?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 19:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/cbb2f976-eef6-49cc-a930-275d1a3156d2_0583192a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港中华煤气公司 (Towngas) 及母公司 Bravo Transport Services香港主要巴士营运商城巴公司已签署协议，将在港岛开发一座加氢站，并探索使用氢气作为替代燃料来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两家公司将合作建设城巴车厂根据周日的一份声明，香港岛项目在 12 个月内竣工后，每天将能够提取约 500 公斤氢气，足以每天运营 10 至 12 辆氢气公交车。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;煤气将负责现有管网的设计和扩建、供应燃料电池级氢气、安装氢气提取设施以及提供维护服务，而城巴将负责采购和维护氢气&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两家公司正在“为未来每个人轻松使用氢能源铺平道路”，Peter Wong Wai-港华燃气董事总经理易先生在声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港氢能公交车背后的财团将建造第二个加气站&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我期待由港华燃气提供动力的氢能公交车服务于香港周日的声明是在上周有消息称，香港首个加氢站位于城巴西九龙车厂 – 得到城巴股东Templewater的支持和支持之后，周日发表的声明。和 Hans Energy – 将于 10 月投入运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;投资者表示，香港可以在氢动力运输领域占据主导地位&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Towngas 与 Bravo Transport 之间的协议被视为推动香港的气候目标。环境局副局长黄淑娴表示，此次合作支持香港《气候行动计划2050》的政策方向，参与推动绿色交通发展，从而实现香港在2050年之前实现汽车零排放和碳中和的目标声明称，第二个站的规模将明显大于第一个站的规模。 Wan Yufeng, Citybus&#39;s director and investor Templewater&#39;s partner and head of impact investing, said Towngas is a “strong partner” for the introduction of the second hydrogen refuelling station based on Hong Kong Island, thanks to its experience and gas supply chain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wan was “delighted” to see more hydrogen projects being approved by the government, including Hong Kong&#39;s second hydrogen refuelling station, a hydrogen-fuelled light rail vehicle and hydrogen tube trailers, according to a statement on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Citybus is set to introduce no fewer than five hydrogen buses in the coming year, the Thursday statement added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UK lawmakers urge BBC to probe underwear call allegations while broadcaster’s presenters distance themselves]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227079/uk-lawmakers-urge-bbc-probe-underwear-call-allegations-while-broadcasters-presenters-distance?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 18:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/09/79efc260-9d51-46a3-a32b-f5e542a5e80a_5e0d3317.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Senior British politicians on Sunday called on the BBC to rapidly investigate claims that a leading presenter paid a teenager for explicit photos.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The publicly funded national broadcaster is under pressure after British tabloid The Sun newspaper reported allegations that the male presenter gave a youth £35,000 (US$45,000) starting in 2020 when the young person was 17.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neither the star nor the youth was identified. Amid speculation on social media about the identity of the presenter, several of the BBC&#39;s best-known stars spoke up to say it was not them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though the age of sexual consent in Britain is 16, it is a crime to make or possess indecent images of anyone under 18.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Government minister Victoria Atkins said the allegations were “very serious”. She told Sky News that “as public attention and concern grows, the BBC is going to have to act very swiftly to deal with these allegations and to set out what they are doing to investigate them”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rachel Reeves, economy spokeswoman for the opposition Labour Party, said the BBC needed to “speed up their processes” and “get their house in order”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The young person&#39;s mother told The Sun she saw a picture of the presenter on her child&#39;s phone, in which he was “sitting on a sofa in his house in his underwear” and she said she was told it was “a picture from some kind of video call”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Sun said the teenager&#39;s family complained to the BBC on May 19.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The BBC reported on the story in its news bulletins throughout Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;New Zealand broadcaster suspends journalist for &#39;pro-Kremlin garbage&#39; on Ukraine&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On the News at Ten presented by Clive Myrie, special correspondent Lucy Manning said: “I think this is very serious for the BBC, let&#39;s make no bones about this.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The understanding is the presenter isn&#39;t due on air in the near future, but we haven&#39;t been told, and we have asked, we haven&#39;t been told by the BBC whether there has or hasn&#39;t been a formal suspension.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The BBC will need to answer if the investigation should have happened sooner, if it should have been more thorough, and if it&#39;s fair to other presenters unconnected to this that their names are now sort of in the headlines.” Manning said she thinks this “really does have the potential to severely dent the BBC&#39;s reputation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Sun reported that while the presenter is off air, he has not been suspended.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Saturday, amid speculation on social media, a number of BBC stars tweeted to say they were not the presenter at the centre of The Sun story.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rylan Clark tweeted: “Not sure why my name&#39;s floating about but re that story in the Sun – that ain&#39;t me babe. I&#39;m currently filming a show in Italy for the BBC, so take my name out ya mouths.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jeremy Vine tweeted: “Just to say I&#39;m very much looking forward to hosting my radio show on Monday – whoever the &#39;BBC Presenter&#39; in the news is, I have the same message for you as Rylan did earlier: it certainly ain&#39;t me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gary Lineker tweeted: “Hate to disappoint the haters but it&#39;s not me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nicky Campbell appeared to suggest he had contacted police about being mentioned in connection with the story.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He tweeted a screenshot which featured the Metropolitan Police logo and the words: “Thank you for contacting the Metropolitan Police Service to report your crime.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;BBC crisis escalates as players and stars rally behind Gary Lineker&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In his tweet, he wrote: “I think it&#39;s important to take a stand. There&#39;s just too many of these people on social media. Thanks for your support friends.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A BBC spokesperson said: “We treat any allegations very seriously and we have processes in place to proactively deal with them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As part of that, if we receive information that requires further investigation or examination we will take steps to do this. That includes actively attempting to speak to those who have contacted us to seek further detail and understanding of the situation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If we get no reply to our attempts or receive no further contact that can limit our ability to progress things but it does not mean our enquiries stop.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If, at any point, new information comes to light or is provided – including via newspapers – this will be acted upon appropriately, in line with internal processes.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China plans massive listening programme at the North Pole after declaring success in Arctic test of underwater device]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3226755/china-plans-massive-listening-programme-north-pole-after-declaring-success-arctic-test-underwater?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/06/3eccb704-3819-4ba4-8b75-061f890d53cd_14674093.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China has completed the field testing and evaluation of an underwater listening device that will be deployed on a large scale in the Arctic Ocean, according to the Polar Research Institute of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move is expected to bring further tension to the Arctic region, which is becoming increasingly important in global power plays because of its strategic location, natural resources and the potential for new shipping routes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The acoustic information collected by the planned large-scale listening network could be used in a wide range of applications, including “subglacial communication, navigation and positioning, target detection and the reconstruction of marine environmental parameters,” the institute said in a study published in the Chinese Journal of Polar Research last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These are some of the hottest issues in the world.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shanghai-based institute is a central government agency that plans and coordinates China&#39;s polar activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese scientists and engineers installed the “polar subglacial shallow surface acoustic monitoring buoy system” on a chunk of floating ice in a remote area of the Arctic Ocean on August 9, 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[It is] one of the regions with the most severe climate change in the world,” the institute said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The system carried several instruments, but the most important was a vector hydrophone with multiple sensors arranged in different orientations to measure both the pressure and particle motion of sound waves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sound pressure data can be used to track whales, seals and other sound-emitting sources. The horizontal and vertical vibration of water particles can help scientists understand marine conditions such as currents, waves and the sea floor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fresh data was transmitted to a command centre in China via satellites.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When they left, the scientists were not sure how long the hardware could survive in the harsh polar environment. But its performance surpassed their expectations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“All the sensors equipped in the system exceeded the design indicators by 17.4 per cent,” the institute said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The hardware was built with mature technology and at low cost.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It can be massively used in the construction of the Arctic Ocean environmental monitoring network,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese government has conducted several surveys and placed many monitoring devices, including buoys, in the Arctic region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it had never planted a listening device there, the institute said, partly because of the technical challenges of leaving automatic monitoring of the Arctic water unattended. The long-term operation of the system requires, for instance, a lithium battery that can survive low temperatures and also has sufficient energy to power a large number of electronic equipment and regular communication with the satellite.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Geopolitics may also be a contributing factor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US government has strongly opposed Chinese activities in the area, which is covered by ice caps that can be used by nuclear submarines for transit and hiding.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia has similar concerns although in recent years its position has thawed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We see cooperation with Chinese partners in developing the transit potential of the North Sea Route as promising,” Russian President Vladimir Putin told Chinese President Xi Jinping during a meeting in Moscow in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s interest in the North Pole has increased with rising global temperatures, according to the institute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rapid melting of ice caps is expected to create a much shorter route for marine trade between East Asia, Europe and even North America, giving China greater incentive to engage in Arctic affairs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The opening and commercial use of the Northeast Passage has become a reality,” the institute said. “Our polar research started late.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russian &#39;spy&#39; whale surfaces in Sweden&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the Polar Research Institute test, the vector hydrophone was activated every two hours to detect targets of interest in an attempt to save energy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a trial that lasted more than three months, it detected loud, low-frequency noises that could be produced by human activities such as shipping and oil and gas exploration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The stream of data also helped Chinese scientists better understand the impact on sound by the formation and melting of ice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As seawater freezes, it can release brine and change the salinity and density of the surrounding water.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The amount of hydrophone data is more than 1,000 times greater than that collected by other sensors combined, according to the institute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some researchers complained it was too expensive to send the data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The institute used an American communication satellite service in the test.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Iridium communication system is mostly used in the high-latitude regions of the Arctic at present, the communication cost is high and the signal is unstable due to the lack of satellite update and maintenance in recent years,” the institute said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said China&#39;s polar listening network was likely to shift to Chinese BeiDou satellites for communication.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is not known if the network is already under construction, when it will be finished or how big it will be. The institute did not respond to queries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a report in April, the Centre for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS), a Washington-based think tank, said China&#39;s Arctic research was focused on advancing scientific knowledge, including sea ice composition, space weather and marine life,.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the CSIS said China&#39;s research expeditions in the Arctic also involved extensive oceanographic surveys and acoustic modelling that could help Chinese naval activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has two permanent research stations in the Arctic, one in Norway&#39;s Svalbard archipelago and the other in Iceland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing plans to expand its land-based presence in the region but faces increasing roadblocks from the US and other countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2018, the Polar Research Institute of China tried to buy an airport in Lapland, Finland. The deal was reportedly killed by the Finnish government under pressure from the US.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 18:20:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Marry someone else’: US$40,000 bride price complaint by man in China attracts ridicule on social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226778/marry-someone-else-us40000-bride-price-complaint-man-china-attracts-ridicule-social-media?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/07/9114539a-22df-4e68-a8f4-80ec57793712_09f1ead6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A man in China who complained on a government website about the level of bride price set by his girlfriend&#39;s parents has been widely ridiculed on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man, surnamed Liu, demanded government action after being asked to pay 288,000 yuan (US$40,000).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 15, Liu registered his complaint with the Mayor of Zhenyuan County in Gansu province in northcentral China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When my girlfriend&#39;s parents heard we wished to marry, her mother said the minimum local bride price is 288,000 yuan. And that&#39;s not even mentioning the flat and the car required. In our county, the bride price is only about 120,000 yuan,” Liu wrote in his complaint.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since we really like each other, I don&#39;t even dare to tell her that my family cannot afford such a high bride price.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lengthy complaint letter used a mix of compliments and attempted pressure to convince officials to act on the man&#39;s demands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is a saying, &#39;The poorer the area, the higher the bride price&#39;. Zhenyuan County has experienced rapid economic development in recent years, which even earned recognition from the provincial government. Economic development always liberates ideologies; however, the bride price in some local areas is still remarkably high,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He then sought to justify his request by name-dropping the “No 1 Central Document” for 2023, a set of guidelines released by the China Central Committee and State Council calling for regulation to rein in exorbitant bride prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Four days later, the local government publicity department replied with a letter published on the government website, stating that the overall trend for bride prices in the county has been downwards, adding that they will continue working to reduce it further.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man&#39;s complaint failed to win any sympathy online after it was published and began trending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “I really don&#39;t understand; if you cannot agree on the bride price, just don&#39;t marry her. You should marry someone else who doesn&#39;t ask for a bride price.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person agreed: “By stirring up such a fuss, even if the girl doesn&#39;t ask for a bride price in the end, she won&#39;t marry you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A third person joked that the man was spoiled: “I also want to write a letter to the county mayor, saying that housing prices are too high, the high school enrolment rate is too low, hospital charges are too much, there are too few choices of films in the cinema.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A custom dating back to ancient times, a bride price is money paid by the groom&#39;s family to that of the bride and originally signified the transfer of rights to control a woman&#39;s body and labour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has been cracking down on exorbitant bride prices, which along with escalating marriage costs, has deterred couples from marrying, further exacerbating China&#39;s declining marriage and birth rates which pose significant challenges as the country&#39;s population rapidly ages.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 18:20:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>