<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China says AI should not become a ‘runaway horse’ as UN Security Council holds first meeting on tech risks]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228169/china-says-ai-should-not-become-runaway-horse-un-security-council-holds-first-meeting-tech-risks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/19/aec3498a-1911-4131-9e6a-dcb4ae14e536_f0d5badd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;联合国安理会周二举行首次人工智能会议，中国表示这项技术不应该成为“脱缰之马”，美国警告不要使用它来审查或镇压人民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国外交大臣詹姆斯·克莱弗利 (James Cleverly) 在伦敦担任该机构 7 月份主席期间主持了这次会议，他表示人工智能将“从根本上改变人类生活的方方面面。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们迫切需要塑造变革性技术的全球治理，因为人工智能无国界，”他在表示人工智能可以帮助解决气候变化和促进经济。但他也警告说，这项技术会助长虚假信息，并可能帮助国家和非国家行为者寻求武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯、杰克·克拉克等人向由 15 名成员组成的委员会通报了情况。 -备受瞩目的人工智能初创公司 Anthropic 创始人、中英人工智能伦理与治理研究中心联席主任曾毅教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;世界首届全球人工智能监管峰会会“被冻结”吗？ &#39; 来自亚洲的公司？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;古特雷斯说：“人工智能的军事和非军事应用都可能对全球和平与安全产生非常严重的后果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古特雷斯支持一些国家的呼吁仿照国际原子能机构、国际民用航空组织或政府间气候变化专门委员会的模式，建立一个新的联合国机构，“支持管理这一非凡技术的集体努力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国联合国大使张军将人工智能描述为一把“双刃剑”，并表示北京支持联合国在制定人工智能指导原则方面发挥核心协调作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论是好还是坏、善还是恶取决于人类如何利用它、如何规范它、如何平衡科学发展与安全。”张说，并补充说，应该以人和人工智能为好，来规范发展，“防止这项技术成为脱缰之马”。 .”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国驻联合国副大使杰弗里·德劳伦蒂斯也表示，各国还需要在人工智能和其他新兴技术方面开展合作，以应对威胁破坏和平与安全的人权风险。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“任何成员国都不应使用人工智能来审查、约束、镇压或剥夺人民的权力，”他对理事会说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯质疑负责维护国际和平的理事会是否应该这样做俄罗斯副联合国代表表示：“我们需要的是一场专业、科学、基于专业知识的讨论，这可能需要数年时间，而且这种讨论已经在专门平台上进行。”德米特里·波利安斯基大使。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Zealand-China relations: Wellington’s ‘weakest link’ image in focus as Western allies pursue hawkish line on Beijing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3228136/new-zealand-china-relations-wellingtons-weakest-link-image-focus-western-allies-pursue-hawkish-line?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/18/0ef39c29-c768-4b08-afc9-988044162c69_4185ff6a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;分析人士表示，随着惠灵顿的到来，新西兰对中国的和解态度正日益受到威胁新西兰总理克里斯·希普金斯(Chris Hipkins)在上个月访问北京之前，缓和了对侵犯人权、台湾紧张局势和中国大陆问题的批评。拒绝谴责俄罗斯入侵乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京，希普金斯会见了中国国家主席习近平、国务院总理李强，并签署了一系列贸易协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，从美国返回几天后在立陶宛维尔纽斯举行的北约峰会上，希普金斯表示，随着中国变得更加自信，太平洋地区的竞争变得更加激烈，安全性也越来越低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一在奥克兰举行的中国商业峰会上，希普金斯表示，北京试图施加影响力是加剧战略竞争的主要驱动力，特别是在印太地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;惠灵顿维多利亚大学民主项目的地缘政治分析师杰弗里·米勒（Geoffrey Miller）专注于新西兰的外交政策，他表示，该国的平衡方针由于西方伙伴向北京施压，要求其表现得更加加强硬，美国对北京的态度现在受到威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;希普金斯出席本月的北约峰会“显然是一项长期提议，远非一次性举措”。米勒表示，“表现出与乌克兰的团结”，并指出新西兰最近发布了一份评估报告，将未来描述为“严峻”，并指出中国的“自信”外交政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月，New新西兰还与澳大利亚、加拿大、日本、英国和美国一起签署了《反对与贸易有关的经济胁迫和非市场政策和做法的联合声明》。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;反核新西兰“在玩”吗？米勒说：“[这]显然是针对中国的，尽管它没有提到北京的名字。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼古拉斯·罗斯·史密斯坎特伯雷大学欧洲国家研究中心专注于大国竞争的高级研究员表示，新西兰发现自己处于一个充满挑战的境地，战略对冲变得越来越难以实现。&lt;/p>;&lt; “目前，可靠性似乎是西方的一个大问题，新西兰不仅在北约 AP4 中，而且在五眼联盟中都享有最薄弱的一环的声誉，”史密斯说，他指的是跨大西洋安全联盟的四个国家“亚太伙伴”和五眼国际情报联盟，其中还包括澳大利亚、英国、加拿大和美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北约与亚太四国（澳大利亚、日本、新西兰和美国）的关系更加密切。韩国——近几个月来在中国与俄罗斯军事和安全关系不断增强的情况下“加强对话与合作”。北京指责该联盟试图建立一个地区安全集团，以遏制中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;挪威特罗姆瑟大学政治学和国际关系副教授马克·兰泰涅 (Marc Lanteigne) 表示，其中一位专家表示促使希普金斯对太平洋安全感到担忧的因素是上周中国与所罗门群岛签署的警务协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;批评者担心此举将“巩固中国在太平洋岛屿的战略利益，而牺牲新的利益”。兰泰涅说，北京最近宣布即将访问库克群岛。库克群岛是一个与新西兰“自由联合”的自治国家，管理自己的事务，但其人民被视为新西兰公民并享有自由。在那里生活和工作——也加剧了惠灵顿的焦虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新西兰政府面临着一个严峻的可能性，即维持对中国事实上的不结盟政策正在迅速变得不可行，”Lanteigne &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚、新西兰敦促中国就所罗门群岛警察协议“提供透明度”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;所罗门群岛总理上周访问北京期间签署了一系列协议部长玛纳西·索加瓦雷 (Manasseh Sogavare) 表示，其中包括一项允许中国在 2025 年之前在这个太平洋国家维持警察存在的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新西兰奥塔哥大学国际关系教授罗伯特·帕特曼 (Robert Patman) 表示，这种说法是不准确的惠灵顿以“纯粹被动的方式”在中国及其西方盟友之间进行对冲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帕特曼在提到希普金斯 7 月 7 日的外交政策演讲时表示，新西兰已经明确表示，尽管其与中国的关系是该国“最复杂”的，它将坚持与北京进行“诚实和开放的对话”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然希普金斯在访问期间采取了外交手段，但他的政府继续与中国保持着密切的交流北京在一些问题上的立场，”帕特曼说。 “新西兰认为，不能将中国和俄罗斯混为一谈，良好的对华政策将包括挫败普京对乌克兰的非法入侵。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;上周，中国驻新西兰大使新西兰王小龙警告惠灵顿不要与北约合作，在该地区遏制北京，从而“为魔鬼敞开大门”。北京对北约将其利益更正式地扩大到亚太地区的可能性表示关注，并在维尔纽斯峰会发表联合公报后采取了激烈的态度，该公报表示，中国的野心和强制性政策挑战了北约的“利益、安全和价值观”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“北约正在寻求将亚太纳入其战略利益范围，这对北京来说是一个红灯，”兰泰涅说。他补充说，中国希望让新西兰相信保持较少对抗的立场的好处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥塔哥大学帕特曼指出，新西兰自 2012 年以来一直是北约的热情合作伙伴，他表示惠灵顿“拒绝”，并指出南太平洋国家外交部长 Nanaia Mahuta 驳斥了王对安全联盟的描述。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着太平洋超级大国竞争的升级，新西兰有何计划？&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新西兰有何计划？ h3>;&lt;p>;马胡塔表示，其他国家与北约的关系是他们自己的事，但新西兰和北约有着悠久的合作历史，并对基于国际规则的体系有着共同的坚定承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;然而，坎特伯雷大学的史密斯表示，由于新西兰依赖中国作为出口目的地，因此新西兰可能会听取王的评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和新西兰之间的年贸易额超过美国2021年将达到247亿美元，是2008年两国首次签署自由贸易协定时的四倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年4月，两国升级版自贸协定生效，其中包括新的市场准入商品和服务方面的承诺，以及额外的贸易便利化措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地缘政治分析师米勒表示，与惠灵顿与北京的贸易协议相比，与欧盟的协议“凸显了新西兰仍然需要中国”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后一项协议将新西兰牛肉进口量限制在每年 11,000 吨，该地区拥有 4.5 亿人口。新西兰每年向中国出口超过20万吨牛肉。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 elite Hong Kong schools behind city’s 4 top DSE scorers in university entrance exams]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3228170/3-elite-hong-kong-schools-behind-citys-4-top-scorers-dse-exams?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/19/3ef51bf4-a8ff-4865-b595-53692f224668_bb60ce60.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;今年香港高考四位尖子生来自三位传统名校据《华盛顿邮报》报道，周三早上，当学生们返回校园领取成绩时，《华盛顿邮报》获悉，其中两名优秀学生来自中环圣保罗男女中学，其中一名来自蔡区好望学校。洪先生和铜锣湾皇仁书院的另一位学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，该市在中学文凭考试（DSE）考试中取得了 11 名高分，每一位都来自不同的精英学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;今年四门核心科目中，中国语文模块成绩升幅最大，而英国语文成绩跌幅最大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DSE考试于4月21日至5月18日举行， 48,762名考生。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;4名香港学生在DSE考试中获得满分，创历史新低&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两名男生和两名女生在DSE七级评分中获得满分5**香港考试及评核局周二透露，今年所有七门科目的评分均达到了标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中三名学生（两名男孩和一名女孩）在扩展数学模块选修课中获得了 5** 的成绩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;今年的高分考生人数比 2022 年下降了 64%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考试机构秘书长魏向东早些时候表示，这一数字归因于“运气” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然高分学生较少，但获得高分的学生数量与去年相比并不低，”他说，并指出，今年有 107 名学生获得 40 至 42 分，而 2022 年为 102 名.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些学生可能缺乏一点运气，无法成为尖子生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还指出，今年获得5*和5**的考生总数有所增加0.1个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及香港的移民潮是否导致明星学生流失时，魏说：“我们不认为顶尖学生已经离开香港。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;香港 DSE 考试第二周比第一轮更容易管理：学生&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;学生将通过大学联合课程招生系统 (Jupas) 竞争约 12,000 个一年级资助名额，该系统是一个统一的大学联合招生系统 (Jupas)。申请全日制本科课程的机制，或1.45名合资格学生分配一个名额的比例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外3,000个资助名额将提供给通过非联招途径申请的学生。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;四门核心科目中，考生的中文进步最大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共有10.7%的考生取得5级或以上成绩，高于去年的9.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;约58.9%的学生取得三级或以上成绩，这是进入公立大学的基本要求，较去年的58.5%略有上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港学生完成中学文凭核心科目后松了一口气考试结束&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与去年相比，英语语言成绩在所有核心科目中下降幅度最大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有 9.7% 的学生在英语语言方面取得了 5 级成绩，低于 10 分%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高达 51.6% 的学生在该科目中取得了 3 级成绩，这是进入公立大学的基本要求，比去年的 52% 略有下降。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘I was paying off his loan’: Taiwan woman pays rent for 10 years then discovers boyfriend owns flat after he dumps her]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3227688/i-was-paying-his-loan-taiwan-woman-pays-rent-10-years-then-discovers-boyfriend-owns-flat-after-he?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/56795231-a733-4299-ae9b-34a52dd08c3d_52dfd832.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾女子以为自己要和男友分摊10年的房租&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该女子在大陆社交媒体上发帖称，两人恋爱已有多年。 20年了，在男友坚称比买房更划算后，两人一起租了一套公寓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该女子说，她的男友似乎立刻就找到了他们现在的公寓，三房一卫，每月有房租。租金为新台币 28,000 元（900 美元），尽管从未看到租赁协议或任何有关租金金额的文件，但他们均摊了租金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，她只看到了她被引导相信的房主。一次。每当公寓里有什么东西需要修理时，都是由技工来完成的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我联系所谓的业主时，他告诉我，因为他拥有多处房产，所以他雇用外部承包商来处理维修事宜。这在租赁行业很常见，所以我没有怀疑什么。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的男朋友也向她保证：“我们的房主非常重视租客的隐私，而且他住得很远，所以除非有必要，他不会来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;租金支付过程现在​​回想起来也很可疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的男朋友会在她付清自己的份额后把钱给“业主”。给他。他还声称，业主的地址离他工作的地方很近，所以他更容易直接与他打交道，并声称他担心如果她遇见他，业主可能会尝试和她约会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在在他们交往的第 12 年，这位女士开始了一份新工作，需要更长的通勤时间，并提议搬到离工作单位更近的地方。然而，她的男朋友立即拒绝了这个想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他一直恳求我，承诺找出长途通勤的解决方案。他甚至提出开车送我上下班，并承担所有家庭责任。”她在帖子中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位女士补充说，20 年后，她认为他们都在期待结婚。她错了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，令她惊讶的是，男人突然结束了他们的关系，指责她懒惰、小气，说他们没有未来，并让她搬出去。&lt;/p>;&lt;与此同时，一封写给男友的房贷还款信可疑地寄到了公寓，终于惊悉男友竟是他们居住了10年的公寓的业主。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“看来有人故意转发这封信。信封上明显有被打开过的痕迹。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每月的抵押贷款金额与她“分享”的租金金额相同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以我只是她还清了抵押贷款，结果却被抛弃了。”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的故事很快引起了网上观察人士的同情，其中许多人还就她如何行使其对该房产的合法权利提出了建议.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以你男朋友只付了首付，然后让你替他还了20年的贷款？如果您通过银行转账支付租金，仍有机会拿回钱。但如果你给了他现金，我很遗憾地告诉你，你可能不得不接受损失。”一位人士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位人士补充道：“你的男朋友可能犯了诈骗罪。收集证据并咨询律师。先别和你男朋友对质，这可能会引起他的警觉！”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tricked into trafficking? Hong Kong drug mules face uphill fight to prove innocence, with most spending years in prison before release]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3228156/tricked-trafficking-hong-kong-drug-mules-face-uphill-fight-prove-innocence-most-spending-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/19/09b75011-6939-44a3-aef4-1a61a80a67bf_10d4557d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Aminah* 和她的阿姨 Sunarti* 抵达香港国际机场时感到震惊海关人员用电钻将她们的行李箱拆开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关人员在袋子里发现了5公斤冰毒（俗称冰毒），印尼妇女因贩毒被捕&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在 2019 年 6 月被捕前几周，居住在龙目岛的 25 岁家庭主妇阿米娜 (Aminah) 与她在香港担任家庭佣工的印度尼西亚朋友卡蒂尼* (Kartini*) 取得了联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;上半年香港机场检获毒品猛增80%&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Kartini表示，她结识了一名正在创业的尼泊尔年轻人，需要从印尼进口物资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他愿意为每人提供 1,000 美元，”阿米娜告诉《华盛顿邮报》。 “我阿姨病了，我想用这笔钱让她去香港接受治疗。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;55岁的Aminah和Sunarti同意携带两个行李箱从印度尼西亚到香港，但不知道里面有毒品&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿米娜因被捕并被关押在新界戒备最高的监狱大榄女子监狱而感到震惊，但当她发现自己怀上了第一个孩子时，情况发生了转变。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020 年，她在伊丽莎白女王医院产下一名男孩，并被允许在监狱里陪伴孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2019 年因毒品被捕的年轻人数量下降了 24%香港：警方&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这两名女子在监狱里待了三年等待审判，去年被无罪释放，因为有足够的证据让法官相信她们被骗了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aminah，她的孩子和她的阿姨已经返回龙目岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些妇女是因贩毒或走私而被捕的少数人之一，她们成功地让法院相信她们被欺骗了，从而避免了香港的严厉处罚被判处无期徒刑和 500 万港元（64 万美元）罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港海关的数据显示，自取消 Covid-19 旅行限制以来，更多毒品通过&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年首5个月，机场检获约1,840公斤危险药物，价值8.98亿港元，较去年同期增加1.5倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 据当局称，国际贩毒集团增加了利用快递员向香港走私毒品的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年前六个月，有 30 名入境航空旅客因涉嫌走私近 46 公斤毒品而被捕价值3,900万港元的毒品。 2022年全年，共有20名航空旅客因走私罪被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们年龄在14岁至72岁之间，来自巴西、爱沙尼亚、埃塞俄比亚、马达加斯加、乌干达、蒙古、丹麦和美国。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;青少年毒骡被捕时年仅 15 岁。现在她已服刑 17 年&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;神父约翰·沃瑟斯彭 (John Wotherspoon) 是一名监狱牧师，也是“囚犯之声”(Voice for Prisoners) 的首席执行官，该组织是一个帮助被骗贩运人口后被捕的人的非政府组织，他说他看到了各种各样的策略诱骗人们携带毒品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有些男人在建立了长期恋爱关系后欺骗他们的女朋友，旅行社提供好得令人难以置信的优惠，还有网上骗子愚弄人们相信他们&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我估计，大约 20% 的被捕者都被骗了，”76 岁的 Wotherspoon 说，他是一位来自澳大利亚的天主教神父，已在香港生活了 30 多年。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“被骗成为毒骡的人不是罪犯，也不是贩毒集团的成员，他们是无辜的受害者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去的八年里，囚犯之声帮助了 16 名囚犯。被指控走私毒品的人被无罪释放。该非政府组织目前正在帮助另外四名案件正在审理中的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该非政府组织所帮助的大多数是女性。沃瑟斯彭说，单身母亲或处境绝望的妇女往往成为目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于那些最终被无罪释放的人来说，收集证据以对抗指控的整个过程需要时间，这意味着有时要在监狱里待上几年才能最终获得自由.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;阻止150名毒骡进城的监狱牧师&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;被“好朋友”欺骗&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;51岁的马来西亚私人助理西蒂*被捕2018年6月，她从巴西圣保罗抵港后，行李箱内藏有2公斤可卡因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她表示，自己被一名在吉隆坡认识、相识11年的尼日利亚男子欺骗。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他是一个好朋友，他认识我的家人，并且会来我们家，”她告诉《华盛顿邮报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名男子在吉隆坡经营一家家具出口业务。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我曾为他做过翻译工作，所以当他邀请我去圣保罗和香港参加一些会议时，我同意了，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当她抵达圣保罗后，西蒂被告知会议已取消，但她并没有怀疑任何事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我在巴西呆了三天，正准备前往机场前往香港，这时他从吉隆坡打来电话，让我帮他带一箱衣服回来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港机场海关人员拆开箱子，发现了毒品。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;毒贩利用旅行津贴和快速现金引诱青少年参与人口贩卖&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;通过与她在吉隆坡的家人合作，“囚犯之声”帮助收集了足够的证据来证明她被欺骗，审判时的陪审员一致认为她被欺骗了。是无辜的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位四个孩子的单亲母亲在被还押两年后于 2020 年 12 月被无罪释放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在回到吉隆坡，西蒂说她无法工作，因为她必须照顾生病的母亲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公务员帕尔瓦蒂*（印度国民）住在吉隆坡，当时她以为是旅行社的人向她提供了为期一周的全包优惠。 2019年香港跟团游&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我到达香港时，导游告诉我，团队还没有到达，我可以在等待期间免费在柬埔寨玩几天， ”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我无处可住，而且很紧张，因为我以前从未离开过马来西亚，所以我去了柬埔寨。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在金边呆了很长时间。跟着导游三天。在出发飞往香港的航班之前，他问她是否可以帮他拿一个包回来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我开始怀疑一些事情，”她回忆道。 “我一直在问，为什么我一定要拿它？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，她让金边国际机场的海关人员对行李进行了两次扫描，因为她担心自己被陷害，但他们发现什么都没有。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;城市的年轻走私者告诉：你的年龄不会阻止你入狱&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我以为在那之后一切都很好，”帕瓦蒂说。 “我正要离开香港机场，海关人员拦住并搜查了我的包。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们在发现4公斤可卡因后被捕，并在大榄被拘留了30个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当她的案件于 2021 年开庭时，她的律师能够出示她与那些被指控欺骗她的人之间的短信记录作为证据。检方撤销了此案。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“真正的罪犯逃跑了”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;为那些被指控走私毒品到香港的人辩护的 57 岁律师乔纳森·米奇利 (Jonathan Midgley) 回忆起一名泰国妇女的经历。被告知，如果她不携带一袋毒品到香港，她就再也见不到她的孩子了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“幸运的是，她被无罪释放了，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;批评长刑期他说：“骡子经常被判20年徒刑，而幕后黑手很少被抓到。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“理由是，严惩骡子。”起到了威慑作用，但我怀疑它是否有效，因为许多人被欺骗或在胁迫下被迫这样做。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在与囚犯一起工作的这些年中，沃瑟斯彭了解到各种贩毒集团将毒品运送到香港孔来自世界各地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他曾前往非洲、南美、马来西亚和泰国，敦促犯罪团伙成员停止欺骗无辜者运送毒品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我飞往2018 年圣保罗寻找那里的毒枭，”他说​​。 “我听说他们在贫民窟的食堂里闲逛。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港与加拿大合作，从源头上遏制大麻走私&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他只带了旅行包、护照脖子上挂着十字架，他去了食堂，开始询问他认为参与走私毒品的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我走近一组人，恳求他们停止欺骗无辜的人走私毒品。 ，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他回忆起其中一人对他说的话：“如果你珍视自己的生命，那么你现在就离开。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沃瑟斯彭说，他此行的目的是不仅要面对毒枭并恳求他们停止（他承认这不太可能奏效），还要追溯“为囚犯之声”提供帮助的人们的足迹并收集证据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他之前曾使用过证据获得的证据以及他与贩毒集团互动的证据，写信给监督案件的法官，这些案件已以无罪告终，其中最著名的是中国公民李丹丹一案，他被骗经吉隆坡走私 2 公斤冰毒到香港。 /p>;&lt;p>;这名广州女子于 2015 年在香港机场被捕，背包中装有毒品。她于 2018 年被无罪释放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wotherspoon 表示，防止人们上当受骗非常重要。毒品走私者的伎俩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为此，他的非政府组织要求因走私毒品而被捕的囚犯写信警告其他人不要做他们所做的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些参加这场反毒品活动的人- 毒品运动有时会减刑，非政府组织相信这有助于阻止许多人成为毒骡。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;未经审判就被监禁数月，然后在 48 小时内离开香港：6 名外国人毒品指控撤销后，国民被告知“滚出去”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;犯罪团伙使用各种方法让人们为他们携带毒品跨境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沃瑟斯彭表示，帮助嫌疑人要困难得多吞下藏在体内的装有毒品的颗粒后被抓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我从未见过此类案件中有人被无罪释放，很难证明他们是被强迫的，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港海关发言人表示，在打击跨境贩毒方面，海关一直密切留意全球及本地的毒品趋势，并采取有效的执法策略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月26日，海关人员在机场拦截了一名从吉隆坡抵达的 42 岁女子，她在琼脂粉盒中发现了 14 公斤疑似可卡因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就在 9 天前，一名 25 岁的女子从巴西通过吉隆坡警方在警方发现七个装有假隔间的香水瓶，用来藏匿近一公斤疑似可卡因后被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月14日，一名来自美国的62岁男子从Sao抵达Paulo经巴黎被捕，涉嫌携带价值800万港元的液体可卡因浸泡在17张床单中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“迅速调整执法策略和资源部署，加强打击各类毒品发言人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他又表示，市民可致电海关24小时热线（2545 6182）或举报罪案专用电邮账户举报怀疑贩毒活动。 (crimereport@customs.gov.hk)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;* 为保护受访者身份而更改姓名&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea fires two missiles after US submarine arrives in South Korea]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3228167/north-korea-fires-two-missiles-after-us-submarine-arrives-south-korea?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 07:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/19/3b4c5661-bc58-45a9-b415-e7ea5fa4ba3e_309c8e58.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本和韩国军方表示，朝鲜周三早些时候向东发射了两枚弹道导弹就在美国弹道导弹潜艇四十年来首次抵达韩国港口几个小时后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本防卫省表示，这两枚导弹似乎都落在日本专属经济区之外。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国参谋长联席会议（JCS）呼吁朝鲜停止此类发射。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们强烈谴责朝鲜连续发射弹道导弹，这是破坏和平的严重挑衅行为and stability of the Korean peninsula as well as the international community, and are a clear violation of UN Security Council resolutions,” the JCS said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;North Korea threatens to shoot down US planes as it condemns nuclear moves&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US military said it was aware of the missile launches and was consulting closely with its allies and partners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The launches do not appear to pose an immediate threat to the United States or to its allies, but the events highlight the destabilising impact of North Korea&#39;s illicit weapons programme, the US Indo-Pacific Command said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first missile reached an altitude of 50km (31 miles) and covered a range of 550km, while the second one rose as high as 50km and flew 600km, Japanese Defence Minister Yasukazu Hamada told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan lodged a protest against the missile launches through diplomatic channels, he said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The firing comes nearly a week after North Korea tested its latest Hwasong-18 intercontinental ballistic missile, a launch Pyongyang said was a warning to the United States and other adversaries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also on Tuesday, a US soldier facing disciplinary action fled across the inter-Korean border into North Korea. The soldier is believed to be in North Korean custody, Washington said, creating a fresh crisis between the two foes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“North Korea&#39;s latest firing of ballistic missiles is probably unrelated to an American soldier crossing the inter-Korean border, but such an incident doesn&#39;t help matters either,” said Leif-Eric Easley, a professor at Ewha University in Seoul.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;North Korea “undoubtedly opposes” a new US-South Korea nuclear war planning group that met for the first time on Tuesday, as well as the visit of the US nuclear ballistic missile submarine, he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Johnson & Johnson must pay US$18.8 million to man who says he got cancer from baby powder]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228168/johnson-johnson-must-pay-us188-million-man-who-says-he-got-cancer-baby-powder?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 07:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/599a27c5-86ce-42ce-9ca7-14b61f710cb3_bd64980f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Johnson &amp; Johnson must pay US$18.8 million to a California man who said he developed cancer from exposure to its baby powder, a jury decided on Tuesday, a setback for the company as it seeks to settle thousands of similar cases over its talc-based products in US bankruptcy court.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jury ruled in favour of Emory Hernandez Valadez, who filed suit last year in California state court in Oakland against J&amp;J, seeking monetary damages. Hernandez, 24, has said he developed mesothelioma, a deadly cancer, in the tissue around his heart as a result of heavy exposure to the company&#39;s talc since childhood.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The six-week trial was the first over talc that New Brunswick, New Jersey-based J&amp;J has faced in almost two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jury found that Hernandez was entitled to damages to compensate him for his medical bills and pain and suffering, but declined to award punitive damages against the company. Hernandez will not be able to collect the judgment in the foreseeable future, thanks to a bankruptcy court order freezing most litigation over J&amp;J&#39;s talc.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;J&amp;J has denied that its talc products contain asbestos, which is linked to mesothelioma, or cause cancer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In closing arguments to the jury on July 10, J&amp;J&#39;s lawyers said there was no evidence either linking Hernandez&#39;s kind of mesothelioma to asbestos or proving that Hernandez was ever exposed to tainted talc. Hernandez&#39;s lawyers during closing arguments accused J&amp;J of a “despicable” decades-long cover-up of asbestos contamination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hernandez testified in June, telling jurors that he would have avoided J&amp;J&#39;s talc if he had been warned that it contained asbestos, as his lawsuit alleges. Jurors heard from Hernandez&#39;s mother, Anna Camacho, who said she used large amounts of J&amp;J&#39;s baby powder on her son when he was a baby and through childhood. She cried as she described Hernandez&#39;s illness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tens of thousands of plaintiffs have sued, alleging that J&amp;J&#39;s baby powder and other talc products sometimes contained asbestos and caused ovarian cancer and mesothelioma. J&amp;J has said its talc products are safe and do not contain asbestos, which has been linked to mesothelioma.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Record US$417m award in lawsuit blaming cancer on baby powder&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;J&amp;J subsidiary LTL Management in April filed for bankruptcy in Trenton, New Jersey, proposing to pay US$8.9 billion to settle more than 38,000 lawsuits and prevent new cases from coming forward.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the company&#39;s second attempt to resolve talc claims in bankruptcy, after a federal appeal court rejected an earlier bid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most litigation has been halted during bankruptcy proceedings, but US Chief Bankruptcy Judge Michael Kaplan, who is overseeing LTL&#39;s Chapter 11, let Hernandez&#39;s trial proceed because he is expected to live only a short time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hernandez&#39;s form of mesothelioma is extremely rare, making his case different from the vast majority pending against J&amp;J.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asbestos plaintiffs are seeking to have LTL&#39;s latest bankruptcy filing dismissed. They have argued the filing was brought in bad faith to insulate the company from litigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;J&amp;J and LTL have argued that bankruptcy delivers settlement payouts to plaintiffs more fairly, efficiently and equitably than trial courts, which they have likened to a “lottery” in which some litigants get large awards and others nothing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;J&amp;J said in bankruptcy court filings that the costs of its talc-related verdicts, settlements and legal fees have reached about US$4.5 billion.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Marshall Islands seeks US apology and full compensation for damage from its 67 nuclear tests]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228166/marshall-islands-seeks-us-apology-and-full-compensation-damage-its-67-nuclear-tests?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 07:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/20584455-c441-48d2-b43b-494a543284ef_b8a147d2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Marshall Islands on Tuesday called on Washington to pay “full” compensation for the health, environmental and cultural damage caused by 67 nuclear tests carried out by the American government, refusing to accept the Joe Biden administration&#39;s newest version of a strategic agreement that has steered bilateral ties for decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the people of the Pacific nation who played a major role in helping Allied forces capture Japanese invaders in the region during World War II, said Kenneth Kedi, speaker of the country&#39;s parliament, in testimony before an Indo-Pacific task force of the House Natural Resources Committee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Narrating what he called a brief history of the sacrifices made by the Marshall Islands for the US, Kedi told the panel that, after the wartime fighting ended, it was the Marshallese who “without a choice” found themselves in the middle of the Cold War.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The nuclear tests in question took place across the archipelago between 1946 and 1958, and the US made a “massive display of power” by detonating the bombs on the islands, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kedi testified that the tests “unfortunately” led to high rates of cancer and extensive environmental damage, explaining that both his parents died prematurely from cancer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And this is not a unique story for me or for the Marshall Islands. Most families have gone through the same.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Marshallese politician quoted a UN report in urging the US to go on record and apologise to his country, saying: “We are yet to get an apology.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Combined, the tests were “thousands of times as powerful as the bomb dropped on Hiroshima”, according to a 2015 report published by the Pulitzer Centre. Cancer is a leading cause of death on the Marshall Islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As US sees future in Pacific islands, has China &#39;overplayed its hand&#39;?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Kedi cited the findings of a nuclear claims tribunal set up between the US and the Marshall Islands “to adjudicate and pay substantiated and warranted claims”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the tribunal ran out of funds after paying a small fraction of the damages it awarded, with the total amount of unpaid awards standing at US$3 billion in current dollars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marshallese people had sacrificed significantly by giving their traditional land to the US for military use, Kedi testified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the event of “any war coming from, who knows where,” the Marshall Islands would be “the first shield of defence before anything”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As US Congress debates budget, Pacific island nations watch with concern&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The American military installation on the country&#39;s largest island, Kwajalein Atoll, has been described by the US Department of Defence as “an important asset that would be costly and difficult to replicate”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After administering Micronesia, the Marshall Islands and Palau under a UN trusteeship after World War II, the US signed international treaties with each as sovereign Pacific nations in 1986 and 1994 under the Compact of Free Association or Cofa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pacts granted the US military access to each nation&#39;s land, air and sea in exchange for financial assistance and permission to legally live, work and go to school in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For decades following World War II, Washington did not regard the Pacific island region as a national security priority. But as China&#39;s economic and geopolitical influence in the Indo-Pacific grew, the US took more notice of the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We see the presence and influence of China on a daily basis,” Joseph Yun, President Joe Biden&#39;s special envoy for Cofa negotiations, told the panel on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yun accused China of employing “coercive tactics” in Cofa states as well as in other Pacific nations like the Solomon Islands and Fiji, noting a security deal signed between Beijing and Honiara last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To take somehow our friendship with these compact states for granted will be a real mistake,” he cautioned the lawmakers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Cofa pacts are set to expire this year and next. The Biden administration budget for 2024 has proposed more than US$7 billion for more than 20 years to extend the deals, the largest-ever congressional budget request for the region. Out of this total, US$2.9 billion would be earmarked for the Marshall Islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, Yun said the US had finalised compact terms with Micronesia and Palau and that he hoped the Marshall Islands would soon follow suit. However, the negotiations have dragged on.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China confirms signing of Solomon Islands security pact&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Biden administration&#39;s enhanced budget for the region also awaits congressional approval, with new Cofa promises extremely difficult to fulfil amid fierce partisan disagreements over federal spending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yun believed that if Congress was unable to pass the budget in a timely manner “our credibility will suffer enormous damage”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Palauan President Surangel Whipps Jnr sounded a similar warning before the House committee on Tuesday, testifying that despite the US installing on Palau its closest early- warning radar to Asia, his country had remained “economically challenged”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He described access to federal programmes and financial assistance as “inadequate”, saying Palau and the US “are joined at the hip, and Palau recognises Taiwan&#39;s right to exist”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Continuation of the relationship”, Whipps added, “can&#39;t be taken for granted”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China says it will launch reusable spacecraft as soon as 2027]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3228139/china-says-it-will-launch-reusable-spacecraft-soon-2027?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/18/52670e97-7ea0-4830-b4af-70b731436461_e7894933.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s first reusable spacecraft will be launched as soon as 2027, according to the deputy chief engineering designer of the country&#39;s manned space programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang Liwei, who was the first Chinese sent into space, also told Guangzhou Daily on Monday that the new spacecraft would be able to transport seven astronauts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It will also play a critical role in future construction of China&#39;s space station and moon landing mission,” Yang was quoted as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the China Manned Space Engineering Office, the spacecraft will be reusable for both near-Earth orbit and deep-space exploration missions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A full-size prototype successfully completed a 67-hour test flight, carried by a Long March 5 rocket, in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It uses new materials and structures that take its heat resistance to three to four times that of China&#39;s Shenzhou spacecrafts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The materials can withstand temperatures as high as 3,000 degrees Fahrenheit during re-entry, while the weight of the heat-resistant structure has been reduced by more than 30 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The spacecraft has also been designed to be reused – the return capsule will be ready for the next mission once it is examined and its “coating” replaced. That means – theoretically at least – key parts of the spacecraft can be reused up to 10 times, significantly reducing launch costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Western companies drawn to China&#39;s lunar research station project&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Zhou Jianping, chief designer of China&#39;s manned space programme, told state broadcaster CCTV last month that the latest design retained a “blunt bullet-head shape” but the internal space is larger than previous versions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The design has been streamlined from three compartments to two, making it safer and more economical,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With capacity to carry seven astronauts, it will be comparable to the new generation of American manned spacecraft – SpaceX&#39;s Dragon V2 and Boeing&#39;s CST-100 Starliner. Nasa&#39;s Orion MPCV carries six.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 8.8 metres and weighing 21.6 tonnes it is also twice the size of the Dragon V2, which weighs about 9.5 tonnes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new spacecraft will be use for China&#39;s crewed moon landing programme, working with a separate landing spaceship, specialised lunar spacesuits, manned rovers and other equipment to achieve this goal by 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has not yet been named. The China Manned Space Engineering Office said on its official WeChat page on Friday that a competition would soon be launched to name the new-generation spacecraft as well as the new lunar landing spaceship.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The office on Monday also put out a call to universities, research institutions and tech companies to submit scientific payloads to be taken to the moon with the lander by 2030.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Search warrant served in Tupac Shakur killing investigation, almost 30 years after shooting, by Las Vegas police]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228165/las-vegas-police-serve-search-warrant-1996-tupac-shakur-killing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 05:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/71c0ab5a-0086-4fad-a038-9ce9a23e2077_29e880c5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Authorities in Nevada confirmed on Tuesday that they served a search warrant this week in connection with the long-unsolved killing of rapper Tupac Shakur nearly 30 years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shakur, one of the most prolific figures in hip-hop, was killed on the night of September 7, 1996, in a drive-by shooting in Las Vegas. He was 25.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Las Vegas Metropolitan Police Department said the search warrant was executed on Monday in the nearby city of Henderson.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Department spokesman Aden OcampoGomez said he could not provide further details on the latest development in the case, including whether it was served at a home or a business, citing the open investigation. Nevada does not have a statute of limitations for prosecuting homicide cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tupac was gunned down inside a black vehicle stopped at a red light near the Las Vegas Strip. Shot multiple times, the rapper was rushed to a nearby hospital, where he died a week later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Largely considered one of the most influential and versatile rappers of all time, the six-time Grammy Award nominated Shakur has had five No 1 albums: 1995&#39;s Me Against the World, 1996&#39;s All Eyez on Me, and three posthumous releases: 1996&#39;s The Don Killuminati: The 7 Day Theory, which was recorded under the name Makaveli, as well as 2001&#39;s Until The End of Time and 2004&#39;s Loyal to the Game.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2017, he was inducted into the Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame by Snoop Dogg. In June of this year, the rapper received a posthumous star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His professional music career only lasted five years, but Tupac secured 21 Billboard Hot 100s, including two top 10 hits: “Dear Mama/Old School” in 1995, and his best-known track, 1996&#39;s “How Do U Want It/California Love” featuring K-Ci and JoJo.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why Tupac still reigns in hip hop 20 years after his death, and why his legacy is at risk&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The latter song spent two weeks at the No 1 spot on the Billboard Hot 100. It came from his final studio album and Death Row Records debut, All Eyez on Me.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Luminate, Tupac has sold 33 million albums (41 million when including track sale and streaming equivalents).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rapper&#39;s on-demand video and audio streams total 10.1 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has also had some museum exhibits that paid homage to his life, including “Tupac Shakur. Wake Me When I&#39;m Free”, which opened in 2021 and has toured multiple American cities.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[An American economist is getting a top EU job. And France’s Emmanuel Macron isn’t happy about it]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3228164/american-economist-getting-top-eu-job-and-frances-emmanuel-macron-isnt-happy-about-it?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.19 04:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/34927eea-d292-4172-9dbb-ce8b1d130afb_bf8a08a9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;With French President Emmanuel Macron insisting the European Union needs more strategic independence, he seemed decidedly piqued on Tuesday over the EU head office&#39;s plans to hire an American expert as its chief competition economist.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Is there really no great European researcher with academic qualifications that could do this job?” Macron asked at a summit of EU leaders with their Latin American counterparts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a bloc of some 450 million people, “is there no one in the 27 member states that has a researcher good enough to advise the Commission? That is a real question mark”, Macron said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EU&#39;s executive Commission announced last week that it had appointed Yale economics professor Fiona Scott Morton as chief competition economist in its department tasked with ensuring that “all companies compete equally and fairly on their merits within the single market, to the benefit of consumers, businesses and the European economy as a whole”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron insisted that he has nothing against Scott Morton herself, an economist with multiple diplomas from elite schools.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the French leader demanded answers from the commission, and suggested that hiring a non-EU citizen to such a senior job should not be allowed under EU statutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some other politicians and EU lawmakers – mainly French – have also voiced their complaints.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Macron insists France won&#39;t be US &#39;vassal&#39; on Taiwan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While the commission stressed Scott Morton&#39;s track record in advising US government agencies, Macron stressed her experience consulting for private companies – which include big tech firms such as Microsoft – and suggested that could pose a conflict of interest in her new job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron called it “extremely worrying” if no one in the EU is qualified for the job, and a sign that “we have a very big problem with all European academic systems” and “must massively invest in academic research in economics”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scott Morton is expected to start work September 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 19 Jul 2023 04:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>