<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[South Korea pivots to ‘hard-line stance’ on China as Yoon questions envoy’s comments]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3223908/south-korea-pivots-hard-line-stance-china-yoon-questions-envoys-comments?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 15:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/0f40eeb7-4cb3-4bea-94d7-5d49e6b28166_c67fc16e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国总统尹锡烈周二表示，他怀疑中国大使是否据当地媒体报道，韩国在与北京的关系中正转向“强硬立场”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yoon 是在中国特使与北京举行的一次内阁会议上发表上述评论的。韩联社援引多位与会人士的话说，警告首尔不要在中美竞争中做出“错误的赌注”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，首尔外交部召见了大使邢海明，此前他指责韩国受美国影响导致双边关系恶化，敦促韩国停止与中国“脱钩”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“看邢大使的态度，是否有相互尊重的态度值得怀疑或作为外交官促进友谊，”韩联社援引 Yoon 在会议上的话说。 “我们的人民对他的不当行为感到不满。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国《东亚日报》周二报道称，在两国会晤后，首尔在与中国的关系中转向“强硬立场”北京使用了“强硬”的外交言辞，援引一位“关键”政府官员的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首尔将寻求减少对中国供应链的依赖，如果需要，可能会改变韩国对“三不”安全的定义东亚援引未具名的韩国官员的话报道称，与中国达成共识。该报报道称，该官员称，由于中国的“荒谬”言论，两国关系恶化，除非中国尊重韩国，否则很难追求共同价值观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报报道称，“风险”来自其对电池材料等中国商品的依赖，并强调还没有达到与世界第二大经济体完全脱钩的程度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报告是最新的在最近两国之间的外交来回中，两国关系在 2017 年出现下滑。中国当时反对韩国部署美国终端高空区域防御导弹防御系统，担心其强大的雷达会允许监视中国的导弹系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“深刻反省”：中国以针锋相对的方式召见韩国特使&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;时任总统文在寅通过承诺“三不”平息了北京的愤怒” 没有新的萨德部署，没有参与美国的导弹防御网络，也没有将美国、日本和韩国之间的安全合作转变为军事联盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大使邢本月告诉韩国反对党领袖李在明表示，如果现任总统尹恩惠政府在与中国打交道时摆脱外部因素，他将不胜感激，这可能是指首尔与美国的关系不断加深。韩国第一任外交部副部长张浩镇于次日召见邢，就其认为挑衅和干涉韩国国内政治的言论发出严厉警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，中国作出回应，根据北京政府的一份声明，中国在会见韩国大使郑在镐时对首尔的言论表示“严重关切和不满”。声明还说，中国领导人希望韩方反思当前双边关系中存在的问题并认真对待。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及有关情况时，中国外交部发言人汪文斌表示，当前中南关系面临的挑战韩国关系“不是中国造成的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国指责前三星高管窃取中国芯片工厂建设&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;韩国正在等待中国对大使的适当措施韩联社在另一份报告中援引尹办公室一位未具名官员的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尹被夹在韩国的主要安全盟友美国和韩国最大的贸易伙伴中国之间。他表示支持拜登政府重组全球供应链以减少对中国依赖的呼吁，这招致了北京方面的批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，中国国家主席习近平呼吁加强高科技制造和工作领域的合作共同维护确保供应链安全的全球自由贸易体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国已向包括韩国在内的盟友施加压力，要求它们遵守其对向美国销售先进芯片和芯片制造设备的全面限制措施中国，SK 海力士公司和三星电子公司等韩国主要半导体制造商在中国设有工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong authorities endorse deal to give public servants up to 4.65 per cent pay rise]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3223909/hong-kong-authorities-endorse-deal-give-public-servants-465-cent-pay-rise?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 15:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/8637fb8c-f8c9-45cb-b609-5e26ecabcabb_e2ef7209.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港公务员的加薪幅度将高达 4.65%当局周二批准的一项交易将使纳税人今年花费 52 亿港元（6.63 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管多个工会呼吁提高高级公务员的加薪幅度，但行政会议已从 4 月 1 日起，高薪和中低级员工分别保持 2.87% 和 4.65% 的涨幅，坚持自己的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府需要向立法机关申请 115.2 亿港元的拨款，用于公务员的加薪——全年达 52 亿港元——以及香港反贪局、受资助机构和辅助人员的加薪。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“在作出这个决定时，行政长官和行政会议已全面考虑员工方面对薪酬优惠的回应，以及公务员每年调整薪酬机制下的其他相关因素，包括香港的经济状况;政府的财政状况；生活成本的变化；净薪酬趋势指标；及公务员士气，”公务员事务局周二表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府会尽快将公务员薪酬调整方案提交立法会财务委员会审议。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;行政会议批准提高香港公务员薪酬的计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这将是自 2019 年以来的最高增幅，此前 2022 年所有薪金级别的增幅减少了 2.5%，并且两次 -在 Covid-19 大流行期间，年薪冻结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港高级政府官员协会和中国公务员协会等几个工会早些时候对高级官员 2.87% 的拟议加薪表示失望工作人员，称政府没有考虑士气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前者呼吁提出全面加薪 5% 的反提议。立法会公共服务委员会将于下周一讨论调整。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 15:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Gay Games organisers refuse to cancel event in face of activists’ warning that anyone criticising Beijing or city could be arrested]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3223903/hong-kong-gay-games-organisers-refuse-cancel-event-face-activists-warning-anyone-criticising-beijing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 14:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/cbefd49b-7d69-4010-9a03-ae22de4d0444_3bae5f6d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港同性恋运动会的组织者拒绝取消为期 9 天的呼吁活动将于今年晚些时候在香港举行，此前五名人权活动人士指责该团队“与迫害香港人的亲独裁者结盟”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运动会将于 11 月在香港举行今年3-11，将成为亚洲第一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们对同志运动会香港代表队的诚信遭到毫无根据的诽谤深感悲痛，并完全拒绝任何取消运动会的呼吁， ”组织者周一在其网站上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们对香港以外的某些人正在积极破坏和破坏今年晚些时候成功举办的奥运会感到沮丧和失望。”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“我真的不知道他们为什么要提出这些指控，正如我们在公开声明中所说，整个领导团队都是志愿者，”该活动的联合主席 Lisa Lam 告诉周二发布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去六年来，我们一直在这样做，我们的唯一目的是为香港带来包容性的奥运会。这一直是我们的目标和目的。我们不是政治组织。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该声明是在上周三发表在体育新闻网站上的评论之后发表的，其中五名人权活动人士呼吁取消在香港举行的赛事，因为“人类-权利问题太大了”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自称为 LGBTQ 香港人权活动家的 Alex Chan、Clark Leung、Lorraine Pan、Adam Nelson 和 Samuel Bickett 在评论中警告说，国家的实施国安法意味着任何批评北京或香港并参加活动的人一进入城市就有被捕的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港同志运动会组织者对 Covid 限制解除后的投票率持乐观态度&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;“这意味着许多 LGBTQ 运动员，包括无数中国、台湾和香港的 LGBTQ 持不同政见者，甚至无法考虑参加奥运会，”他们说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾同志运动会附属机构已他们表示，出于对运动员安全的担忧，他们已经退出了赛事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还指责奥运会的领导团队“与对香港人民的广泛迫害负有责任的亲独裁人物结盟” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我肯定会拒绝这种说法，”Lam 说。 “我认为每个人的安全和保障当然是最重要的。我们一直在孜孜不倦地开展这项活动，包括确保每个参与者的安全。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港同志运动会 (GGHK) 说：“在亚洲，LGBTQ+ 社区没有那么多机会以如此规模聚集在一起，并参加一项庆祝广泛社会并不总是接受的身份认同的国际活动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;同性恋运动会在没有公开的赞助商的帮助下“将带出香港” funding&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这就是为什么我们 200 多名充满热情和使命感的志愿者团队如此努力工作，为香港带来一届成功的奥运会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们有制定了全面的政策和程序，以确保参加比赛的每个人都感到安全和受到保护，”它继续说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港的 LGBTQ+ 人群，虽然没有其他国家和地区已经实施的一些权利，例如作为同性婚姻，能够在公共场合公开和真实地生活，并且 LGBTQ+ 游客在访问这座城市时没有安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港被评为世界上最安全的城市之一，并且基于性别或性取向针对某人的仇恨犯罪很少见。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam 和 GGHK 的营销和公共关系总监 David Ko 表示，他们已经与台湾的许多人进行了沟通，他们表示有兴趣&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在同志运动会的强烈反对声中，冷静的头脑必须占上风&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“很遗憾，台湾的团体觉得他们不能参加，”Lam说。 “但我们仍然有来自台湾的人表现出兴趣，并询问他们如何以个人身份加入我们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ko 也是文章中点名的领导团队成员之一。他被指责为“一个直言不讳的反民主倡导者、集中营否认者，以及政府镇压香港人的狂热支持者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对我来说，尊重多元化非常重要现在有一群志愿者，”Ko 说。 “我们的个人政治是什么真的无关紧要。我从一开始就坚持这一点。这是关于我们聚在一起要做的事情，那就是创造一个非常成功的活动。我们需要专注于此。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市正在与墨西哥瓜达拉哈拉共同举办第 11 届奥运会，后者将在同一时期举办多项体育赛事。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;同志运动会让香港有机会展示其宽容、热情的一面&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这是该赛事 40 年历史上首次在亚洲和拉丁美洲同时举行。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;批评香港同志运动会的活动人士要求将整个活动转移到瓜达拉哈拉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年活动的注册人数很少；截至 5 月 11 日，香港只有 433 名付费注册者报名参加，而瓜达拉哈拉有 780 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，Lam 表示，这一数字仅考虑了个人注册，并基于他们的企业承诺有，他们预计总数约为 1,300。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港同志运动会原定于 2022 年 11 月举行，但由于 Covid-19 大流行而推迟。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Faster and cheaper way to check for microplastics in Hong Kong drinking water unveiled by Education University]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3223850/faster-and-cheaper-way-check-microplastics-hong-kong-drinking-water-unveiled-education-university?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/fd36ee97-261f-4ac7-91fb-551ecfc7356c_b458bb86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港科学家开发出一种更快、更便宜地测试水中微塑料水平的方法。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教育大学的团队周二表示，新测试可以在传统方法的 10% 内完成，成本仅为传统方法的 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新技术使用总有机碳分析仪，一种通常在过滤站和废水处理厂中使用的设备，用于测试环境中的微塑料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然这些设备用于测量环境中有机碳、无机碳或总碳的含量水或土壤样本，无法给出确切数量的塑料碎片或识别样本中微塑料的类型，它们可以提供总体数量以供参考。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就像检测 Covid-19 的快速测试.它可以显示给定区域的感染率。但你仍然需要聚合酶链反应测试才能更准确地了解，”领导该项目的大学环境科学副教授 Chris Tsang Yiu-fai 解释说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsang 说这项技术可以完成分析时间从 40 小时缩短到 60 小时，并且能够处理各种样品，包括饮用水、海水、污泥和土壤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;传统方法涉及测量微塑料的存在&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些设备的成本在 300,000 港元（38,300 美元）到 500,000 港元之间，而传统的实验室标准光谱仪的成本可能在 150 万到 230 万港元之间。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;科学家补充说，他们希望这项技术可以应用于监测城市的饮用水和废水，以帮助政府找到应对快速增加的污染物的方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城市的饮用水主要由邻近广东省的东河供应，每年向该市供应多达 11 亿立方米（2900 亿加仑）的淡水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这项发明可以为当局提供日常概览水质，例如东河饮用水中的微塑料含量，”Cheng 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;研究表明，数十亿塑料碎片涌入香港海域&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;较大塑料分解产生的微小颗粒，例如由合成纤维制成的瓶子和衣服。该术语还包括含有微珠的商业产品，例如去角质磨砂膏和洗面奶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种小于 5 毫米长的颗粒几乎随处可见，甚至在 3,000 米（9,843 英尺）以下的海底沉积物中也是如此。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 12 月在挪威进行的一项开创性研究表明，微塑料可以穿过胎盘进入未出生的婴儿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些颗粒被证明会破坏人体细胞和 DNA，有助于将毒素吸入血液并触发&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际自然保护联盟的研究发现，合成纺织品是微塑料的最大来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人造织物占全球释放量的 35%微塑料，其次是轮胎磨损，占 28%，城市灰尘占 24%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;饮用水中的微塑料没有公认的国际水平，也没有测试水样污染物的全球标准化方法。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;香港需要电动汽车电池回收设施来处理日益增多的垃圾：专家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;水务署表示将与内地当局、国际组织和城市机构“保持最新状态”并在必要时采取适当的行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位女发言人说：“传统的处理工艺……旨在去除微粒，因此有望有效去除小于一微米的微塑料。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新鲜目前，来自东河的水或水库收集的雨水经过各种混凝剂处理以去除杂质，然后再进行过滤、消毒并通过管道输送给客户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环境保护署和渠务署表示教育大学技术所能提供的信息有限，无法进行准确评估。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它无法区分不同类型的微塑料，也无法提供有关微塑料数量、大小、颜色或形状的任何信息，所有这些都构成了评估微塑料污染的有用和重要信息，”一位女发言人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“微塑料相关研究和监测计划的主要主题和关键考虑因素之一是对有意义的分析方法进行标准化数据基准和共享。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她补充说，环保部门欢迎“与当地学术界的建议和合作机会，以进一步提高我们的微塑料监测和评估能力”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong can still handle big golf events even after land from Fanling course is taken back, city leader John Lee says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3223894/hong-kong-can-still-handle-big-golf-events-even-after-land-fanling-course-taken-back-city-leader?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 13:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/899f66ee-af7c-4fc4-803c-feae8b11a518_7af3b7fd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;即使在政府采取措施后，香港仍有能力举办国际高尔夫锦标赛该市领导人曾表示，这座城市最古老的公共住房球场的后部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超周二还表示，政府“准备并愿意”将该场地借给高尔夫锦标赛组织者在 9 月收回了 32 公顷的土地之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee 的言论是在前一天沙特阿拉伯支持的高尔夫锦标赛阿美石油公司系列赛 (ATS) 的组织者发出警告后发表的，如果该计划继续进行，将被迫为 10 月份的香港回合寻找其他地点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们收回土地后，我们将开放给公众使用，”李在每周例会前说执行委员会是该市的最高决策机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“同时，如果需要，我们准备并乐于提供球场来组织高尔夫锦标赛的相关活动，例如停车、促销和接待.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[归还32公顷场地后]，仍将有两个完整的18洞球场加上第三个球场的10个洞。我们的评估是它们足以举办大型比赛。因此，回归不会对赛事产生任何影响。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港“如果住房计划继续进行，可能会失去阿美车队系列高尔夫赛事”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Old 的 32 公顷土地球场是私人香港高尔夫球会租用的 172 公顷粉岭场地的一部分。政府原计划到 2029 年建造 12,000 套公共公寓，以帮助解决该市长期存在的住房危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在环保部门要求保护林地后，该项目可能不得不缩减规模。发展当局还计划将该地块从住宅区重新划分为“未确定”区，为重新设计争取时间，这将使住房项目推迟两年。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港高尔夫球场摊牌：住房计划的支持者、反对者辩论&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府的重新分区申请吸引了各方在城规会周一开始的公开听证会上表态赞成或反对房屋建议，该听证会安排了至少五场会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括 ATS 锦标赛总监 Vicky Jones，她警告说，如果继续推进该项目，该市可能会失去锦标赛和其他未来赛事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，由沙特阿拉伯支持的 LIV Golf 举办的锦标赛，根据两个月前在澳大利亚阿德莱德举办的一场活动，这座城市正在争取明年举办，可能会产生超过 7000 万美元的经济效益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee 表示政府将听取董事会的建议&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个方案在上届政府首次提出时，已经收到了很多公众的意见，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在已经进入公开听证程序城市规划委员会会在听取不同意见后提出建议。政府将听取董事会的建议，然后再对土地作出最终决定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说：“但无论决定如何，政府都会如期在 9 月份收回土地。” &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;有争议的在香港高尔夫球场建造房屋的计划接下来会怎样？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港领导人还表示，公开听证会表明该市尊重言论自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“这充分表明香港居民表达意见的权利受到尊重，政府一定会听取他们的意见，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该委员会去年收到了 6,788 份公众回应，压倒性的 99.6% 反对该计划。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Not a beauty contest’: threat to ground ‘overweight’ flight attendants by Chinese airline sparks storm of online criticism]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3223796/not-beauty-contest-threat-ground-overweight-flight-attendants-chinese-airline-sparks-storm-online?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/f741ab57-8815-473a-892d-ab8be5d5bab7_2a45168d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一家中国航空公司裁定“超重”空乘人员必须停止工作网上一片批评声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海南航空公司 6 月初发布的重量要求还附带一项命令，要求空乘人员在履行日常工作职责的同时密切监测自己的体重。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;该公司甚至强加了一个特定的体重与身高的公式来计算它认为的标准体重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，身高 165 厘米的服务员应该保持 0超过 55 公斤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新政策意味着，超过规定体重限制的 5% 到 10% 的空乘人员将有 30 天的时间“自行减轻”体重，并进行监测每周一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，在此期间，他们将被停飞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司表示，该措施旨在维护专业形象并展示吸引人的“名片” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，这个被网友戏称为“创举”的项目，却面临法律审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四川方策律师事务所律师郭刚，对上游新闻表示，对员工限重，极端情况下停工，属于违法行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着争议升级，公司内部人士告诉澎湃新闻，该规定适用于所有乘务员，无论其是否&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这项措施背后的意图是通过设定参考目标来促进健康的生活习惯，”该知情人士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，公众的强烈反对仍在继续。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位网友说：“海航的标准与职业形象无关，更像是刻板印象。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有人说：“我们生活在哪个世纪？选拔空乘人员不应被视为选美比赛。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“航空公司的首要任务应该是确保安全和舒适，同时提供可承受的票价。这是正确的道路，”三分之一的人说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Huawei wins lion’s share of China Mobile’s 5G base station contracts, in much needed boost to revenue]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3223886/huawei-wins-lions-share-china-mobiles-5g-base-station-contracts-much-needed-boost-revenue?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/5dc303b2-54bf-4abe-b2ce-4b82ea88fbf3_bcf2b02a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;华为技术将为中国最大的电信公司中国提供超过一半的 5G 基站2023 年至 2024 年之间的移动业务，分析师表示，在美国严厉制裁期间失去利润丰厚的智能手机业务后，该交易将有助于巩固其核心收入基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为获得了中国移动 52% 的 5G 基站工作，今年招标的合同中所占比例最大。根据《南华早报》使用中国移动公布的投标详情计算得出，这笔交易将涉及出售 45,426 个 5G 基站，价值约 41 亿元人民币（5.74 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为的同城竞争对手中兴通讯是第二大赢家，约占授予合同的26%，相当于销售了23,227个5G基站。中国公司大唐、芬兰的诺基亚和瑞典的爱立信是剩余的中标者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国制裁的华为通过地方政府交易加强了对国内市场的关注&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中标公司于上周五公布，大约一个月后，中国移动征求设备供应商投标两份合同，在 2023 年至 2024 年期间安装总共 86,980 个 5G 基站，增加中国现有的 5G 网络，该网络被认为是世界上最大的。中国移动招标代表了今年授予的最大 5G 基站合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国移动赢得 5G 对这家中国科技冠军来说是一个福音，近年来在美国限制措施后其收入增长失去了动力研究公司 Omdia 的高级首席电信分析师杨光表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国营电信公司一直是华为的重要收入来源，华为于 1987 年在深圳成立任正非，最初是为了销售电话交换机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿以国家安全为由，禁止华为购买现成的先进半导体或使用晶圆代工服务来制造它们，这对华为造成了沉重打击曾经利润丰厚的手机业务。去年，包括智能手机和其他消费电子产品在内的华为消费者业务收入同比下降 11.9% 至 2145 亿元人民币。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运营商业务销售额微增 0.9% 至 2840 亿元人民币元。私营企业华为报告称，2022 年全年销售额总计 6423 亿元人民币，比 2021 年的 6368 亿元人民币微增 0.9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在经历了过去四年的 5G 建设热潮之后， “中国的5G基础设施发展已经放缓并过了高峰期，”杨说。 “所以从长远来看，华为仍然必须想办法解决其在半导体方面的困境。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方数据显示，截至 2 月底，中国已安装了 238 万个基站&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https //feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia wedding bus was going too fast before fatal crash, police say: ‘if you think that was fast … watch this’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3223892/australia-wedding-bus-was-going-too-fast-fatal-crash-police-say-if-you-think-was-fast-watch?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 14:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/7a88145c-243e-4102-998b-606ab090e532_7fb1009d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当他的 57 座车辆翻滚时，澳大利亚的一名公交车司机开得太快了警方周二称，它的一侧在大雾中撞上了护栏，导致 10 名婚礼宾客死亡，另有 25 人受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;58 岁的布雷特·安德鲁·巴顿 (Brett Andrew Button) 驾驶 35 名乘客从周日晚些时候，2009 年款沃尔沃巴士在环形交叉路口翻滚时，Wandin Estate Winery 和 Singleton 镇的婚礼招待会均位于新南威尔士州的猎人谷葡萄酒产区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Button 一直在周二，他在塞斯诺克 (Cessnock) 法庭出庭时被警方拘留，但被保释，他被控犯有 10 项与每起死亡事件有关的危险驾驶罪和一项疏忽驾驶罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早些时候，代理警察助理局长大卫·瓦德尔 (David Waddell)声称巴顿“以不符合条件的方式进入环形交叉路口”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“显然，速度太快，他无法通过环形交叉路口，导致车辆向左侧倾斜并造成这些人受伤，”Waddell 告诉记者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是澳大利亚自 1994 年以来最致命的交通事故，当时一辆公共汽车在布里斯班的一条高速公路上侧滑并滑下陡峭的路堤，造成 12 人死亡和受伤38.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方表示，巴顿在周日晚上接受了强制性药物和酒精检测，但未检测到任何损伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官考特尼·布鲁姆反对保释巴顿。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;澳大利亚葡萄酒之乡发生“可怕的”婚礼巴士车祸后 10 人死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“有 10 名证人就巴顿先生的长期行为和危险驾驶提供了证据，”布鲁姆告诉法庭.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“情况说明书中有证据表明他们 [乘客] 系好安全带，”Broom 补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辩护律师 Chris O&#39;Brien 指出 Button 的无辜罪犯在他 30 年的驾驶记录中，只有 7 次交通违法行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地方法官罗宾·理查森 (Robyn Richardson) 表示，他的家庭关系和保释条件可以降低他逃离该国或干扰证人的风险。 She also noted a trial was unlikely to be heard before late 2024.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His bail conditions include that he does not drive and that he observes an overnight curfew at his Hunter Valley home of Maitland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Button sat with his head bowed throughout the short bail hearing and wept when Richardson noted that he was clearly suffering and said she had concerns about his well-being.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is clear to this court he suffers along with the rest of the community,” Richardson said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Broom said Button could face further charges in relation to the seriously injured survivors.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;She survived 5 days in Australia&#39;s outback – on nothing but lollipops and wine&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Of the 25 passengers taken to hospitals in the latest incident, 14 had not been discharged by Tuesday, with two remaining in an intensive care unit in critical but stable condition, Waddell said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dead and injured were aged from their 20s to their 60s, Waddell said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He declined to comment on media reports that Button told passengers through the bus&#39;s microphone shortly before the crash, “If you think that was fast … watch this”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Waddell also declined to comment on reports that passengers were standing moments before the crash.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Linq Buslines, which provides school bus and event charters, owns the bus involved in the crash. Its website says all its buses are equipped with seat belts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New South Wales law requires bus passengers to use seat belts if they are available.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tragedy has rekindled public debate about Australia&#39;s seat belt laws and whether there should be national rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New South Wales Premier Chris Minns, while not commenting on Button&#39;s case, said bus drivers in that state were legally responsible for ensuring passengers wore seat belts.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;They&#39;re starving to death&#39;: Australia told to shoot its surplus kangaroos&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s always the driver of the vehicle whose responsibility it is to ensure that there&#39;s enforcement with the law and to reinforce the point,” Minns told Australian Broadcasting Corp.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Victoria state Premier Daniel Andrews said: “This is an incident that I&#39;m sure every state and territory will learn from.” Several of the passengers were from Victoria.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Andrews said he was open to a national approach on bus seat belts, but noted complexities around school, charter and public transport types and difficulties in striking a deal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Sometimes getting a national agreement can add a long period of time to the process of developing rules,” Andrews said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tasmania Premier Jeremy Rockliff said his government would also consider any recommendations that come from the crash investigation.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Scientists hold US nuclear tests responsible for South China Sea radioactivity]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3223896/scientists-hold-us-nuclear-tests-responsible-south-china-sea-radioactivity?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 14:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/13/05f47bb9-770e-487f-927f-e58254692485_13f678e9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Nuclear weapons testing by the US in the 1940s and 1950s has been blamed for higher than average levels of radioactivity thousands of kilometres away in the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After more than a decade of study, scientists said they have found the last piece of evidence that testing in the Marshall Islands during the Cold War polluted the entire waterway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The peer-reviewed study, published in the Chinese language journal Environmental Chemistry, will help China&#39;s “environmental assessment” of the region, according to the team, led by Peng Anguo, an associate professor with the University of South China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The study found that radioactive pollutants from the US Pacific Proving Ground (PPG) tests were carried by ocean currents more than 5,000km (3,000 miles) and spread throughout the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The researchers said the pollutants are still present in the region today, including in some previously unchartered areas in the waterway&#39;s south.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The findings are likely to add to tensions in the South China Sea, where China and other countries have overlapping claims to islands, reefs and other features.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The territorial disputes may also make it more difficult for affected countries to coordinate their efforts in any demand for compensation from the US, if any clear causal links to environmental damage could be established, one expert said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Peng&#39;s team traced the radioactive pollutants to their origin by analysing the ratio of two plutonium isotopes in samples of sediment to precisely identify where they had come from.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ratio of 240Pu and 239Pu varies depending on the source of the plutonium, with the PPG nuclear test site yielding a range of 0.306-0.36. This is higher than the ratio for atmospheric nuclear tests but lower than weapons-grade plutonium.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sediments analysed in the new study were collected from the seabed of Nansha, also known as the Spratly Islands in the southern South China Sea in 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Peng – whose research university in Hengyang, Hunan province is closely linked to China&#39;s nuclear programme – and his colleagues found that PPG contributed between 7.15 per cent and 15.89 per cent of the plutonium in Nansha.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Their findings suggest that the US nuclear test site was a significant source of plutonium pollution to the last unexplored area of the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Previous Chinese studies over the past decade have found evidence of PPG pollutants in other parts of the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Could China support for Asean nuclear weapon-free zone be &#39;counter-intuitive&#39;?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sediment samples from its central and northern sections were consistent with the US nuclear test site&#39;s signature and contributed up to 87 per cent of local plutonium levels, the earlier research showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Peng&#39;s team said the variation in pollution levels in the different areas of the South China Sea are due to a range of complex factors, including ocean currents, wind patterns, and the physical and chemical properties of the pollutants themselves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, plutonium tends to bind strongly to sediment particles and can accumulate in areas with high sedimentation rates, the researchers said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Shangri-La Dialogue: US and China stand ground on Taiwan, South China Sea&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to the paper, the discovery of PPG pollutants in sediment samples from the Nansha Islands fills a gap in the scientific understanding of the distribution of radioactive pollutants in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The presence of the plutonium in multiple locations throughout the South China Sea suggests the entire region may have been affected by the nuclear testing and related radioactive waste, the researchers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US conducted 67 nuclear tests at the PPG in the Marshall Islands between 1946 and 1958, yielding a total 210 megatons of TNT – setting off the equivalent of more than two Hiroshima-sized bombs every two days, according to some scientists&#39; estimates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tests, which included both atmospheric and underwater detonations, released large amounts of plutonium, caesium, strontium and other radioactive materials which were carried by winds and ocean currents to other parts of the Pacific region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People living on nearby islands were exposed to high levels of radiation causing increased cancer rates, birth defects and other health problems which persist to this day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The environmental damage was significant, with widespread contamination of the soil, water, and marine life in the immediate vicinity. The tests also caused the destruction of coral reefs and other marine habitats.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The available evidence suggests the transport of pollutants from the PPG to the South China Sea is a real and ongoing phenomenon with significant environmental and health implications for the region, the researchers said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The South China Sea is influenced by several ocean currents, including the major Kuroshio Current which flows northward along the eastern coast of Taiwan before turning eastward into the Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Nord Stream blast, regional tensions halt China&#39;s floating nuclear reactor plans&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Kuroshio Current – part of a larger system of ocean currents known as the North Pacific Gyre, which circulates clockwise – can carry pollutants from the western Pacific to the Luzon Strait between Taiwan and the Philippines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From there, the polluted waters can enter the South China Sea through the Taiwan Strait and the Bashi Channel, the researchers said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other currents influencing the waterway include the South China Sea Warm Current, which flows northward along the eastern coast of Vietnam and China, and the North Equatorial Current, which flows westward across the Pacific, entering the South China Sea through the Luzon Strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A Beijing-based expert in marine environmental science suggested China could join the Marshall Islands and other affected countries to hold the US accountable for the environmental damage caused by the nuclear tests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The environmental scientist, who was not involved in the study, said there are valid reasons for China to join with other countries and seek compensation for the impact of the testing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing, Asean agree on next step for delayed South China Sea code&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“There are questions about the legality and ethics of the tests. This may give affected countries a basis for seeking compensation,” said the researcher, who asked not to be named because of the issue&#39;s political sensitivity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US established a nuclear claims tribunal in 1986 which has awarded more than US$2 billion in compensation to the people of the Marshall Islands for health and property damage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are still remaining issues. The compensation has been criticised as inadequate, given the scale and scope of the environmental and health impacts. Some advocates have also called for additional payments to address the ongoing impacts of the tests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From a legal perspective, the question of compensation for environmental damage caused by the nuclear tests is complicated by a number of factors, including the US government&#39;s sovereign immunity in many cases, the environmental scientist said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The passage of time could also make it difficult to establish a clear causal link between the tests and specific environmental or health impacts, he said, adding that “the environmental and health impacts of the PPG tests are still being studied and are not yet fully understood”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps the biggest stumbling block is the different priorities and interests of the countries with overlapping claims in the South China Sea. They may be reluctant to work together on issues related to the PPG tests, the scientist said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the territorial disputes may also make it more difficult for affected countries to coordinate any demand for compensation from the US, he believes it is still possible for them to work together to address the issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cooperation and dialogue will be key, the environmental scientist said. “A special fund can be set up and managed by the UN,” he added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese electric cars to capture 15 per cent of European market by 2025 in leap forward for exports: KPMG economist]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3223875/chinese-electric-cars-capture-15-cent-european-market-2025-leap-forward-exports-kpmg-economist?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 12:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/13/6a321ff1-c8c6-4604-ab79-fb0b598bdbaa_ec22c90e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese carmakers are expected to capture around 15 per cent of Europe&#39;s electric vehicle (EV) market by 2025, as players such as BYD, Nio, and Li Auto gain popularity among European consumers, according to an economist at KPMG.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This would represent a fast step forward for the Chinese car brands, as their cars accounted for less than 10 per cent of the 1.28 million battery electric vehicles (BEVs) sold in Europe last year, according to a report released by KPMG on Monday in Shanghai at China&#39;s first Carbon Neutrality Expo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Home-grown Chinese brands such as BYD, Nio, Xpeng, and Li Auto have huge potential in the European market and could contribute the most to future sales increase there,” said Kevin Kang, chief economist at KPMG China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Europe is the world&#39;s second-biggest and fastest-growing EV market after China, and is expected to see surging demand for EVs following the European Union&#39;s announcement that it will ban the sale of new fossil-fuel cars starting in 2035 to combat climate change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Europe accounted for about half of the 1 million new-energy vehicles (NEVs) – an umbrella term that covers BEVs, plug-in hybrids, and fuel-cell vehicles – that China exported last year, according to KPMG.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Chinese EV makers expand their footprints by opening more stores and plants overseas, as well as providing more services and products tailored to international consumers, they are expected to improve their brand recognition and increase their share of the market, Kang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese makers have advantages in affordable prices and a wide range of models catering to different consumer needs, KPMG said. The average price of a Chinese EV was US$30,000 in Europe in 2022, according to KPMG, compared with more than US$45,000 for Tesla&#39;s cheapest Model 3.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;EV firm Human Horizons&#39; US$5.6b deal among those signed at Arab-China summit&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In 2022, Chinese NEV makers introduced 136 models for consumers to choose from, including 110 BEV models, ranking first in the world, KPMG said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Chinese makers still lack brand familiarity among European consumers, understanding of the overseas market and effective globalisation strategies, said Kang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, the top three Chinese BEV models sold in Europe last year were Volvo, MG, and Polestar – all European brands acquired by Chinese car companies, while China&#39;s home-grown BEV models accounted for less than 2 per cent of all EVs sold in Europe, KPMG found.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Nio cuts EV prices by US$4,200, ends battery-swapping services as sales fall&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Norbert Meyring, partner in charge of the automotive industry for KPMG China, suggested Chinese EV makers can improve their brand visibility by collaborating with local car dealers, or by acquiring more local car brands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Setting up local stores, customer-service centres, and local production plants through greenfield investment are also common and effective actions for Chinese carmakers in the overseas market, said Kang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shenzhen-headquartered BYD, which last year overtook Tesla to become the world&#39;s bestselling NEV brand, confirmed last month that it&#39;s considering building a factory in France.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese EV start-up Hozon ramps up exports amid rising popularity of Neta SUV&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to the European Automobile Manufacturers Association, by 2030, three out of every five cars in Europe will be electric.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Exporting Chinese new-energy vehicles to Europe is an important step for the globalisation of China&#39;s auto industry, and it is also an inevitable choice for China&#39;s new-energy vehicle industry,” Michael Jiang, head of clients and markets at KPMG China said in the report.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Asia has 14 of the world’s top 25 shortest countries – can you guess who’s No 1?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/article/3223878/asia-has-14-worlds-top-25-shortest-countries-can-you-guess-whos-no-1?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.13 12:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/13/08e7538f-4ecf-428c-aab4-3c9f09f89435_d9014309.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Worldwide, scientists have found that there&#39;s around a 20cm, or 7.8 inch, difference between the average height of a child in the tallest and shortest countries, according to the BBC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When it comes to adults, in countries like the Netherlands – ranked as the tallest on Earth – the average person towers as high as 175.62cm (5 feet 7.96 inches). But at the other end of the scale, the average height is considerably lower.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Below is a ranking of average height data compiled using a 2020 medical database run by NCD Risk Factor Collaboration, a project linked to Imperial College London. It lists separate figures for male and female heights for each country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An average of those two figures was taken to get a rough idea of the average height of a person in each country. The separate figures for men and women are also listed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Here are the 25 countries with the shortest average populations:&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average Sri Lankan is 160.12cm (5 feet 3.04 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average man in Sri Lanka is 165.68cm (5 feet 5.23 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average woman in Sri Lanka is 154.56cm (5 feet 0.85 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average person in Honduras is 160.11cm (5 feet 3.03 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Honduran man is 166.39cm (5 feet 5.5 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Honduran woman is 153.84cm (5.056 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average Liberian is 159.66cm (5 feet 2.85 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An average Liberian man is 163.66cm (5 feet 4.43 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An average Liberian woman is 155.66cm (5 feet 1.28 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average person in Myanmar is 159.52cm (5 feet 2.8 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An average Myanmar man is 164.67cm (5 feet 4.83 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An average Myanmar woman is 154.37cm (5 feet 0.77 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average Bruneian is 159.49cm (5 feet 2.79 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Bruneian man is 165cm (5 feet 4.96 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Bruneian woman is 153.98cm (5 feet 0.62 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average person in Bhutan is 159.46cm (5 fet 2.77 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Bhutanese man is 165.3cm (5 feet 5.07 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Bhutanese woman is 153.62cm (5 feet 0.48 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average Mozambican is 159.37cm (5 feet 2.74 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An average Mozambican man is 164.79cm (5 feet 4.88 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Mozambican woman is 153.96cm (5 feet 0.61 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average Solomon Islands person is 159.27cm (5 feet 2.7 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Men, on average, in the Solomon Islands are 164.14cm (5 feet 4.62 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While woman in the Solomon Islands are, on average, 154.41cm (5 feet 0.79 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Papuans are an average 159.21cm (5 feet 2.68 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Papuan men are 163.56cm (5 feet 4.39 inches) tall on average.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Papuan women are 154.87cm (5 feet 0.97 inches) tall on average.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average height of a person in Peru is 159.08cm (5 feet 2.63 inches).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An average Peruvian man is 165.23cm (5 feet 5.05 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An average Peruvian woman is 152.93cm (5 feet 0.21 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;People in Vietnam have an average height of 159.01cm (5 feet 2.60 inches).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vietnamese men are on average 164.44cm (5 feet 4.74 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vietnamese women are on average 153.59cm 5 feet 0.46 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Indians are 158.76cm (5 feet 2.5 inches) tall on average.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An average Indian man is 164.94cm (5 feet 4.93 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Indian women is 152.58cm (5 feet 0.07 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Rwandans have an average height of 158.73cm (5 feet 2.49 inches).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rwandan men are on average 162.67 (5 feet 4.04 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rwandan women are on average 158.73cm (5 feet 2.49 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;People from Malawi are 158.31cm (5 feet 2.32 inches) tall on average.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average man from Malawi is 162.22cm (5 feet 3.86 inches) tall, and the average women from the country is 154.4cm (5 feet 0.78 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;People in Indonesia are an average of 158.17cm (5 feet 2.27 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesian men are 163.55cm (5 feet 4.39 inches) tall on average.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesian women are 152.79cm (5 feet 0.15 inches) tall on average.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Cambodia, people are 158.11cm (5 feet 2.24 inches) tall on average.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The men are an average 163.32cm (5 feet 4.30 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The women are an average 152.9cm (5 feet 0.19 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average Bangladeshi is 157.29cm (5 feet 1.92 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Bangladeshi man is 163.8cm (5 feet 4.48 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Bangladeshi woman is 150.78cm (4 feet 11.36 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;An average person in the small Micronesian nation of the Marshall Islands is 157.05cm (5 feet 1.83 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A man from the Marshall Islands is on average 162.8cm (5 fet 4.09 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A woman from the Marshall Islands is on average 151.3cm (4 feet 11.56 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average Yemeni is 156.92cm (5 feet 1.78 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average male in Yemen is 159.88cm (5 feet 2.94 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average female in Yemen is 153.97cm (5 feet 0.61 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average person in Nepal is 156.58cm (5 feet 1.64 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Nepali man 162.31cm (5 feet 3.9 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Nepali woman is 150.86cm (4 feet 11.39 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average person in the Philippines is 156.41cm (5 feet 1.57 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Filipino man is 163.22cm (5 feet 4.25 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Filipino woman is 149.6cm (4 feet 10.89 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average Guatemalan is 156.39cm (5 feet 1.57 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Guatemalan man is 163.4cm (5 feet 4.33 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Guatemalan woman is 149.38cm (4 feet 10.81cm) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The average person in Madagascar is 156.36cm (5 feet 1.56 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Malagasy man is 161.54cm (5 feet 3.6 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Malagasy woman is 151.18cm (4 feet 11.51 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;An average person from Laos is 155.89cm (5 feet 1.37 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Lao man is on average 160.51cm (5 feet 3.19 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao women are 151.26cm (4 feet 11.55 inches) tall on average.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;People in East Timor are on average 155.47cm (5 feet 1.28 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Timorese man is 159.79cm (5 feet 2.9 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average Timorese woman is 151.15cm (4 feet 11.5 inches) tall.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Genetics is only part of the answer, Majid Ezzati, who runs the NCD study at Imperial College London, told BBC News.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking of how national average heights change over decades, he said: “About a third of the explanation could be genes, but that doesn&#39;t explain the change over time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Genes don&#39;t change that fast and they don&#39;t vary that much across the world,” he said, adding: “So changes over time and variations across the world are largely environmental.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why are some children taller? Diet a bigger factor than genes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Environmental factors such as poor diet are likely part of the answer, according to the BBC, citing a study that found a 20cm (7.9 in) difference between children in the tallest and shortest nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It could also help explain why average heights in several nations have both risen and fallen over the last decades – while nations like Japan, South Korea and China have seen height increases, some sub-Saharan African nations like Uganda and Sierra have seen male height decreases, the BBC reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Only one of the officially listed world&#39;s shortest living people is from a country on this list. Their heights stem from forms of dwarfism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2009, the Guinness World Records split the category of shortest person into mobile and non-mobile people, to differentiate between people who can walk unassisted and those who cannot.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Small statures, big hearts: life lessons from a couple with dwarfism&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The world&#39;s shortest mobile woman is actress Jyoti Amge from India, who stands at 62.8 centimetres (2ft 0.75 inches). Social media personality Afshin Esmaeil Ghaderzadeh from Iran, who is 65.24cm (2ft 1.6 inches), is the shortest mobile man.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world&#39;s shortest non-mobile woman is Wildine Aumoithe, a Haitian-American who is 72cm (2ft 3.5 in). As of 2021, she was studying to be a pharmacist.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At present, there is no non-mobile male record holder.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This article was first published on &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>