<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong security chief slams ‘artistic creations’ used as guise to endanger national security, does not confirm if Pillar of Shame sculptor is wanted]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3231897/hong-kong-security-chief-slams-artistic-creations-used-guise-endanger-national-security-does-not?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 15:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/bbab5be2-ef2c-4a21-a240-3eabaea65293_e9118d88.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港保安局长猛烈抨击了他所说的使用“艺术”的常见策略保安局局长邓炳强在丹麦向传媒披露的一封信中如此表示。艺术家 Jens Galschiot，他创作了纪念 1989 年天安门广场镇压的《耻辱之柱》作品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Galschiot 本月早些时候写信给地方当局，要求澄清国家安全警察是否如报道的那样对他发出了逮捕令&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港保安局长称没收雕塑与 6 月 4 日纪念活动无关&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“为了不影响任何执法行动的有效性，唐在周一的一封信中写道，并由 Galschiot 披露。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耻辱之柱，此前位于嘉道理中心 (Kadoorie Centre)。香港大学 (HKU) 经营的农业研究机构元朗于 5 月因一起颠覆罪被警方查封。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邓表示，香港在将此事纳入调查时“会毫不犹豫”将任何违反国家安全的人绳之以法，并指出警方早些时候采取行动，对每逮捕八名海外并根据该立法通缉的香港逃犯悬赏 100 万港元（127,600 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他警告说：“打着‘和平倡导’、‘艺术创作’等借口从事此类行为和活动，是那些企图危害国家安全的人的惯用手法。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Galschiot总部位于丹麦的 周一对唐的答复表示失望，并告诉记者，他已联系丹麦外交部，并呼吁其与香港当局联系，以澄清他的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是令人困惑的是，[唐]在信中花了大量精力描述[国家安全法]的要素，却没有透露我是否受到正式指控，而这正是我调查的核心，”他说，并补充说他将回应香港的要求&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;民主女神雕像、天安门纪念碑从香港校园移除&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;耻辱柱雕塑自 1997 年起一直矗立在香港大学校园，并定期在香港大学校园展出。每年 6 月 4 日在维多利亚公园举行的守夜活动。但大学管理层于 2021 年 12 月将这件艺术品移至嘉道理中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Galschiot 一直要求将这座雕像（他说这是他的私人财产）归还给他，并表示他愿意前往香港亲自取回该作品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐在信中没有对个别案件发表评论，但表示任何因涉嫌涉及国家安全犯罪的犯罪活动而被扣押的财产或展品都将得到处理并可能被处置” 1989 年，在北京于 2020 年对天安门广场实施国家安全法之前，人们举行守夜活动，悼念天安门广场上的遇难者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方以 Covid-19 大流行期间的公共卫生问题为由，禁止了 2020 年和 2021 年的这一年度活动。 2022年没有尝试举行守夜活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港支持中国爱国民主运动联盟自1990年以来一直组织守夜活动，已于2021年解散。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前香港爱国民主运动联盟副主席周恒东、该组织前主席李卓人和前副主席何俊仁正在等待颠覆罪名的审判。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:50:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia shoots down 2 Ukrainian drones over Moscow region, flights briefly disrupted]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3231888/russia-shoots-down-2-drones-over-moscow-region-flights-briefly-disrupted?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 14:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/fb8c43dc-67e4-44e3-90a4-2a6bf87432a1_7874f660.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯在莫斯科地区击落两架乌克兰无人机，无人伤亡，并击落一架俄罗斯国防部周二表示，又有两架无人机飞越与乌克兰接壤的布良斯克地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社记者在莫斯科地区政府所在地克拉斯诺戈尔斯克镇看到，一架无人机受到轻微损坏。一栋高层住宅楼上的瓷砖和一些公寓的外窗玻璃破碎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;掉落的碎片还造成了轻微损坏，例如停在下面的汽车挡风玻璃被砸碎。警方封锁了现场，俄罗斯联邦安全局安全部门的调查人员收集了看起来像是无人机碎片的东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰没有立即发表评论，乌克兰很少对针对俄罗斯领土或控制地区的无人机袭击承担直接责任俄罗斯发起的攻击，但自 5 月初两架无人机在克里姆林宫上空被摧毁以来，俄罗斯似乎加强了此类袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此类袭击有时会短暂扰乱俄罗斯各地的航班，并对建筑物造成大多轻微损坏。莫斯科地区州长表示，一天前，一架被俄罗斯防空系统摧毁的乌克兰无人机的部分部件落在莫斯科地区的一所房屋上，造成至少两人受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名路透社记者在莫斯科地区附近的奥金佐沃地区。周二凌晨，两架无人机中的一架在莫斯科以西的 Chastsy 定居点被击落，当地时间凌晨 3 点刚过，就听到四声爆炸声。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;普京会见领导乌克兰攻势的高级将领。俄罗斯南部&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“窗户在摇晃，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部表示，在最近的袭击中没有人受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一次尝试基辅政权利用无人机实施恐怖袭击的计划今晚被挫败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“莫斯科地区上空的防空系统发现并摧毁了两架无人机。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一份声明中称，在与乌克兰接壤的布良斯克地区上空，防空系统检测到另外两架乌克兰无人机，并在被干扰系统击落后坠毁，没有造成人员伤亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据塔斯社报道，俄罗斯首都上空短暂关闭，莫斯科三个机场暂停航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯航空管理局表示，有 9 架航班在莫斯科伏努科沃机场和莫斯科机场改道。多莫杰多沃机场，但首都所有机场目前均正常运行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯官员一再警告称，军用无人机在飞越莫斯科上空时可能会造成重大灾难，而莫斯科及其周边地区的人口为近 2200 万人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰军事情报局 (GUR) 周一表示，它监督了对卡卢加州俄罗斯谢科夫卡军用机场的一次袭击，并表示有几架飞机受损。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当被问及周一对莫斯科的袭击时，GUR 发言人安德烈·尤索夫 (Andriy Yusov) 表示，“GUR 正在发挥作用”，但拒绝透露细节。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Air Koryo plane lands in China, first commercial North Korean flight in 3 years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231884/air-koryo-plane-lands-china-first-commercial-north-korean-flight-3-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/94777777-7292-48f6-8445-55c39a87e627_b6bbb645.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二早上，一架从平壤起飞的客运航班降落在北京，这是第一架已知的商业航班自 2020 年因 Covid-19 大流行而关闭边境以来，来自朝鲜的航班已从朝鲜起飞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据航班数据，由朝鲜国有航空公司高丽航空运营的 JS151 航班于上午 9 点 17 分抵达中国首都在北京首都国际机场网站上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此前，中国外交部周一宣布，在北京今年早些时候放松疫情限制后，中国已批准了与邻国之间的定期航班计划。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“2023年夏秋航季过渡期间，中方按程序批准了高丽航空平壤至北京至平壤的定期航班计划以及该航空公司要求的其他客运航线。”外交部发言人汪文斌表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尚不清楚朝鲜航班上有谁。 Flightradar24 数据显示，这是一架 Tu-204——俄罗斯设计的客机，可容纳 210 名乘客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国通讯社韩联社报道称，这架飞机定于周二下午 1 点 05 分再次离开北京。 ，这引发了人们的猜测，即它可能正在收集在大流行期间无法返回该国的朝鲜公民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩联社表示，早上的航班可能正在将朝鲜官员运送到北京，或者返回该航班可能会将驻中国大使馆官员带回平壤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社早些时候报道称，该航班原定于周一举行，但因不明原因被取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;当金正恩为“真战”，朝鲜黑客瞄准美韩演习&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据北京首都国际机场网站，目前每周有3班从平壤飞往北京的航班——周二周六的JS151，以及每周二周六的JS251据自由亚洲电台报道，周四，所有早间航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜和中国边境城市新义州和丹东之间的客运列车也将于本周恢复。据首尔新闻网站 Daily NK 去年年底的统计，目前约有 8 万名朝鲜人居住在丹东。据估计，有超过 10 万朝鲜人居住在中国各地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜的大部分贸易都依赖长期盟友中国，在疫情期间通过丹东在两国之间运行的货运列车进行运输。据报道，北京还向平壤提供了 Covid-19 疫苗和其他医疗用品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平壤去年 5 月首次证实，朝鲜正在应对 Covid-19 疫情，据信有数百万人被感染。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据高丽航空网站称，该航空公司还将运营飞往俄罗斯符拉迪沃斯托克的航班。俄罗斯媒体报道称，从平壤飞往符拉迪沃斯托克的首趟航班预计将于本周晚些时候开通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，朝鲜领导人金正恩在会晤期间接待了俄罗斯国防部长谢尔盖·绍伊古和中共中央政治局委员李鸿忠。平壤举行纪念朝鲜战争停战 70 周年的活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李是自疫情爆发以来访问朝鲜的最高级别中国官员。随着美国、韩国和日本同意扩大安全联盟以对抗中国和朝鲜，北京和平壤正在加强联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia sends its biggest warship to joint drills with Philippines, US]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3231885/australia-sends-its-biggest-warship-joint-drills-philippines-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 15:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/3699d5d2-2271-479b-9e47-084def72ec89_befda4dd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚最大军舰参加与菲律宾和美国的联合演习周一，两国就南海争议展开争论，面对中国不断增强的军事存在，两国寻求加强防务关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国部署了数百艘海岸警卫队、海军和其他船只，在有争议的海域巡逻并对珊瑚礁进行军事化，尽管国际裁决认为其立场没有法律依据，但它几乎完全主张这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;堪培拉号军舰是参与菲律宾阿隆演习的几艘舰艇之一，该演习首次以澳大利亚年度印度-太平洋奋进活动的一部分。 Alon 在他加禄语中是“波浪”的意思。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自澳大利亚和菲律宾的 2000 多名士兵参加了 8 月 14 日至 31 日的海陆空演习。大约 150 名美国海军陆战队员也参加了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一在菲律宾巴拉望岛南部进行的模拟空袭发生在距南沙群岛约 200 公里（125 英里）处，马尼拉和北京之间长期紧张关系在那里&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与菲律宾一样，澳大利亚希望建立一个和平、稳定和繁荣的地区，尊重主权并以基于规则的秩序为指导，”澳大利亚驻马尼拉大使 Hae Kyong Yu 在会议期间表示。黎刹市的舰对岸演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;菲律宾任命曾辱骂中国的外交官为北京“特使”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;此类演习“至关重要”，因为“通过这些演习，我们将我们的承诺付诸行动”，她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国、日本和澳大利亚本周还将在菲律宾附近举行联合海军演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这一直是计划，”澳大利亚两栖特遣部队指挥官菲利帕·海伊（Phillipa Hay）上尉在堪培拉号皇家海军舰艇上告诉记者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些船只来自 Talisman Saber（在澳大利亚演习），每个人都在回家的路上，这非常令人沮丧。”我们在往返演习时与合作伙伴一起进行训练是很正常的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚副总理兼国防部长理查德·马勒斯将于本周访问菲律宾，观看阿隆训练，并会见他的副总理兼国防部长理查德·马勒斯。菲律宾外长吉尔伯托·特奥多罗 (Gilberto Teodoro) 办公室周一宣布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次演习是在菲律宾前往南沙群岛仁爱礁的补给任务于 8 月 5 日被中国海警船使用高压水枪拦截后进行的，引发了外交争端争端和国际社会的愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中一艘向前哨基地运送物资的包租船被阻止到达浅滩，而另一艘则成功卸下了货物。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;挑衅的菲律宾向南方提供补给尽管北京阻止，中国海船仍继续前进&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;菲律宾军方表示，将向这个偏远的前哨基地运送更多物资，那里一艘生锈的海军舰艇上驻扎着少数菲律宾海军陆战队员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; BRP Sierra Madre 于 1999 年故意搁浅在该礁上，以阻止中国在该海域的进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国要求菲律宾移走该船，并为其行为辩护为“专业”。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 15:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore ‘fortunate’ to have Tharman Shanmugaratnam and me running for president but I have independent edge: Ng Kok Song]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3231880/singapore-fortunate-have-tharman-and-me-running-president-i-have-independent-edge-ng-kok-song?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 14:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/4e371077-fd55-436c-8844-dc73a95eaf95_c90a25d4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新加坡即将举行的总统选举有两名国际知名候选人 - 即他本人和前高级官员黄国松 (Ng Kok Song) 表示，部长尚达曼 (Tharman Shanmugaratnam) 已在海外引起了极大兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位总统候选人、主权财富基金 GIC 前首席投资官表示，英国前首相戈登·布朗 (Gordon Brown) 和亿万富翁投资者雷·达里奥 (Ray Dalio)是那些赞扬他竞选的人之一，两人都评论说他和尚达曼是“他们能想到的最好的两个总统候选人”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些观察家告诉他，新加坡人“很幸运” ” 吴恩达在周二的提名日之前告诉《亚洲周刊》，要选择这样的候选人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们会说，嗯，我们知道尚达曼是一位政治领袖，一位央行行长，作为财政部长，但我们知道您 — Kok Song — 作为全球商业领袖，”他说。 “我们知道您是帮助 GIC 成为世界领先主权基金之一的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴先生在 2007 年至 2016 年期间负责监督 GIC 的投资组合，花费了四十多年的时间与淡马锡控股和新加坡金融管理局一起管理新加坡储备的组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 75 岁的老人一直在努力反驳一种普遍的观点，即他的国际地位不如尚达曼曾在多个全球组织中担任职务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴说，他和前政策制定者尚达曼“以不同的方式为我们的国家服务”，两人都可以在国际舞台上并肩作战 – 指出然而，他的声誉是在全球企业生活最高层的私人交易中建立起来的，而他的对手的声誉则是在公共领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴指出，他完全没有政治背景，也没有随之而来的义务或忠诚。 – 这是他相对于尚达曼的最大优势，尚达曼从政 22 年，作为执政党人民行动党的一部分在政府最高层任职，该党控制着议会约 90% 的席位。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;新加坡将于 9 月 1 日举行三轮总统竞选&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;吴表示，过去的政治背景可能会阻止尚达曼对政府进行有效制衡。新加坡总统在很大程度上是一个礼仪性的国家元首，没有行政职务，但该办公室确实拥有某些阻止使用储备金和任命公共部门最高职位的权力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[假设]有一天，我们有一位腐败的总理，我们有一位腐败的财政部长。你去找总统说‘我想动用过去的储备’。现在，如果总统是该执政党的长期成员，那不是会让他陷入非常困难的境地吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴说，这种情况并非“异想天开”，因为他说，如果没有政治独立，总统可能无法在日益两极分化的社会中发挥“团结新加坡人民”或“超越政治”的作用。说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们无法改变我们的历史。我们不能说‘昨天我是这样，今天我也是这样’，”吴说。 “很可能会有一个与执政党关系如此密切的人敢于反对执政党。我认为这不是一件容易的事，因为你是这个体系的重要组成部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;观察家质疑吴恩达的政治独立主张，因为 GIC 直接对政府负责，是一个不可分割的组成部分。新加坡金融生态系统的特点，促使一些人说他与尚达曼属于同一个建制派。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但吴恩达否认了这一观点，称存在“对‘建制派’这个词的误解”，并认为许多人认为他是“建制派”。像他这样的高级公共部门官员一直回避政治活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡宪法要求提名人在竞选总统之前必须退出任何党派。然而，传统上，人民行动党领导人会公开支持首选候选人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自从宣布打算参选以来，吴恩达和尚达曼都竭尽全力说服选民在关于总统的角色和权力的激烈公开辩论的背景下，他们的独立性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长期以来，人民行动党的竞争对手将总统选举视为挑战其统治地位的机会和提出政策的平台据当地媒体报道，吴恩达将他和尚达曼之间的较量比作“大卫与歌利亚”之战，因为政府的支持者批评了这些尝试，称其为机会主义。他没有像他的对手那样长时间出现在公众视野中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Income Insurance Ltd（新加坡最大的保险公司之一，以前称为 NTUC Income）的前首席执行官 Tan Kin Lian 也在该公司的名单中。跑步。他此前曾参加过 2011 年总统选举，但因未能获得至少八分之一的选票而失去了押金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自五周前宣布参选以来，吴一直活跃在社交媒体上并接受了采访。到新加坡街头争取支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“结果越接近，对我来说就越好，”他说。 “如果尚达曼获胜，这对他也有好处，这样他就能得到新加坡人民的授权。但无论结果如何，无论获胜与否，我已经尽了自己的职责来兑现总统职位，我已经让新加坡人民能够行使投票权，这不会是一次轻松的事情。如果我做到了这一点，那会让我感到相当满足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我获胜，这将是我能从新加坡人民那里得到的最大荣誉：能够再次为他们服务，在我人生的这个阶段，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现任总统哈莉玛·雅各布 (Halimah Yacob) 在 2017 年轻松选举后宣誓就职，此前一年修改了宪法以保证少数族裔代表权，有效提高了门槛&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这引发了罕见的抗议活动——在新加坡，未经许可进行公开示威是非法的，芳林公园的演讲角除外——其口号是“选举被抢劫#NotMyPresident”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，今年的选举竞争更加激烈，在公众对物价上涨、住房问题和就业不确定性不满之际，将被视为政府支持度的晴雨表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;吴说，在过去几周的竞选活动中，他感觉到年轻的新加坡人存在“相当程度的焦虑”和“绝望的因素”，他们可能没有像他们的父母那样拥有同样的机会，并补充说他认为这些情绪“令人担忧”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为，只要我们关注哪些因素使新加坡在世界上脱颖而出，新加坡最美好的日子就在我们面前，”他强调道。国家金融安全、良好治理和社会团结是使该国巩固其全球地位的品质。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;李总理表示，新加坡必须防止“挥霍”储备&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他强调的另一个问题是这个紧凑城市国家的贫富差距不断扩大，有关富有的外国人在新加坡设立家族办公室的多则新闻报道加剧了当地人的紧张和不满。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然政策受益很重要吴恩达引用前总统唐纳德·特朗普领导下的美国的例子，警告不要陷入采取民族主义政策的陷阱，“新加坡人优先”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是我们面临的挑战：如何获得好处增长——如何分配[经济]增长，让新加坡人觉得他们是第一个从中受益的？”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 14:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong leader John Lee calls for immediate curbs on Japanese seafood after country announces plans to release Fukushima waste water starting Thursday]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231886/hong-kong-leader-john-lee-calls-immediate-curbs-japanese-seafood-after-country-announces-plans?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 14:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/90a0b33f-218b-4e4d-aeb9-8a15dae14354_bb0e6c16.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港特首李家超要求政府部门立即实施进口限制在日本宣布将于周四开始将处理后的核废水排入海洋后，李从日本进口了海鲜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李在周二的社交媒体帖子中猛烈抨击日本“不负责任地将其问题强加给其他国家”并誓言将食品安全和公共卫生放在首位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我已立即指示环境生态局局长和相关部门立即启动进口管制措施。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;市政府上个月表示，如果东京继续实施将处理后的核废水排入大海的计划，将禁止从日本 10 个都道府县进口海鲜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拟议中的都道府县上个月宣布的禁令包括东京、福岛、千叶、栃木、茨城、群马、宫城、新泻、长野和埼玉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市的购物者和食客周二表示，他们可能会减少日本食品的消费继东京当天早些时候宣布将从周四开始将福岛核电站的放射性废水排入海中之后，海鲜市场也出现了变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管联合国对日本的放射性废水排放计划表示担忧，但香港仍对日本的放射性废水排放计划持谨慎态度。继续&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;25岁的会计师Ryan Sun当时与父母在铜锣湾的一家寿司店吃饭，他说他们在听到计划出院的消息后决定在那里吃饭。他们在这顿饭上花了 700 港元（89.36 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们可能会停止吃日本海鲜一到两个月，看看是否发布了任何测试报告以确保安全，”他说。 “我们希望结果会好，因为我们通常每周都会吃几次日式餐。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位在City&#39;super购物的姓Ngai的女士说，她来超市是为了买三文鱼。听到这个消息后，生鱼片。她表示，废水排放后，她不会再吃日本生鱼片了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本将从周四开始将福岛废水排入海洋&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“虽然放射性水中的物质不能肉眼可见，我们不知道从长远来看它们是否会损害我们的健康。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位只透露自己姓周的男子表示，他会减少生鱼片的摄入量。摄入量从每周三次减少到一次。他表示，他也会劝阻16岁的女儿不要吃国内的海鲜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们会尽量避免购买福岛附近的海鲜，而是选择北海道的海鲜。”他在购物时说道崇光百货。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 14:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong property fire sale: Eric Chu selling hotel, luxury flats after wife Truong My Lan arrested in Vietnam scandal]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3231883/hong-kong-property-fire-sale-eric-chu-selling-hotel-luxury-flats-after-wife-truong-my-lan-arrested?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 13:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/8e0f83ff-d289-470c-b7b7-f1e437c986eb_e5e8b9ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名妻子在越南被捕的香港商人成为最新的绝望卖家在香港日益动荡的房地产市场中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eric Chu 正在出售香港的从酒店到豪华公寓的房产，有时在他的越南妻子 Truong My Lan 卷入其中一场事件后，他会遭受重大损失。这是东南亚国家最引人注目的丑闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇在出售了价值至少 10 亿港元的房产后，在该市拥有价值约 80 亿港元（10 亿美元）的商业地产&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然此次出售更可能是个人财务问题的结果，但较低的交易价格可能会削弱香港本已疲弱的市场情绪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朱卸载了根据政府文件和媒体报道，他于 6 月以几乎是 2017 年价格一半的价格购买了天后地区的一家酒店。同月，他以4.12亿港元将鲗鱼涌在建住宅及商业空间项目出售予本地开发商宏安地产。这远低于据报道他在 2018 年为该资产支付的 6.78 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇剩余的商业地产包括位于中环中心地带的 Nexxus 大厦，香港银行家俱乐部为该大厦的租户；中心商务区两栋商业建筑；以及山顶豪华项目 Severn 8 的几栋洋房。据《星岛日报》最近报道，一位买家已提出以超过 60 亿港元的价格购买 Nexxus 大厦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据几位房地产经纪人称，Chu 的所有房产均开放接受报价。这些资产要么由他、Lan、他们的女儿或与他们公司有联系的同事持有。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;山顶豪华别墅正在招标，售价可能高达 1.225 亿美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >; 夫妇俩于 2000 年代中期开始积极投资香港房地产市场，购买了从山顶别墅到摩天大楼的各种商品。现在，他们正在向近十年来最糟糕的商业地产市场出售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次抛售恰逢市场上出现了许多陷入困境的房产，其中包括那些以前由陷入困境的中国人拥有的房产开发商。中国恒大集团的债权人在夺取其香港总部近一年后仍未找到买家。房地产大亨陈红天的一栋商业建筑也被债权人收购，最近将其出售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据高力国际集团的数据，香港写字楼价值已较 2018 年的峰值下跌约 35% 。高力数据显示，6 月份该市总体空置率接近 15%，是 2019 年的三倍多。由于利率随着供应量上升，投资者购买香港写字楼的兴趣不大。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港山顶豪宅卖家损失1,660万美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这并不容易也可以在豪华住宅市场出售。第一太平戴维斯 (Savills) 的数据显示，第二季度高端市场交易量较今年前三个月下降了 24%。该公司表示，持续的高利率、股市动荡以及富裕的中国大陆买家的缺乏导致了价格下跌。第一太平戴维斯预计，在不久的将来，不良销售将主导市场，交易很少且价格波动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南开发商 Van Thinh Phat Holdings Group 董事长 Lan 于 10 月与包括该集团高管在内的其他三人一起被捕根据警方声明，首席执行官涉嫌在 2018 年和 2019 年挪用数万亿越南盾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司没有回复通过电子邮件发送的置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名 66 岁的人16岁开始卖化妆品，在越南认识了Chu。两人结婚后，开始从事餐饮和酒店业务，然后进入房地产投资领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Van Thinh Phat 集团由 Lan 于 1991 年创立，据越南胡志明市政府称，Van Thinh Phat 集团是胡志明市第一家私营公司。公司网站。 VTP 集团的开发项目涵盖住宅物业、写字楼、酒店和购物中心，其中包括与马来西亚亿万富翁 Kok-Thay Lim 的云顶集团合作的一项名为西贡半岛的 60 亿美元项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾被越南共产党列为慈善社交名流。党媒称，自 Lan 被捕以来，该国一栋顶级摩天大楼的所有者与越南当局冻结了 700 多个 VTP 集团单位的相关资产，这对该集团的业务造成了打击，并给家族带来了现金压力。&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Man in China caught by neighbour burying stray cat he tortured to death fired by employer after case exposed online]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3231623/man-china-caught-neighbour-burying-stray-cat-he-tortured-death-fired-employer-after-case-exposed?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/21/81204fa3-a65b-4d0d-b779-2aad804fd5c8_39c5a08e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A man in China who tortured and killed a stray cat and was caught by a neighbour disposing of the body has been terminated by his employer for animal abuse after the story went viral online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the evening of August 14, the man kidnapped, tortured and killed a cat named Dabao from a “cat house”, a shelter for stray cats built by neighbourhood cat lovers in a residential community in Shanghai, on China&#39;s central coast, reported news site eastday.com.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was later noticed trying to get rid of the feline&#39;s body by a neighbour who just happened to be reviewing the surveillance footage of the cat house. Volunteers installed the surveillance camera to protect the animals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Suddenly, two legs appeared, and a man holding a blue plastic bag grabbed Dabao by his neck and put him into the bag, then left the cat house,” the neighbour recalled in a social media post. “I immediately had an inauspicious premonition, so I alerted another volunteer and asked her to check on the cat house.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The other volunteer soon identified the man in the video as a neighbour and located his address. However, when the volunteer knocked on the door, the man did not answer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just minutes later, the volunteer saw the same man near an exercise area trying to bury the now lifeless body of the cat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When confronted by the volunteer, the man said he drowned the cat and his motive for the killing was that he “lost control”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After learning of Dabao&#39;s death, the first neighbour who raised the alarm called on Chinese authorities to enact laws swiftly banning animal cruelty and to impose harsh punishments for killing and abusing animals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;d like to say all kinds of swear words against him. I call on the state government to make laws against animal abuse. I hope this man can be put under a spotlight.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the details of the killing were exposed on mainland social media, some neighbours shared them with the man&#39;s employer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two days later, the company, whose name was not revealed in the report, told eastday.com that the man had been sacked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After verifying the case, we found the man is an employee, surnamed Fan. We feel very guilty and extremely outraged by his actions. At an emergency meeting about the case, we decided to fire him immediately and will never hire him again,” the company said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fan&#39;s neighbours reported him to a police station in the Yangpu District, where the case was closed after mediation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He agreed to pay 5,000 yuan (US$680) to the neighbours looking after the cat house, and in return, they agreed to delete online posts about his killing of the cat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fan also apologised for the killing in a confession letter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am sorry for all the good-hearted people who had fed the cat before. I won&#39;t do anything to harm small animals in the future. Please give me another chance to correct my mistakes,” he wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has no anti-animal abuse laws, and the killing and abuse of animals remain common, with perpetrators often go unpunished.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, a college student in southwestern Chongqing municipality shared videos of himself abusing cats on social media. The college said it had reprimanded the student, told him to reflect on his actions and delete the videos. The school added that it would punish the student in line with its internal disciplinary rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, a man in eastern China&#39;s Zhejiang province outraged the public after he threw a pet Samoyed dog out of a 7th-floor flat window during a fight with his partner. The dog died instantly.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese build-up helps draw US-Japan-South Korea closer amid ‘worrisome’ security environment in Asia: Washington]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231881/chinese-build-helps-draw-us-japan-south-korea-closer-amid-worrisome-security-environment-asia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 13:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/9e7dfbdf-778e-4384-9437-6e2d95faaff8_ddcabcb1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Rising anxiety and a “more worrisome” security environment in Asia, including China&#39;s military build-up, has drawn Seoul, Tokyo and Washington to raise cooperation, US officials said of last week&#39;s Camp David summit that Beijing said undermined “regional peace and stability”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a digital briefing on Monday, Kurt Campbell, deputy assistant to US President Joe Biden, said the meeting between the leaders of South Korea, Japan and the US was an “appropriate” effort to “constructively and peacefully” preserve the democratic engagement system between the three countries in response to the unstable regional security environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is undeniable that the security environment in Asia is not only more complicated, but more worrisome to each of us,” said Campbell, who is also the coordinator for the Indo-Pacific at the US National Security Council.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have the unprovoked illegal war in Ukraine, we have provocations on a regular basis from North Korea … We&#39;ve seen a number of steps on the part of China that are provocative, massive military build-up and a number of steps that have caused anxiety, not just in Japan and South Korea, but in the region as a whole.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Campbell said China had quietly supported Russia in its war in Ukraine, where it was “undeniable” that the invasion was “deeply destabilising and concerning” not only to the people of Ukraine, but also the surrounding regions, including northeast Asia. He said anxiety had provoked a desire for like-minded countries to cooperate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has long denied providing military support to Moscow in the Ukraine war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February, Chinese foreign ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin responded to a US accusation that China was shipping the weapons to Russia despite international sanctions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is the US and not China that is endlessly shipping weapons to the battlefield...We urge the US to earnestly reflect on its own actions and do more to alleviate the situation, promote peace and dialogue, and stop shifting blame and spreading false information,” Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US-Japan-South Korea summit represents &#39;new era&#39; of cooperation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Campbell echoed Biden&#39;s remarks during the summit in saying the principles laid out in the summit did not just target China but addressed a broader context of increasing a security commitment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[South Korea and Japan] owed to long-standing grievances [and] difficulties, and so to overcome them is a remarkable feat, and really has very little to do with China,” said Campbell.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I do not believe that these countries – the United States, Japan and South Korea – believe that they are taking steps aimed at China … they&#39;re taking steps they believe, to protect themselves, that to ensure that the progress that they made is protected and secured and to work more closely together in a world increasingly uncertain.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Daniel Kritenbrink, US State Department Assistant Secretary for East Asian and Pacific affairs, said the summit touched on China because it was a geopolitical factor faced by the three countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One cannot deny the strategic environment in which we exist and operate. So of course, it was natural that we would discuss some of the concerns and issues related to actions carried out by [China] that are of significant concern to our three countries, and to many others around the region and around the world,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, Biden met South Korean President Yoon Suk-yeol and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida at Camp David, a country retreat for US presidents near Washington DC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the first time the Biden administration invited foreign leaders to Camp David.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the summit, the three leaders agreed to raise trilateral security cooperation, pledging to immediately consult each other in the event of common threats, to hold annual summits between the leaders and ministers and joint military exercises, and cooperate closely to create a stronger missile defence against North Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They also pledged to increase economic ties such as cooperation on supply chain resilience, especially on semiconductors and batteries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The joint statement after the summit expressed the three countries&#39; shared concerns about Beijing&#39;s military action in the South China Sea and Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We strongly oppose any unilateral attempts to change the status quo in the waters of the Indo-Pacific,” the statement said. “There is no change in our basic positions on Taiwan, and we call for a peaceful resolution of cross-Strait issues.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Amid China&#39;s economic woes, US can gain clout with indebted countries: analysts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing criticised the trilateral summit and said the three leaders&#39; joint statement on Taiwan and South China Sea was an “act of gross interference in China&#39;s internal affairs”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Asia-Pacific should be a highland of peaceful development. It must not become a boxing ring for great powers, let alone a battlefield for cold or hot wars,” Chinese foreign ministry spokesman Wang said on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kritenbrink said the leaders of the three countries would continue to cooperate to institutionalise the outcomes of the Camp David summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We intend to work expeditiously together to make real those commitments and to deliver those benefits to partners across the region, across the world,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 13:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hongkongers moving into transitional housing to get one-off special allowance of up to HK$11,550, with highest amount for those in New Territories]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3231878/hongkongers-moving-transitional-housing-get-one-special-allowance-hk11550-highest-amount-those-new?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 12:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/df55d5c9-e5e5-4189-b3d6-feb2d03fef6a_2db8a73f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hongkongers moving into new transitional housing flats will be granted a one-off special allowance of up to HK$11,550 (US$1,474) under a new trial scheme, with authorities hoping the sum will motivate residents to relocate to the New Territories.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Acting secretary for housing Victor Tai Sheung-shing on Tuesday said tenants who chose to relocate to the New Territories and outlying islands would receive more than double the amount for those moving to transitional housing projects in urban areas, noting the extra challenges faced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We set a difference between those moving into urban areas and the New Territories because we realised the latter tend to be more in need,” Tai told a radio show.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong authorities call for resolution of unpaid wage dispute at housing site&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Many of our potential residents are those living in unsuitable environments, such as subdivided flats in urban areas, and they need more help moving into a new district.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He cited as an example children of such households having to buy new supplies when they changed schools.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Transitional Hong Kong housing site completed for more than 400 low-income families&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Transitional housing is a government initiative to help families waiting for public rental flats and those forced to live in poor conditions in tiny subdivided spaces. With 135,500 families and single elderly applicants in the queue, the average waiting time for public flats is 5.6 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the occupancy rate of transitional housing in the New Territories has been lower than those in urban areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the new trial scheme aimed at alleviating tenants&#39; financial pressure from relocation, households moving into transitional housing on or after June 16 will be eligible for the special allowance. Families will get a sum ranging from HK$1,800 to HK$11,550 depending on the number of people in each household and district they are moving into.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong to build 16,000 transitional homes by mid-2023: housing chief&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On the same radio show, Sze Lai-shan, deputy director of the Society for Community Organisation, said the subsidy was helpful in aiding lower income families to move into their new homes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the past, we had to run sourcing for second-hand furniture and appliances for these residents. It was hard,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some families had to move into empty units if we failed to find them anything. Those who lived in &#39;cage houses&#39; might not even have a bed.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said while the amount was “low”, it was “better than nothing”.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore kick-starts presidential campaigning amid Tan Kin Lian ‘pretty girls’ controversy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3231879/singapore-kick-starts-presidential-campaigning-amid-tan-kin-lian-pretty-girls-controversy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 13:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/2b00036d-cd3b-448c-932b-46ccfc6f6d5c_69639f13.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Campaigning for Singapore&#39;s September 1 presidential poll is set to kick into high gear, after election officials on Tuesday formally approved the candidacies of the three men vying for the largely ceremonial job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Observers had mostly expected Tuesday&#39;s nomination-day proceedings to be a sedate affair, but the occasion became clouded by controversy after the past comments of one of the candidates – Tan Kin Lian – regarding women were thrown into sharp relief in recent days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tan, 75, an ex-CEO of Income Insurance Singapore, one the city state&#39;s biggest insurers previously known as NTUC Income, is going up against Ng Kok Song, 75, former chief investment officer of state investor GIC, and former ruling party heavyweight Tharman Shanmugaratnam, 66.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The consensus view among observers is that the election is Tharman&#39;s to lose, given his popularity over the 22 years he served with the People&#39;s Action Party (PAP) – rising from a junior minister to become Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong&#39;s top economic tsar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The long-ruling PAP has not formally endorsed Tharman – election rules bar political parties from backing a presidential candidate – but various influential figures close to the ruling establishment have openly voiced support for him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singapore&#39;s past presidents have all had significant ties with the PAP and their candidacies have been seen as having the tacit backing of the party that has governed the republic since 1959. The incumbent, President Halimah Yacob, was a former PAP MP and parliamentary speaker.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore set for three-way presidential contest on September 1&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ng and Tan have stressed that they are a better fit to be president as they do not have strong links to the PAP like Tharman.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The formal acceptance of the three men&#39;s candidacies kick-starts a 10-day campaign period ahead of next week&#39;s vote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some 2.7 million citizens are eligible to cast their ballots. Voting is compulsory in the city state and failing to do so results in a voter&#39;s removal from the electoral rolls, with reinstatement requiring a valid excuse or the payment of a S$50 (US$37) penalty.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tan, 75, was the subject of intense social media chatter on Monday after influential women&#39;s rights group Aware issued a statement criticising what it said was his track record of objectifying women on his Facebook page.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It referred to various posts where he discussed “pretty girls” he had encountered while commuting on public transport or elsewhere in public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Such behaviour from anyone in or aspiring to a position of influence suggests that it&#39;s acceptable to trivialise women and overlook their myriad abilities and contributions,” the group said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aware also questioned the government-appointed Presidential Elections Committee for its certification of Tan as a person qualified to run for the presidency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The five-person committee made that determination last week, ascertaining that Tan, Tharman and Ng met the constitutional criteria to be president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To qualify as a candidate, former public officials – ministers, chief justices and permanent secretaries, among others – must have held top senior positions for at least three years over the preceding two decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Private sector candidates must have served an equivalent period as the CEO of a company with at least S$500 million (US$369 million) in shareholders&#39; equity and generated profit after tax throughout the entire period.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Committee members must also be satisfied that candidates are people of “integrity, good character and reputation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Responding to the public outcry, the committee said in a statement issued late on Monday that it was unaware of Tan&#39;s social media posts and that it was “not legally entitled” to rescind the certificate of eligibility it had granted him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Any additional facts regarding a candidate, which come to public attention after the candidate&#39;s certificate has been issued, would be for the electorate&#39;s consideration and assessment before casting their votes,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tan, who was among the losers in 2011&#39;s four-way presidential election, said on Tuesday morning that he was the subject of a “smear campaign”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the government complex where the three men submitted their nomination papers on Tuesday, most of the gathered supporters were there for Tharman.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore warns against foreign interference ahead of presidential poll&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Alvin Tan, a resident of Jurong district – where Tharman was an MP before he vacated the seat to contest the coming polls – said he believed the politician had proven himself both on the domestic and international front.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A trained economist and a former central bank chief, Tharman has been one of the most recognisable Singaporean leaders on the world stage, alongside Prime Minister Lee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We do feel he can do a fantastic job as the head of state for Singapore because he represented us really well internationally,” Tan said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>