<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[First Hong Kong reporter convicted over search on government vehicle registry wins appeal, court rules journalism a valid reason to access records]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3222942/first-hong-kong-reporter-convicted-over-search-government-vehicle-registry-wins-appeal-court-rules?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 11:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/05/8a0f37ae-55ff-48e9-a224-37e85e6b50d2_d65ff367.j​​pg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港首位因搜查被判违法的记者在政府的车辆登记处进行的表演赢得了对其定罪的最后上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;终审法院周一裁定，新闻是自由制片人鲍蔡玉玲接触官方的正当理由记录，并补充说检察官未能证明对她的指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡女士曾在公共广播公司香港电台工作，因被指控故意向交通部作出虚假陈述，于 2021 年 4 月被罚款 6,000 港元（766 美元）部门对她使用其汽车登记数据库的行为提出异议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港记者因搜查车辆数据而被定罪的最终上诉获得批准&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;地方法官以拒绝新闻报道为进行搜查的理由裁定她有罪，这项裁决引发了对该市新闻自由的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choy 在 2020 年年中两次进行搜查，以追查一辆面包车的车主，据信这辆面包车向 100 名身穿白上衣的男子提供武器，以攻击反恐组织-2019 年 7 月 21 日在元朗火车站的政府抗议者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她联合制作了电视节目《香港连线》的一集，调查警方对暴徒袭击的反应，引发了面包车的投诉所有者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港记者因元朗攻击计划被定罪，罚款港币 6,000 元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该纪录片获得外国记者会和金耀裕出版社颁发的人权新闻奖自由奖，由香港记者协会颁发。香港电台以对其运营进行审查为由拒绝了这两个奖项。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong mall stabbing: court orders psychiatric review for jobless man facing 2 counts of murder]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3222939/hong-kong-mall-stabbing-court-orders-psychiatric-review-jobless-man-facing-2-counts-murder?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 10:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/05/65f1afc3-4090-4ab5-a6ee-5a4a6f02abae_5207672b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港一家法院周一下令对一名面临两项罪名的失业男子进行精神病学检查上周，他涉嫌在一家购物中心的一次袭击中刺死两名妇女后，被控谋杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;39 岁的司徒成光早上被押解到观塘法院，在那里对他提出的指控是读。他表面上镇定自若，证实自己理解这些指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;司徒被控于 6 月 2 日在香港象棋、围棋学院和三丽鸥礼品店附近谋杀方晓东和刘启希于钻石山荷里活广场。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港商场刺伤嫌犯被控谋杀，将于周一出庭&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;控方要求延期两周，以取得两名精神科医生报告以确定被告是否适合认罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法律程序是根据被告的心理健康状况评估被告是否可以理解刑事诉讼的过程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;司徒由律师代表出庭。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我好害怕”：目击者回忆香港商场谋杀案的恐怖和创伤&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;代理首席裁判官郑其康命令被告人还押在小榄精神病治疗中心接受精神科医生检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;案件押后至 6 月 19 日。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Hurts my feet’: love of doting father who replaces sand in play pit with finer grains for young daughter arouses envy on Chinese social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3222556/hurts-my-feet-love-doting-father-who-replaces-sand-play-pit-finer-grains-young-daughter-arouses-envy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/3ab42123-fdfa-4ddb-ab79-c3e01024d33c_05edc427.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国东部的一位父亲在女儿之后更换了小区沙坑中的沙子告诉他“我的脚疼”在内地社交媒体上疯传。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在女孩姓谢的母亲发布了一条帖子后，这位来自山东省的父亲用更细的沙子代替了沙子，并在抖音上疯传。 5月25日全程视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢某说，她两岁的女儿禾苗很喜欢在沙坑里玩，但原来粗沙夹杂着小石子，玩起来很吃力。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;她的丈夫，其名字未被列入报告，于是决定自费更换更细的沙子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在征得物业公司同意后，他咨询了多方建筑材料花 800 元（110 美元）从附近的镇上挑选最优质的沙子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢说，她的丈夫关注禾苗好恶的每一个细节，并开玩笑地形容他是他们女儿的“奴隶”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最爱公主的不是王子，而是国王。”她打趣道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙子到了之后，体贴的父亲把它铲进了在物业人员的帮助下，沙坑一直保持清洁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢补充说，升级后的沙坑已成为小区里孩子们的新玩乐场所，禾苗的父亲不仅给女儿买了一车沙子还开了“朋友圈”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;父亲的慈爱姿态在内地社交媒体上引起羡慕&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“真羡慕女儿，所以一个人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“父亲非常慷慨，为大院里的所有孩子买沙子，而不是只为家里的女儿买沙子，”另一个人评论说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些父母也分享了他们爱孩子的例子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位女士说，她的丈夫买了10公斤的决明子，这是一种传统的中草药，让他们的儿子在家门外玩沙坑&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一名男子说，在他女儿说她想念他包的饺子后，他一天从他工作的地方走了 2800 公里回到家，只为给女儿煮饺子。&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong must go beyond land grants to make proposed technopole succeed, learn from past mistakes at Science Park and Cyberport, experts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3222913/hong-kong-must-go-beyond-land-grants-make-proposed-technopole-succeed-learn-past-mistakes-science?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/0209e897-2fbb-4c2f-8907-3e8a2d491502_88fec95a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港需要做的不仅仅是提供土地补助，以确保成功新技术中心，因为这座城市必须从过去的错误中吸取教训，在发展公司和人才方面表现出更多的承诺，专家说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这座占地 627 公顷（1,459 英亩）的城市靠近中国大陆边境新田科技馆拥有 300 公顷的土地用于创新和科技 (I&amp;T) 用途，其余土地保留用于建设新的市中心，以提供多达 54,000 套公寓和社区设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与其将土地出售透过公开招标使用创科科技，政府正考虑直接批出10至70公顷的地块给可自行规划设施的跨国公司。当局表示，他们将在租约和运营协议中加入条款，以确保为城市的最佳利益服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的目标是在边境附近划出 300 公顷的土地用于 I&amp;T 目的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是过去在建设该市现有的两个科技中心过程中遇到的问题引发了人们对新开发项目能否取得成功的质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于新界吐露港的科学园于 2004 年开放，提供 371,612 平方米的办公空间，入驻了来自22个国家和地区的1100多家科技公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，园区仅提供办公空间，其四期开发用地已于2014年被政府收回用于建设家园。园区，现在被豪宅包围，正在研究填海附近更多土地进行扩张的可行性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港科技园公司前主席尼古拉斯布鲁克说，拟议的新田批地将对跨国公司更具吸引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当他们来到一个地方时，他们想把它当作自己的家，但他们也希望能够成长，”布鲁克说。 “[新田的计划] 具有灵活性，跨国公司可以在 15 到 20 年内看到他们可以将业务发展成为香港非常特别的东西。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了科学园，政府还在私营部门的帮助下，在港岛电报湾开发了科技中心数码港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局于 1999 年在没有公开招标的情况下将这个项目授予电讯公司盈科集团，以建设高科技代表政府的技术办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为回报，该公司开发了大约 3,000 套豪华住宅，并有权获得销售利润的 35.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该设施于2002 年成立，截至 2021 年 3 月，吸引了约 2,000 家科技和金融科技公司，培育了 890 多家初创企业。但评论员对数码港是一个房地产项目而非技术中心表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但克里斯托弗教授理工大学研究与创新副校长 Chao 表示，他相信新天不会重蹈历史覆辙。他解释说，缺乏数码和金融科技产业阻碍了数码港的初期增长，迫使它依赖房地产开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“数码港必须发展为房地产才能生存。这是不可避免的。随着它逐渐创建了一个行业生态系统，它现在变得更好了，“Chao说。 “新田的公司在开发原型时，可以跨越大陆寻找买家。它可以满足市场的需求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“香港科技园批出的土地不能空置、随意出售”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他说，计划中的新田项目，相当于17 个科学园的规模，也将有社区设施，为工人创造更好的居住环境，但当局必须做更多工作来吸引龙头企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港作为一个国际城市充满活力但对人才的补贴不够有吸引力，”他说，并补充说目前每个 I&amp;T 工人每月 10,000 港元（1,280 美元）的生活津贴太少了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chao 说他希望新中心能够还设有大学实验室和研究所，为跨国公司提供研究人才。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发展局局长 Bernadette Linn Hon-ho 早些时候驳斥了有关拟议的技术中心根据过去的经验是空洞承诺的担忧。她表示，作为政府主要决策机构的行政会议将审查土地出让申请，当局将在稍后阶段公布政策框架。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港与重庆将在 11 个领域开展合作，包括科技、金融和艺术&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港规划师学会会长李建华敦促政府加快拟定于 2034 年在新田兴建的铁路发展计划，但最早可分配创科用地2026 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于科学园的港铁火车站预计最迟将于 2033 年启用，距离枢纽启用将近 30 年。与此同时，政府仍在研究将港铁延伸至数码港的建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“良好的城市规划并非一切，因为它仍依赖于其他政府部门的支持，”李说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还建议成立一个指定办公室，安排人员跟进创科用地发展的进度。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港扩充的快速签证人才名单中的人工智能专家、建设者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;立法会议员兼中文大学工程学院副院长黄锦辉教授建议为尚未赚取任何收入的创科公司减税，以吸引他们进驻香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;他说，政府必须与领先的企业接触，因为大约 20 年前上海失去了在上海建造半导体制造厂的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划得到了投资公司 H&amp;Q Asia-Pacific 的支持1999 年，目标是到 2008 年创造 195,000 个就业机会，并为该市的国内生产总值增加 300 亿美元。但由于当时的政府拒绝授予该项目任何特许权条款，该计划被取消。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“当我们推动新经济向前发展时，例如 I&amp;T，很难完全依靠市场，因为它涉及高风险并且没有人愿意投资，”Wong 说。 “我们需要行政主导方法的某个部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sammy Heung 的补充报告&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore’s Sentosa Island: from pirates, prisoners-of-war and death to a casino, golf and Trump-Kim]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222935/singapores-sentosa-island-pirates-prisoners-war-and-death-casino-golf-and-trump-kim?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 11:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/05/c540c55e-fb7c-48e1-9ea1-e619aac2b21e_943acd67.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;圣淘沙岛，一个毗邻新加坡的豪华旅游胜地，几乎从未发生过。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;在经历了海盗、疟疾、战俘营和大规模处决的黑暗和残酷的过去之后，该岛——以前称为 Pulau Blakang Mati”或“死亡背后的岛屿”——几乎变成了埃索岛炼油厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当一些有关人士提出另一个想法时，政府已经同意了石油公司——为什么不把它变成像迪斯尼乐园一样的热门旅游目的地？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是如何做到的一定是今天的样子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在离新加坡大约一英里的地方，您会发现圣淘沙岛，这是一个 500 公顷的岛屿，形状像烟斗的末端。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从高处看，它就像一个被森林包围的海滩两旁的迪斯尼乐园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是这个岛有一段黑暗的历史。直到大约 50 年前，它还被称为“Pulau Blakang Mati”，意思是“死亡背后的岛屿”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 19 世纪，它是海盗的常规藏身地，一些专家认为它的名字指的是他们埋葬死者的地方。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“岛屿的野蛮人”：中国商人对新加坡的早期描述&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;大约在这个时期，岛上的小人口也因被认为是疟疾而大量减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;19 世纪末，当新加坡处于英国控制之下时，其军队在全岛建造了五个沿海堡垒，包括山顶上的西乐索堡垒。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;1942 年，他们从这些堡垒与日本人作战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国人战败后，日本人将这座堡垒改造成澳大利亚和英国士兵的战俘营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;其他堡垒年久失修。一个现在被徒步旅行者用作了望点，另一个据 CNN 报道，深受“废墟色情”爱好者的欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本人还在圣淘沙的一个海滩上大规模处决了数千名中国男子，后来改建为色拉蓬高尔夫球场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1965 年，新加坡获得独立。到 1960 年代末，新加坡新政府同意让 Esso 在岛上建造炼油厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;计划将其扩建为石化油库。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡的油轮随着俄罗斯黑油船队的增长，缉获量飙升至历史新高&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;有些人反对将郁郁葱葱的岛屿变成炼油厂的想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;住房和开发建筑师 Alan Choe，他被要求想出令人信服的替代方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了该岛曾是城市的“绿肺”这一事实外，他没有太多可以继续的地方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1967 年，他写了一篇论文，使当局相信该岛需要保持“绿肺”状态，并且可以将其转变为旅游目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府同意将炼油厂搬到另一个岛上，并于 1969 年宣布了计划&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1972 年，该岛更名为“圣淘沙”，意为“和平与安宁”。这是为重新命名该岛而举行的公开竞赛的获奖作品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡政府还组建了圣淘沙开发公司 (SDC)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它对该岛制定了宏伟的计划， &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡的圣淘沙湾如何从疯狂富有的亚洲人变成穷人的巴厘岛&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“它一直是一个军事岛屿。当我们接手时，没有钱，也没有堤道，”Choe 告诉亚洲新闻频道。 “因此，我们首先改造了许多英国人用作军事要塞的旧建筑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1974 年，随着圣淘沙高尔夫俱乐部的开业，圣淘沙的知名度越来越高。尽管收取昂贵的费用，它还是立即受到欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SDC 还推出了连接岛屿和大陆的缆车。他们被吹捧为同类中第一个穿越整个海港的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1979 年，约有 850,000 人访问了该岛，但它仍然不是投资热点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;公司抱怨基础设施不足和设施条件差。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1983年，一艘油船撞上缆车线路后，圣淘沙的发展陷入停滞。事故导致两辆汽车坠入海中，造成 7 人死亡，13 人被困。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是一场灾难，该岛的游客和商业兴趣立即下滑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了让事情重新开始，它需要税收优惠和独特的土地购买规则，开发商可以支付部分土地的费用，并在开发项目启动并运行后用他们的收入支付其余部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;仍然，进展仍然缓慢。就在 1989 年，岛上还没有像样的豪华酒店，只有几家青年旅馆。但在 1992 年圣淘沙长堤开通后，该岛变得更容易到达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 1990 年代，SDC 专注于通过投资数亿美元在圣淘沙开设更多酒店。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但岛上的人气已经减弱。旅游顾问 Christopher Khoo 说圣淘沙“让人联想到古老或陈旧的景点”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主题公园和景点开放和关闭，包括“火山乐园”和水上乐园“梦幻乐园”，其中两个人们死了。 1991年开园的亚洲最大水下水族馆“海底世界”历时较长，但也于2016年倒闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国怀念新加坡要拆圣淘沙鱼尾狮&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>; 1995 年，岛上揭幕了新加坡最大的鱼尾狮，它是半鱼半狮城市的神话守护者。它高 370 米（121 英尺），耗资 800 万美元建造。它于 2019 年被拆除，以便为重建让路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们把它建得很高；人们可以乘电梯上到山顶，我们把它的眼睛做成雷达灯，到处闪烁，冒出烟雾，发出轰鸣声，”Choe 告诉亚洲新闻频道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2002 年，新加坡人政府向该岛投资 30 亿美元以使其恢复活力，其中包括投资 2000 万美元升级巴拉望海滩和翻新西乐索堡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;圣淘沙湾是该岛的主要开发项目之一，于 2003 年启动. 位于岛屿东部边缘的尖端，是新加坡一些最富有的公民居住的地方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;占地 117 公顷的封闭式社区拥有 2,600 套住宅，是新加坡唯一一个非居民可以购买土地，但价格并不便宜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7,000 至 10,000 平方英尺的房屋售价高达 1000 万美元。 2022 年，一辆以 1600 万美元的价格售出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;精英社区的销售额达数亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个想法是为了让富人把车停在前面是游艇，后面是游艇，”Choe 告诉亚洲新闻频道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;来自中国的买家正以创纪录的速度抢购新加坡的豪华房产&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据《洛杉矶时报》报道，该岛已经“一只脚踏入梦幻之地，另一只脚踏入新加坡所拥抱的未来，好吧，南加州，拥有由豪华住宅和游艇码头组成的封闭式社区。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新酒店也在 2000 年代开始开业，包括新加坡嘉佩乐酒店、新加坡 W 酒店和新加坡圣淘沙索菲特水疗度假酒店。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还建造了新景点，包括跳伞和冲浪模拟器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但它在据《时代》杂志报道，2010 年圣淘沙名胜世界开业时，圣淘沙达到了发展的顶峰。这是东南亚第一个环球影城主题公园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它也是新加坡第一家赌场的所在地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个度假村非常大，它开垦了大约 7 公顷的海岸线。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们通常认为圣淘沙岛是人造的。这不是真的，但据美国有线电视新闻网报道，自 1972 年以来，它的面积已经增长了约 220 公顷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;圣淘沙名胜世界产生了立竿见影的影响。从 2010 年到 2011 年，圣淘沙的游客人数从 780 万增加到 1910 万。在大流行之前，游客人数每年继续增长近 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Covid-19 大流行促使旅游业陷入停顿，但圣淘沙的游客再次稳步上升。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;尽管进行了所有开发，圣淘沙仍然是新加坡的“绿肺”。根据一份政府机构 2011 年的报告，估计岛上有 55,000 棵树和 45 公顷的次生林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡政府还实施了限制措施，以确保岛上 60% 的森林和未受破坏的空间.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，Shangri-La Rasa 度假村坐落在树木之中，其车道必须围绕新加坡据报道最古老的树木 Angsana 设计。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普-金峰会：在新加坡，媒体风暴前的平静&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2018 年，前总统唐纳德·特朗普在岛上与朝鲜领导人金正恩举行历史性峰会，金正恩承诺解除核武器，圣淘沙成为头条新闻。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;至于未来，政府计划将圣淘沙岛与附近一个名为 Palau Brani 的岛屿连接起来，以在未来 20 年内打造一个更加令人印象深刻的旅游目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然大流行推迟了计划，圣淘沙肯定会在不久的将来成为一个更大、更颓废的岛屿目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href= &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; 样式=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia claims it repelled ‘large scale’ Ukrainian assault in Donetsk]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222940/russia-claims-it-repelled-large-scale-ukrainian-assault-donetsk?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 10:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/05/bfb5a2fc-bce2-42dd-b81f-82dba9368878_00f00d71.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部周一早些时候宣布，其部队挫败了乌克兰在东部省份顿涅茨克，但尚不清楚这是否是乌克兰反攻的开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部在一段罕见的清晨视频中表示，其部队击退了乌克兰周日在顿涅茨克南部的五个据点，这是俄罗斯去年秋天非法吞并的四个乌克兰地区之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“敌人的目标是在他们认为最脆弱的前线部分突破我们的防御，”说该部发言人伊戈尔·科纳申科夫 (Igor Konashenkov)。 “敌人没有完成任务。但没有成功。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科纳申科夫说，250 名乌克兰人员丧生，16 辆乌克兰坦克、3 辆步兵战车和 21 辆装甲战车被摧毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰没有发表评论，并经常等到其军事行动完成后才确认其行动，在此期间实施新闻封锁。目前尚不清楚为什么俄罗斯国防部要等到周一早上才宣布这次袭击，据称袭击是从周日早上开始的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几个月来，乌克兰官员一直在谈论计划发动春季反攻以收复俄罗斯领土自去年 2 月 24 日入侵以来一直占领，以及它在 2014 年夺取的克里米亚半岛。但他们就什么构成反攻发出了令人困惑的信号——初步的、有限的攻击以削弱俄罗斯军队和军事设施，或者全面——在整个 1,100 公里（684 英里）的前线展开同时进攻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至少有两个因素在影响反攻的时机：等待冬季过后部队和装备移动的地面条件改善，以及部署更先进的西方武器，并训练乌克兰军队使用这些武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部发言人说，乌克兰在袭击中使用了六个机械化营和两个坦克营，并发布了一段视频，声称展示了破坏情况&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰：国防官员说，尽管有俄罗斯的导弹弹幕，但反攻仍在进行中&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;罕见地具体提到了俄罗斯最高军事领导人的存在在战场行动中，该发言人表示，俄罗斯武装部队总参谋长瓦列里·格拉西莫夫将军“在前线指挥所之一”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宣布格拉西莫夫直接参与可能是对批评的回应一些俄罗斯军事博主和雇佣军组织负责人 Yevgeny Prigozhin 表示，俄罗斯的军事高层在前线的表现不够明显，也没有对其国家在乌克兰的军事行动进行足够的控制或承担责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在战场的其他地方，乌克兰当局周日表示，一名乌克兰男子赶往市中心第聂伯城郊外的家中，希望能救出他的家人，却发现他 2 岁的女儿已经死亡，妻子受重伤，因为他帮助将他们从废墟中拉出来公寓在俄罗斯最近的一次空袭中被毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女孩丽莎的尸体被发现后，乌克兰总统沃洛德米尔·泽伦斯基在 Telegram 上写道，至少有 500 名乌克兰儿童在袭击中丧生战争。联合国表示，还有大约 1,000 名其他乌克兰儿童受伤，另有数千人被强行驱逐到俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Volodymyr Zelensky 说：“俄罗斯的武器和仇恨继续夺走和摧毁乌克兰人的生命每天都有孩子，”他补充说，“他们中的许多人本可以成为著名的学者、艺术家、体育冠军，为乌克兰的历史做出贡献。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须坚持并赢得这场战争！”他说。 “整个乌克兰，我们所有的人民，我们所有的孩子，都必须从俄罗斯的恐怖中解脱出来！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六晚上，一枚俄罗斯导弹落在她公寓楼旁边的院子里时，莉莎身亡。第聂伯罗彼得罗夫斯克地区州长 Serhiy Lysak 说，她和她的母亲在家。女孩的父亲下班赶回家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“父亲值班，据我所知，他亲自清理了瓦砾，把妻子和女儿救了出来。”想象一下这场悲剧的规模吧，”乌克兰副总理伊琳娜·韦列舒克在报道一直持续到周日早些时候的救援行动时说。女孩的母亲住院接受重症监护。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;第聂伯罗的罢工导致 2 岁女孩死亡，至少 20 人受伤：乌克兰官员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;泽伦斯基说，25 名受伤者中有 5 名儿童在星期六的袭击中，两栋住宅楼受损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中一名儿童的母亲坐在她公寓附近的破碎混凝土、扭曲的金属、儿童玩具和衣服中，并描述了发生的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“我从发电站跑到马路对面，”Alyona Serednyak 回忆道。 “我正跑回家。我的孩子一个人在家。我们试图把我的孩子从窗户上的笼子下面拉出来。”她说他们设法解救了他，他被送进了医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，俄罗斯无人机和巡航导弹袭击了该国的多个地区，包括首都基辅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰空军部队更新了早些时候的数据，称防空系统击落了 8 架 Shahed 自爆无人机中的 6 架，以及发射的 6 架巡航导弹中的 4 架。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰空军发言人 Yurii Ihnat 说，两枚导弹击落了位于乌克兰中部 Kropyvnytskyi 的军事空军基地乌克兰基洛沃格勒省。他没有报告损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部表示，军方在对乌克兰机场的袭击中摧毁了乌克兰战机和弹药库，但没有提供更多细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯军方据报道，最近几天乌克兰防空炮台、空军基地、部队和弹药库、军事生产工厂和战场阵地遭到袭击。虽然乌克兰官员没有宣布启动他们备受期待的反攻以收复更多被俄罗斯占领的领土，但军事活动的步伐表明行动可能正在进行中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰军队继续对俄罗斯军队施加压力东部城市巴赫穆特，莫斯科在这场战争中持续时间最长、最血腥的战斗后于上个月宣布控制该城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在其他地方，与乌克兰军队并肩作战的俄罗斯人宣布，他们对与乌克兰接壤的俄罗斯别尔哥罗德地区发动了新的攻击。其中一个团体，俄罗斯志愿军，周日发布了一段视频，显示了据称的突袭并提出与俄罗斯当局交换囚犯。视频的真实性无法得到独立验证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;别尔哥罗德州州长维亚切斯拉夫格拉德科夫在他自己的一段视频中回应了囚犯交换提议，称他怀疑俘虏还活着，但他开会讨论互换。俄罗斯志愿军在后来发布的一段视频中说，没有举行会谈，俄罗斯战俘将被移交给乌克兰军队，乌克兰军队在为数不多的合作领域之一定期与俄罗斯交换战俘。&lt;/p>; p>;Gladkov 还报告说，乌克兰周日对 Shebekino 边境地区和邻近地区进行了更多炮击。他说，周六至少有两人死亡，多人受伤。俄罗斯国防部表示，该国军队击退了对新塔沃尔然卡镇的一次企图入侵。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰战争：平民丧生，俄罗斯别尔哥罗德附近数百人逃离地区&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一些观察员在别尔哥罗德看到袭击，这促使俄罗斯当局疏散了数千名居民，作为乌克兰分散莫斯科注意力并扩大其力量以帮助反攻成功的努力的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在克里米亚，地区领导人谢尔盖·阿克谢诺夫报告说乌克兰无人机袭击了克里米亚周日清晨，占凯伊市。他声称其中五架攻击无人机被击落，另外四架被卡住被迫降落，并补充说没有人员伤亡。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can Vietnam’s plan to boost energy capacity work amid rolling outages, electricity shortages?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3222755/can-vietnams-plan-boost-energy-capacity-work-amid-rolling-outages-electricity-shortages?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 09:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/7c0067be-f19f-455a-a8b5-0e806787a906_44fc9f1d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;5 月中旬，在一段极热的时期，Diep Nguyen 在她在越南北部下龙市的家中，一场森林大火烧毁了输电线路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然很难应对，但并不意外。 “In the news there are daily discussions about power shortages that could occur due to extreme weather,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response, Diep is reducing her electricity consumption with the help of an app that monitors her home&#39;s energy use, while following government recommendations to set her air conditioning no lower than 26 degrees Celsius (79 degrees Fahrenheit).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m trying to reduce my air-con use since I work from home and set up another workspace with just a fan,” she said. “If two or three people are home, we try to use the same room instead of each working in their own room with the A/C on.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Crippling heatwaves deepen Asia&#39;s reliance on Russian energy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The family&#39;s situation is far from unique, with tens of millions across the nation – and elsewhere in Southeast Asia – also having trouble dealing with the sweltering heat as global warming intensifies, and at a time when energy supplies are more limited thanks to the knock-on effects of Russia&#39;s war in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh recently warned of nationwide power outages for his country&#39;s 100 million residents amid record temperatures and an unprecedented demand for electricity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In early May, Vietnam recorded its highest-ever temperature – 44.1 degrees Celsius (111.38 degrees Fahrenheit) – breaking a previous record set in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Drought conditions have brought many hydropower reservoirs to critically low levels and delayed coal imports have threatened operations at thermal power plants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Ho Chi Minh City officials have advised residents to not wear formal clothing to work, while the government of Da Nang has ordered public decorative and advertising lighting to be turned off at 8pm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The town of Mong Cai, on the border with China, has been disconnected from the national grid and is instead buying its power from Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Large-scale blackouts have been avoided thus far, but rolling scheduled outages have occurred from the Mekong Delta in the south all the way up to the capital Hanoi in the north. There, some street lights have been turned off to save electricity as demand for air conditioning soars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parks in the city of eight million people are now plunged into total darkness after 11pm, while two-thirds of street lights are also switched off at the same time.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The crisis comes at a particularly momentous time for Vietnam&#39;s energy sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 15, Prime Minister Chinh approved the much-anticipated Power Development Plan 8 (PDP8), which lays out the country&#39;s power strategy until 2030 and beyond. It calls for more than doubling Vietnam&#39;s energy capacity to 150 gigawatts (GW) from the current 69GW.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PDP8 was delayed by over two years and went through numerous drafts as policymakers wrestled over how to provide energy for continued robust economic growth while also meeting international climate commitments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most notably, at COP26 in November 2021, Chinh pledged that Vietnam would achieve net-zero emissions by 2050, an enormous task for a country still heavily reliant on coal-fired energy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new plan, meanwhile, calls for a significant increase in Vietnam&#39;s already substantial base of renewable energy capacity, along with huge growth in gas-fired power, especially from imported liquefied natural gas (LNG) that would replace much of the current coal-fired capacity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;LNG has become even more important since Russia began reducing its exports of natural gas, forcing countries to find alternative sources of energy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many nations are relying on LNG to fill the gap, with suppliers including Australia, the US and Qatar, but so much is being shipped that tankers are queuing up at ports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“PDP8 marks a radical departure from the way Vietnam had traditionally powered its economy, and in many ways, signals its commitment to fuel a modern, international economy powered by the private sector,” said Matthew McGarvey, chief investment officer at Pacific Rim Investment Management.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What makes this such an ambitious policy is the transformation government ministries will have to undertake to attract the roughly US$300 billion from international partners needed to power its economy and prepare for climate change.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the World Bank, Vietnam will need US$368 billion in investment by 2040 to place the country on a net-zero pathway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Up to US$15.5 billion in financing has been offered by a group of wealthy countries including those in the European Union, the United Kingdom and the United States through a Just Energy Transition Partnership (JETP) signed in December, but this leaves an enormous gap.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Giles Cooper, a partner at international law firm Allens Linklaters, focused on energy investment in Vietnam, believes PDP8 could have been bolder in its outlook.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The 2030 mix could have been even more aspirational in terms of total renewable energy mix,” he said, adding that PDP8 “might have benefited from another few months to fully scope, agree, and integrate the JETP component”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the outlined increase in onshore wind is particularly important, as Vietnam now has a proven track record of developing this energy source, unlike offshore wind or LNG.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Solar energy also plays a key role in PDP8, with Vietnam already having the most solar capacity in Southeast Asia. This is largely concentrated in large-scale solar farms, something the plan aims to change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The most important takeaway from PDP8 for households and businesses is that the government wants unlimited investment in rooftop solar for self-consumption,” said Minh Ha-Duong, a senior scientist at the Vietnam Initiative for Energy Transition Social Enterprise. “It is in the consumers&#39; interest to avoid the risk of power shortages and reduce their electricity bills.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to reducing household energy costs, more rooftop solar panels would help address a critical challenge: Vietnam&#39;s grid is not currently capable of moving the huge amounts of solar energy generated in sun-drenched provinces on the south-central coast to energy-hungry major cities and industrial hubs elsewhere.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This has led to a situation in which the country simultaneously has an energy surplus and a shortage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is due to the inability of the grid infrastructure to deliver energy where the demand is,” Cooper explained. “This, in turn, is caused by the rapid development of renewable energy, especially solar power, in areas where the relevant resource is abundant but infrastructure is not. In short, too many projects were allowed to be built in areas that couldn&#39;t accommodate them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PDP8 calls for the national grid to be upgraded, but this will largely be carried out by Electricity of Vietnam (EVN), the state-owned energy monopoly that lost US$1.2 billion in 2022 and may double those losses this year due to rising input costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The challenge is mostly economic, as the US$1.5 billion needed to invest in grid infrastructure remains with the public sector,” Ha-Duong said. “Electricity prices are fixed, but when EVN imports coal, and soon gas, it pays the international price, which can vary a lot.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While the energy plan&#39;s arrival has been celebrated, the government is still working on the precise strategies and regulations needed to make its vision a reality, and many questions remain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Implementation is the biggest challenge,” said Cooper. “Most significantly, the market needs to know how investors will be selected to implement specific projects, what they will be paid, and what the contractual terms will be. The market has been waiting for PDP8 but without answers to these questions investment decisions can&#39;t be made and projects can&#39;t be financed and built.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government, meanwhile, is moving quickly to sign temporary pricing agreements with dozens of completed solar and wind projects that have sat idle while waiting for new regulations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Ha-Duong, this will not be enough to head off further power shortages, especially given the already overloaded grid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Demand is increasing so fast that even if these projects help through the summer, the problem will still be there next year,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Off-grid solar brings light, time and income to remotest villages in Indonesia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The challenges, therefore, are clear, and McGarvey believes the leadership knows what must be done.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“PDP8 shows that the national government is acutely aware of what is required to power a modern economy in an increasingly competitive and uncertain world that is also getting hotter,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The real challenge will be creating bankable pathways for international investors to access projects, as domestic capital markets alone cannot support the level of investment required to finance this next phase in Vietnam&#39;s development.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Diep, for her part, will continue to track her electricity use while striving to save money.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think people are too worried, but they are keeping in mind that they need to be smart about using electricity,” she said. “The more electricity you use, the more you pay, especially during peak hours, so monitoring your use is important.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She also worries that record temperatures are a big hint of the future. “It&#39;s just so hot here right now.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Agence France-Presse&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s services activity picks up in May as new orders shore up consumption-led economic recovery]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3222934/chinas-services-activity-picks-may-new-orders-shore-consumption-led-economic-recovery?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 09:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/05/d1d5c8bd-fdfe-437b-a554-01f92fc27c04_374e0b00.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s services activity picked up in May, a private-sector survey showed on Monday, as a rise in new orders shored up a consumption-led economic recovery in the second quarter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Caixin/S&amp;P Global services purchasing managers&#39; index (PMI) rose to 57.1 in May from 56.4 in April. The 50-point mark separates expansion from contraction in activity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reading contrasts with the official PMI released last week that showed a slower pace of expansion in the services sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some economists warn the pent-up demand for in-person services may fade due to slowing income growth and mounting unemployment pressures, raising headaches for policymakers already struggling with weak foreign demand and an uneven post-coronavirus recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Caixin survey showed service companies reported a rise in new business last month when the first May Day holiday following China&#39;s reopening boosted orders for hotels, restaurants and travel agencies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Increased workloads led firms to grow headcount for the fourth consecutive month, although the speed of job creation slowed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Average prices charged by service companies rose by the fastest since February 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The survey also indicated that capacity pressures persisted, as highlighted by sustained growth in outstanding business.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Jobs, the yuan and beyond: 4 things to look out for in China&#39;s economy in June&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Caixin/S&amp;P&#39;s composite PMI, which includes both manufacturing and services activity, picked up to 55.6 from 53.6 in April, marking the quickest expansion since December 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even if firms in the services sector remained upbeat with business activity over the next 12 months, the level of optimism eased to the lowest since December 2022 when Beijing lifted antivirus curbs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s economy rebounded faster than expected in the first quarter but lost momentum at the beginning of the second quarter as April data broadly undershot forecasts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Factory activity in May shrank faster than expected on weakening demand, reinforcing the unbalanced feature in the economic recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In general, it remains a prominent feature of the Chinese economy that the services sector is stronger than manufacturing,” said Wang Zhe, senior economist at Caixin Insight Group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This divergence highlights that economic growth is lacking internal drive and market entities lack sufficient confidence, underscoring the importance of expanding and restoring demand.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China jobs: is ‘flexible’ work the only solution to unemployment woes?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3222789/china-jobs-flexible-work-only-solution-unemployment-woes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/d873451f-df68-4ed1-a91d-2c80cbeb0f4e_c632332e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The pressure from career counsellors at her university in northern China&#39;s Hebei province became too much for Kayla Liu to bear - she had to find employment, no matter what.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, the 21-year-old English major, unable to secure a full-time job after months of searching, opted to become an entrepreneur – selling handmade beaded bracelets on e-commerce site Taobao.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu said staff from her university have been coercing graduates-to-be to sign “flexible employment” contracts – a directive she suspects is aimed at reducing the unemployment rate of fresh graduates so it does not reflect poorly on her school.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It feels like our university is pushing those who cannot get into graduate school or find a job to apply for flexible employment and to get proof of employment. They will do anything to boost their employment rate. It&#39;s like we aren&#39;t allowed to be unemployed upon graduation,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This adds to the psychological pressure of fresh graduates who are already struggling to find a job in this grim job market.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unemployment rate among 16- to 24-year-olds in China hit a record high of 20.4 per cent in April, after rising from 19.6 per cent in March. And more than 11 million fresh graduates are expected to join the labour market this summer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response, the central government has adopted an “employment-first strategy”, with hopes of adding 12 million new jobs this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As &#39;weak confidence remains&#39;, nearly 20 per cent of China&#39;s youth jobless&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Liu&#39;s online shop, which brings in around 300 yuan (US$42) a week, makes enough to sustain her daily expenses while she hunts for a full-time job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And her situation is far from unique. Many students say they are pressured by their schools to secure employment before graduation – a phenomenon that Chinese media brought to light during the 2022 graduation season.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last June, Caixin reported that students from graduating classes had been told that they would not receive their graduation certificates if they did not submit proof of employment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Ministry of Education responded by warning tertiary institutes against misreporting employment figures, and vowing to investigate any reports accordingly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ministry said schools were not allowed to force or entice students to sign employment or labour contracts, could not withhold graduation certificates as means to coerce students to sign employment contracts, nor could they make students sign a false proof of employment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can China&#39;s &#39;out of touch&#39; vocational system fill blue-collar void?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;By identifying as a “flexible” worker, Liu has joined the likes of millions of freelancers across China. According to the most recent figures from the National Bureau of Statistics, China had 200 million “flexible workers” by the end of 2021, nearly three times more than in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 16 per cent of all college graduates in China in 2020 and 2021 chose flexible employment, according to data from the China Higher Education Student Information and Career Centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who are flexibly employed are not bound by formal employment contracts and include those working part-time, temporary and seasonal jobs, as well as freelancers and entrepreneurs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the growth of the gig and digital economy, flexible workers in China are finding employment in a range of sectors, including food delivery, street vending, live-streaming, and social media content creation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local governments across the country in recent weeks have also bumped up their support for the flexibly employed, with Hubei, Shandong, Zhejiang and Guangdong provinces setting up mobile stations to help jobseekers find such work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With more than one in five Chinese aged 16 to 24 unemployed, flexible employment appears to be one of the solutions for lowering China&#39;s record-high youth unemployment rate – an issue compounded by a shrinking and ageing population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It feels like everyone is fighting for the same few positions,” said Chelsea Li, a human resources major from Chengdu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 22-year-old, who abandoned hope of finding work on recruitment platforms such as Boss Zhipin and Zhilian Zhaopin, has decided to start her own street-vending business selling cupcakes and desserts. By making around 60 portions at a rented kitchen in the morning, she is able to earn about 500 yuan every day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Frankly, this is the happiest I&#39;ve been since graduating, it gives me a sense of satisfaction. Job hunting and sending in resumes is an exhausting process,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For some of China&#39;s young people, the option of flexible employment coupled with digitalisation and the rise of new media means they are no longer sticking to traditional notions of work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leon Liu, a 26-year-old architecture graduate, said that with flexible employment he can afford to spend half his year travelling while working completely remotely.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My family was not very supportive at first and initially wanted me to find a permanent job in a company, but I feel that this sort of flexibility is more realistic,” said Liu, who is currently based in Shanghai. “Now that I have gotten the hang of managing my own workload and income, they are more accepting of my lifestyle.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu, who is fluent in English, French and German, teaches languages online and started a business coordinating cultural exchanges between students from China and the Middle East. He is also a freelance consultant for engineering and architecture projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Working online and being my own boss has given me so much joy, and what I earn is enough to sustain my travels,” he said. “I get to choose whom I work with, what projects to work on, and can do things that are truly meaningful to me, like interacting with people from different cultures.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s firms &#39;never want no experience&#39;, graduates face another tough year&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Summer Huang, a 33-year-old based in Guangzhou, quit her job at a tech company two years ago and started taking on clients as an independent social media manager while freelance writing and creating content for the online lifestyle platform Xiaohongshu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her monthly income ranges from 20,000-50,000 yuan, depending on the jobs she takes on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Not everyone can handle this much freedom,” warned Huang, who works four days a week. “Honestly, sometimes it is even more tiring than working at my previous full-time job. You are your own boss. If you stop working, the money stops coming in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You need to be prepared for instability. Income can be unpredictable. That&#39;s the trade-off for having more freedom.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lu Sina, 28, quit her full-time job at a maternity-products company in 2022, after working there for three years. She is now a freelance operations consultant and career adviser based in Hangzhou, earning around 20,000 yuan a month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her first attempt at entrepreneurship failed in 2016, when she found that running her own travel agency was too exhausting, largely due to her lack of expertise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This time around, Lu spent nine months planning ahead, saving money and detailing her strategies to ensure a steady income flow before quitting her job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Although I&#39;m now earning a little less than my previous job, I have a lot more freedom, spending time with my family, and have more chances to gain more life experiences like while travelling. I think the trade-off is worth it. I don&#39;t see myself returning to a traditional role in the near future,” Lu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Being flexibly employed also resulted in her rethinking other possibilities in life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now, I&#39;m looking to further my studies,” she said. “I have other friends in their thirties who are also flexibly employed, and many of them said they feel like applying for schools or programmes that they didn&#39;t manage to get into when they were younger.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I feel like being flexibly employed makes us feel less restricted by our age or life stage. We feel more free to pursue what we want.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Bless their stationery: plan by Chinese parents to sanctify children’s  study tools in temple ritual for exam luck halted by school]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3222440/bless-their-stationery-plan-chinese-parents-sanctify-childrens-study-tools-temple-ritual-exam-luck?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/eccf5d84-133b-444f-94eb-0e1cc0b05416_88151e11.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A plan by a group of Chinese parents to consecrate the study tools of their children at a Taoist temple to bring exam luck has been scuppered by their school.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 28, in a WeChat group for the parents of a second-year secondary school class in southern China&#39;s Hunan province, a mother announced the plan to bless their children&#39;s stationery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dedication ritual was due to take place the following day at the popular Grand Temple of South Mountain which is situated at the foot of Mount Heng in the province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mother said the event, which would cost 1,000 yuan (US$140), had been approved by the parent committee and would be led by a teacher.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It would act to bless the children ahead of the “first ever big exam of their life”, the biology and geography general examination which is of great importance to their educational future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After word of the plan reached the local education bureau, a member of staff with the school told Jimu News on May 29 that neither the school nor the teacher mentioned in the message knew about the “ceremony”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is anti-science and irrational,” the staff member said, adding that the school had already stopped it and asked the parents to disband the chat group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the unidentified teacher did admit that there was nothing the school could do to stop the parents if they wanted to go ahead with the ritual privately.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Consecration, or kai guang, originally refers to the Taoist ritual performed by a priest on deity statues and artefacts to endow them with spiritual properties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Chinese Buddhist temples had a similar ritual named jia chi, or “blessing”, the term “consecration” later replaced the original name.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, as younger generations in China resort to temple visiting to alleviate the stress of everyday life, the consecration custom has been applied to a broader range of items, such as jewellery and other small personal items.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also, it is not the first time that Chinese parents have performed special rituals to bless their children ahead of examinations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every June during the National College Entrance Examination, or gao kao, one of the nation&#39;s most important exams, mothers often wear qipao to bring luck to their children, as the character qi is the same as qi kai de sheng, which means “achieving a quick victory” in Chinese.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How the humble jellyfish is helping China to supercharge agriculture, medicine production]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3222910/how-humble-jellyfish-helping-china-supercharge-agriculture-medicine-production?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/04/5108fa26-5df5-40dc-8fc9-0858e53e1572_ce4084f1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Researchers in China have unlocked the secrets of a compound found in jellyfish that could revolutionise a 100 billion yuan (US$14 billion) market that includes everything from medicine and cosmetics to fertiliser.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The discovery could lead to the large-scale production of the compound known as polyglutamic acid (PGA), known for its remarkable ability to retain water.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The research team from Nanjing University of Technology was awarded a top national prize for innovation for their work on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s wheat crops face &#39;unprecedented&#39; risks as the world heats up&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Jellyfish are able to thrive in high-pressure, high-salinity ocean environments, without dehydrating, an ability made possible by a biological polymer inside its body called polyglutamic acid, or PGA.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PGA has excellent water solubility, strong absorption capacity, and is biodegradable. Those qualities make it a desirable potential ingredient in cosmetics and food items, where it can help lock in moisture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And in a time of growing global concerns about food insecurity, PGA can act as a biofertiliser, improving crop yields while aiding in the slow release of fertilisers and water, according to the researchers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s fertiliser crunch leaves farmers grasping at straws in early spring&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But sourcing PGA from nature has been a scientific challenge. Aside from jellyfish, the compound can only be found in natto, a traditional Japanese fermented food.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Technical hurdles, which also posed considerable challenges to industrial production, were eventually overcome by using microbial fermentation to produce and extract PGA, making large-scale, cost-effective production a reality, the researchers said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It took us a full decade to produce and extract polyglutamic acid in the laboratory using microbial fermentation,” said professor Xu Hong, the team&#39;s lead scientist, in a report published by China Science Daily on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The journey faced many obstacles. Experiments with traditional bacterial strains had resulted in low yields and the scientists were only able to collect a minimal amount of final product. The complex components in the final fermentation were also difficult to separate and purify, leading to chronically slow industrial production.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After revealing the mechanisms that drive microbial metabolisms, Xu&#39;s team pioneered a process to sequence the genome of the bacterial strains used for production. The result was a new breeding technology to screen the most suitable strains. They also adopted a unique technique to extract high-purity PGA from fermentation products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu&#39;s team has since collaborated with Nanjing Shineking Biotech to establish the world&#39;s first PGA production line with an annual capacity of 100,000 tonnes. The product has found extensive applications in various fields including agriculture, cosmetics and food, and is being exported to Europe and Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our polyglutamic acid product is 30 per cent more concentrated than international advanced products. The conversion rate of reactant substrates has more than doubled, and the amount of ethanol used in production has been significantly reduced,” Nanjing Shineking Biotech co-founder Feng Xiaohai said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For her scientific contributions, Xu Hong was awarded the National Innovation Award on May 30 by the China Association for Science and Technology in conjunction with the Ministry of Science and Technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More potential uses for PGA are being explored. Adding PGA to fertilisers, for example, can improve the utilisation of nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium Trials on crops such as rice, wheat, and corn as well as melons and tobacco have shown promising results.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Products produced by the team have been used by more than 100 large fertiliser and pesticide enterprises, giving a technological boost to the industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our product has contributed to the production of 10 million tonnes of bioactive fortified fertiliser in the past three years,” Xu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Every five tonnes of fortified fertiliser in China contains one tonne of our team&#39;s product.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>