<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Thai parliament to convene session on July 3, enabling vote for new prime minister]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225306/thai-parliament-convene-session-july-3-enabling-vote-new-prime-minister?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 15:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/aa6af24a-f90b-4a5b-8794-6f52070aceef_ef276e67.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;泰国新当选的议会将于 7 月第一周举行会议，启动新政府组建过程，随后投票选举总理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;皇家公报已发布一项法令，要求议会于 7 月 3 日召开。据《泰晤士报》报道，国王玛哈·哇集拉隆功将主持开幕式众议院秘书处。一天后，议员们将投票选举众议院议长和两名副议员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 14 日举行了 500 名议员的众议院选举，结果是民主党派赢得了足够的席位以结束近十年的军事支持统治 - 周一由民意调查小组认证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据泰国规定，议会必须在结果认证后 15 天内召开会议，宣誓就职。选举新议员并选举众议院议长。随后，下议院和参议院将举行联席会议，选出总理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“前进”组织已组建八党联盟，组建由领导人皮塔·利姆贾罗恩拉特 (Pita Limjaroenrat) 领导的下一届政府，被确认为最多席位的获胜者，获得 151 个席位，紧随其后的是为泰党，获得 141 个席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了皮塔涉嫌拥有媒体股份的持续障碍可能会扼杀他担任总理的雄心之外，一个小组军方任命的参议院议员目前正在调查与他的资产和债务申报有关的问题。这次审查是对皮塔资格的另一项挑战，可能会说服更多参议员不要投票支持他担任领导人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为参议院政治发展和公众参与委员会主席的参议员 Seree Suwanpanont 表示，该委员会已启动据《曼谷邮报》报道，对皮塔的资格和参加大选的资格进行了进一步调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，前进党秘书长 Chaithawat Tulathon 本月早些时候表示，支持皮塔的参议员人数已增加至据《曼谷邮报》报道，大约有 40 人。尽管皮塔的联盟获得了约 312 名议员的支持，但仍低于确保其获胜所需的 376 票（议会 750 个席位中的一半以上）。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href= “https://feedx.best” style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong may relax mortgage loan-to-value ratios amid sluggish property market: Financial Secretary Paul Chan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3225309/hong-kong-may-relax-mortgage-loan-value-ratios-amid-sluggish-property-market-financial-secretary?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 15:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/2f115cfe-ec75-4d8a-8d55-0a49db5a7951_c3d0e44e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港政府正在考虑略微放宽部分住宅的抵押贷款与价值比率香港财政司司长陈马宝表示，政府正在与香港金融管理局合作，仔细考虑平衡金融稳定和首次购房者的利益。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港去年将首次购房者首付 10% 的购房上限从 800 万港元提高到 1,000 万港元（130 万美元） 。陈说，一些房主呼吁政府在他们组建家庭后协助购买更大的公寓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈还提醒居民不要在高利率环境下生活，因为市场预期美联储将加息一次。或今年下半年两次。由于本地货币与美元挂钩，香港的利率与美国同步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，陈告诉立法者，他将考虑进一步放宽第一批贷款与价值的比率。时间购房者，但拒绝了放松房地产降温措施的建议，包括调整印花税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港住宅市场在第一季度短暂反弹后出现新的疲软迹象。花旗集团上个月表示，今年年底房价可能与 2023 年初相比保持不变，即下降 7%。二手房价格较 2021 年的最高纪录下跌 13%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，鸭脷洲一个新住宅开发项目的第一轮销售在几小时前突然取消由于需求疲软以及预期加息之前库存高企，香港开发商竞相以较低价格出售公寓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由庄氏中国投资开发的 Aruna 项目根据原来的销售资料，计划推出25个单位，面积由205平方尺至317平方尺，折扣后售价介乎531万至858万港元，即每平方尺25,945至27,498港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;2月份，政府将价值300万港元以下房屋的房屋销售从价印花税从之前的200万港元下调至100港元，以帮助首次购房者登上购房阶梯。&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 15:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea marks 73rd Korean war anniversary as Yoon Suk-yeol lauds sacrifice of fallen soldiers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3225301/south-korea-marks-73rd-korean-war-anniversary-yoon-suk-yeol-lauds-sacrifice-fallen-soldiers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/88539aa5-f8ab-43db-987c-b396f957cee5_ec7330e6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;尹锡烈总统周日赞扬 1950 年阵亡士兵的牺牲- 53 朝鲜战争，并呼吁全国在战争爆发 73 周年之际记住他们的“流血制服”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尹在 Facebook 帖子中表示，“战争退伍军人及其他们所流下的血和泪水”永远不会忘记家庭”，强调“只有强大的力量才能保证真正的和平”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还誓言将进一步保卫韩国，为人民带来繁荣和自由做出贡献，以便“为人民的牺牲”做出贡献。尹指出，包括178万美国士兵在内的195万联合国士兵“赶来保护”韩国人民的自由朝鲜战争期间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国总理韩德洙周日回应了尹的观点，并发誓要用“强大的自卫”能力保卫国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府韩国将通过强有力的自卫来保护我们的安全，而不是基于朝鲜虚假善意的虚假和平。”韩在一场标志着战争开始的全国仪式上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;紧张局势继续在朝鲜半岛蔓延。朝鲜半岛的武器试验，包括上个月发射的军事间谍卫星失败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“朝鲜仍然无法从朝鲜战争的空洞幻想中醒来，”韩补充道。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;朝鲜战争于 1950 年 6 月 25 日爆发，朝鲜坦克部队入侵韩国。美国和其他 20 个盟国在联合国旗帜下与韩国并肩作战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约有 14 万韩国士兵在战斗中阵亡，其中来自 22 个国家的约 195 万联合国士兵，包括韩国美国、英国、加拿大和土耳其参战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从技术上讲，两个朝鲜仍处于战争状态，因为冲突以停火而非和平条约结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早些时候本月，韩国当选为2024-2025年联合国安理会非常任理事国，扩大其在联合国机构的立足点，以更好地解决朝鲜问题和其他全球安全挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在当选联合国安理会非常任理事国后，韩国瑜表示，韩国将加强与美国和日本的合作，应对朝鲜的核威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“韩国的加入成为联合国安理会非常任理事国是进一步扩大韩美日在朝鲜核威胁问题上的团结与合作的契机。”韩说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 15:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Timeline of how Russia’s mercenary revolt unfolded]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225305/how-russias-mercenary-revolt-unfolded?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 15:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/dc306ada-014c-4c42-8c7b-672d66fa769a_404a8a0a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;叛变的俄罗斯雇佣兵一路猛冲到莫斯科，直到他们的领导人表示他们已经同意返回以避免流血。以下是事件发生的时间线。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;- 瓦格纳私人军队的老板叶夫根尼·普里戈任 (Yevgeny Prigozhin) 发布了一段视频，加剧了他与俄罗斯军方高层的不和并首次拒绝了弗拉基米尔·普京总统入侵乌克兰的核心理由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;- 在 Telegram 上发布的一系列随后的录音中，普里戈任表示，俄罗斯军事领导层的“邪恶”行为“必须被制止”，并且他的瓦格纳雇佣军将领导一场针对俄罗斯军队的“正义游行”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——俄罗斯联邦安全局安全部门对此作出回应，对普里戈任提起刑事诉讼，称他呼吁武装叛变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;– 俄罗斯乌克兰战役副司令谢尔盖·苏罗维金将军敦促瓦格纳民兵放弃对军事领导层的反对，返回基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;–普里戈任说，他的手下已经从乌克兰越过边境进入俄罗斯，并准备好“一路”对抗俄罗斯军队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——普里戈任在一份声明中说，瓦格纳战斗机已经进入俄罗斯南部城市罗斯托夫。 Telegram 上发布的录音。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫表示正在监视涉及俄罗斯和瓦格纳部队的局势，并将就事态发展与盟友和合作伙伴进行磋商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;– 州长俄罗斯南部毗邻乌克兰的罗斯托夫地区的居民要求居民保持冷静并待在室内，因为瓦格纳部队显然已经控制了罗斯托夫市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;– 俄罗斯国防部发表声明，呼吁瓦格纳武装分子放弃普里戈任，称他们“被欺骗并被拖入犯罪冒险”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——俄罗斯安全部门消息人士告诉路透社，瓦格纳武装分子已经控制了沃罗涅日市的所有军事设施，距离约 500 公里（300 公里）莫斯科以南数英里处&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——普京发表电视讲话，誓言镇压他所谓的武装叛乱。他指责普里戈任“叛国”和“背后捅刀子”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——普京盟友、车臣领导人拉姆赞·卡德罗夫表示，他的部队已准备好帮助镇压普里戈任的叛乱，并使用严厉手段必要时采取措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——包括英国、法国、德国和意大利在内的欧洲各国政府发表声明称，他们正在密切关注俄罗斯的事态发展。白天，世界各地许多其他国家的政府也发表了类似的声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——在连夜夺取罗斯托夫后，俄罗斯军用直升机向一支叛军雇佣兵车队开火，该车队已经向莫斯科前进了一半以上，闪电般推进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;– 乌克兰总统弗拉基米尔·泽连斯基表示“俄罗斯的弱点是显而易见的”，莫斯科在乌克兰保留军队和雇佣军的时间越长，就会给国内带来越多的混乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;– 谢尔盖·纳雷什金 (Sergei Naryshkin)据塔斯社报道，俄罗斯 SVR 对外情报部门负责人表示，普里戈任破坏社会稳定并引发自相残杀的内战的企图显然已经失败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;– 俄罗斯士兵在根据《Vedomosti》报纸发布的照片​​，莫斯科西南边缘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——照片还显示，武装警察聚集在 M4 高速公路（叛乱的瓦格纳雇佣兵正在沿着这条高速公路行驶）到达俄罗斯首都的地方。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;- 土耳其总统表示，塔伊普·埃尔多安总统与普京通电话，敦促他按照常识行事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;- 白俄罗斯发表声明，重申与俄罗斯的联盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;- 白俄罗斯发表声明，重申与俄罗斯的联盟。 p>;&lt;p>;——白宫表示，美国总统乔·拜登已与法国、德国和英国领导人通话，他们确认了对乌克兰的支持。美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯也表示，他已与七国集团外长和欧盟外交事务高级代表进行了交谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——普京签署了一项法律，允许在戒严地区对违反戒严令的人进行 30 天的拘留据俄新社报道，瓦格纳雇佣兵已被许诺，如果他们放下武器，“但他们应该尽快行动”，塔斯社援引议员帕维尔·克拉申尼尼科夫的话说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;- 俄罗斯外交部发表声明，警告西方国家不要利用瓦格纳集团的叛变“来实现其仇俄目标”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;- 白俄罗斯总统亚历山大·卢卡申科办公室表示，他已经与普里戈任达成了一项协议，普里戈任同意缓和局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——普里戈任说，他已命令他的战士在车队中向莫斯科推进，掉头返回基地以避免流血。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;- 普里戈任说，他已命令他的战士在车队中掉头返回基地。 >;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net NET&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/分区>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia rebellion threat revives concern over nuclear arsenal security]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225299/russia-rebellion-threat-revives-concern-over-nuclear-arsenal-security?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 14:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/3ea7e392-1dcf-4a11-b45e-524d07294c5d_edc74e91.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;瓦格纳雇佣军向莫斯科进军，在华盛顿重燃了一种古老的恐惧：会发生什么瓦格纳的老板叶夫根尼·普里戈任周六同意命令他的战士返回营地，这平息了人们对俄罗斯境内发生重大冲突的担忧。但这一事件表明，俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京(Vladimir Putin)对权力的掌握正在减弱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯街头坦克的形象让人想起1991年共产主义强硬派发动的失败政变，引发了人们对苏联核武库安全的担忧，美国前情报官员表示，流氓指挥官窃取弹头的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“IC（情报界）将高度关注（俄罗斯）核储备，”前情报官员马克·波利梅罗普洛斯 (Marc Polymeropoulos) 表示中央情报局高级官员，负责监督该机构在欧洲和欧亚大陆的秘密行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你想知道谁控制着核武器，因为你担心恐怖分子或像（车臣领导人拉姆赞）卡德罗夫这样的坏人曾担任中央情报局莫斯科站站长的前中央情报局高级官员丹尼尔·霍夫曼 (Daniel Hoffman) 表示： ，这座南部城市被普里戈任的战士占领，然后又放弃，并发誓要帮助镇压叛乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;瓦格纳领导人的流亡结束了叛乱，但留下了人们对普京权力的质疑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;可以肯定的是，美国官员们表示，他们认为俄罗斯战略和战术武器的安全不会受到直接威胁。克里姆林宫发言人德米特里·佩斯科夫表示，将瓦格纳战士送回营地的协议旨在避免对抗和流血。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们没有看到俄罗斯核力量的部署发生任何变化，”一位国家安全官员表示。市议会发言人回答路透社提问。 “俄罗斯负有维持对其核力量的指挥、控制和保管的特殊责任，并确保不采取危及战略稳定的行动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这些武器的安全性一直是俄罗斯人的担忧。华盛顿。美国情报机构在 2023 年年度威胁评估中表示，“尽管自 20 世纪 90 年代以来俄罗斯核设施的材料保护、控制和核算有所改善，但俄罗斯的核材料安全……仍然令人担忧”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位国会助手指出克里姆林宫近年来投入了额外的资源来实现其武器库的现代化，并补充说，“俄罗斯的战略力量总体上状况良好”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在让规划者担心的情况可能是出现流氓军事派系的可能性如果普里戈任叛变所暴露的乌克兰战争分歧再次爆发，美国及其盟国将不禁想知道新的权力机构将如何使用这些武器”，霍夫曼说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是向西方勒索任何你想要的东西的能力。他们可能不会遵循普京的同样规则，”他说，并指出俄罗斯领导人没有对他为回应西方支持乌克兰打击俄罗斯占领军而发出的核威胁采取行动。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;俄罗斯的核武库是世界上最大的，美国科学家联合会估计 2022 年拥有 5,977 枚弹头，而美国估计拥有 5,428 枚弹头&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;收集有关俄​​罗斯战略部队指挥结构和战略的信息前中央情报局官员表示，库存的安全和其他方面长期以来一直是美国间谍机构的最高优先事项。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着俄罗斯安全危机迅速展开，美国及其盟友进行了磋商&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;随着普京于 2022 年 8 月决定停止美国根据《新削减战略武器条约》检查俄罗斯核设施，这项工作变得更加困难。该条约允许双方检查和监测彼此的战略核力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一决定使华盛顿高度依赖波利梅罗普洛斯表示，通过间谍卫星评估核武器地点和弹头的安全性，并通过通信拦截来监控俄罗斯指挥官的忠诚度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这一直是（美国）超高情报霍夫曼说：“俄罗斯的核武器收集优先权以及指挥和控制。” “我们都知道这很危险，这就是为什么我们签订了所有这些条约，我们有很多透明度，但现在已经消失了。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s ability to achieve economic growth subject to external factors as government’s intervention has limited impact, says Paul Chan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3225304/hong-kongs-ability-achieve-economic-growth-subject-external-factors-governments-intervention-has?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 14:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/645a98b9-224f-42d7-869a-96d671e7ec64_ed46c43c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港财政部长承认香港经济能否实现 5.5% 的增长今年的国内生产总值将受到外部因素的影响，因为政府支持本地企业和消费的努力的影响有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财政司司长陈茂波周日也表示，政府支持本地企业和消费的努力将受到有限的影响。仍在研究协助购房者的措施，包括是否将范围从首次购房者扩大到那些希望用更大的公寓取代房屋的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈早些时候在其年度预算蓝图中透露，该市的国内生产总值预计2023年GDP增​​速将较上年增长3.5%至5.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被问及香港能否实现最佳预测GDP增长时，陈在电台中表示秀：“我们将竭尽全力。说实话，这确实取决于外部环境。归根结底，香港是一个小而开放的经济体……如果环境不好，我们就有一定的困难。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管我们发放了消费券，支持了中小企业，对当地就业和消费的影响仍然有限。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府连续第三年发放消费券。这项措施预计将花费政府约 330 亿港元（40 亿美元），并使国内生产总值 (GDP) 增长 0.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据今年的安排，永久居民和 18 岁及以上的新来港人士以上人士每人可获赠价值港币5,000元电子礼券。第一轮 3,000 港元已于 4 月中旬发放，第二期将于下个月发放。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;财务总监表示，由于出口依然疲弱，香港经济由本地支出推动&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;陈重申，由于该市出口继续面临挑战，未来六个月将依靠消费和旅游业来实现经济目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，旅游服务业快速反弹尽管香港4月份的旅客人数仅达到290万人次左右，仅为疫情前的50%，但零售和餐饮业已达到疫情前水平的90%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，出口行业面临全球地缘政治因素、欧洲经济表现温和以及美国高利率等压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年前四个月出口较上年下降16.5%。 2022年同期。4月份出口总额为3,383亿港元，同比下跌13%，跌幅较3月份1.5%的跌幅更严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，财政部长表示，政府将宣布措施与香港金管局研究后表示协助购房者，强调调整将是“微小的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些人还表示，他们想在成家后换到更大的单位。我们正在考虑如何划定界限。”陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，他们正在考虑如何帮助那些购买自用房屋的人，同时维护他们的利益和财务安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港防范外围风险挑战：陈茂波本月早些时候表示，他将考虑放宽首次购房者的贷款与价值比率，这意味着他们可能会借更多钱陈先生周日还表示，房地产市场稳定，但敦促居民对房地产市场保持谨慎态度。利率相对较高。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘What you said is truly ugly’: woman passengers hit back at man over ‘scantily-clad’ taunts on China subway train in viral video]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3224902/what-you-said-truly-ugly-woman-passengers-hit-back-man-over-scantily-clad-taunts-china-subway-train?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/52e44551-55aa-41f1-af8d-837be1f95da5_a2a04cdb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一名女子因反击男子而在大陆社交媒体上赢得掌声指责一名穿着正常的年轻女地铁乘客“衣着暴露”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;星视频报道，上海一名身份不明的男子批评该年轻女乘客的着装，称其在公共场合穿着过于暴露。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在目睹他的粗鲁行为后，一名年长的妇女站了起来并进行了干预。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一段病毒视频显示，身穿黑色连衣裙的年轻女乘客和穿着黑色 T 恤的年长妇女她保护年轻女子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“别人穿什么关你什么事？”老妇人说道，并补充道：“女性必须穿遵守传统美德的衣服吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在美国，有人在街上穿比基尼，”这位女士继续说道，举起手来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;男子回答：“那是在美国，但这是中国，好吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“上海是一座国际化城市，你知道吗？” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当年轻女乘客和她的同伴以及火车上的其他乘客在一旁观看时，该男子再次发起言语攻击，称年长的女性“丑陋”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“你说的真难听？ “你真的很丑。”年长的女人回应道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然一些乘客试图阻止该男子，但他无视他们并拉扯年轻女子同伴的包。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随后发生了扭打，直到年轻女子在下一站下车并向警方寻求帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事在中国媒体上疯传，许多人为这位年长女子鼓掌并批评该男子的不恰当和过时的判断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个人说：“我向这个女人的勇敢致敬。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个人写道：“如果我遇到这样的男人，我希望我能像这位勇敢的女人一样勇敢地面对他。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“男人绝对没有权利对女人说教她的着装风格，”另一位补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他生活在古代？另一位评论者开玩笑说，我们生活在一个自由着装的时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= “color:orange” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why a joke about the PLA has got China’s stand-up comics worried]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3225142/why-joke-about-pla-has-got-chinas-stand-comics-worried?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/c0bb268b-e272-4c85-9e67-691eea0cd8b6_e5b6a737.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国的单口相声演员面临着艰难的人群。许多人表示，他们坚持谈论安全话题，避免任何过于敏感的话题，因为担心审查机构会进行压制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，喜剧场景在中国年轻人中越来越流行。但自从上个月一名喜剧演员受到警方调查后，表演者能走多远的不确定性越来越大。他开的是解放军的玩笑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“演出少了，我们不得不远离边界——所以就谈论一些与日常生活有关的事情吧。” ”，一位不愿透露姓名的喜剧演员在北京深夜演出结束后说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位喜剧演员在播客上表示，许多表演者现在都在进行自我审查。 “事件发生后，许多人开始感到困惑和失落，并删除了[节目中的敏感内容]，”这位喜剧演员说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该事件是五月中旬在北京的一场节目。李浩石以他的艺名“豪斯”而闻名，当他拿自己的两只狗开玩笑时，他称赞它们“品行优良，有能力打胜仗”，这也是习近平主席为解放军使用的口号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;北京警方的一份声明称，李现因“严重侮辱解放军”正在接受调查。他下落不明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他所在的公司——上海笑果文化传媒——被罚款1335万元人民币（190万美元），同时没收133万元“违法所得”。单口喜剧公司被无限期禁止演出。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“已经是尾声”：审查、削减成本打击中国媒体行业&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;审查制度长期以来一直是在中国，单口喜剧是一个因素，就像任何形式的公共表达——从电影到媒体一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;喜剧演员多年来一直被要求向审查机构提交节目剧本，审查机构检查是否有与政治、宗教或毒品等禁忌话题相关的材料。有些人对处理性别问题等有争议的话题持谨慎态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，北京每晚都有喜剧表演。工作、爱情和婚姻都处于火线，还有爱好、养老金制度，甚至“镇压美帝国主义”——根据一位漫画家的说法，所有这些话题都被认为是“有点安全”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;表演结束后，北京的另一位喜剧演员下台时表示，他不认为李有侮辱军队的意思。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为任何人都没有必要故意做这样危险的事情。事情，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有红线，敏感问题——那些穿制服的人……政治是绝对被禁止的……你可以说这是这个国家的传统，”这位喜剧演员说。 “我不会碰这些事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;单口喜剧近年来一直蓬勃发展。一份行业报告估计，2021年约有18,500场演出，总收入为3.91亿元人民币，比2019年增长超过50%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在李被调查、公司受到处罚后，其他演出暂时被搁置。据几位喜剧演员说，剧本被暂停了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，有人说审查已经过度了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相关部门现在对剧本的审查更加严格，”一位喜剧演员说道，并补充说节目重新开始，他认为李的案件不会影响整个行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于其他人来说，这种情况是一个新的材料来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你们都知道我们的本周，一位喜剧演员在北京一场拥挤的演出中打趣道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但如果我们喜剧演员足够努力，我们可能会在合法渠道获得一些曝光度，”他说。到一个国营电视频道，该频道报道犯罪以进行公共教育。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia-Asean trade ties set for turning point: ‘now, there’s a different appetite’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3225284/australia-asean-trade-ties-set-turning-point-now-theres-different-appetite?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/fa5f85c6-17e3-4006-83ee-31c5009e8268_f6019f91.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由于在东南亚拓展业务面临挑战，澳大利亚与东南亚的经济关系好坏参半，但观察人士表示，随着堪培拉在与中国关系疲软的情况下加强其在该地区的利益，两国关系可能会迎来转折点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“澳大利亚大大小小的机构越来越相信东盟正在走上正轨。到第一世界。澳大利亚前贸易部长安德鲁·罗伯（Andrew Robb）是推动与东南亚加强接触的人士之一，他表示：“首先，东盟正在向世界开放。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗伯在他于 2013 年至 2016 年间任职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然亚洲金融危机等事件增加了在该地区投资的风险，但罗布表示，企业争相在中国以外寻找替代制造中心和东南亚国家联盟经济的成熟现在可以改变澳大利亚的胃口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一旦他们对贸易征收大量关税，他们就会有一个不可能通过的官僚机构，政府会产生怀疑。商人……有其他选择。中国出现了，”他说。 “早在 2015 年、2016 年，我们就在打基础……现在，人们的胃口不同了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出口到亚洲更容易，但在东南亚开店或在亚洲扩张仍然具有挑战性，企业家告诉《亚洲周刊》。企业家面临的常见障碍包括寻找合适的当地联系人或合作伙伴以及获得熟练劳动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，澳大利亚在东盟的直接投资约为 280 亿澳元（187 亿美元），而来自新西兰的投资 – a country of 5 million people, or less than 1 per cent of Asean&#39;s population – were more than double at A$75 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite Indonesia having a US$1.2 trillion economy, making it the largest Asean member state, it appeared to have attracted no direct investments from Australia between 2018 and 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was no data for publication, according to the investment report for 2022 released by the Australian Bureau of Statistics last month.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Undertaking direct investments – which are often riskier – reflects investors&#39; willingness for long-term stakes in a country, so low levels of Australian direct investments in Asean convey a weak financial commitment to the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; While direct investments could take a while to increase as businesses learned to divert capital away from “blue chip” countries, Asean and Australia had over the course of the last two decades negotiated a swathe of free-trade deals that could serve as a bedrock for more trade in the interim, Robb said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two-way trade between Australia and Asean reached A$150 billion in 2021-22, exceeding that of the European Union at A$97 billion and the United States at A$77 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia and Vietnam linked by banh mi, beer and shared concerns over China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A new economic strategy to be launched later this year could also help Australian businesses make further inroads into Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “Southeast Asia Economic Strategy to 2040”, part of Canberra&#39;s efforts to boost ties with the region, aims to map trade and investment opportunities across key Southeast Asian sectors to Australian capabilities. It will also propose ways to boost mutual trade and how Australian businesses can support and contribute to the region&#39;s energy transition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Businesses were keen to seize on the strategy&#39;s potential commercial benefits but less interested in using it as a political tool to “win friends” in Asean, said Francis Wong, chair of the Australia-Asean Business Forum, which begins on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The architect of the strategy, Australia&#39;s new Special Envoy for Southeast Asia Nicholas Moore, is set to speak at the forum alongside Asean heads of missions and business leaders.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In 2014, a report by advisory firm PwC said Australian businesses were missing out on the growth of Southeast Asia and wider Asia due to a culture of being unwilling to deal with change or to operate in an Asian environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Putting it bluntly, Australian business has operated in a relatively sheltered, comfortable competitive environment. And we have become complacent,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PwC Asia Practice director Sung Lee said there had since been improvements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Over the last decade, Australian businesses have become less evangelistic about economic opportunities in Asia. Instead, we have in general become more strategic and smarter in our pursuit of economic opportunities in Asia,” Lee said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Results of business chamber Austcham-Asean&#39;s annual survey last year showed more Australian firms had operated in Asean markets compared with the previous years, and many said they intended to expand. There was a 15 per cent increase in international operations across the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Businesses told Austcham-Asean that “Asean integration was crucial for enhancing the region&#39;s economic environment” despite facing challenges including corruption.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;However, just talking up Southeast Asia domestically would not accelerate Australian expansions in the region, said Dale Schilling, who founded “insurtech” start-up Hillridge Technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Schilling found his drive for Asia through living there. He had spent five years in Japan while on a scholarship from the Japanese government to study the language.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If we are going to pivot our country to Southeast Asia … I would like to see far more exchanges with students and also business matching,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, Hillridge launched a new agricultural insurance product that protects farmers in Vietnam from the risks of drought, with assistance from various levels of Australian governments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Government support, however, was only one part of the puzzle, Schilling said. Aside from living in Asia, he also attributed his success to the right working environment, such as his co-working office at Haymarket HQ in Sydney. Haymarket HQ specialises in expansions into Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I felt that if I&#39;d gone to one of the other co-working spaces, it would have just felt very focused on Australia and then if you&#39;re going to export, of course you go to America and then next, it&#39;s Europe,” Schilling said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Jacques Markgraaff, who is leading Australian clean energy firm Lavo&#39;s expansion into Asia in his role as chief operating officer, business networks have opened doors faster into Brunei as a potential hub for his company to expand its customer base, for instance, even as Australian governments have been supportive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Markgraaff said “there remains work to be done at the intergovernmental level to help accelerate cross-boarder collaboration” for places like Brunei, which has a comparative advantage of having a deep capital pool and strong relationships with other countries such as China, the rest of Southeast Asia and Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Research eventually helped him have “good conversations” with the Brunei and Singapore high commissions, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m not sure why things are not moving fast enough across the Southeast Asian region from a political standpoint but they should be, especially given the economic [and] environmental implications at stake and I believe we will start to see more positive momentum happening soon,” Markgraaff said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Wagner leader’s exile ends Russia revolt but leaves questions about Putin’s power]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225298/wagner-leaders-exile-ends-russia-revolt-leaves-questions-about-putins-power?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 14:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/6a476d2a-d31c-4087-9e98-aa960a8f5563_2743b6ba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The greatest challenge to Russian President Vladimir Putin in his more than two decades in power fizzled out after the rebellious mercenary commander who ordered his troops to march on Moscow abruptly reached a deal with the Kremlin to go into exile and sounded the retreat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The brief revolt, though, exposed vulnerabilities among Russian government forces, with Wagner Group soldiers under the command of Yevgeny Prigozhin able to move unimpeded into the Russian city of Rostov-on-Don and advance hundreds of kilometres toward Moscow. The Russian military scrambled to defend Russia&#39;s capital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the deal announced Saturday by Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov, Prigozhin will go to neighbouring Belarus, which has supported Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine. Charges against him of mounting an armed rebellion will be dropped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government also said it would not prosecute Wagner fighters who took part, while those who did not join in were to be offered contracts by the Defence Ministry. Prigozhin ordered his troops back to their field camps in Ukraine, where they have been fighting alongside Russian regular soldiers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin had vowed earlier to punish those behind the armed uprising led by his one-time protégé. In a televised speech to the nation, he called the rebellion a “betrayal” and “treason”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In allowing Prigozhin and his forces to go free, Peskov said, Putin&#39;s “highest goal” was “to avoid bloodshed and internal confrontation with unpredictable results”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US, allies consult as security crisis unfolds rapidly in Russia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The risk for Putin is whether he will be seen as weak, Western analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Putin has been diminished for all time by this affair,” former US ambassador to Ukraine John Herbst said on CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moscow had braced for the arrival of the Wagner forces by erecting checkpoints with armoured vehicles and troops on the city&#39;s southern edge. About 3,000 Chechen soldiers were pulled from fighting in Ukraine and rushed there early Saturday, state television in Chechnya reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russian troops armed with machine guns put up checkpoints on Moscow&#39;s southern outskirts. Crews dug up sections of highways to slow the march.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wagner troops advanced to just 200km (120 miles) from Moscow, according to Prigozhin. But after the deal was struck, Prigozhin announced that he had decided to retreat to avoid “shedding Russian blood”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin had demanded the ouster of Defence Minister Sergei Shoigu, whom Prigohzhin has long criticised in withering terms for his conduct of the 16-month-long war in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, he accused forces under Shoigu&#39;s command of attacking Wagner camps and killing “a huge number of our comrades”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If Putin were to agree to Shoigu&#39;s ouster, it could be politically damaging for the president after he branded Prigozhin a back-stabbing traitor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US had intelligence that Prigozhin had been building up his forces near the border with Russia for some time. That conflicts with Prigozhin&#39;s claim that his rebellion was a response to an attack on his camps in Ukraine on Friday by the Russian military.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How Wagner&#39;s Prigozhin turned from Putin pal to critic of military&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In announcing the rebellion, Prigozhin accused Russian forces of attacking the Wagner camps in Ukraine with rockets, helicopter gunships and artillery. He alleged that General Valery Gerasimov, chief of the General Staff, ordered the attacks following a meeting with Shoigu in which they decided to destroy the military contractor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Defence Ministry denied attacking the camps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Congressional leaders were briefed on the Wagner build-up earlier last week, a person familiar with the matter said. The person was not authorised to speak publicly and spoke to The Associated Press on the condition of anonymity. The US intelligence briefing was first reported by CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A possible motivation for Prigozhin&#39;s rebellion was the Russian Defence Ministry&#39;s demand, which Putin backed, that private companies sign contracts with it by July 1. Prigozhin had refused to do it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It may well be that he struck now because he saw that deadline as a danger to his control of his troops,” Herbst wrote in an article for the Atlantic Council.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Early Saturday, Prigozhin&#39;s private army appeared to control the military headquarters in Rostov-on-Don, a city over 1,000km south of Moscow, which runs Russian operations in Ukraine, Britain&#39;s Ministry of Defence said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russian media reported that several helicopters and a military communications plane were downed by Wagner troops. Russia&#39;s Defence Ministry has not commented.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the agreement de-escalated tensions, video from Rostov-on-Don posted on Russian messaging app channels showed people cheering Wagner troops as they departed.普里戈任开着一辆SUV，后面跟着一辆大卡车，人们向他打招呼，有些人跑过去与他握手。 The regional governor later said that all of the troops had left the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wagner troops and equipment also were in Lipetsk province, about 360km south of Moscow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moscow Mayor Sergei Sobyanin declared Monday a non-working day for most residents as part of the heightened security, a measure that remained in effect even after the retreat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukrainians hoped the Russian infighting would create opportunities for their army to take back territory seized by Russian forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These events will have been of great comfort to the Ukrainian government and the military,” said Ben Barry, senior fellow for land warfare at the International Institute for Strategic Studies. He said that even with a deal, Putin&#39;s position has probably been weakened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said late Saturday, shortly before Prigozhin announced his retreat, that the march exposed weakness in the Kremlin and “showed all Russian bandits, mercenaries, oligarchs” that it is easy to capture Russian cities “and, probably, arsenals”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wagner troops have played a crucial role in the Ukraine war, capturing the eastern city of Bakhmut, an area where the bloodiest and longest battles have taken place. But Prigozhin has increasingly criticised the military brass, accusing it of incompetence and of starving his troops of munitions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 62-year-old Prigozhin, a former convict, has long-standing ties to Putin and won lucrative Kremlin catering contracts that earned him the nickname “Putin&#39;s chef.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He and a dozen other Russian nationals were charged in the United States with operating a covert social media campaign aimed at fomenting discord ahead of Donald Trump&#39;s 2016 presidential election victory. Wagner has sent military contractors to Libya, Syria, several African countries and eventually Ukraine.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Israeli security chiefs vow crackdown on settler ‘terrorism’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3225296/israeli-security-chiefs-vow-crackdown-settler-terrorism?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 14:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/f877485b-04d4-4360-b8b0-55f4b3a63326_a5082a79.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Israeli security chiefs on Saturday designated settler attacks on Palestinian villages in the occupied West Bank as “nationalist terrorism” that merited stepped-up countermeasures, and their remarks drew anger from far-right cabinet ministers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A surge of violence over the past week in the West Bank included rampages by scores of Israeli settlers on Palestinian towns and villages that drew international condemnation and concern from the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Saturday, settlers torched at least two homes in the Palestinian village Umm Safa near Ramallah, residents said. Israel&#39;s military said at least one Israeli suspect had been arrested.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Defence Minister Yoav Gallant condemned the attack.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a joint statement, Israel&#39;s military, police and domestic security service chiefs said the settlers&#39; actions amounted to “nationalist terrorism” which they pledged to fight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The military will boost its forces in the area to prevent such violence, they said, and the Shin Bet domestic security service would enhance arrests, including “administrative detention” in which suspects can be held without charge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That practice is largely used by Israel against Palestinian security suspects and is denounced by rights groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statement drew sharp rebuke by two members of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu&#39;s nationalist-religious government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The attempt to equate murderous Arab terrorism with civilian counter actions, as serious as they are, is immoral and dangerous,” said Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He called on security forces to step up their efforts against Palestinian attacks and on settlers to refrain from “taking the law into their own hands”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;National Security Minister Itamar Ben-Gvir, who has past convictions for support for terrorism and incitement against Arabs, echoed Smotrich&#39;s remarks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, White House national security adviser Jake Sullivan expressed concerns about settler attacks on Palestinian villages in a call with his Israeli counterpart, hours after Ben-Gvir called on settlers to expand their presence across the West Bank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The settlers&#39; assaults this week followed intense gun battles in Jenin that left seven Palestinians dead, a Palestinian shooting attack that killed four Israelis and a rare Israeli air strike in the area against militants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier on Saturday, a Palestinian militant opened fire at a West Bank Israeli checkpoint and wounded a security guard, Israel&#39;s police said. They added that the Palestinian gunman was then shot dead by forces at the scene.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Israeli drone targets &#39;terrorist cell&#39; as West Bank violence escalates&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The gunman was claimed by Al-Aqsa Martyrs Brigade, an armed group associated with Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas&#39; Fatah party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US-brokered peace talks between the Palestinians and Israel aimed at establishing a Palestinian state in the West Bank, East Jerusalem and Gaza, collapsed in 2014 and show no sign of revival.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most countries deem the settlements Israel built on land it seized in the 1967 war as illegal, a view Israel disputes.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>