<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[India FM rebukes Canada over parade float showing assassination of Indira Gandhi]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3223438/india-fm-rebukes-canada-over-parade-float-showing-assassination-indira-gandhi?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 21:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/8ff69238-fe30-4c77-94e2-95e91b0446ac_973511c1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度外交部长周四抨击加拿大允许游行队伍中的花车描绘1984 年印度总理英迪拉·甘地 (Indira Gandhi) 被她的保镖暗杀，这被认为是锡克教分离主义者对暴力的美化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为，给予分离主义者和极端分子的空间存在更大的潜在问题苏杰生 (S. Jaishankar) 在新德里评论游行中的场面时告诉记者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为这对人际关系不利，对加拿大不利，”他说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拿大驻印度高级专员也谴责了锡克教激进分子在加拿大安大略省宾顿市举行的游行中发生的事件。最近几天流传的互联网视频显示了游行的画面，画面中甘地身穿血迹斑斑的白色纱丽，双手高举，而身穿头巾的男子则用枪指着她。幕后的海报上写着：“复仇”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我对加拿大庆祝已故印度总理英迪拉·甘地遇刺事件的报道感到震惊，”卡梅伦·麦凯在 Twitter 上说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“加拿大没有仇恨或美化暴力的容身之地。我坚决谴责这些活动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社未能立即联系到游行的组织者征求意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英迪拉·甘地 (Indira Gandhi) 于 1984 年在允许游行后被两名锡克教保镖暗杀。攻占最神圣的锡克教寺庙，目的是驱逐要求将独立家园称为 Khalistan 的锡克教分离主义者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袭击寺庙激怒了世界各地的锡克教徒。袭击中的死亡人数仍然存在争议，印度当局称死亡人数为数百人，而锡克教团体则为数千人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拿大是印度旁遮普邦以外锡克教徒人口最多的国家。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，印度召见加拿大高级专员，表达对加拿大亲哈利斯坦抗议者破坏印度外交使团和领事馆安全的关切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国之间的双边商业关系值得我们关注根据印度的数据，1000 亿美元，其中包括 700 亿美元的加拿大证券投资。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong vows to tighten curbs on Japanese food imports if radioactive waste water discharged into sea near Fukushima]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3223443/hong-kong-vows-tighten-curbs-japanese-food-imports-if-radioactive-waste-water-discharged-sea-near?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 21:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/40fadaff-57f2-4c5f-8369-027e5036ac19_7aaf1b98.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港环境部长警告说，如果日本正在推进一项有争议的计划，将放射性废水排放到海中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际社会应首先就可能涉及的危险以及日本应采取的下一步行动达成共识，环境与生态部长说谢展云星期四。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“日本政府无视国际社会的强烈关切，执意将放射性废水排入海中，这是不负责任的做法，”谢展云用措辞强硬的措辞说。当地报纸的评论文章。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本要求香港：在限制核废料计划之前权衡数据&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该国最近表示将释放用于冷却熔化核燃料的废水今年夏天，福岛第一核电站流入大海，引发了广泛的食品安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月在核电站所在的港口捕获的一条鱼被发现含有 180 倍于最大限值的放射性物质日本食品安全法允许的元素铯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢说，这一发现证明食品安全问题是“现实中的一个严重问题”，“不仅仅是学术讨论”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，该局已与日本当局、驻香港领事馆和中国外交部驻香港办事处联系，表达其关切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我真诚地希望日本当局不要排放废水并在国际社会达成共识之前不可逆转地危害环境和食品安全，”Tse 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果日本政府对处理过的放射性废水的安全性有信心，他们应该在国内使用它用于灌溉等目的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管在 2018 年取消了一些限制，但该市是 2011 年核灾难后继续限制从该国进口蔬菜和乳制品的 12 个辖区之一。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;据日本政府称，该市是 2022 年日本第二大农渔业出口市场，带来了价值约 123 亿港元（16 亿美元）的商品。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;大多数日本人香港公司热衷于扩展到贸易协定涵盖的地区&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府统计处的数字显示，日本进口食品占香港食品总供应量的 2% 左右，占全部食品供应量的 6.75%当地消费的海鲜来自该国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然香港不依赖日本食品，但它是许多香港人的最爱，而且该市有很多日本餐馆，”谢说。 “当局防范日本食品的安全隐患很重要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去 12 年里，对来自日本的 778,000 多个食品样本进行了检测，没有发现任何食品的辐射水平超标，他说。将对进口食品进行更多检测，包括那些带有日本当局颁发的证明该商品适合消费且辐射水平未超过规定限值的证书的食品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个跨学科工作组将谢说，一旦国家开始排放废水，立即禁止从福岛和附近的高风险县进口水产品。其他地区被认为有风险的货物也将受到严格限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府还将与食品进口和餐饮业以及公众保持密切联系，提供最新情况&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港日本食品及厨艺协会创会主席黄杰龙表示，业界预计原产于该国东海岸的海鲜产品将被禁止至少半年计划的废水排放量。该禁令可能会覆盖从岩手县一直到千叶县的五个县。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 Wong 表示，他认为对当地餐饮业的影响将是有限的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说进口商可能会避免从福岛以北的宫城县和岩手县等主要供应区采购。他预测，即使没有全面禁令，此类举措也会持续下去，因为可能长达数周的检测制度将直接影响海鲜的质量。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本领事馆告诉香港，提防扒手nationals&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“但是还有很多选择，比如青森、北海道和关西。广岛的生蚝也非常有名……而且不会产生太多额外成本。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，许多业者也在缩短订货周期，从一年缩短至一个月，甚至更短， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果政府在实施限制和监控时能够采取有针对性和科学的方法，那么对整个行业来说都是好事，因为顾客无需担心在这里食用不安全的海鲜，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邮报已联系日本领事馆征求意见。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: China’s semiconductor equipment purchases slump as US and allies boost domestic chip production, data shows]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3223431/tech-war-chinas-semiconductor-equipment-purchases-slump-us-and-allies-boost-domestic-chip-production?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/cbb5ab0c-a9aa-4996-a3fe-1e834551c821_929d43ad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;今年前三个月，对中国的半导体设备销售额大幅下降与同期对北美和全球市场的出货量增加形成鲜明对比的是，世界第二大经济体正在努力应对华盛顿及其盟友施加的更严格的贸易限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 3 月份的季度中，芯片的销售-全球行业协会 SEMI 周二发布的数据显示，为中国公司制造设备的销售额同比下降 23%，比前三个月下降 8%，至 58.6 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管下降，中国仍然是世界第二大半导体设备市场，仅次于台湾，领先于韩国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，2022 年第一季度对中国的半导体设备销售额同比增长 27% SEMI 数据显示，同比增至 76 亿美元。当时，中国是全球最大的半导体设备市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在拜登政府去年 10 月扩大贸易限制的情况下，中国公司被禁止从美国购买先进的芯片制造工具，除非获得特殊待遇允许。日本将于 7 月实施类似的出口限制，以限制 23 种先进芯片相关设备和材料的销售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而中国公司一直在争相抢在日本之前储备芯片制造设备根据中国海关早些时候公布的数据，由于荷兰的禁令和潜在限制，该国近几个月从主要供应国进口的半导体设备有所下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1 月至 4 月，中国购买了 10.5 亿美元来自美国的芯片制造和其他机器的价值，比去年同期下降了近 50%。其中包括用于制造晶圆、半导体设备、集成电路或平板显示器的工具。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前中国最大的半导体设备供应商日本的出货量下降 12% 至 35 亿美元，而来自日本的出货量下降 12%台湾和韩国同期下降了大约一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;获得重要设备的困难影响了中国最大的芯片制造商中芯国际公司，该公司在 2 月份警告说，其位于北京的新工厂将无法进行大规模生产由于采购方面的挑战，可能会推迟一到两个季度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司在今年前三个月的物业、厂房和设备投资较上一季度下降了约三分之一，其财务报表&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然中国进口的芯片设备一直在减少，但随着美国和日本等国家宣布计划促进国内半导体制造，世界其他地区出现了相反的趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;2023 年第一季度，全球芯片设备销售额同比增长 9% 至 268 亿美元，其中增幅最大的是北美，根据 SEMI 数据，该地区的销售额增长了约 50%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在台湾，世界上大部分最先进的半导体都在这里生产，尽管比上一季度下降了 13%，但销售额同比增长了 42%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对欧洲的销售额上升第一季度为 19%。主要芯片设计商 Arm 的所在地英国等国家/地区一直在推动提高半导体供应链的安全性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管宏观经济逆风和充满挑战的行业环境，第一季度半导体设备收入依然强劲”，SEMI 总裁兼首席执行官 Ajit Manocha 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“支持 [人工智能]、汽车和其他增长应用的重大技术进步所需的长期战略投资的基本面仍然健康。”&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s state banks cut deposit rates to bolster economy, but officials at Lujiazui Forum remain tight-lipped]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3223402/chinas-state-banks-cut-deposit-rates-bolster-economy-officials-lujiazui-forum-remain-tight-lipped?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/1dd47602-c1d2-44e7-b8ad-c20291de9dcb_cec57cef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国五大国有银行今年首次下调存款利率周四，市场预计指标将进一步疲软，并呼吁出台更多政策来解决经济困境，但高级金融官员在重要论坛开幕日几乎没有提供任何线索。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，官员们表示中国经济正在在上海举行的为期两天的陆家嘴论坛开幕式上，有弹性和正在改善——北京经常使用这些词来淡化强有力的刺激措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，市场参与者正在讨论央行可能下调政策利率&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国工商银行、中国银行和交通银行等五家主要银行联手降息。周四，经常账户存款利率上调 5 个基点至 0.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国 5 月份贸易数据的 4 个要点是出口下滑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他们还降低了三年期和五年期存款利率分别上调 15 个基点至 2.45% 和 2.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新一轮的存款利率下调，以及迅速恶化的出口、扩大的房地产困境、持续的通货紧缩以及可能的[美国联邦储备委员会]暂停[加息]，提高我们对降息呼吁的信心，”日本投资银行野村证券表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多机构警告说，世界第二大经济体现在正在复工后的内需无法抵消海外订单下降、地方债务危机迫在眉睫，同时还面临通缩风险和投资者信心动荡的十字路口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领先投行中信证券的经济学家也表示提出自8月以来首次可能降息的问题，称中国已经进入经济企稳的重要窗口期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陆家嘴论坛是感受北京年中评价的重要平台7月下旬中央政治局季度会议上，新任国家金融监督管理总局局长李云泽在论坛上表示，当前的经济和金融状况，他们的政策意图和计划中的任何大转弯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，中国经济发展持续回升向好，市场需求稳步回升，积极因素持续增多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“关键是恢复和扩大有效需求，我们将继续改善金融服务，”今年 5 月被任命为新金融监管机构党组书记的李克强说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他简要提到了为新能源汽车、绿色家电、城中村改造等提供更多融资支持重点关注金融风险防范。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国新监管机构誓言“筑起金融安全的铁墙”&lt;/h3>; p>;与此同时，中国人民银行行长易纲在周四的论坛上将他的整个演讲都集中在绿色金融和中国的碳中和目标上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;易纲在任期间没有使用大规模刺激措施自 2018 年以来，在今年早些时候表现出不愿下调政策利率——包括一年期中期借贷便利 (MLF)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的主要货币政策参数保持在合理水平，而且实际利率水平也是合适的，”他在 3 月表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国央行在 3 月下旬将商业银行的存款准备金率下调 25 个基点，注入 5000 亿元人民币（70.2 美元）亿美元）的资金在降低银行必须持有的现金储备后流入市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，中国的经济状况和投资者情绪在 4 月和 5 月迅速减弱，引发了人们对冠状病毒后复苏的担忧正在失去动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在本周发布的另一系列令人失望的数据中，5 月份出口同比下降 7.5%，与 4 月份的增长相反。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方制造业采购经理人指数上月也跌至 48.8 的五个月低点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们普遍认为，中国拥有许多资源和工具来应对其经济问题，包括需求不足和地方债务危机，而且它是由于 2022 年的比较基数较低，中国被视为能够实现今年 5% 左右的国内生产总值增长目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的消费者、工厂通货膨胀问题增强了对支持的“巨大需求” &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与受高通胀束缚的西方同行不同，中国货币当局面临的约束较少，因为 4 月份的消费者价格指数仅增长 0.1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中央政府还拥有丰富的金融资源，杠杆率远低于发达国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约 2000 亿元人民币（280 亿美元）的一年期 MLF 将于 6 月 15 日到期，这是一个重要的时机看看政策制定者是否会调整利率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月的贷款最优惠利率将于 6 月 20 日公布，央行在 5 月连续第九个月保持基准贷款利率不变。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Mandy Zuo 的补充&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What next for controversial plan to build public housing on exclusive Hong Kong golf course?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3223435/what-next-controversial-plan-build-public-housing-exclusive-hong-kong-golf-course?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 20:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/199a0079-7818-42b5-a9e2-b883539121ed_5e4e9b9b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一项有争议的计划，即在专属高尔夫球场的一部分建造数千套公共住房公寓在香港政府周一表示将修改计划并将该地块的拟议用途从“住宅”暂时更改为“未定”后，该地块重新成为人们关注的焦点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府此举引发了人们对它是否会将继续实施该计划，以解决该市长期存在的住房短缺问题，而香港高尔夫球会和来自不同行业的重量级人物正在加紧努力，以挽救占地 172 公顷的粉岭球场的指定部分，使其免于重建。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;邮报审查了提案的曲折。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;1.计划是什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该计划是五年前由现已解散的土地供应专责小组提出的中短期提案之一，该小组就解决土地供应短缺问题展开了长达数月的公开辩论时任行政长官林郑月娥任期内的房屋用地。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;锦标赛不会扰乱香港高尔夫球场的房屋计划：官员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;林郑月娥去年 6 月任期届满前，政府制定计划，在粉岭兴建占地 32 公顷的老球场，并由高尔夫球会归还土地。该计划涉及一块 9.5 公顷的土地，预计到 2029 年为约 33,600 人建造 12,000 个公共住房单位，其余区域保留用于休闲和保育用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;独家香港高尔夫球会，将返回Old Course于9月向政府提出强烈反对该计划。它说该市最古老的高尔夫球场的生态将受到破坏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治家、商人和住房顾问都支持该俱乐部。香港最高决策行政会议召集人、俱乐部成员叶刘淑仪此前曾敦促政府放弃该计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2．最新进展如何？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府周一表示，将暂时将这块 9.5 公顷用地的拟议用途从“住宅”改为“未定”，以争取时间调整房屋布局和密度，因为&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环境保护署上个月批准了该计划，条件是根据环境咨询委员会的建议，将其视觉影响降至最低，并保留了 0.4 公顷的林地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;顾问们在 8 月份的前一次会议上未能达成共识后于上个月提出了他们的建议，当时该会议应该做出决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，高尔夫俱乐部正在继续努力挽救旧的Course，透露它正在争取明年举办沙特阿拉伯支持的 LIV 高尔夫联赛，并表示它可以充当中国和中东之间的桥梁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当它返回土地归政府后，高尔夫俱乐部仍将拥有两个完整的 18 洞球场以及第三个球场的 10 洞球场。但它在周一表示，老球场曾被用于停放和存放过去赛事的设备，并警告说，如果该计划继续进行，香港未来可能会输掉一些备受瞩目的比赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政会议召集人叶周三敦促政府审查如何使用土地及其收回土地的决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;3.高尔夫球场上会建住宅吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周三，开发主管 Bernadette Linn Hon-ho 表示，在该地区建造公共住房的意图“没有改变”，但公寓数量可能会减少。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“审查后能否维持12000的建设量，我觉得客观条件在告诉我们，我们可能做不到。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “如果我今天空口承诺无论如何都能达标，那就等于说我不需要关注环评程序对我们提出的要求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;政府表示，将力争在 2031 年之前为居民提供住房，比拟定目标晚了两年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Linn 还表示，农村机构乡议局提出的一项类似规模项目的提案没有“替代”高尔夫球场计划，并指出建议的地点是分散的私人所有权，并且没有道路通行。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港农村团体提议在有争议的高尔夫俱乐部地点附近进行住房计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周二，农村领导人建议在坪岗村建造 12,000 套公共住房，该村有废弃的农田和一些毗邻高尔夫球场的寮屋。如果政府收回土地，土地所有者将获得补偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;4.关注点是什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;关注土地问题的非政府组织Liber Research Community的成员Brian Wong Shiu-hung表示，政府的最新举动给公众留下了负面印象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“五年前的土地辩论期间就高尔夫球场住房项目达成了共识……这让人质疑政府是否还会实施该计划，”Wong 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社区组织协会服务于弱势群体的非政府组织 ，表示，截至 3 月，公屋的平均轮候时间为 5.3 年，政府实施该项目的速度太慢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这对那些等待的人产生了巨大影响用于公共住房，”Sze 说。 “每个项目都会遭到反对。这是否意味着我们放弃了所有这些？”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;开发香港农田“无法替代”在高尔夫球场上建造房屋&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;5.接下来会发生什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;评估土地申请的法定机构城市规划委员会将于本月就整体重建计划举行五次公开听证会，从周一开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高尔夫球俱乐部代表、商界重量级人物和关注住房的团体预计将出席并发表意见，而委员会早些时候收到了 6,500 多份反对住房提案的回复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管拟议的土地用途发生了变化，但委员会仍然最迟要在11月底前就高尔夫球场的整体重建计划作出决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;之后，政府将开始修改提案，并在年底前向环保部门提交新的计划明年。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Beijing calls on US to let Hong Kong leader John Lee attend San Francisco Apec meeting in November]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3223426/beijing-calls-us-let-hong-kong-leader-john-lee-attend-san-francisco-apec-meeting-november?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 19:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/c83bd0a7-ef48-4361-8f94-2ebb729cda01_09f8dd53.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京呼吁华盛顿履行其作为亚太地区东道主的义务今年晚些时候举行首脑会议，并允许香港特首李家超出席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在两党美国国会议员呼吁拜登政府禁止李家超进入香港后，中国外交部周四发表讲话国家参加 11 月在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 论坛活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国会议员早些时候表示，李光耀是“受到制裁的侵犯人权者”，他出席会议将是“侮辱所有受到中国共产党和中华人民共和国及其在香港的代理人迫害的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但外交部发言人王文斌表示，APEC 有自己的内部规则，东道国有责任确保所有成员都能出席会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，美国已承诺履行东道主义务，遵守 Apec 规则并帮助成员出席会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们相信美国会履行义务，并确保包括中国香港在内的所有 Apec 成员都能顺利参加会议，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港于 1991 年加入 Apec，并继续参与在 1997 年香港回归中国统治后作为独立的正式成员以“中国香港”的名义参加会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港由行政长官代表参加该组织的经济领导人会议&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在北京对香港实施国家安全法后，李是 2020 年华盛顿制裁的中国官员之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国声称该立法破坏了香港的自治并限制了其人民的自由和权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国必须“按照惯例行事”，邀请香港参加亚太经合组织：李&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;上个月，当被问及是否会参加旧金山峰会时，李将球交给了组织者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说华盛顿有责任“按照惯例行事”并邀请 Apec 成员.政府消息人士还表示，他们希望在 11 月之前取消限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务院发言人在 5 月份表示，该活动的邀请尚未最终敲定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘兆佳北京半官方智库中国港澳研究会的一名顾问表示，华盛顿可以考虑向李光耀发放单次入境签证，以便他参加会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他说美国内部政治可能会使 Apec 峰会的处理方式复杂化，因为民主党的乔·拜登面临 2024 年的总统大选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“正在寻求连任的乔·拜登可能会被批评对中国过于软弱或香港，如果他做出太多让步，”刘解释道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港高级官员将在 3 年内首次访问美国和英国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他补充说，这次禁令是由一个两党团体发出的，而不仅仅是反对党共和党成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但香港或北京是否会接受一次性签证的安排是另一回事， ”最近被任命为香港政府政策专家顾问的刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他强调了华盛顿最近试图安排美国和中国国防部长在新加坡举行的会议——但遭到拒绝&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北京只是简单地说‘不’。对中南海领导来说，这是原则问题。你不能随心所欲地制裁我，然后要求我提出暂时解除制裁与你交谈，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;商务及经济发展局局长邱英华上个月出席了一个亚太经合组织部长们在底特律举行会议，谈到了促进该地区可持续和包容性贸易的必要性。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China to draw up AI regulation in 2023 as Beijing races against EU, US to roll out new laws covering the technology]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3223429/china-draw-ai-regulation-2023-beijing-races-against-eu-us-roll-out-new-laws-covering-technology?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 19:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/df9733ae-7cb9-4670-91e0-1a5c835a3e9e_2f8148ad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国有望准备好人工智能 (AI) 法草案随着 ChatGPT 的快速发展，随着北京率先推出针对这项技术的新法规，中国立法者将在今年内进行审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国务院 2023 年立法计划，中国内阁，根据本周全国人民代表大会 (NPC) 常务委员会发布的一份文件，包括提交人工智能法草案在内的 50 多项措施将提交全国人民代表大会 (NPC) 常务委员会审议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;常务委员会据全国人大网站称，全国人大的常设机构，中国的国家立法机关，在将一项措施付诸表决之前，“正常情况下”将对新法律草案进行三次审议。它表示，如果仍有“需要进一步研究的重大问题”，这一过程可能会延长并需要进行更多审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了人工智能法（其细节尚未公布）外，国务院还在努力涉及电信、互联网数据安全、无人机和对外贸易法修正案的新措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国政府的立法计划反映了世界各地迫切需要建立一个强大的法律基础设施，以遏制快速发展ChatGPT 等生成式 AI 服务的开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦肯锡咨询公司称，生成式 AI 描述了可用于创建新内容（包括音频、代码、图像、文本、模拟和视频）的算法。该领域最近的突破有可能彻底改变人们处理内容创作的方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“生成式 AI 彻底改变了游戏规则，”欧洲竞争事务专员玛格丽特·维斯塔格 (Margrethe Vestager) 本月早些时候在欧盟 (EU) 和美国之间的第四次贸易和技术委员会会议。她表示，欧盟和美国将在未来几周内为该技术制定一份“行为准则”草案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，欧洲议会的一个重要委员会批准了欧洲人工智能法案。欧盟 27 国的人工智能法有望成为事实上的全球标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国和欧盟为人工智能和其他新技术制定规则，但在中国威胁问题上存在分歧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;4 月，互联网监管机构中国国家互联网信息办公室 (CAC) 公布了一套针对类似 ChatGPT 服务的新规则草案。 It would require developers to pass a security assessment before launching their services to the public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those businesses should also make sure that their products uphold Chinese socialist values, and do not generate content that suggests regime subversion, violence or pornography, or disrupts economic or social order, according to the CAC. Its draft rules, which completed soliciting public opinion in May, has yet to be implemented.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On a smaller scale, tech hub Shenzhen in southern Guangdong province passed China&#39;s first local government regulation focused on boosting AI development in September last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That regulation, which went into effect in November, requires the government to establish an AI ethics committee that will draw up safety guidelines and research the technology&#39;s impact on data protection, employment and other social issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Existential risk&#39;: OpenAI CEO suggests global agency could oversee AI&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s efforts to address the latest AI developments even received the attention of Tesla chief executive Elon Musk during his recent visit to China. On his meeting with senior leadership, Musk said they “had some very productive discussions on artificial intelligence risks, and the need for some oversight and regulation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT took the world by storm upon its release in November, a number of Chinese tech companies soon launched their own generative AI products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Online search provider Baidu, e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding, AI firm SenseTime and voice recognition developer iFlytek have each introduced their own alternative domestic services to ChatGPT, which took the world by storm after its launch in November. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Block all overseas calls: police in multiple Chinese cities issue ‘urgent reminder’ as anti-fraud drive scaled up]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3223390/block-all-overseas-calls-police-multiple-chinese-cities-issue-urgent-reminder-anti-fraud-drive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/08/4ae2d42c-58e6-44ae-bc2e-ec7c0fddc8b0_6562d1e6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Police in at least three provinces in China have called on residents to block all incoming overseas calls if they did not have regular contacts outside the mainland, saying this will protect them from telecoms fraud.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Online messages posted over the weekend by police in Xuzhou and Lianyungang in the eastern province of Jiangsu advised residents on ways to turn off the “receive overseas calls” function.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Urgent reminder! Please turn off incoming calls from overseas!” police in both cities said on their official WeChat accounts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The anti-fraud centre of the Public Security Bureau reminds you that if you do not need to receive incoming overseas calls, you can take the initiative to turn off the function to reduce the risk of being scammed and protect your money!” the posts added, referring to the bureau representing the main civilian police force in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The same notice was issued earlier last week by police in Sanming, in the southeastern coastal province of Fujian.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police in Weifang, in eastern Shandong province, reposted a Ministry of Public Security instructional video on battling telecoms scams, as part of a similar anti-fraud warning late last month on their official account on Weibo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They then described in detail how customers of the country&#39;s three major telecoms operators – China Mobile, China Unicom and China Telecom – could stop receiving calls from abroad. A service to automatically block all incoming overseas calls was launched by the three carriers last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The flurry of public appeals is part of China&#39;s campaign to combat rampant online fraud, by systemically scaling down mobile users&#39; exposure to communication means the authorities find hard to police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A new law to tackle growing telecoms and online fraud that came into force in December gives enforcement agencies the power to hunt down suspects overseas, and makes it mandatory for telecoms firms and banks to help hunt down fraudsters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And late last month, police in multiple Chinese cities urged parents to delete encrypted messaging apps from their children&#39;s smartphones to prevent their becoming an “accomplice” to fraud.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apps to be guarded against included the home-grown Seagull, Shimida and Miliaomao, as well as foreign ones such as Telegram, WhatsApp and Twitter – which are blocked in China and can be accessed only via a virtual private network.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the authorities&#39; high-handed approach to tackling telecoms fraud has also raised questions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An anti-fraud app rolled out nationwide in March 2021 sparked public complaints about forced installation and data privacy breaches.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s top app download is developed by police, stoking privacy concerns&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The “National Anti-Fraud Centre” app was developed by the public security ministry and the computer emergency response team under the Cyberspace Administration of China – the country&#39;s top internet regulator. Authorities say it is designed to warn users of any calls, text messages or installed apps suspected of being associated with fraudulent activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China should “win a new victory in the people&#39;s war against fraud”, Wang Xiaohong, the minister of public security, told officials at a meeting on combating telecoms fraud on May 30.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should further intensify our efforts to resolutely break the arrogance of criminals and ensure that the trend of a high incidence of telecoms and online fraud crimes is effectively contained,” Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the latest figures released by the ministry, 464,000 cases of telecoms fraud were solved nationwide last year, up 5 per cent from 2021.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South China Sea: Asean to hold first joint military drills amid rising China tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223411/south-china-sea-asean-hold-first-joint-military-drills-amid-rising-china-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 19:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/08/00a16daf-26bb-4533-b482-65686f05071c_83abe94d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Southeast Asian bloc Asean will hold its first-ever joint military exercise in the South China Sea, its chair Indonesia said on Thursday, the latest multilateral security drills at a time of rising tension and uncertainty in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision was taken at a meeting of military commanders of the 10-member Association of Southeast Asian Nations (Asean) in Indonesia, which will host the exercise in the North Natuna Sea, the southernmost waters of the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia&#39;s military chief, Admiral Yudo Margono, told state-run news agency Antara the exercise would be in September and would not include any combat operations training. The purpose, Margono said, was strengthening “Asean centrality”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asean&#39;s unity has for years been tested by a rivalry between the United States and China that is being played out in the South China Sea. Asean members Vietnam, the Philippines, Brunei and Malaysia have competing claims with Beijing, which asserts sovereignty over vast stretches of ocean that include parts of Indonesia&#39;s exclusive economic zone (EEZ).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesian military spokesperson Julius Widjojono said the exercise was related to the “high risk of disaster in Asia, especially Southeast Asia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A conduit for about US$3.5 trillion of annual ship-borne trade, the South China Sea has seen constant tension of late as China presses its claims with a huge deployment of coastguard and fishing boats as far as 1,500km (932 miles) off its coastline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China claims sovereignty via an expansive “nine-dash line” based on its historic maps, which an international arbitration court in 2016 ruled had no legal basis.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia and Vietnam linked by banh mi, beer and shared concerns over China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Asean has been pushing for a long-awaited maritime code of conduct with China to be completed and several of its members have had run-ins with Beijing in recent months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vietnam criticised China&#39;s deployment of a research vessel near several gas blocs in its EEZ, while Beijing was accused of sending suspected maritime militia into waters where navies of India and Asean countries held an exercise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippines chided China&#39;s coastguard for “dangerous manoeuvres” and “aggressive tactics” and plans to hold joint patrols with the United States, on top of an inaugural trilateral coastguard exercise they held with Japan this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China maintains its coastguard is performing regular operations in what is Chinese sovereign territory.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Web3 firm Animoca’s bet on non-US markets offers buffer from SEC’s labelling of Sand token as security]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3223414/hong-kong-web3-firm-animocas-bet-non-us-markets-offers-buffer-secs-labelling-sand-token-security?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 18:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/08/5e6070e1-075c-4300-a317-a210fd4ca3df_09e29b8f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong-based blockchain unicorn Animoca Brands said it is focusing more on markets outside the US after the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) labelled the firm&#39;s Sand cryptocurrency token an unregistered security in lawsuits against the exchanges Binance and Coinbase Global.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sand is the native crypto token used by Animoca&#39;s metaverse platform The Sandbox, and it was one of more than a dozen such tokens to have been explicitly named by the SEC as securities, with others including Solana, Polygon and Mana, the token used in the Decentraland virtual world. The SEC action raises legal risks for any companies selling these tokens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Animoca Brands is not focused on a single territory but operates globally,” company co-founder and chairman Yat Siu said via email. “The SEC focuses on the US, so that should not have an impact on Animoca Brands in broader markets where Sand is widely available and accepted, including in more progressive jurisdictions like Hong Kong and Japan.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Animoca has already “started to take steps to place more emphasis on other markets”, Siu added, because of the recent “blockchain-hostile” approach in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The Sandbox gears up for new growth amid fizzling metaverse hype&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong has said that Coinbase has no plans to delist the tokens named by the SEC, setting it up for a legal fight over what types of crypto constitute a security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the move can have a chilling effect for other exchanges that are not so invested in selling those tokens. Dan Gallagher, chief legal compliance and corporate affairs officer for US brokerage Robinhood Markets, told a congressional committee this week that the company could not simply list tokens through its registered broker, in part because of rules regarding “issuer disclosure”, since many crypto tokens are created by organisations outside the US that do not follow SEC rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are actively reviewing the SEC analysis to determine what, if any, actions to take” regarding Robinhood&#39;s current crypto offerings, Gallagher said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In August last year, Binance.US said that it would delist a token called Amp “out of an abundance of caution” after the SEC identified it as an unregistered security in a separate lawsuit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the heart of the issue for the SEC is whether a token was used for fundraising and buyers expected a return on their investments. The SEC complaints against Binance and Coinbase say Sand purportedly raised US$3 million through private sales on Binance.com and that holders were led “reasonably to view Sand as an investment in and to expect to profit from [the company&#39;s] efforts to grow the Sandbox protocol”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Labelling cryptoassets as securities is a strategy for the SEC that “supports their enforcement proposition against those exchanges”, and is “not particularly fatal” to their operators because there has yet to be a judgment from the legal proceedings, said Pádraig Walsh, a partner at Tanner De Witt in Hong Kong. But the allegations do raise the legal risk for firms in the US, he noted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What it does constitute is a public statement in public enforcement proceedings that a regulator in a particular jurisdiction believes that the tokens may be securities,” Walsh said. “So that would attract a degree of legal risk.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since it could take years to get a definitive judgment from these cases, a more imminent consequence might be that crypto firms continue to move away from the US because it is perceived as “too uncertain”, Walsh added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Sandbox&#39;s co-founder and chief operating officer Sabastien Borget told crypto-focused outlet Decrypt on Thursday that the SEC&#39;s claim does not change the platform&#39;s business “on a day-to-day basis”, and that the company does not “necessarily agree with the characterisation” that its token is a security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other companies targeted by the SEC have also sought to continue their growth outside the US. Ripple, which the SEC sued in 2020 in a case over its XRP token that is still ongoing, has mainly been expanding in Asia, according to Brooks Entwistle, APAC managing director and senior vice-president of global customer success at the blockchain firm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The result is we are building our business outside the US,” Entwistle said in an interview with the Post on May 24. “We have added the majority of our people in the last period of time outside the US, the majority of our businesses outside the US, and … the bulk of that is in this dynamic Asia region.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Animoca, which is based in Hong Kong, announced in March that it was planning a major push into the Middle East, looking to put “significant investment” valued “in the tens of millions of dollars” into the region.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia, Indonesia unite to fight ‘discriminatory’ EU over palm oil curbs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3223401/malaysia-indonesia-unite-fight-discriminatory-eu-over-palm-oil-curbs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 18:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/08/c731f9ef-33d1-41d5-a3de-80c4132b8959_f101b5d9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The leaders of Malaysia and Indonesia, the world&#39;s two largest producers of palm oil, pledged on Thursday to work together to force the European Union to rollback “discriminatory” forest protection measures that could hit exports of the lucrative commodity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two Southeast Asian nations have so far acted separately to address a raft of regulations implemented by the EU that they claim impose unfair conditions on supply chains of palm oil, the world&#39;s most widely consumed vegetable oil.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Malaysia and Indonesia account for more than 80 per cent of the world&#39;s total palm-oil exports, which can be found in everything from pastries to cosmetics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a joint statement, Malaysia&#39;s Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim and Indonesian President Joko “Jokowi” Widodo said both countries will cooperate closely to address “highly detrimental discriminatory measures” imposed on palm oil following the introduction of the European Union Deforestation Regulation (EUDR).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The EU needs to promptly address such discriminatory measures and work towards a fair and equitable resolution,” said the statement, issued after the two leaders held a meeting during Jokowi&#39;s first official visit to Malaysia since 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, the European parliament approved the EUDR, a landmark deforestation law that will ban the import of goods if they are found to be linked to the destruction of forests in their country of origin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aimed at eliminating deforestation from the EU&#39;s supply chains, the law will require companies selling goods to the bloc to produce a due diligence statement and verifiable information to prove that the products were not grown on land that had been deforested after 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Besides palm oil, the law will also apply to soy, beef, wood, cocoa, coffee, rubber, charcoal and derivative products such as leather, chocolate and furniture, according to a Reuters report.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Malaysia has described the new law as “unjust” and an attempt to protect the EU&#39;s domestic oilseeds market, which cannot compete with palm oil, and that it would have an adverse effect on small-scale farmers who would be unable to meet compliance costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EU policymakers have denied these claims, saying the rules apply to all commodities produced anywhere in the world and that the EU market remains open to sustainably produced palm oil.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, Malaysia and Indonesia made their case in a joint-trade mission to Brussels where they met with top EU officials to raise their concerns over the new law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both nations also suspended trade talks with the EU pending negotiations for fairer treatment of palm oil smallholders affected by the EUDR, the Financial Times reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EUDR is only the latest issue to affect ties between the EU and the world&#39;s top two palm-oil producers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, Indonesia filed a lawsuit with the World Trade Organization, calling out the EU for unfair trade practices in its decision to stop the use of palm oil-based biodiesel. Malaysia filed a separate challenge with the WTO in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Anwar and Jokowi also discussed measures to protect the rights of Indonesian citizens working in Malaysia, with both leaders agreeing to establish a mechanism “to address all issues pertaining to all migrant workers in a comprehensive manner”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia is a key source of labour for Malaysia, where foreign workers are typically hired in the tens of thousands to pick oil palm fruit in large commercial plantations and to staff factories, and also as domestic helpers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, Indonesia briefly stopped allowing its nationals to take up work in Malaysia following a dispute over the system used to recruit Indonesian domestic workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can Malaysia afford to ban all palm oil exports to the EU?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Malaysia&#39;s government said at the time that numerous cases of abuse suffered by Indonesian domestic workers at the hands of their Malaysian employers was a major reason behind the temporary ban.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia is Malaysia&#39;s sixth-largest trade partner, with 130.14 billion ringgit (US$28.4 billion) of total trade done by the two regional neighbours last year, according to Malaysian government data.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>