<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Putin seeks to project business-as-usual image as Wagner mutiny questions linger]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225998/putin-seeks-project-business-usual-image-wagner-mutiny-questions-linger?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 23:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/2f9ea318-f646-4a49-80c1-60849b628c6c_54f2eef9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;弗拉基米尔·普京总统继续努力重申其权威，并表现出一切如常的感觉瓦格纳雇佣兵的叛变威胁到了他在俄罗斯近四分之一个世纪的统治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京定于周四在莫斯科举行的一个名为“新时代的强创意”的论坛上发表讲话，该论坛是一年一度的活动，其在瓦格纳领导人叶夫根尼·普里戈任的军队在距首都 200 公里（124 英里）范围内发动叛乱后，这个头衔具有了意想不到的象征意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的评论将受到密切关注，以了解是否涉及最近发生的事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;总统连夜从俄罗斯南部达吉斯坦共和国返回莫斯科，在那里他与地区官员就促进旅游业发展进行了会谈。尽管一名官员感谢普京“在如此困难的时刻”到访，但并未提及周六的叛变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不同寻常的是，国家电视台显示普京与欢呼的当地居民混在一起，甚至亲吻了一名年轻女孩的头部并摆出姿势与她合影。这与克里姆林宫长期以来对任何与普京会面的人实行严格的Covid-19隔离制度形成鲜明对比，以避免这位70岁的领导人可能受到感染。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管努力描绘叛变危机截至最后，关于军队和安全部门内部人员在多大程度上了解普里戈任计划进军莫斯科推翻国防部高级官员的问题仍然悬而未决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦格纳的全副武装的部队首先控制了俄罗斯南部城市顿河畔罗斯托夫，然后跨越780公里领土迅速向莫斯科进军，沿途封锁了军队部队，没有遇到重大抵抗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任只是叫停了前进在接受白俄罗斯总统亚历山大·卢卡申科斡旋的一项协议后，在对瓦格纳创始人或其战士的刑事指控被撤销后，他可以前往邻国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;令人眼花缭乱的一系列事件已经离开了美国、欧洲中国对一场叛乱造成的政治后果感到困惑，这场叛乱粉碎了普京作为俄罗斯领导人的不可战胜的形象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这场危机凸显了俄罗斯内部因乌克兰战争而存在的激烈分歧，乌克兰战争是二战以来欧洲最大的冲突，乌克兰的反攻继续试图将普京的军队赶出被占领土。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US Supreme Court curbs affirmative action in university admissions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225996/us-supreme-court-ends-affirmative-action-university-admissions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 22:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/7912c8bb-5ee9-489a-b92f-f09949a1fe1e_f0dbb69b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国最高法院周四驳回了哈佛大学具有种族意识的学生招生计划和北卡罗来纳大学的平权行动政策遭受了严重挫折，这些政策通常用于增加校园中黑人、西班牙裔和其他代表性不足的少数群体的数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官做出了有利于一个名为“由反平权行动活动家爱德华·布鲁姆 (Edward Blum) 创立的“学生公平招生”组织，对下级法院维持两所著名学校为培养多元化学生群体而使用的项目的裁决提出上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该决定由法院的保守派法官与持不同意见的自由派法官，以 6 比 3 战胜北卡罗来纳大学，以 6 比 2 战胜哈佛大学。自由派法官 Ketanji Brown Jackson 没有参与哈佛案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在去年同样由保守派法官牵头的重大裁决中，法院推翻了 1973 年罗伊诉韦德案的裁决，该裁决使堕胎在全国范围内合法化并扩大了枪支范围两项具有里程碑意义的裁决中的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首席大法官约翰·罗伯茨（John Roberts）代表多数派撰文表示，“哈佛和北卡罗来纳大学的招生计划无法与平等保护条款的保证相一致”，他指的是美国宪法的承诺法律下的平等保护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与此同时，”罗伯茨说，“正如各方都同意的那样，本意见中的任何内容均不应被解释为禁止大学考虑申请人关于种族如何影响的讨论布鲁姆的团队在 2014 年提起的诉讼中指控北卡罗来纳大学歧视白人和亚裔美国申请者，以及哈佛大学对亚裔美国申请者存在偏见。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学生公平招生组织声称，公立大学北卡罗来纳大学采取的非种族中立的招生政策违反了宪法第十四修正案对法律平等保护的保证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;该组织认为哈佛大学是一所私立大学，违反了具有里程碑意义的联邦法律《1964 年民权法案》第六章，该法案禁止在接受联邦财政援助的任何计划或活动中基于种族、肤色或国籍的歧视。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;许多高等教育机构、企业和军队领导人长期以来一直支持校园平权行动，不仅是为了纠正美国生活中的种族不平等和排斥现象，也是为了确保人才库能够为工作场所带来多种观点和美国武装部队军衔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据哈佛大学的数据，大约 40% 的美国学院和大学以某种方式考虑种族问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈佛大学和北卡罗来纳大学表示，他们仅将种族问题视为一个因素考虑到对无配额录取的一系列个性化评估（最高法院之前的判例是允许的），并且限制其考虑将导致代表性不足群体的学生入学率大幅下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国的平权行动大学不公平，尤其是对亚裔美国人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;几十年来一直试图推翻这些政策的批评者认为，这些政策本身就是歧视性的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多美国保守派和共和党民选官员认为无论动机或情况如何，给予某一种族优势都是违宪的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些人提出了不再需要补救性优惠的论点，因为美国已经超越了过去的种族主义政策，例如种族隔离和变得越来越多样化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这场纠纷为最高法院的保守派多数派提供了推翻其先前允许种族意识招生政策的裁决的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下级法院驳回了该组织的主张，引发了上诉向美国最高法院要求法官推翻一个重要先例，即大学可以将种族作为招生过程中的一个因素，因为创建多元化的学生群体具有迫切的兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“没有解决这个问题问题：马来西亚的土著政策，五十年来&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;平权行动几十年来经受住了最高法院的审查，最近一次是在 2016 年一项涉及一名白人学生的裁决中，该裁决得到了布鲁姆的支持，布鲁姆在被起诉后起诉了德克萨斯大学&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最高法院自 2016 年以来向右转，现在包括对德克萨斯大学案件持异议的三名法官以及前共和党总统唐纳德·特朗普任命的三名新法官。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 23:20:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU leaders debate Russia mutiny, pledge support for Ukraine]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225995/eu-leaders-debate-russia-mutiny-pledge-support-ukraine?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 22:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/2ec92234-ecbd-47f6-bd3e-64c53e263ac3_52cff515.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧盟领导人周四齐聚一堂，讨论俄罗斯流产的兵变，并讨论其角色欧盟可以履行西方加强乌克兰安全的长期承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领导人在抵达布鲁塞尔参加峰会时表示，他们仍然致力于支持乌克兰应对去年 2 月俄罗斯入侵其邻国引发的战争德国总理奥拉夫·肖尔茨 (Olaf Scholz) 对记者表示：“我们必须做好准备，这种情况会持续很长时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“重要的是，我们要进行磋商并表示我们正在准备长期坚持下去，提供乌克兰所必需的财政和人道主义支持，而且在武器方面也是如此。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北约秘书长延斯·斯托尔滕贝格与领导人共进工作午餐并预计乌克兰总统泽连斯基也将通过视频连线在峰会上发表讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为期两天的峰会是欧盟 27 国领导人的定期聚会，议题包括移民、经济安全和关系等一系列议题与中国的一切都提上了议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但主要话题是乌克兰战争，领导人还讨论了上周末瓦格纳雇佣军组织流产的叛变可能如何影响俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领导人表示，他们将密切关注瓦格纳领导人叶夫根尼·普里戈任被流放的白俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些人还表示，兵变削弱了普京的实力，但这并不意味着西方可以放松。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“普京的削弱是一个更大的危险，”欧盟外交政策负责人何塞普·博雷尔表示。 “不稳定的俄罗斯也会成为一种风险。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多领导人强调，叛乱是俄罗斯内部事务，无论如何，欧盟都应该继续支持乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着西方国家制定一揽子长期保证措施，向基辅提供武器、装备、弹药、训练和其他军事援助，这种援助也在布鲁塞尔的谈判桌上提出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;峰会结论草案表示欧盟及其成员国已准备好为未来对乌克兰的安全承诺做出贡献，“帮助乌克兰长期保卫自己，威慑侵略行为并抵制破坏稳定的努力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交官们表示，法国 –欧盟发挥更大安全作用的拥护者提出了该文本，称其想法是建立在欧盟举措的基础上，例如为基辅提供军事援助的基金和乌克兰士兵的培训任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但该案文引起了奥地利、爱尔兰、马耳他和塞浦路斯等军事上不结盟的欧盟成员国以及波罗的海国家等跨大西洋合作坚定支持者的担忧，这些国家坚称欧洲安全主要是北约的事务。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯的高级将领在哪里？瓦格纳叛变后谣言四起&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“对于我们作为中立国来说，很明显我们不能提供这样的安全保证。奥地利、爱尔兰、马耳他和塞浦路斯已明确表示反对，”奥地利总理卡尔·内哈默在参加峰会的路上说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们肯定会讨论这个问题，我们会找到可以接受的方案对我们来说也是如此。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括美国、英国、法国和德国在内的国家正在讨论下个月在立陶宛维尔纽斯举行的北约峰会之前为乌克兰提供的可能的安全保证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;荷兰首相马克·吕特表示，欧盟的任何角色仍有待讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须讨论它能走多远，以及是致命还是非致命支持。我们必须考虑到一些欧盟国家不是北约成员国。”吕特说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰：基辅指控当地男子指挥导弹袭击，造成 10 人死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;同时，在有报道称俄罗斯瓦格纳雇佣兵计划转移到邻国白俄罗斯后，波兰计划加强其东部边境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;波兰副总理雅罗斯瓦夫·卡钦斯基周三晚间表示，将增加军装部队和“保护防御工事” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡钦斯基是在政府安全与国防问题委员会特别会议后发表上述评论的。他援引波兰情报称，多达 8,000 名瓦格纳战士可以在白俄罗斯避难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;波兰是欧盟和北约成员国，与白俄罗斯有 418 公里（260 英里）的边界。 2021 年夏末和秋季，边境局势升级，数千人试图非法进入欧盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟指责白俄罗斯领导人亚历山大·卢卡申科将移民从危机地区带到欧盟有组织地对外边界向西方施压。此后，波兰在边境陆地部分安装了 5.5 米高的围栏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任周六暂时占领了俄罗斯南部城市顿河畔罗斯托夫，然后率领他的战士前往莫斯科，瓦格纳首领与莫斯科军事领导层之间长期酝酿的权力斗争升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;距离俄罗斯首都约200公里，武装起义突然中止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢卡申科据称，普里戈任调解了这次叛变，据报道，普里戈任和他的雇佣兵承诺免受俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京的起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据卢卡申科称，普里戈任现在在白俄罗斯。白俄罗斯强人还允许雇佣军战士进入他的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德新社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Global recruitment effort by Hong Kong to ease hospital staffing problems shows healthy results with 20 veteran specialists already signed up]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3225994/global-recruitment-effort-hong-kong-ease-hospital-staffing-problems-shows-healthy-results-20-veteran?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/eca151da-056f-433b-919b-4ce931426a9c_efdc2d8a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;20名专家获批到香港公立医院进行短期交流卫生主管表示，这是一项新的全球人才计划的一部分，旨在帮助缓解城市医生的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次招聘活动是在该市公立医院的医疗保健专业人员继续保持高流动性的情况下进行的。过去一年，超过 450 名护士流失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但医院管理局周四表示，将继续加大全球招聘力度，以解决人员短缺问题，其中包括一项新的全球医疗保健人才计划，该计划已经吸引了20位来自欧洲、东南亚和中国内地的资深专家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构主席范鸿龄解释说，这些专家预计将在城市医院工作一到两年，以加强&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所有来港工作的医生都必须获得医务委员会的有限注册，这将确保”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范补充说，退伍军人不会占用城市医务人员的专科培训名额或晋升机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，医生将获得与同等资质的城市工作人员薪资待遇相同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范透露，截至4月下旬，过去12个月内已有超过2,450名护士加入公立医院，但约有2,900人离开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同期，医生的人员配置情况稍好一些，新增528人，留下449人，增加了79人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;护士的流失率为10.9%，医生的流失率为7.1%，范表示。补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“情况并不理想。虽然我们竭尽全力招募更多医生，但如果失去这么多护士，我们就无法保持平衡。”他承认&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们欢迎政府提出限制护士注册的建议，并会走向海外一旦法案在立法会获得通过，就会立即招募人才。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;作为招聘竞标的一部分，香港向英国医生提供了超过 130 个工作机会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据该提案，未在香港接受过培训的护士无需通过执照考试即可在香港工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们可以进行有限注册工作，这将允许他们在香港担任职位护理学校或护理院，或进行特殊注册，这将使他们能够在公共医疗机构中找到工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局早些时候飞往英国和澳大利亚招募医生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范透露，共有59名来自英国的医生被选中，下半年将加入市医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他早些时候表示，他们之前去英国时收到了超过100份有条件录取通知书。伦敦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范补充说，还有 45 份有条件录取通知书给了澳大利亚医生，当局将很快开始筛选程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医院管理局还推出了低息住房贷款计划去年年底，为了帮助留住合格的员工，目前已收到超过 1,100 份申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;成功的申请者本月获得原则性批准，这意味着他们可以开始找房。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港护理团体将决定新计划资格标准：卫生署署长&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“过半申请来自高流动率职位，申请者平均年龄介乎37岁至42岁 –巅峰时期，”范说。 “这表明该措施在留住人才方面是有效的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在当局工作三年或以上的员工最多可借款600万港元（766,026美元），即其年薪的四倍，最长还款期为20年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范表示，退休年龄从60岁延长至65岁受到好评，明年退休的65名医生和241名护士选择继续留任.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们占计划退休医生的 84%，占护士的 51%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然我们努力在全球范围内招聘人才，但当地员工仍然是我们的核心人员。范说：“我们在海外招聘的人数永远无法与本地工人相比。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“员工的士气也不会受到影响，因为他们是来帮忙的，减轻工作量。” ，不要打扰他们。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Don’t ‘act blindly’ on Taiwan: Beijing should resist US pressure and stay own course, policy influencer says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3225969/dont-act-blindly-taiwan-beijing-should-resist-us-pressure-and-stay-own-course-policy-influencer-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/b3efd15f-261d-4c80-96d7-5fa9c1789bd1_77b7e943.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;面对美国日益加大的压力，北京应避免对台湾盲目行动，前大陆官员、对北京对台政策有影响力的人物孙亚夫表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙亚夫表示，中国大陆在两岸关系上“面临着更加严峻、复杂的挑战和风险”，而且“风口很大” “即使是汹涌的波浪”“仍然很有可能”——这显然是指发生军事冲突的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，他在浙江省东部举行的台湾问题论坛上发表了上述讲话。当天，该演讲发表在海峡两岸研究期刊的社交媒体账户上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙是海峡两岸关系协会的副会长，该协会是北京负责处理两岸关系的半官方组织&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“击落它们”：台湾誓言摧毁“有风险的”中国大陆气球&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该机构成立于 1991 年，作为中国大陆政府在其事务中的非官方代表台北也有一个类似的小组来与北京打交道。这些小组的成立是为了让岛内和大陆能够在没有对方政府官方认可的情况下进行互动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙在 2004 年至 2013 年期间担任大陆台湾事务办公室副主任，并仍然深入参与北京的事务&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在当前反对者被包围、压力增大的情况下，我们既不能着急，也不能盲目行动……我们不能因压力增大而动摇。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“[我们应该]坚持和平统一的方向和努力，同时加强军事斗争准备。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙的讲话为北京的战略战术思维提供了难得的视角。来处理与台北的紧张关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2016 年倾向独立的民进党 (DPP) 的台湾总统蔡英文上台以来，军事紧张局势加剧。孙说，情况变得“在美国利用台湾问题打压中国并在海峡“制造战争气氛”之后，2021年“更加严重”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将这个自治岛屿视为一个必须与台湾重新统一的分裂省份。大陆——必要时使用武力。包括美国在内的大多数国家都不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但华盛顿反对任何使用武力改变现状的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿近年来指责北京加大对台湾的军事压力。台湾并加速统一计划，一些美国官员猜测解放军可能有能力在2027年夺取台湾岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台海局势发生了自建制以来最大的变化” 1979 年中美建交。”孙说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他将此归咎于华盛顿对北京立场的转变——从“可以依赖的力量”转变为“最大的战略力量”。竞争对手”——这是当前紧张局势的根源，也是美国“必须击败中国”的原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，北京和华盛顿在一系列问题上发生了冲突，其中台湾问题是最严重的冲突之一敏感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙中山在讲话中追随北京的官方路线，称美国正在动员亚太地区盟友，对大陆进行“军事胁迫”，并支持民进党“加速推进”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;#MeToo 丑闻动摇了执政党，台湾蔡英文的支持率跌至 4 年来最低&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;孙表示，美国官员频繁访问台湾旨在“煽动战争情绪” ”，并补充说，华盛顿升级了对台湾的军事支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自8月时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台湾以来，北京在台湾附近进行了两轮大型军事演习，并派出战机频繁越过台湾防空识别区（ADIZ）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙说，大陆坚持和平统一是最好的，“在别无选择的情况下，使用武力是最后的手段”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京于2005年出台了《反分裂国家法》，为其使用非和平手段防范台独势力以及台湾可能与中国大陆分离建立了法律框架。但北京对于何时以及在何种情况下援引该法律仍含糊其辞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙呼吁北京主动反对外国干涉，并指出美国及其盟国“已经挑战了这一规则”解决台湾问题是中国内政，为其武装干涉制造借口”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，北京在台湾问题上应保持“战略信心、战略冷静、战略主动”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“在国家统一问题上，我们牢牢站在道义制高点上。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“争取和平统一既是国家发展总体战略的需要，也是国家发展的需要。”我们对国家稳定和同胞团结的道义责任。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech War: US chip restrictions dominate debate among Chinese semiconductor veterans at Semicon industry conference]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225986/tech-war-us-chip-restrictions-dominate-debate-among-chinese-semiconductor-veterans-semicon-industry?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/076f9a77-8986-48a3-9bf8-1780b0ce0314_08d31115.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国芯片限制措施的迫在眉睫，以及半导体供应链中断的恶化在上海举行的行业论坛上，这已成为中国芯片专家的主导话题，一些专家宣称“全球化已死”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;业内人士在周四于上海举行的 Semicon China 会议上分享了他们对中断的担忧据报道，华盛顿考虑进一步收紧出口管制，以减缓人工智能芯片流向中国。新规则将适用于Nvidia A800图形处理单元等芯片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;清华大学微电子研究所所长、中国半导体行业协会官员魏少军表示，中国是全球逆全球化的最大受害者。因为该国期望能够开发半导体产业全球资源。 “当全球化被破坏时，[行业]模式存在很大缺陷，因为中国无法实现资源的全球配置，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国芯片制造商长江存储看到半导体行业的“动荡和无序”&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;魏表示，《华尔街日报》周二报道华盛顿正在考虑禁止 Nvidia A800，这将为中国带来新的挑战和机遇。他表示：“如果美国禁止销售 A800 芯片，他们就是在堵自己的路。”他补充说，新禁令可能是中国加速替代品采购和开发的一个机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩中国最大的晶圆代工厂中芯国际（SMIC）高级副总裁狄表示，中国必须找到新的方式嵌入跨境供应链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“传统的产业合作模式面临新的挑战和机遇。”韩说。他建议我国重点发展芯片材料和元器件，发展先进芯片制造能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中芯国际作为中国大陆领先的集成电路企业，一直坚持合规经营的态度开放创新、合作共赢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年10月，美国升级对华技术出口管制，进一步限制其获取先进芯片和设备。根据更新后的规定，未经美国政府批准，中国代工厂不得向中国出售能够制造 14 纳米节点级别及更先进芯片的工具。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;芯芯中国总裁龙楚表示在地缘政治紧张和产业低迷的背景下，芯片行业的低迷已波及整个供应链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国半导体行业协会常务副理事长兼秘书长张莉表示，中国芯片行业持续低迷受产业低迷和“贸易环境不稳定”影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国电子商会会长王宁在活动中表示，“行业技术水平仍存在较大差距”国内半导体制造业与国外半导体制造业的比较”。他称这是一个大问题，因为 5G 技术和类似 ChatGPT 的生成人工智能服务增加了对先进芯片的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英伟达认为中国出口限制将永久丧失机会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国落后于美国清华大学魏教授表示，无论是先进芯片的技术还是产能都与美国相比，尽管中国愿意投入巨资，但这个问题短期内无法解决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须以量产为目标”急需的高端芯片已被西方禁止或限制。”魏说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China sees critical grains cut into copious cotton yields, including in boycotted Xinjiang region]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3225965/china-sees-critical-grains-cut-copious-cotton-yields-including-boycotted-xinjiang-region?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/626ff5ef-2641-48c7-915a-142378f3e71f_6f4c6506.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;全球最大棉花种植国中国的棉花种植面积大幅下降在以美国为首的抵制和北京积极推动提高全国粮食产量的情况下，在一年之内，农民种植了约 4140 万亩棉花（276 万公顷）。周三，该国国家棉花储备运营商旗下的一个市场监测平台使用中国通用计量单位表示，同比下降了 10.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下降主要是由转变所致中国国家棉花信息中心在一篇帖子中援引上个月的一项全国调查称，近年来，出于对粮食安全的担忧，北京加大了粮食产量的力度，因此，粮食播种的力度加大了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位农业教授表示，这也是全球服装行业抵制中国最大棉花生产国新疆维吾尔自治区棉花的结果，原因是涉嫌强迫劳动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;已经受到极端天气破坏的中国农业正在做好准备应对早期厄尔尼诺现象&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据官方数据，中国提供了全球20%以上的棉花，而去年新疆的棉花产量占全国总产量的90%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据该中心称，由于政府鼓励农民改种粮食，今年该地区已被要求额外划拨 480 万亩耕地种植粮食，其中大部分将取代棉花。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，四月份中央政府降低了对新疆棉农的补贴，以及播种季节遭遇低温、沙尘暴和大雨等恶劣天气影响，导致棉花产量下降。棉苗被毁后，许多农民不得不转向种植玉米等其他作物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着成本上升和利润下降，该国其他棉花种植区的兴趣也逐渐减弱，预计播种面积将减少报告称，面积高达四分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，在不考虑补贴的情况下，中国农民种植每亩棉花的平均利润仅为 58.4 元（8 美元），而且据中国棉花协会称，棉花产量比上年下降了 97%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民大学农学教授郑凤田表示，确保粮食自力更生是北京方面的首要任务。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去几年，中国政府有意将棉花种植转移到新疆，以进行集约化生产，但在西方国家的抵制之后，中国可能需要重新考虑这一做法。”郑说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果说美国发起抵制之后，中国的纺织品出口没有受到影响，那是无稽之谈。 Under such circumstances, we may need to put our eggs in different baskets,” said Zheng, referring to diversifying planting areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US&#39; Uygur Forced Labour Prevention Act, which went into effect last June, has effectively blocked American imports of all products wholly or partially sourced from Xinjiang. The Communist Party has been accused of committing rights abuses such as forced labour against Uygur Muslims and other minorities in the region, but Beijing has consistently denied the allegations.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thai passenger has leg amputated at Bangkok airport after getting trapped by moving walkway]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225988/thai-woman-has-leg-amputated-bangkok-airport-after-getting-trapped-moving-walkway?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 20:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/49ad16a6-6589-4217-92ec-8351a8654a0c_08fc24bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A woman&#39;s leg had to be amputated in a Thai airport after it was trapped by a moving walkway on Thursday, officials said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 57-year-old Thai passenger was due to board a morning flight from Bangkok&#39;s Don Mueang Airport to the southern Nakhon Si Thammarat province when she was caught by the walkway in the airport&#39;s Terminal 2.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A medical team eventually had to cut her left leg off from above the knee, according to airport officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On behalf of the Don Mueang International Airport, I&#39;d like to express my deepest condolences regarding the accident,” Don Mueang Airport Director Karun Thanakuljeerapat said during a press conference. “I&#39;d like to insist that we will ensure that no such accident will happen again.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the airport will be fully responsible for the woman&#39;s medical costs and will be open to negotiations on other compensation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The medical team at the hospital she was initially sent to informed Karun that they could not reattach her leg, but the woman requested to be transferred to another hospital to assess the possibility, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Images shared online showed the lower part of the woman&#39;s leg trapped beneath the belt at the end of the walkway as she was being assisted by airport staff.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A suitcase lying near her was missing two wheels, and yellow comb-like plates were seen broken off from where they typically cover the edge of the belt where the moving walkway ends.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Karun said the suitcase wheels were found underneath the belt, but it was unclear how it might relate to the accident. He said walkways at the airport are checked daily, with an additional monthly inspection. He said the walkway has been closed and a team of engineers was inspecting it to determine the cause of the accident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The walkway was manufactured by Japanese company Hitachi and was installed in 1996, the airport director said, adding that there is a plan to request for a budget to change to a newer model in 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, a passenger&#39;s shoe was damaged after it was caught in the airport&#39;s moving walkway in Terminal 1. The airport released a statement after that saying the faulty walkway was repaired and reopened in about an hour.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korean tech giant Samsung skips MWC Shanghai 2023 trade show for unknown reasons in break from annual participation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225895/south-korean-tech-giant-samsung-skips-mwc-shanghai-2023-trade-show-unknown-reasons-break-annual?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/4f1ba25a-44cc-4516-b56d-bddb635494b3_5502ef07.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Samsung Electronics, the world&#39;s largest smartphone vendor, was conspicuously absent for unknown reasons at MWC Shanghai, the regional edition of the world&#39;s biggest mobile communications industry trade show, in a break from the company&#39;s annual participation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The South Korean tech conglomerate&#39;s absence at the three-day MWC Shanghai, which returned as an in-person event this year and concludes this Friday, marks the first time the company has not taken part in the annual trade show since at least 2017, according to public information on its website. Samsung even had a booth at MWC Shanghai during the event&#39;s pandemic-marred 2021 edition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By contrast, Seoul-based Samsung – which remained the top global smartphone vendor in the first quarter and the whole of 2022, according to research firm IDC – had eight stands at MWC Barcelona 2023, organiser GSM Association&#39;s (GSMA) flagship annual mobile industry trade show, which was held from February 27 to March 2 in the capital of Spain&#39;s autonomous community of Catalonia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Samsung did not immediately respond to requests for comment since Wednesday. MWC Shanghai organiser GSMA, which represents the interests of mobile network operators worldwide, said it had no response to Samsung&#39;s absence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, there were other major industry stalwarts that did not exhibit at this year&#39;s MWC Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Swedish telecommunications equipment maker Ericsson and US-based Qualcomm – a developer of semiconductors, software and services related to mobile communications – also did not have booths at the Shanghai event this year, according to a representative from GSMA.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ericsson planned to set up a booth at MWC Shanghai, but then “backed out” just before the event opened this week, according to the representative who declined to be named. Qualcomm was initially booked as an exhibitor, but later decided to cancel for reasons unknown to the trade show&#39;s organiser.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But unlike Samsung, both Ericsson and Qualcomm were included among MWC Shanghai&#39;s 15 major corporate sponsors. Senior executives from the two firms were also among the featured speakers at the event.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;MWC Shanghai returns as in-person event after 2-year pandemic hiatus&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Samsung&#39;s no-show at MWC Shanghai has come at a time of rising tensions between China and South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relations between Seoul and Beijing have soured since the South Korean government denounced China for committing a “serious diplomatic discourtesy” after a Chinese official said recent comments by President Yoon Suk-yeol on Taiwan amounted to verbal meddling, according to Yonhap News.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ties between the two countries have never fully recovered after China opposed the US deployment of the Terminal High Altitude Area anti-missile defence system about six years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The once-formidable trade in semiconductors between China and South Korea also continued to decline in May, according to the latest data from Beijing and Seoul, amid geopolitical tensions that have changed the chip supply chain landscape in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China-South Korea tech trade slumps in May amid changes in chip supply chain&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The diminishing tech trade, particularly in semiconductors, between the two countries comes after China&#39;s standing in the global chip supply chain was affected by Seoul&#39;s decision to closely align its interests with Tokyo and Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea forms part of the US government-backed Chip 4 Alliance that includes Japan and Taiwan. Beijing has criticised this coalition as a plot by Washington to exclude China from semiconductor supply chains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese technology companies, meanwhile, seized the limelight at MWC Shanghai, making up for the absence of some major foreign companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huawei Technologies Co, for example, was one of the largest exhibitors at the trade show and also an event sponsor. The Shenzhen-based company&#39;s 1,500-square-metre booth attracted large crowds, as the firm exhibited its latest 5G products and intelligent digital transformation systems.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Huawei, Chinese telecoms firms tout 5G as life-changing tech at MWC Shanghai&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;ZTE Corp had a 1,100-square-metre booth at the trade show, where it displayed its latest information and communications technology hardware products and applications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A delegate from US semiconductor company Advanced Micro Devices (AMD) said China remains “very important” to the company, despite external uncertainties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Compared with the Barcelona event we just attended, the size of the Shanghai event is smaller but the technology is more ahead as China continues to drive innovation,” said Gilles Garcia, a senior director at AMD&#39;s data centre and communications group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 300 exhibitors from across the globe took part in MWC Shanghai at the Shanghai International Expo Centre. The event, which marked its first decade in China, was expected to attract 3,000 visitors, according to London-based GSMA.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan to test airport defence for first time in annual Han Kuang exercises]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3225980/taiwan-test-airport-defence-first-time-annual-han-kuang-exercises?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/4a08bda2-679c-4613-9f36-9286cf929fe5_ce097785.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s military will stage a drill at the island&#39;s main international airport for the first time next month, practising defence of the facility in a cross-strait war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The drill, to be held at Taoyuan International Airport south of Taipei on July 26, is part of the Han Kuang exercises – the island&#39;s major annual war games.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It will be the first time the airport has been used for a military drill since it opened in 1979.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The drill will test the readiness of the island&#39;s troops to repel an airborne assault, including forces parachuted in by the People&#39;s Liberation Army, according to Taiwan&#39;s defence ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Members of the Aviation and Special Forces Command and Army Airborne Special Forces will pose as the invading forces to be repelled by the ground troops,” a ministry official said on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official said the drill would last about an hour, with rehearsals on July 12 and 19.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ministry had already notified the airport and relevant authorities of the exercise and the preparations, including closure of part of the airport and flight rescheduling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Airport officials said flights would be suspended for two hours because the military needed time to prepare for the drill and the airport needed to manage the resumption of traffic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The north runway and part of the south runway will be closed down from 9am to 11am on July 26 and also on July 12 and 19,” an airport official said, adding air traffic control notices would be issued to all airlines for coordination and flight rearrangements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the facility was busy during the summer travel season, the official asked for understanding from customers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have estimated that more than 65 flights and 4,000 travellers will be affected during the exercise on July 26,” the official said, adding this also applied to the two rehearsals on July 12 and 19.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unprecedented inclusion of the airport – the island&#39;s major gateway to the world – in the exercise was apparently the result of a proposal by a group of US experts following their observation of the Han Kuang Exercise last year, according to local news media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Military experts said the drill was necessary because Taoyuan airport was just 3km (1.9 miles) from Zhuwei beach – one of the “red beaches” on the island that PLA forces could target for a landing and swift access to the island&#39;s capital of Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his 2017 book The Chinese Invasion Threat, Ian Easton says that while most of the island&#39;s coastal regions would present serious challenges, 14 of these beaches would likely allow potential enemies to establish a beachhead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shuai Hua-min, a retired army lieutenant general, said: “If the Chinese communists choose to land at Zhuwei beach, they definitely will push their forces further north to take over Taoyuan airport so that they can transport troops and weapons to Taiwan.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the PLA would need the airport to support its air-sea-surface operations, involving the navy&#39;s amphibious force and landing craft and its air force&#39;s paratroopers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shuai said that from the airport, the PLA could send forces to attack Taipei in less than an hour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shu Hsiao-huang, an analyst of the Institute for National Defence and Security Research, a government-funded think tank in Taipei, said that if the PLA intended to attack Taiwan, it would not destroy all of the island&#39;s air and sea ports because it would need continuous supplies and troops for its operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Capturing Taoyuan airport thus became an important mission for the PLA,” he said, adding that was why the island&#39;s military needed to familiarise itself with the airport.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the Taiwanese military was not familiar with the airport all because it had never staged any anti-airborne and anti-takeover drills at the facility.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fraud in Hong Kong: banks and businesses vow not to collect client data by text in joint effort with authorities to clamp down on phishing scams]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3225990/fraud-hong-kong-banks-and-businesses-vow-not-collect-client-data-text-joint-effort-authorities-clamp?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/6b8c16c0-6e42-4269-857b-99cf0ce1bce0_b469cf2f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Banks and major merchants in Hong Kong have promised to refrain from sending out texts containing hyperlinks that extract client information, as part of a joint drive with the government to clamp down on scammers using instant messages to target victims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fifteen businesses from various sectors came together on Thursday to mark the launch of the Anti-Scam Consumer Protection Charter, a pledge created by the Hong Kong Monetary Authority and the Hong Kong Association of Banks to curb the use of instant messages containing hyperlinks that collect personal information.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If residents get this type of message, they should be vigilant and refrain from clicking on those links,” said Eddie Yue Wai-man, the authority&#39;s chief executive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The signatories include logistics service providers SF Express, delivery platforms Deliveroo and Foodpanda, as well as online retailer HKTV Mall, while all 23 of the city&#39;s credit-card issuing banks also agreed to the charter.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Phishing messages from fake &#39;Scameter&#39; app prompt Hong Kong police warning&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Under the agreement, participants must train frontline staff to handle scam-related customer inquiries and provide communication channels that allow users to verify any messages they have received.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The clampdown on phishing scams follows the launch of an intelligence-sharing platform for banks by the authority and local police earlier this month. The initiative aims to help lenders detect and intercept accounts linked to fraudulent activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest data from the authority found it received 519 complaints related to scams and financial crimes between January and May. The city&#39;s de facto central bank recorded 555 incidents in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the complaints received during the first five months of this year, 382 involved unauthorised credit card transactions. The authority only recorded 391 such cases last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police figures show 1,408 victims had fallen prey to phishing scams during the first three months of the year, losing a total of HK$26.1 million (US$3.3 million).&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong accountant loses HK$700,000 in phishing scam, joining 1,408 others&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Arthur Yuen Kwok-hang, the authority&#39;s deputy chief executive, on Thursday urged residents to make sure they only carried out online transactions on official platforms and to be wary when submitting their personal details over the internet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When conducting any kind of transaction, please ensure you are logged into the official platform via formal channels before completing the transaction. Don&#39;t try to log in via hyperlinks,” he said as he moderated a panel of industry representatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Please also verify the identity of the counterparty [during online transactions] and be careful about sensitive information such as personal details, credit card information and one-time passwords. Do not hand them over to the other party.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representatives for a local bank and two major merchants said customers should look out for phishing messages that used official-looking email addresses and offered fake discounts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The panel also urged residents to check the email addresses of suspicious requests for unpaid postage fees or to collect packages, as well as those notifying recipients of lottery prizes or impersonating major businesses in the city.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>