<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Indonesian critics ask: what use is Dutch recognition of 1945 independence without reparations?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3224915/indonesian-critics-ask-what-use-dutch-recognition-1945-independence-without-reparations?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 19:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/e384986c-c6d4-43d0-bfb2-f1caf13affff_c6d6bd72.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;荷兰最近承认其前殖民地印度尼西亚的官方独立日是“观察家表示，雅加达的承认缺乏必要的法律反响，是对雅加达的“巨大侮辱”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月 14 日，荷兰首相马克·鲁特曾表示，荷兰“完全且毫无保留地承认” 印度尼西亚于 1945 年 8 月 17 日独立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将公告视为 [一个] 历史事实，”吕特在海牙的一次议会会议上说，并补充说他“将咨询”印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多 (Joko Widodo) 谈到如何“共同实现那个独立日”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;维多多第二天表示，承认是“一件好事”，但他会就其潜在影响咨询外交部长.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;荷兰的道歉是否会促使印度尼西亚“把所有的骨架都拿出来”？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;然而，根据 Jeffry Pondaag 的说法，Rutte 的声明是对印度尼西亚的“巨大侮辱”，总部位于荷兰的荷兰名誉债务委员会基金会主席，该基金会积极向荷兰人寻求军事进攻的赔偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的政府必须小心，不要只是接受承认，[赔偿] 荷兰在印度尼西亚 350 年的殖民统治？我们不能就此忘记它，”Pondaag 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚第一任总统苏加诺于 1945 年 8 月 17 日宣布独立，但荷兰人试图通过为期四年的外交和军事行动夺回殖民地1945 年至 1949 年的战争——这段时期在印度尼西亚被称为革命战争，在荷兰被称为革命战争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;荷兰人最终于 1949 年 12 月 27 日在一项名为《海牙协定》的条约中承认印度尼西亚独立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;然而，荷兰迅速避免了吕特声明可能导致的法律后果。这位荷兰领导人表示，他的承认“不会改变任何现有的法律依据”，而他的发言人表示，海牙将继续承认 1949 年为印度尼西亚独立年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“主权于 1949 年移交。我们不能荷兰媒体 NL Times 援引该发言人的话说，“扭转这一局面”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;观察家批评 Rutte 的承认没有得到法律承认，因为它避免了荷兰对归还印度尼西亚在革命战争期间作出的赔款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1949 年的海牙协定要求印度尼西亚为荷兰在战争中的损失支付 45 亿荷兰盾。雅加达最终在 2003 年全额偿还了这笔款项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rutte 的“不绅士”声明意味着荷兰正在“避免承担 [归还我们为战争赔款支付的款项] 的责任，以及被标记为战争犯罪分子，因为他们直到 1949 年仍将印度尼西亚视为他们的殖民地”，雅加达历史学家兼印度尼西亚语历史杂志 Historia 创始人邦妮·特里亚纳 (Bonnie Triyana) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邦妮说，承认 1945 年 8 月 17 日这一日期可能这意味着荷兰在 1947 年和 1948 年发动军事攻势时入侵了一个主权国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国于 1948 年 12 月 10 日通过了《世界人权宣言》，即荷兰对印度尼西亚发动第二次进攻的前 9 天，“这意味着侵略是对人权的侵犯，正义没有到期日”，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邦妮补充说，吕特的声明并不是什么新鲜事，因为荷兰前外交部长伯纳德·鲁道夫·博特 (Bernard Rudolf Bot) 2005 年已经表示，海牙“在政治和道义上”接受印度尼西亚于 1945 年独立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚前外交部长哈桑·维拉朱达 (Hassan Wirajuda) 也抨击吕特的声明“不真诚”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“承认独立性的声明伴随着各种最终否定声明本身的资格，”哈桑周五告诉当地频道 Metro TV。哈桑补充说，与英国、比利时和德国等其他西方国家对其前殖民地的道歉相比，该声明“来得太晚了”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邦妮呼吁维多多在任何会议中寻求“具体结果”与 Rutte 的合作，例如印度尼西亚人在访问荷兰时可免签证入境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们需要有更多的尊严，因为我们不是一个小国，”Bonnie 说。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Rutte 上周在荷兰议会下议院发表声明，在去年发布的一项研究发现荷兰军方在此期间，有系统地对印度尼西亚人使用“极端暴力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由来自荷兰和印度尼西亚的 115 名研究人员组成的团队进行的为期六年的研究还发现，荷兰人实施了“法外处决、虐待和酷刑” ，在不人道的条件下拘留”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《荷兰时报》报道，海牙拒绝了一些荷兰政党将暴力归类为“战争罪”的呼吁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Agus Suwignyo 博士，日惹加查马达大学的一位历史学家表示，出于对参与入侵的荷兰退伍军人的考虑，荷兰选择将其在印度尼西亚的行为归类为“极端暴力”。据《荷兰时报》报道，荷兰国防部长 Kajsa Ollongern 上周表示，大多数退伍军人“不应为暴力事件负责”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着政府声明 1945 年 8 月 17 日是印度尼西亚的正式独立日，荷兰军队在此之后直到 1949 年 12 月 27 日的所有行动都被视为对其他主权国家领土的侵略。退伍军人感到道德上处于不利地位，因为他们属于侵略者的范畴，”Agus 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;‘说实话’：英国在 1965 年印度尼西亚的种族灭绝中所扮演的角色面临挑战&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这位历史学家也注意到年轻一代的荷兰人对该国的殖民历史感到不安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与殖民时期没有直接关系的新一代在进入博物馆、在学校阅读教科书时感到不安“当时的荷兰人收回了他们的殖民地，从荷属东印度群岛带来了大量藏品，并将它们作为他们的财产在荷兰博物馆展出，”Agus 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然来自公众的压力不足以迫使荷兰对印度尼西亚的军事入侵承担法律责任，阿古斯敦促雅加达也要求对四年战争期间的“大规模杀戮”进行赔偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在荷兰第二次进攻后的七个月里研究称，1948 年 12 月，至少有 46,000 名印度尼西亚战斗人员丧生，并补充说荷兰方面有大约 5,300 人伤亡，其中包括几名忠于荷兰王室的印度尼西亚人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[German Isis woman convicted of keeping young female slave in Iraq, repeatedly raped by husband]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224916/german-isis-woman-convicted-keeping-young-female-slave-iraq-repeatedly-raped-husband?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 19:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/7565fd37-6869-4ee4-8eab-6215f4df3c7f_80b08451.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三，一名德国妇女被判有罪，罪名是在在伊拉克和叙利亚与伊斯兰国组织合作，并被判处九年零三个月监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西部城市科布伦茨的州法院判定这名 37 岁的人犯有危害人类罪，是一名成员德国新闻社 dpa 报道说，他是外国恐怖组织的成员，并且是种族灭绝的帮凶。当局根据德国隐私规则，仅将她确认为 Nadine K.。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法院认定，被告三年来“作为家庭奴隶，为了自己的利益”虐待了一名年轻的雅兹迪妇女。它说她的丈夫把这名妇女带到他们家里并经常强奸她，被告知道这一点并且应该进行干预。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;德国伊希斯妇女因谋杀“奴隶”女孩而被判入狱 10 年&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;检察官表示，被告于 2014 年与丈夫一起前往叙利亚，并加入了伊斯兰国。 2015 年，这对夫妇搬到了伊拉克小镇摩苏尔，据称他们在那里关押了这名雅兹迪妇女。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被告从叙利亚东北部的一个营地被带回德国后于 2022 年 3 月被捕，那里有疑似成员IS 的成员已被关押。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在辩护律师在她的审判中宣读的一份声明中，她否认曾在任何时候胁迫过这名雅兹迪妇女。她说，她经常因为这名妇女在场而与丈夫发生争执，她为没有为她做更多事情而感到羞愧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月，这名雅兹迪妇女在庭审中作证，并表示她认识被告。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是德国几起审判中的最新一起，案件涉及前往叙利亚和伊拉克伊斯兰国控制地区的妇女。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一个案件中，一名皈依伊斯兰教的德国人被定罪2021 年，她被指控允许一名 5 岁的 Yazidi 女孩被她和她的丈夫当作奴隶，在阳光下渴死。她的丈夫随后也被定罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，上诉法院下令对这名妇女进行新的量刑听证会，该妇女被判处 10 年徒刑。她现在面临更长的刑期。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Beijing confirms strategic bombers circled Taiwan in 2018 night mission]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3224910/beijing-confirms-strategic-bombers-circled-taiwan-2018-night-mission?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/76394ae8-f5a5-4013-b238-8573f6b4c8d1_4e3d5ec1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国大陆首次证实在夜间派出H-6K轰炸机2018 年绕台湾飞行的任务——在两岸关系恶化和人民解放军 (PLA) 加强针对该岛的行动的情况下承认这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“近年来，我们飞越了第一岛链空军 95183 部队第二飞行大队中校张斌中校说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; .我们晚上在台湾岛周围巡航，”他在中央电视台周一发布的题为“为胜利而飞”的宣传视频中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾空军司令部在 2018 年表示，解放军有，第一时间派出轰6K重型轰炸机夜间包围自治岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大陆国防部当时承认有行动，但未直接证实所用机型&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国对北京希望和平解决台湾问题的疑虑越来越大&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自去年 8 月，时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台北以来，北京已派出在台湾附近部署更多的军用飞机和军舰，它认为台湾是一个分离的省份，必要时可以使用武力控制。包括美国在内的大多数国家都不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但华盛顿反对使用武力改变现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，中央电视台开始播出一系列报道和一段宣传视频关于吹嘘轰6K轰炸机及其飞行员能力的轰炸机大队——显然是中共最高领导人授予该飞行大队荣誉称号的前奏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宣传部周二，党中央委员会授予该团体“时代楷模”荣誉称号——参考了中国国家主席的标志性思想，即“习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“我们近年来的远海任务不像过去那样，我驾驶 H-6K 飞机在那里，”张告诉中央电视台。 “现在，它是关于各种大小和形状的编队。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“例如，我们的电子战机、预警机、加油机、掩护我们的战斗机，甚至海上的军舰——他们的共享作战态势的数据和信息以及其他形式的支持让我们更有信心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;轰炸机大队张成良少校说，这种演习现在涉及卫星、预警机和海军。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;另据央视报道，2015年8月，该轰炸机大队成员飞越巴士海峡前往台湾南部地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年7月，他们在包括北京在内的岛礁巡逻控制的黄岩岛，中国称黄岩岛，位于南海。台湾和菲律宾也声称对这群岩石小岛拥有主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中央电视台没有说明轰炸机群所在的位置。然而，报告中显示的空军基地与 2022 年 7 月湖南省邵东市附近一个军用机场的卫星图像相符。谷歌地球上的图片显示 17 架 H-6K 停在停机坪上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CCTV 报道中显示的 H-6K 轰炸机的序列号表明这些飞机属于第 22 团根据荷兰航空协会运营的航空数据库 Scramble，第八航空师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自佩洛西去年访问该岛以及随后解放军围绕该岛进行一系列演习以来，解放军飞机经常飞越中线台湾海峡的分界线，这是双方几十年来基本遵守的事实上的边界线。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China says US fentanyl sanctions are ‘smears and suppression’ just days after apparent agreement to work with Washington]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224918/china-says-us-fentanyl-sanctions-are-smears-and-suppression-just-days-after-apparent-agreement-work?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 20:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/a2d32cb4-84a6-4905-a702-fc93571e977c_02912d49.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国对制裁被控帮助的公司和个人表示“强烈不满”为美国的芬太尼危机火上浇油。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就在几天前，美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯 (Antony Blinken) 表示，两国已同意探讨成立一个工作组，以阻止可用于&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2019 年之前，在北京应华盛顿的要求实施更严格的出口管制之前，中国被认为是非法芬太尼进入美国的主要来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从那时起，尽管最终产能已大部分转移到墨西哥等国家，但美国表示中国仍然是关键原料的主要来源，并将目标锁定在那些它指责参与其供应的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京一直强烈否认&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;墨西哥表示将向中国提供芬太尼走私的证据&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周三，国家统计局副局长余海滨禁毒委员会在新闻发布会上表示：“中方对美方一再以毒品问题为由制裁中国企业和公民，抹黑打压中国表示强烈不满。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;于指责华盛顿“不断炒作”中国化学品流入墨西哥，并坚称中国履行了国际义务，并率先对整个类别的芬太尼物质进行了监管。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;墨西哥加工的芬太尼原产于中国，但所涉及的化学品和相关设备不受国际麻醉品公约或中国和墨西哥法律的管制，”于说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示，美国制裁中提到的物品“压片机、胶囊填充机和压片模具”等也不受监管，而是归类为“普通商品”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两天前，布林肯表示他曾提出合成材料的问题他在为期两天的北京访问期间将阿片类药物列为“优先事项”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我明确表示，我们需要加强合作来解决这一关键问题，”他周一在美国大使馆举行的新闻发布会上说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们同意探讨建立一个工作组或共同努力，以便我们能够切断前体化学品的流动，这助长了这场危机和越来越多的死亡人数。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国外交部表示，双方已同意继续通过工作组进行磋商，“以解决具体问题”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，两国在结束 10 年后恢复了禁毒合作谈判-一个月的间歇期，中国国家药品监督管理局副局长赵军宁和美国食品药品监督管理局副局长 Andi Fristedt 在北京会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;芬太尼——以及更广泛的打击国际毒品贸易 - 长期以来一直被视为两国可以继续合作的关键领域，尽管其他领域的紧张局势日益加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;墨西哥要求中国的习近平帮助控制芬太尼的运输，抱怨美国&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;但中国去年 8 月暂停了在这个问题上的合作，作为对时任美国众议院议长南希佩洛西访问台湾的报复，北京认为这是对其主权的重大侵犯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿片类药物药物过量被认为每年在美国造成数万人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据美国疾病控制中心和预防。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，美国财政部制裁了七家中国实体和六名个人，他们被指控制造和销售用于制造出口到美国的假药的设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后4 月份针对涉嫌向墨西哥卡特尔供应易制毒化学品的两家中国公司和四名国民实施了类似的制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 Yu 说：“防止易制毒化学品转移的主要监督责任在于墨西哥当局。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中美禁毒合作应在各自国内法的法律框架下开展，双边执法合作应依法依规开展。”&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Grab’s job cuts show Singapore tech firm not immune to ‘frosty times’ of higher interest rates, slowing economy: analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3224911/grabs-job-cuts-show-singapore-tech-firm-not-immune-frosty-times-higher-interest-rates-slowing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 19:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/470d518e-5932-4244-80ff-1cce4d487ac4_baefd234.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;东南亚科技巨头 Grab 决定裁员 1,000 人，尽管它去年充满信心分析师表示，可以避免大规模裁员，这表明没有任何一家行业参与者能够免受利率上升和经济增长放缓的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在纳斯达克上市的 Grab 的困境反映了从 Facebook 到亚马逊以及区域性公司 GoTo 和 SEA 等其他科技公司所面临的困境表明，过去在低息债务时期通过积极的员工人数增长和现金注入来实现收入扩张的公司现在不得不削减成本，减少现金消耗&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grab 首席执行官 Anthony Tan 周二在给员工的一封私人信件中表示，裁员（占其跨国员工总数的 11%）是一项战略重组，以适应业务发展环境，而不是“盈利的捷径”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须适应我们经营的环境。变化从未如此迅速，”他写道。 “生成人工智能等技术正在以惊人的速度发展。资本成本上升，直接影响了竞争格局。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举的“主要目标”，他写道，是为了让公司能够“在战略上重组我们自己，以便我们能够更快地行动，更聪明地工作，并根据我们的长期战略重新平衡我们投资组合中的资源”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是该公司自 2020 年以来的首次裁员活动，当时该公司约有 360 名员工出门，作为回应&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 9 月——随着全球技术裁员浪潮的加剧——Grab 的首席运营官 Alex Hungate 表示，该公司“对任何招聘都非常谨慎和明智”，因此不会在裁员的“绝望”点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“年中左右，我们进行了某种特定的重组，但我知道其他公司一直在进行大规模裁员，所以我们看不到自己”Hungate 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在 12 月，Grab 推出了一系列削减成本的措施，包括暂停招聘、冻结高级管理人员的工资以及削减差旅和费用预算。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡的全球人才推介加剧了当地对生活成本低迷的担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2 月，Grab 预测 2023 年收入乐观，并提前了盈利时间表——预测在调整后的核心业务上实现收支平衡从今年第四季度到 2024 年下半年的收益基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新消息传来之际，从美国和中国的巨头到小型金融科技初创企业，科技界都在继续削减开支他们的劳动力。根据追踪该行业裁员情况的网站 Layoffs.fyi 的数据，今年有超过 200,000 名工人失业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与中国腾讯有关联的新加坡 SEA 裁员超过去年裁员 7,000 人，而 Grab 的竞争对手 GoTo 今年裁员 600 人，此外去年裁员 1,300 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么新加坡科技巨头 Sea 在东南亚掀起波澜&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;接受《亚洲周刊》采访的分析师一致认为，包括 Grab 在内的公司在大流行前时代追求的“奢侈增长”不太可能在当前气候下复制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人工智能的兴起他们说，Grab 的 Tan 将其列为其公司面临的主要挑战之一，这只是该行业必须克服的各种障碍之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡国立大学 (NUS) 助理教授 Ng Weiyi ) 商学院表示，由于对电子商务、物流和 IT 平台的需求增加，风险投资和大型科技行业在大流行期间蓬勃发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但此后环境发生了变化，利率上升Ng 补充说，这导致对高风险和高回报技术投资的兴趣减弱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们所看到的并不表明存在泡沫，”他说。 “这确实表明，奢侈支出和‘不惜一切代价实现增长’心态的冷淡时期可能即将结束。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡国立大学 (NUS) 商学教授劳伦斯·罗 (Lawrence Loh) 表示，问题“更多行业，而不是特定于 Grab 的”，并补充说技术发展为该行业创造了更短的交货时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多科技公司现在不得不应对大流行期间技术繁荣时期的动态招聘，这导致现在在经济低迷时期出现盈余，”Loh 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grab 裁员的决定是内部和外部因素共同作用的结果，例如大流行期间的积极招聘和向各种新企业的扩张，因为观察家表示，投资者情绪的转变以及生成式 AI 的兴起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一家战略性人力资源咨询服务公司的创始人兼首席执行官 Carmen Wee 表示，像 Grab 这样的科技公司会根据对未来增长的预期进行招聘。 /p>;&lt;p>;“没有 CEO 可以忽视生成式人工智能及其对他们业务的影响，尤其是在当前的环境下，”她说，并补充说它给公司带来了巨大的不确定性和竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;Grab 在美国上市后，SPAC 会在香港和新加坡起飞吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在外部因素方面，科技人才平台 NodeFlair 的联合创始人 Adrian Goh 表示，投资者情绪已转向“优先考虑盈利能力而非无限增长”，尤其是对于像 Grab 这样的成熟公司而言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鉴于这些情况，包括 Grab 在内的公司在招聘和探索可持续增长方法方面需要做出更慎重的决定，”他补充说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;关于该行业接下来的发展方向，Ng 表示这是一个周期性的过程。他说：“我们花太多钱也太早了，我们削减了成本，我们裁员了，希望我们能以更可持续、更稳定的方式恢复和再次增长。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果那不能不工作，然后循环再次重复。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 19:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong police arrest two men accused of planning to vandalise Shenzhen-based electric vehicle maker BYD’s showroom]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3224912/hong-kong-police-arrest-two-men-accused-planning-vandalise-shenzhen-based-electric-vehicle-maker?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 19:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/112f3054-4957-4075-ba2e-999c4ebb47ee_30ec5ec9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;警察逮捕了两名男子，据称他们正准备在陈列室的物品上泼黑漆上周，总部位于深圳的电动汽车制造商比亚迪在香港发生了一系列袭击事件，成为破坏者的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三凌晨袭击的尖沙咀陈列室是比亚迪四处遭到破坏的设施之一该市上周周一。其中三处标有红色油漆，第四处的卷闸门被一辆偷来的汽车撞坏了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在上周四和周日之间，警方逮捕了与前四起案件有关的八人。其中五人被控犯罪，并于周一和周二被带上法庭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周三的最新事件中，有组织罪案及三合会调查科的人员在午夜时分左右在尖沙咀陈列室附近埋伏收到情报表明它可能是故意破坏的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三凌晨 2 点 30 分左右，两名男子出现在陈列室外并做出可疑行为，警察突袭了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要求偿还债务的票据据该局高级督察黄俊康称，据称在他们身上或在一条小巷里发现了纸供品和一塑料桶黑色油漆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;初步调查发现，当时&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;破坏者袭击了电动汽车制造商比亚迪的香港展厅&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wong 说，这次可能的袭击是由个人财务纠纷，似乎与所涉汽车公司无关。他在新闻发布会上没有点名比亚迪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他没有提供财务纠纷的细节，称调查仍在进行中，可能会有更多人被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至周三下午，两名嫌疑人仍被警方拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周一凌晨 4 点之前，有人发现有人在比亚迪尖沙咀的窗户上泼了红漆，随后发生了第一起破坏性袭击事件警方说，漆咸道南陈列室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新界陈列室的卷帘门被一辆遗弃在外面人行道上的汽车撞坏后，大约 10 分钟后，警方接到报警，赶往元朗喜业街&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方逮捕一名在美国领事馆喷漆涂鸦的男子&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方接到报案称，凌晨 5 点后发生第三起事件，有人泼红漆在湾仔告士打道一幢商厦的玻璃门上。一名内部人士表示，初步调查显示，破坏者的目标是比亚迪的展厅，该展厅位于大楼入口旁边。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第四起案件是在早上 7 点之前曝光的，当时警方接到电话称，比亚迪的停车场入口位于天水围平厦路比亚迪服务中心被红漆覆盖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袭击期间无人受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年1月至3月期间，警方处理全市有 1,214 起刑事破坏报告，比 2022 年同期的 1,164 起上升了 4.3%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 19:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba’s outgoing CEO discusses AI’s risks and benefits with Nobel laureates at digital economy summit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224913/alibabas-outgoing-ceo-discusses-ais-risks-and-benefits-nobel-laureates-digital-economy-summit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 19:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/21/552d64dc-5ae7-44ce-a5f8-8bccd5920ac7_5a84061e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴集团控股即将离任的董事长兼首席执行官张勇、诺贝尔奖获得者等知名人士研究人员聚集在公司开放智库在中国杭州举办的年度数字经济会议上，讨论人工智能 (AI) 带来的机遇和危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对话诺贝尔经济学奖得主 Thomas Sargent , Christopher Pissarides 和 Eric Maskin, Zhang 分享了他对人工智能前景的看法，人工智能已成为阿里巴巴云计算部门的一个重点，因为它致力于将自己的大型语言模型 (LLM) 集成到公司的各种产品中。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“我们处在一个瞬息万变的世界，我们已经证明基础模型是有效的，”Zhang 说，他指的是基于大量数据进行训练的 AI 系统。 “这将产生我们从未见过的新产业或新服务，我认为这会推动整个社会向前发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但张也表达了对切割的出现所引发的伦理问题的担忧——边缘技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“既然可以向机器提供来自公共领域的数据，我们如何知道原始信息和知识的来源？他们怎么能受到尊重？这只是让我非常担心的问题的一个例子，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张是在罗汉堂举办的为期两天的活动上发表讲话的，罗汉堂是一个开放的智库，由阿里巴巴于 2018 年创立，拥有南华早报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次会议恰逢阿里巴巴周二宣布张勇将于 9 月辞去集团董事长兼首席执行官一职，专注于云业务，蔡崇信和吴永明将接任董事长一职&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次令人惊讶的管理层改组是这家科技巨头有史以来规模最大的企业重组的一部分，该重组于 3 月宣布，将分为六个独立运营的实体，每个实体都可能寻求他们的&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张在一份内部备忘录中表示，在云计算部门准备首次公开募股之际，他继续担任阿里巴巴和阿里云的董事长兼首席执行官是“不合适的”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了表现团结，阿里巴巴联合创始人马云和张在周二一起出现在阿里云的办公室，而同为联合创始人的蔡英文出现在杭州总部菜鸟网络，阿里巴巴的物流部门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在会议期间，与会者还就影响数字经济未来的各种挑战交换了意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴数字经济实验室主任 Erik Brynjolfsson Stanford University, said he foresees that around 60 per cent of the US workforce, which are primarily engaged in information and knowledge work, will be “significantly affected” by AI.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And that percentage is not [going to be] very different in Europe or China,” he said, adding that as the technology progresses, a much broader set of individuals will be impacted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pissarides, a professor at the London School of Economics, said people at the “top level” will become the biggest beneficiaries of AI progress, as they know how to utilise technologies, while those at the “bottom level” will face the biggest disruptions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Long, Alibaba&#39;s president for strategic planning and president of the Luohan Academy, stressed that China needs to catch up on key technologies to remain competitive in the global supply chain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China now has many advantages in various manufacturing clusters that, if combined with technologies, can allow the country to maintain its competitiveness in the entire value chain,” Chen said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 19:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong civil servant, firefighter, teachers among 6 accused of having sex with 14-year-old girl]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3224914/hong-kong-civil-servant-firefighter-teachers-among-6-accused-having-sex-14-year-old-girl?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 19:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/21/bd28698f-2761-4980-bdca-8641c07766c0_448f7d39.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Lands Department officer, a firefighter and two teachers were among six men denied bail by a Hong Kong court on Wednesday after being accused of having sex with a 14-year-old girl.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The six appearing in West Kowloon Court were slapped with nine charges, including unlawful sex, buggery and possession of child pornography.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The defendants are: land executive officer Chan Ka-ming, 30; firefighter Tso Kit-ting, 28; teachers Tam Siu-chun, 25, and Man Ka-wing, 40; engineering intern Ng Kai-ching, 21; and YouTuber Wong Pak-hong, 25.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prosecutors said three other men connected with the case were still at large.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The defendants met the girl between May 3 and June 2, according to a charge sheet. Five of them allegedly had sex with her in three hotels in Tsuen Wan and Kwai Chung. Ng allegedly had intercourse with her at his home in Tsuen Wan&#39;s Fuk Loi Estate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The six each face a count of unlawful sexual intercourse with a girl under 16, which carries a maximum jail sentence of five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tso was charged with the more serious offence of buggery with a girl under 21, punishable by up to life imprisonment, over acts he allegedly committed on May 29.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong faces one count of assault occasioning actual bodily harm for allegedly attacking the teen in a hotel room in Tsuen Wan on June 2.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong girl, 9, tricked through online gaming site into sending nude photos&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Man was charged with possessing two photos that depicted a minor in a sexual way at his home in Tsuen Wan&#39;s Luk Yeung Sun Chuen housing estate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The assault offence is punishable by up to three years in prison, while possession of child pornography carries a maximum jail sentence of five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The six defendants were arrested in a police operation on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Summer holiday internet warning as online scammers prey on Hong Kong children&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Magistrate Patrick Tsang Hing-tung adjourned the case for eight weeks on Wednesday to allow police to conduct further investigation, including arranging identification parades and inspecting the defendants&#39; mobile phones. He dismissed requests for bail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All but Chan and Tso have reserved their right to renew their bail bids next week. The six are expected to return to court in mid-August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is illegal in Hong Kong to have sex with a girl under 16.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 19:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China urges Pakistani military to keep up ‘zero tolerance’ crackdown on terror as Chinese interests targeted]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224904/china-urges-pakistani-military-keep-zero-tolerance-crackdown-terror-chinese-interests-targeted?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 18:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/21/3e01826b-6456-4c95-bd03-f180c036ffd2_4d4013af.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese Foreign Minister Qin Gang has urged the Pakistani military to continue its “zero tolerance” crackdown on terrorism, reiterating his call for better protection as Chinese nationals and projects face increasing extremist threats in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We thank the Pakistani army for its long-standing efforts to ensure the safety of Chinese personnel in Pakistan,” Qin told Sahir Shamshad Mirza, chairman of the Pakistan Army&#39;s Joint Chiefs of Staff Committee, as the pair met in Beijing on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We hope that the Pakistani side will not relent in its efforts to combat terrorism with zero tolerance,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qin also highlighted the importance of the Pakistani military in bilateral relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Pakistani army is the mainstay of Pakistan, as well as a staunch defender and promoter of China-Pakistan friendship,” Qin said, describing the country as an “ironclad friend of China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[We] hope the Pakistani military will continue to play its role as the anchor of stability by safeguarding domestic stability and offering new and more contributions to our strategic partnership.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pakistan is a key strategic partner in the region for China&#39;s Belt and Road Initiative infrastructure plan, with the US$54 billion China-Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC) a flagship project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Chinese interests have been targeted in recent years by terrorist groups in Pakistan, especially the separatist Baloch Liberation Army – a designated terrorist outfit – which carried out a deadly attack on Chinese nationals in April last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The attacks, coming as China&#39;s economic influence and closeness to Pakistan grow, have prompted Beijing to demand greater security for Chinese nationals in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the latest such incident, two gunmen described by Pakistani police as “terrorists” tried to attack a Chinese-owned shipyard in the port city of Karachi last month. Pakistani police shot dead one attacker and the other was reported to be on the run.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This came barely a week after Qin met his Pakistani and Afghan counterparts in Pakistani capital Islamabad, and urged them to help fight terror and protect “Chinese nationals, institutions and projects”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Gunman kills Chinese national in targeted attack in Pakistan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the Baloch Liberation Army attack in April last year, four people were killed when a female suicide bomber blew up a van carrying teachers at the University of Karachi&#39;s Confucius Institute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three Chinese nationals, including the school&#39;s director, were among the dead. The fourth was the van&#39;s Pakistani driver.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November, a Pakistani court handed down the death sentence to two men over a July 2021 bus attack that killed 13 people, including nine Chinese nationals. The passenger bus had been carrying workers to the Chinese-funded Dasu Hydropower Project in northwestern Pakistan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Responding to Qin on Tuesday, Mirza said Pakistan would always side with their “Chinese brothers” and “protect bilateral cooperation projects including the CPEC to its full capability”, according to an official Chinese readout.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mirza also met Zhang Youxia, vice-chairman of China&#39;s Central Military Commission, the same day. Both military leaders pledged to “deepen” security cooperation, according to the People&#39;s Daily, the mouthpiece of China&#39;s ruling Communist Party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“No matter how the international and regional situation changes, Pakistan will resolutely support the Chinese position on issues like Taiwan, Tibet, Xinjiang and Hong Kong,” Mirza was quoted as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Terror attacks are a concern as China shores up relations with Pakistan and Central Asia – crucial to its belt and road links to Africa and Europe. This relates especially to Pakistan&#39;s restive tribal areas along the border with Afghanistan, as well as Afghanistan itself, where anti-Pakistan and anti-China militant outfits have become more active since the Taliban takeover of Kabul.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Pakistani Taliban carried out suicide blast at hotel hosting Chinese ambassador&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, China announced it will hold regular counterterrorism talks with Pakistan and Iran, following the first such trilateral meeting on regional security issues and joint actions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qin also held a separate meeting with Pakistani counterpart Bilawal Bhutto Zardari when he visited Islamabad in May. A joint statement following that meeting reiterated the two sides&#39; “firm resolve to counter terrorism” and agreement to “further build on security and counterterrorism cooperation”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[European firms cool on China’s Greater Bay Area, ‘not benefiting’ from its US$1.8 trillion economy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224905/european-firms-cool-chinas-greater-bay-area-not-benefiting-its-us18-billion-economy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 18:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/21/0b5b1a49-ae53-41fb-83f7-64cdd5270bf9_01056056.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;European businesses have reported a plunge in optimism for China&#39;s Greater Bay Area, the highly valued southern city cluster that includes both Hong Kong and Shenzhen, raising questions over how Beijing should improve its attractiveness to hold on to foreign investors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only 44 per cent of the 75 companies surveyed by the European Union Chamber of Commerce in China expressed optimism for the region&#39;s grand development plan, compared to 68 per cent a year earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The results of the survey, released on Wednesday, came as investor suspicions have jumped over China&#39;s fast cooling economic activities, market barriers and lingering geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many South China members are reporting that they are not benefiting from the Greater Bay Area,” said Klaus Zenkel, head of the chamber&#39;s south China chapter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the poll jointly conducted with consultancy firm Roland Berger, 52 per cent of firms stayed neutral to the plan, a rise from 31 per cent a year earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some 4 per cent of the firms surveyed, meanwhile, pointed at a highly pessimistic outlook for the scheme to link Hong Kong, Macau and nine mainland cities of Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Zhuhai, Foshan, Zhongshan, Dongguan, Huizhou, Jiangmen and Zhaoqing into an integrated economic and business hub.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Obstacles mainly stem from the competition between cities rather than uniform policy coordination, according to Zenkel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Greater Bay Area development blueprint was released in 2018, with the aim to build a world-class growth engine to rival the bay areas of Tokyo, San Francisco and New York.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than two thirds of the surveyed European firms said Chinese authorities should do more to clarify the business opportunities available for both Chinese and foreign companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts have called for more policy coordination within the city cluster, as mainland cities in the region generally have a relatively high degree of overlap in areas such as manufacturing, finance and technological innovation, which has led to a certain level of similarity in their converging industrial structures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is more homogeneous competition between cities in the Greater Bay Area, especially the two leading cities – Guangzhou and Shenzhen,” said Yuan Chenjie, the principal representative at private equity firm SAIF Partners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They are different from the ones in Yangtze River Delta, such as Shanghai, Suzhou and Wuxi, as the latter each have their own positioning and they can achieve complementary and virtuous development.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A report earlier this month by Yuekai Securities also pointed to a lack of integration between cities in the Greater Bay Area and a homogeneous industrial landscape.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Industrial support among cities in the Greater Bay Area is not yet complete, and there is the problem of homogeneous competition,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Yuekai Securities report said that market rules are not uniform, with Guangdong province and the special administrative regions of Macau and Hong Kong having differences in industry regulation and intellectual property protection, and a split in the policy pilot areas within the Pearl River Delta.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These can lead to businesses facing additional systemic costs,” the report added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the lack of talent and “outstanding risk” of its industries facing technological sanctions from Washington are creating more uncertainties to the prospects of the Greater Bay Area, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, said the nine mainland cities need to draw more on the practices of Hong Kong, Macau or even Singapore, to address the concerns of foreign investors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After all, Hong Kong and Singapore have the best business environment in the world,” Peng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The combined economy of the Greater Bay Area stood at 13 trillion yuan (US$1.8 trillion) last year, with Shenzhen, Guangzhou and Hong Kong contributing the most, according to the Hong Kong Trade Development Council.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong policeman asks court for HK$160,000 in damages; alleges senior officer said he had sex with subordinate’s wife and mother]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3224903/hong-kong-policeman-asks-court-hk160000-damages-alleges-senior-officer-said-he-had-sex-subordinates?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.21 18:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/21/cb22b914-b7cb-4d04-87ac-2b5eb8356784_d4bb2aba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Hong Kong police officer has filed a HK$160,000 claim (US$20,440) against a senior colleague for workplace harassment and argued the force had failed to implement anti-discrimination policies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Constable Ng Hon-sum also asked the District Court to order the force to donate the same amount to the Our Hong Kong Foundation, a pro-establishment think tank, or the force&#39;s welfare fund as a penalty for allowing a “hostile and/or intimidating work environment”, the writ, filed on Friday, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The document, seen by the Post on Wednesday, alleges Ng was repeatedly harassed by then Senior Constable Lam Man-lung at Tsuen Wan Police Station between July 2020 and June 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The writ said Lam&#39;s animosity started with offensive remarks and rude gestures. It added Lam&#39;s behaviour was noticed by colleagues and fuelled gossip about his character in his team.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng alleged the harassment crossed the legal boundary in June 2021 when Lam said he had had sex with his subordinate&#39;s wife.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The senior constable was said to have added that Ng&#39;s mother had given birth to “a bad boy” because she had also had intercourse with him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng maintained the remarks were in breach of the Sex Discrimination Ordinance because Lam, who was near retirement at the time, had intended to threaten him by purporting to commit a sexual offence against his loved ones.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The words emphasised by [Lam] caused the claimant reasonably to be concerned for the safety of his family members. The negative sentiment remains prevailing and growing around the [claimant&#39;s] private and family life,” Ng wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ernst &amp; Young launches probe into sexual harassment claim in Hong Kong&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He claimed he had been deprived of opportunities to learn new skills and secure promotions because of the smears by Lam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The writ said a police internal investigation had ruled in Lam&#39;s favour and Ng&#39;s request for a review of the findings was rejected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng also filed a complaint to the Equal Opportunities Commission, but it reportedly decided not to investigate further after a preliminary assessment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong court orders firm to apologise to ex-employee over sexual harassment claim&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He is seeking HK$120,000 from Lam for injury to feelings and HK$40,000 for “exploitation and abuse against the claimant, who was vulnerable because of the power imbalance between the parties”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng also asked the court to also find the force liable for Lam&#39;s behaviour and order both to write him an apology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court is expected to hear arguments in the case in mid-August.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 21 Jun 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>