<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China sees critical grains cut into copious cotton yields, including in boycotted Xinjiang region]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3225965/china-sees-critical-grains-cut-copious-cotton-yields-including-boycotted-xinjiang-region?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/626ff5ef-2641-48c7-915a-142378f3e71f_6f4c6506.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;全球最大棉花种植国中国的棉花种植面积大幅下降在以美国为首的抵制和北京积极推动提高全国粮食产量的情况下，在一年之内，农民种植了约 4140 万亩棉花（276 万公顷）。周三，该国国家棉花储备运营商旗下的一个市场监测平台使用中国通用计量单位表示，同比下降了 10.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下降主要是由转变所致中国国家棉花信息中心在一篇帖子中援引上个月的一项全国调查称，近年来，出于对粮食安全的担忧，北京加大了粮食产量的力度，因此，粮食播种的力度加大了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位农业教授表示，这也是全球服装行业抵制中国最大棉花生产国新疆维吾尔自治区棉花的结果，原因是涉嫌强迫劳动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;已经受到极端天气破坏的中国农业正在做好准备应对早期厄尔尼诺现象&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据官方数据，中国提供了全球20%以上的棉花，而去年新疆的棉花产量占全国总产量的90%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据该中心称，由于政府鼓励农民改种粮食，今年该地区已被要求额外划拨 480 万亩耕地种植粮食，其中大部分将取代棉花。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，四月份中央政府降低了对新疆棉农的补贴，以及播种季节遭遇低温、沙尘暴和大雨等恶劣天气影响，导致棉花产量下降。棉苗被毁后，许多农民不得不转向种植玉米等其他作物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着成本上升和利润下降，该国其他棉花种植区的兴趣也逐渐减弱，预计播种面积将减少报告称，面积高达四分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，在不考虑补贴的情况下，中国农民种植每亩棉花的平均利润仅为 58.4 元（8 美元），而且据中国棉花协会称，棉花产量比上年下降了 97%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民大学农学教授郑凤田表示，确保粮食自力更生是北京方面的首要任务。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去几年，中国政府有意将棉花种植转移到新疆，以进行集约化生产，但在西方国家的抵制之后，中国可能需要重新考虑这一做法。”郑说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果说美国发起抵制之后，中国的纺织品出口没有受到影响，那是无稽之谈。在这种情况下，我们可能需要把鸡蛋放在不同的篮子里。”郑说，他指的是种植区域多样化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年6月生效的美国《维吾尔族强迫劳动预防法》有效禁止美国进口全部或部分来自新疆的所有产品。共产党被指控侵犯维吾尔族穆斯林和该地区其他少数民族的权利，例如强迫劳动，但北京一直否认这些指控。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thai passenger has leg amputated at Bangkok airport after getting trapped by moving walkway]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225988/thai-woman-has-leg-amputated-bangkok-airport-after-getting-trapped-moving-walkway?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 20:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/49ad16a6-6589-4217-92ec-8351a8654a0c_08fc24bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名女子在泰国机场被困者困住，腿部被迫截肢官员称，周四，这名 57 岁的泰国乘客正准备登上从曼谷廊曼机场飞往南部洛坤府的早班航班，却在自动人行道上被卡住。机场 2 号航站楼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据机场官员称，医疗队最终不得不从膝盖以上切掉她的左腿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“谨代表廊曼国际机场，我谨对这起事故表示最深切的哀悼，”廊曼机场负责人卡伦·塔纳库吉拉帕特在新闻发布会上表示。 “我想强调，我们将确保不再发生此类事故。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，机场将全面负责该女子的医疗费用，并将就其他赔偿问题进行谈判。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡伦说，她最初被派去的医院的医疗团队通知卡伦，他们无法重新接上她的腿，但该女子要求转移到另一家医院以评估可能性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;网上分享的图片显示，当机场工作人员协助她时，该女子腿的下半部分被困在走道尽头的安全带下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她附近的一个手提箱缺少两个轮子，黄色的梳状板从通常覆盖自动人行道末端的传送带边缘的地方脱落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡伦说，手提箱的轮子是在传送带下方发现的，但目前还不清楚是如何发现的。可能与事故有关。他说，机场的走道每天都会检查，每月还会进行一次检查。他说，走道已关闭，一组工程师正在检查，以确定事故原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机场负责人表示，走道由日本日立公司制造，于 1996 年安装，并补充道计划要求预算在 2025 年更换新型号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年，一名乘客的鞋子被卡在机场 1 号航站楼的自动人行道中后被损坏。机场发布随后发表的一份声明称，有问题的走道在大约一个小时内得到修复并重新开放。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korean tech giant Samsung skips MWC Shanghai 2023 trade show for unknown reasons in break from annual participation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225895/south-korean-tech-giant-samsung-skips-mwc-shanghai-2023-trade-show-unknown-reasons-break-annual?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/4f1ba25a-44cc-4516-b56d-bddb635494b3_5502ef07.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;全球最大的智能手机供应商三星电子因不明原因明显缺席 MWC上海是世界上最大的移动通信行业贸易展的区域版，该公司中断了年度参展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家韩国科技集团缺席了为期三天的 MWC 上海，该展会作为根据其网站上的公开信息，今年的年度展会将于本周五结束，这标志着该公司至少自 2017 年以来首次没有参加年度贸易展。三星甚至在受疫情影响的 2021 年上海世界移动通信大会 (MWC Shanghai) 上设立了展位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，总部位于首尔的三星 — 根据数据显示，该公司在第一季度和 2022 年全年仍然是全球最大的智能手机供应商研究公司 IDC – 在 2023 年巴塞罗那世界移动通信大会上有 8 个展位，这是主办方 GSM 协会 (GSMA) 旗舰年度移动行业贸易展，该展会于 2 月 27 日至 3 月 2 日在西班牙加泰罗尼亚自治区首府举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;自周三以来，三星并未立即回应置评请求。代表全球移动网络运营商利益的 MWC 上海组织者 GSMA 表示，对三星缺席没有任何回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，还有其他主要行业巨头没有参加今年的 MWC 上海。&lt;据 GSMA 的一位代表称，瑞典电信设备制造商爱立信和美国高通公司（移动通信相关半导体、软件和服务开发商）今年也没有在上海展会上设置展位。&lt;据这位不愿透露姓名的代表称，爱立信原计划在 MWC 上海设立展位，但在本周活动开幕前“退出”。高通最初被预定为参展商，但后来决定取消，原因不明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但与三星不同的是，爱立信和高通均被列入 MWC 上海的 15 家主要赞助商之列。两家公司的高管也是此次活动的特邀演讲嘉宾。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;MWC 上海在疫情中断两年后再次以现场活动形式举行&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;三星缺席 MWC上海之行正值中韩关系日益紧张之际。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自韩国政府谴责中国实施“严重外交失礼”以来，首尔和北京之间的关系已经恶化。据韩联社报道，韩国总统尹锡烈对台湾的言论构成口头干涉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自中国反对美国在末端高空地区部署反导系统以来，两国关系从未完全恢复。据北京和首尔的最新数据显示，由于地缘政治紧张局势改变了中国和韩国之间大约六年前的国防系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月份，中国和韩国之间曾经一度强大的半导体贸易也继续下降。亚洲芯片供应链格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于芯片供应链的变化，5月份中韩科技贸易大幅下滑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两国之间的科技贸易（尤其是半导体贸易）减少中国在全球芯片供应链中的地位因首尔决定与东京和华盛顿紧密结合其利益而受到影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国是美国政府支持的芯片 4 联盟的一部分，该联盟包括日本和台湾。北京批评这一联盟是华盛顿将中国排除在半导体供应链之外的阴谋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，中国科技公司在 MWC 上海上抢占了风头，弥补了一些大型外国公司的缺席。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;例如，华为技术有限公司是展会上最大的参展商之一，也是活动赞助商。这家总部位于深圳的公司 1,500 平方米的展位吸引了大批人群，该公司展示了最新的 5G 产品和智能数字化转型系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;华为和中国电信公司在 MWC 上将 5G 视为改变生活的技术上海&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中兴通讯在展会上拥有1,100平方米的展位，展示了其最新的信息和通信技术硬件产品和应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国半导体公司代表Advanced Micro Devices (AMD) 表示，尽管外部存在不确定性，但中国对该公司仍然“非常重要”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与我们刚刚参加的巴塞罗那活动相比，上海活动的规模较小，但技术却很先进。” AMD 数据中心和通信事业部高级总监 Gilles Garcia 表示：“随着中国不断推动创新，中国将取得更大进步。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自全球各地的 300 家参展商参加了在上海国际展览中心举行的 MWC 上海博览中心。据总部位于伦敦的 GSMA 称，该活动标志着其在中国举办的第一个十年，预计将吸引 3,000 名参观者。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan to test airport defence for first time in annual Han Kuang exercises]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3225980/taiwan-test-airport-defence-first-time-annual-han-kuang-exercises?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/4a08bda2-679c-4613-9f36-9286cf929fe5_ce097785.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台军接下来将在岛内主要国际机场首次举行演习月，练习在两岸战争中保卫设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次演习将于 7 月 26 日在台北以南的桃园国际机场举行，是汉光演习的一部分，汉光演习是台湾一年一度的重大演习战争游戏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这将是该机场自 1979 年开放以来首次用于军事演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次演习将测试岛上部队的击退准备情况据台湾国防部称，这是一次空降攻击，其中包括解放军空降的部队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“航空特种部队司令部和陆军空降特种部队的成员将冒充入侵部队进行击退一名国防部官员周四表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该官员表示，演习将持续约一个小时，并于 7 月 12 日至 19 日进行排练。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防部已经向机场和有关部门通报了演习和准备工作，包括关闭部分机场和航班重新安排。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机场官员表示，由于军方需要时间准备，航班将暂停两个小时。演习和机场需要管理恢复交通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北跑道和部分南跑道将于7月26日上午9点至11点关闭，7月12日和19日也将关闭，”机场负责人表示，将向各航空公司发出空管通知，以便协调和重新安排航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于夏季旅游旺季机场繁忙，请旅客谅解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“我们预计7月26日演习期间将有超过65个航班和4000名旅客受到影响”，该官员表示，并补充说这也适用于7月12日和19日的两次演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;据当地新闻媒体报道，将机场——台湾通往世界的主要门户——史无前例地纳入演习，显然是一组美国专家在观察去年的汉光演习后提出的建议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;军事专家表示，这次演习是必要的，因为桃园机场距离竹尾海滩仅 3 公里（1.9 英里），竹尾海滩是岛上的“红海滩”之一，解放军部队可以将其作为着陆和快速进入的目标伊恩·伊斯顿 (Ian Easton) 在其 2017 年出版的《中国入侵威胁》一书中表示，虽然该岛的大部分沿海地区将带来严峻的挑战，但其中 14 个海滩可能会让潜在的敌人建立一个安全的基地。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;退役陆军中将帅华民说：“如果中共选择在竹围滩登陆，他们肯定会进一步北上，占领桃园机场，这样他们就可以占领桃园机场。”可以向台湾运送部队和武器。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，解放军需要该机场来支持其海空作战，其中包括海军的两栖部队和登陆艇以及空军的伞兵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;帅说，从机场出发，解放军可以在不到一个小时内派兵攻击台北。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防安全研究院分析师舒小黄，台北一家政府资助的智库表示，如果解放军打算攻击台湾，它不会摧毁台湾所有的空港和海港，因为它需要持续的补给和部队来进行行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “夺取桃园机场因此成为解放军的一项重要任务，”他说，并补充说，这就是为什么岛内军方需要熟悉该机场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，台湾军方对该机场并不熟悉这一切都是因为它从未在该设施进行过任何反空降和反接管演习。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fraud in Hong Kong: banks and businesses vow not to collect client data by text in joint effort with authorities to clamp down on phishing scams]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3225990/fraud-hong-kong-banks-and-businesses-vow-not-collect-client-data-text-joint-effort-authorities-clamp?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/6b8c16c0-6e42-4269-857b-99cf0ce1bce0_b469cf2f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港银行及主要商户已承诺不会发出含有超链接的短信提取客户信息，作为与政府联合打击利用即时消息瞄准受害者的诈骗者的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，来自不同行业的十五家企业齐聚一堂，庆祝反欺诈系统的启动。 《诈骗消费者保障约章》是香港金融管理局和香港银行公会制定的一项承诺，旨在遏制使用包含收集个人信息的超链接的即时消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果居民收到此类消息管理局行政总裁余伟文表示，他们应该保持警惕，不要点击这些链接。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;签署者包括物流服务提供商顺丰速运、配送平台 Deliveroo 和 Foodpanda作为在线零售商 HKTV Mall，而全市 23 家信用卡发卡银行也同意该章程。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;来自假“Scameter”应用程序的网络钓鱼消息促使香港警方发出警告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据协议，参与者必须培训一线员工处理与诈骗相关的客户查询，并提供沟通渠道，使用户能够验证他们收到的任何消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;打击网络钓鱼诈骗是在启动一项情报之后进行的。本月早些时候，当局和当地警方为银行提供了共享平台。该举措旨在帮助贷方检测和拦截与欺诈活动相关的账户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构的最新数据发现，1 月至 5 月期间收到了 519 起与诈骗和金融犯罪相关的投诉。 2022年，该市事实上的央行记录了555起事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年前五个月收到的投诉中，有382起涉及未经授权的信用卡交易。当局去年仅记录了 391 起此类案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方数据显示，今年首三个月有 1,408 名受害者成为网络钓鱼诈骗的受害者，损失总计 2,610 万港元（330 万美元）。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港会计师在网络钓鱼诈骗中损失 70 万港元，与其他 1,408 人一起损失 &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该管理局副行政长官袁国恒周四敦促居民确保他们只进行了在官方平台进行网上交易，并谨慎通过互联网提交个人信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在进行任何类型的交易时，请确保您通过正规渠道登录官方平台后再完成交易。不要尝试通过超链接登录，”他在主持一个行业代表小组时说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“还请验证（在线交易期间）交易对手的身份，并小心敏感信息，例如如个人详细信息、信用卡信息和一次性密码。不要将它们交给对方。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地一家银行和两家主要商家的代表表示，客户应该留意使用看似官方的电子邮件地址并提供虚假折扣的网络钓鱼消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;该小组还敦促居民检查可疑请求未付邮费或领取包裹的电子邮件地址，以及通知彩票奖品接收者或冒充该市主要企业的电子邮件地址。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[World Economic Forum: China’s economy ‘needs time to recover’, with big rally and massive stimulus seen unrealistic]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3225982/world-economic-forum-chinas-economy-needs-time-recover-big-rally-and-massive-stimulus-seen?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 20:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/38a62f84-b01f-47f9-9ab0-fb2125c51e72_173641b5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国经济短期内大幅反弹，政府大规模刺激经济行业领袖和经济学家在周四世界经济论坛的最后一天表示，支撑疲弱的经济复苏是不现实的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国一直在努力应对复苏势头放缓以及疫情影响带来的伤痕。中国北方城市天津的小组成员表示，导致世界第二大经济体脱轨的冠状病毒需要时间才能消退。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不能低估长达数年的大流行的负面影响，我认为这种影响已经世界工程组织联合会前主席龚克表示：“在很多方面都耗尽了公共资源，我们需要一些时间来恢复。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出口需求的减少也抑制了中国的制造业，房地产市场的低迷和财政支持减少导致房地产和地方政府收入减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国曾希望依靠消费作为疫情后经济复苏的主要动力，但日益严峻的外部和内部挑战催生了新的复杂增长&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际货币基金组织前副总裁、中国人民银行前副行长朱民表示，中国国际经济交流中心副会长朱表示，中国已经在巨额债务压力下苦苦挣扎，期待大规模刺激政策是不现实的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是刺激消费支出的最重要措施之一，就是要确保今年居民收入增速高于国内生产总值（GDP）增速。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[政府还需要]继续完善社会保障体系，在“在养老金、医疗保健和所有其他方面，[以及]加快人们在城市地区获得户口的速度，”他说，并补充说，更宽松的户籍制度将释放数亿人的巨大消费能力。城市人口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;户口是所有中国公民都必须持有的户口登记文件，它根据持有人的出生地控制获得公共服务的机会。农民工将持有家乡户口，这意味着他们在前往工作的任何其他城市享受公共服务的权利非常有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与其采取任何恐慌性的宏观经济刺激措施，不如将重点放在中等水平上。”康奈尔大学经济学教授埃斯瓦尔·普拉萨德 (Eswar Prasad) 表示，“短期增长措施将支持更可持续的增长。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“重建可持续的私营部门信心非常重要，这是促进增长的关键短期内，促进长期更好的增长。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年前5个月，中国整体固定资产投资同比增长4%，低于去年同期的增幅前四个月增长 4.7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;事实确实如此：总理在“夏季达沃斯”上表示，中国经济增长更快&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但私营企业固定资产投资下降了 0.1% %，低于前四个月0.4%的增幅，与1-5月国有企业8.4%的增长形成鲜明对比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三开当日在素有“夏季达沃斯”之称的第十四届新领军者年会上，李强总理表示，中国二季度GDP增速预计将快于前三个月4.5%的增速&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示，北京方面希望中国能够实现 2023 年 5% 的总体增长目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国预计将在中期发布第二季度 GDP 数据- 7 月，尽管市场预期积极，但增长将部分受到去年同期基数较低的推动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海是经济强国，李克强在上海升任前曾担任市委书记。 3 月，经历了去年两个月的封锁，2022 年第二季度中国经济仅增长了 0.4%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why China gives Africa’s leaders the red-carpet treatment – and a chance to ask for favours]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3225939/why-china-gives-africas-leaders-red-carpet-treatment-and-chance-ask-favours?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/7952974a-cc6b-4c9e-afc9-c42e86b94c43_ed45bf66.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;厄立特里亚总统阿费沃尔基上个月访问北京时，习近平主席到场迎接在人民大会堂金色大厅举行了仪仗队、鸣放21响礼炮和欢迎宴会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这与12月阿费沃尔基不在美国时的情况形成鲜明对比。甚至受邀参加在华盛顿举行的美非领导人峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;厄立特里亚因涉嫌侵犯人权而受到西方国家的严厉制裁，但习近平告诉阿费沃尔基，北京“反对外部干涉厄立特里亚内政，反对对厄立特里亚实施单边制裁”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;非洲矿产巨头的目标是在中国与西方的资源竞赛中获得更大的利益&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;刚果民主共和国 (DRC) 总统费利克斯·齐塞克迪 (Félix Tshisekedi) 也受到了类似的待遇。上个月在北京会见了习近平。 2019年访问华盛顿时，他会见了时任美国国务卿迈克·蓬佩奥，但尚不清楚他是否会见了时任美国总统唐纳德·特朗普。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非洲领导人对中国进行国事访问时，北京竭尽全力让他们感到受欢迎、重要、有影响力和被倾听——这是他们在访问美国或许多欧洲国家时很少得到的待遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京的盛大招待会不仅仅是一场表演热情好客，但非洲领导人有机会获得对重大基础设施项目的支持，并推动解决债务和贸易问题，不过分析人士表示，随着中国减少对非洲大陆的承诺，这些访问现在带来的好处比过去要少。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;为领导人铺上红地毯是中国王朝时代的传统之一。在这种被称为“耆英外交”的做法中，中国皇帝不遗余力地表现出优雅的待客之道，甚至亲自招待客人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所有中国现代国家主席 — — 包括习近平 — —华盛顿国防大学非洲战略研究中心的中非专家保罗·南图亚表示，中非已将其微调为一种外交艺术形式，以培养积极情绪、培养互惠感并赢得有利协议。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;非洲领导人相信，如果他们与中国国家主席面对面会面，他们更有可能解决问题或满足请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赞比亚总统哈凯恩德就是这样的领导人之一希奇莱马上个月表示，他正在等待与中国外长会面，以解决该国拖延已久的债务重组问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赞比亚在 2020 年出现外债违约，欠中国债权人约 60 亿美元截至 2022 年底，外债总额达 186 亿美元，使中国成为最大的官方双边贷款国。北京尚未宣布希奇勒马访华，但这位赞比亚领导人表示，与习近平会面将加快债务减免进程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非洲领导人也希望访问中国，因为他们相信中国更愿意投资Nantulya 表示，在西方国家完全缺席或极不愿意充分参与公路、铁路、机场、港口等基础设施以及水电大坝和太阳能等能源项目的领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，中国愿意向非洲国家提供非常规融资和偿还体系，例如“基础设施换资源互换协议”，即非洲国家通过向中国转移资源来偿还部分债务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月在中国获得一流待遇的其他非洲领导人包括坦桑尼亚总统萨米亚·苏鲁胡·哈桑、加蓬总统阿里·邦戈·翁丁巴和科特迪瓦总理帕特里克·阿奇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除国家元首外，中国还最近接待了埃塞俄比亚、刚果民主共和国、津巴布韦和塞拉利昂的外交部长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;访问是双向的，今年有几位中国高级外交官和官员访问了非洲大陆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1月，中国外交部长秦刚访问非洲五国及非盟总部、阿盟总部。这延续了三个十年的传统，即中国外交部长每年年初访问五到六个非洲国家，这是中国外交日历上的第一件事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，中国外交部长赵乐际全国人大常委会访问塞内加尔和摩洛哥。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国向塞拉利昂提供巡逻艇是为了争夺几内亚湾吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自从成为十年前，习近平主席就曾三次访问撒哈拉以南非洲地区：首先是2013年3月访问坦桑尼亚、刚果共和国和南非，然后是2015年访问津巴布韦和南非，最后访问塞内加尔、卢旺达2018 年，他还访问过北非一次，并于 2016 年访问了埃及。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管自 Covid-19 大流行爆发以来，习近平尚未​​访问过非洲大陆，但他可能会前往南非如果该国最终主办金砖国家峰会，则将于 8 月举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 1943 年以来，美国总统总共只访问了非洲 54 个国家中的 16 个国家，而美国国务卿平均每两到三个国家就访问了 6 个非洲国家据美国国务院称，上一位访问撒哈拉以南非洲的美国总统是巴拉克·奥巴马(Barack Obama)，他在任期八年中四次访问该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普执政期间，华盛顿在非洲的影响力降至最低水平，特朗普因贬低非洲大陆的言论而成为头条新闻。他在担任总统的四年中从未访问过非洲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，美国总统乔·拜登希望扭转华盛顿与非洲大陆缺乏接触的局面，并于去年主办了美非领导人峰会，并承诺提供 55 美元三年内拨款十亿美元资助非洲大陆的基础设施，并承诺派遣更多美国领导人前往非洲国家。此后，美国副总统、国务卿、财政部长等多位美国官员先后访问非洲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南图利亚表示，2008年至2018年，中国各级领导人79次访问非洲，非洲国家领导人访华222次。 “因此，这些访问不仅仅是象征性的，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，中国最高领导机构——共产党中央政治局常务委员会的成员领导着与非洲国家经常互动和接触的组织，他指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所有这些都表明，无论谁担任中国最高职位，中非关系实际上是多么制度化和结构化。可以预见，中非关系的未来是建立在长期积累的基础上的。 “这不是一种临时关系，也不是一系列事件。”南图亚说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月在北京举行的非洲日招待会上，秦表示，中非关系随着“加速按钮”的发展而发展。 and entered a fast track towards a “new era of a stronger China-Africa community with a shared future”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said China and Africa enjoyed close friendly exchanges and “ever-deepening win-win cooperation”, and that “leaders of the two sides visit each other as often as relatives do”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Yuyuan, deputy director of the Centre for West Asian and African Studies at the Shanghai Institutes for International Studies, said China- Africa cooperation had made significant contributions to the continent&#39;s development, including improving transport and energy infrastructure, electricity, industrial development and job creation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The reality has proven China a credible friend and partner,” he said.&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Zhou added that because of multiple internal and external shocks, African countries faced severe development and security challenges and might want China to play a more positive role on a bilateral, multilateral and international level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“China has given high importance to building close ties with Africa, as we can see the rapid development and significant progress of China-African cooperation in the past decades,” Zhou said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mandira Bagwandeen, senior researcher at the University of Cape Town&#39;s Nelson Mandela School of Public Governance, said China also sought to strengthen relations and possibly use its tried-and-tested tactic of “chequebook diplomacy” to secure votes at the United Nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; For example, she said, the African vote played a significant role in quashing a US-led proposal at the UN last year to debate the alleged mistreatment and abuse of Uygurs and members of other Muslim minority groups in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;China&#39;s belt and road funding in sub-Saharan Africa falls to historical low&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Bagwandeen said China, which aimed to be a global leader in renewable energy, wanted to secure the lion&#39;s share in the scramble for Africa&#39;s critical minerals , which are necessary for the transition to a low-carbon economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With the US showing that it is willing to challenge China in international [forums], such as at the UN, China needs to maintain and shore up relations with African states.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China knows very well how decisive the African vote can be in multilateral settings,” Bagwandeen said, pointing to Beijing&#39;s experience unseating Taiwan at the UN in 1971.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Benjamin Barton, an associate professor at the University of Nottingham Malaysia, said that given China&#39;s role as a rising power and key constituent of the Global South, “it is very much in the interest of African leaders to maintain cordial ties with a country which may, in the not-so-distant future, play an even more determinant role in global politics than it currently does”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Barton said there was a sense that the conflict in Ukraine and attempts by the West to isolate Russia internationally, as well as Russian counter-diplomacy to legitimise its war effort, had spurred the Chinese foreign policy establishment into action in Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Indeed, Africa is quickly becoming – yet again – a proxy battleground between the West and Russia for geopolitical influence against the backdrop of the war in Ukraine,” Barton said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But despite the pomp and pageantry of African leaders&#39; visits, some have left China without the goodies – such as mega-project funding – they could expect just a few years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bagwandeen said the Chinese economy was still reeling from the impact of Covid-19, and many African nations were struggling to make repayments on their Chinese loans, which had likely made Beijing wary of lending to countries on the continent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This in no way means that China will completely stop lending – it just means that it will be more prudent and is likely to favour smaller commercial lending packages worth millions instead of billions of dollars,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nantulya said China had become more cautious and risk-averse when it came to certain types of aid it had previously given liberally to its African partners. For example, despite major overtures by Kenya, China has held firm in refusing to take part in the extension of the Chinese-built and financed Mombasa-Nairobi-Naivasha Standard Gauge Railway to Malaba on the Ugandan border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Barton said China was increasingly conservative in its financial promises to African leaders during their visits to the country, which was in line with the reduced financial promises Beijing made during the 2021 Forum on China–Africa Cooperation (FOCAC) ministerial meeting in Dakar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The nature of talks may be leaning more towards issues of debt restructuring, solvency and relief than simply new and unfettered lines of credit and trade creation,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘No success excluding half’: German FM says more women needed in conflict resolution]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225981/no-success-excluding-half-german-fm-says-more-women-needed-conflict-resolution?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 20:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/f6075327-22e0-4510-a55b-0b0860019a64_4557bfc6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock has called for more women to be involved in resolving international crises and conflicts at a meeting centred on feminist foreign policy in the Mongolian capital of Ulaanbaatar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“No society on Earth can be successful if you exclude half of your population,” Germany&#39;s top diplomat said on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting of women foreign ministers from Asia, Africa and Europe focuses on the role of women in promoting peace and security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should organise more strongly to cooperate, but also to learn from each other,” Baerbock said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Talking about universal human rights, she said, also means talking about women&#39;s rights, which is “in line with three R&#39;s – rights, representation and resources. And as long these three R&#39;s are not being fulfilled as they are fulfilled for men, something is wrong in society”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South African Foreign Minister Naledi Pandor also stressed the importance of including women in peace and diplomacy efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When you have women in the room, they change the focus of the negotiations to a more inclusive discussion,” Pandor said. If women are absent, the focus is on power and structures, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taliban leader claims Afghan women have &#39;free, comfortable, prosperous life&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“But when women are there, suddenly equality is discussed,” Pandor added. Socio-economic rights are also addressed, so there is a broader discussion, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the concept of feminist foreign policy, Baerbock plans to involve women more often in conflict resolution mechanisms for international crises.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: chairman of YMTC, China’s top memory chip maker, warns of ‘turbulence and disorder’ in semiconductor sector amid geopolitical tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3225983/tech-war-chairman-ymtc-chinas-top-memory-chip-maker-warns-turbulence-and-disorder-semiconductor?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 20:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/01ce0b8a-4460-45f5-bb5f-a7f5ff244089_c80e145d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The global semiconductor industry is facing turbulence because of rising geopolitical tensions and the national security concerns of some countries, threatening the sector&#39;s future growth, according to the head of Chinese chip maker Yangtze Memory Technologies Co (YMTC).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Nanxiang, chairman and acting chief executive of top Chinese memory chip maker YMTC, warned that “significant uncertainties” lie ahead for the industry owing to those disruptions in his keynote presentation at Thursday&#39;s opening in Shanghai of the three-day trade show Semicon China, the world&#39;s largest semiconductor exhibition and conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his 20-minute speech, Chen expressed his disappointment at how the chip industry has become more about “controlling the value chain, reducing risks and inhibiting the development of other countries”, which has upset industrial harmony and balance across the sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The YMTC chairman, without elaborating on the challenges confronting his company, indicated that “turbulence and disorder” are now the new norm in the semiconductor industry, following a half-century of vigorous growth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The speech by Chen offered a first-hand impression from the head of a major Chinese semiconductor enterprise about the current business prospects in the industry amid US-led trade sanctions, which have derailed the mainland&#39;s chip self-sufficiency efforts and its standing in global supply chains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;YMTC had been hit hard by export controls on chip-making machinery, imposed by the US Commerce Department last October, which aim to cap China&#39;s logic semiconductor production at the 14-nanometre node process, and DRAM and NAND flash at 18-nm and 128 layers, respectively.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, the company was said to be laying off as much as 10 per cent of its nearly 6,000 workforce, according to a Post report in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Founded in 2016 in Wuhan, capital of central Hubei province, YMTC was a latecomer to the NAND Flash chip sector, but raced ahead to become a leading company in the market. A TechInsights report in December credited YMTC with producing “232-layer NAND Flash, ahead of its rivals”, including Samsung Electronics, SK Hynix and Micron Technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;YMTC&#39;s Chen highlighted in his speech how “harmonious” globalisation is threatened, as geopolitical tensions have affected market competition, innovation and technology standards, supply chain, mobility of talent and allocation of resources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past 30 years, China&#39;s semiconductor market has developed rapidly with more than 80 per cent of the market supplied by foreign companies, according to Chen. Similarly in the US, more than 60 per cent of chip products come from non-American companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This demonstrates that the globalisation of markets and competition are significant driving factors for the development of our industry,” Chen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He indicated that nearly 50 countries are directly or indirectly involved in the global industrial system, forming a balanced global supply chain.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China needs to foster &#39;cooperation&#39; to break US tech restrictions, says chip expert&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But with traditional resource allocation being disrupted, Chen said there has been an increase in resources and investments flowing into the US and countries that were not considered major chip hubs before, including Singapore, India, Malaysia and Vietnam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As countries like the US, Japan and South Korea double down on manufacturing capabilities, he warned that these economies could see an oversupply in chip production facilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 1,100 companies are expected to take part in Semicon China, which concludes this Saturday, according to event organiser Semiconductor Equipment and Materials International.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong government to sell only 2 plots of residential land in second quarter of financial year amid weak market sentiment]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3225978/hong-kong-government-sell-only-two-plots-residential-land-second-quarter-financial-year-amid-weak?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 19:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/e0531e2a-4378-47f9-b25e-3e1d42b2ddbc_89b43cd2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s government has defied market expectations by announcing it will sell only two plots of residential land in the second quarter of the financial year – about half the number forecast by some analysts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The parcels in Kai Tak, the site of Hong Kong&#39;s former international airport, and Tung Chung on Lantau Island, which will provide 1,739 flats in total, will be put up for tender between July and September, Secretary for Development Bernadette Linn Hon-ho said on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The provision is smaller than the 2,400 flats from two sites offered in the three months to June, which are in Kennedy Town and Tsuen Wan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the total supply for the first half of the financial year – including private developments – is expected to support some 8,280 flats, which is about 65 per cent of the government&#39;s annual target for housing, Linn said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts suggested the surprisingly small offering of land in the second quarter may reflect the gloomy market conditions, though the government denied this was a factor in its decision.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A rapid succession of interest rate increases has cast a long shadow over a growing property oversupply that is being exacerbated by newly built flats coming onto the market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The current sentiment in the land market is not particularly good. In fact, there is a risk of having the tender withdrawn,” said Cyrus Fong, senior director, head of valuation and advisory at Knight Frank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Generally developers would be conservative in bidding for the tender due to the uncertainty in the economy as well as the interest rate hikes.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alex Leung, senior director at CHFT Advisory and Appraisal, had predicted four or five plots of land would go up for grabs in the second quarter of the financial year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The interest rate remains the main adverse factors,” he said. “Developers would not be willing to offer aggressive prices.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rising construction costs are likely to be another factor that would deter developers from investing in land at the moment, according to James Cheung, executive director at Centaline Surveyors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also, the reopening of Hong Kong&#39;s international borders did not generate the expected surge of Chinese buyers back to the city&#39;s property market, Cheung added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The land sales plan comes after prices of lived-in homes in Hong Kong fell in May for the first time this year, as looming interest rate increases dampen demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Linn denied that the decision to sell off just two sites had anything to do with the slowing market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For government land sales, we primarily cater to our economic and housing land needs,” she said. “We cannot only sell land when the market is very good. The government does not [look at] market prices.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Book Fair’s 760 exhibitors urged to abide by national security law as event returns to city on July 19]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3225979/hong-kong-book-fairs-760-exhibitors-urged-abide-national-security-law-event-returns-city-july-19?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 19:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/0cb5f3f0-9993-4e16-8de6-b6dd24f41d93_ccc22cf4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong Book Fair organisers have urged exhibitors to only offer titles that conformed with the national security law, as they expected a huge number of visitors from neighbouring mainland cities in the first post-pandemic show despite an admission fee hike.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The annual week-long fair will run from July 19 to 25 and feature about 760 exhibitors. Admission is HK$30 (US$3.80), up from last year&#39;s HK$25.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Trade Development Council, which is organising the fair, said the theme this year was children&#39;s and young adult literature, adding it had reminded exhibitors to follow the law when selecting their offerings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We do ask our exhibitors to abide by Hong Kong law, and that includes the national security law,” said Sophia Chong Suk-fan, deputy director of the council.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We do not apply any censorship on any of the publications in the book fair, as long as they belong to [Class] I,” she added, referring to the category of publications that are suitable to be distributed to any age group under the Control of Obscene and Indecent Articles Ordinance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We do not have lists of books that could or could not be displayed, as we trust our exhibitors,” Chong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added the council occasionally received complaints about books in the past, which they relayed to the exhibitors. But it was up to them to remove the offending titles, she stressed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong Book Fair 2022 closes with total of 850,000 visitors&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The fair, with a 33-year history, will be held alongside the Hong Kong Sports and Leisure Expo and the World of Snacks event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Holders of full-day tickets bought for the first two days of the fair will be able to visit the event two more times after 7pm between July 21 and 24.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chong said the price increase was in response to inflation and the higher statutory minimum wage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year more than 700 exhibitors took part in the fair, attracting 850,000 visitors, who on average spent HK$879. Attendees had to use the government&#39;s Covid risk-exposure app and produce valid vaccine passes.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Challenged books&#39; swept off Hong Kong library shelves, but what about shops?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“This year, more people are expected to come across the border,” Chong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She cited the opening of the MTR Exhibition Centre station, which makes it convenient for travellers from Shenzhen to get to the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre, where the book fair would be held.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We anticipate a big crowd from the Greater Bay Area,” she said, referring to the national strategy to integrate Hong Kong, Macau and nine southern mainland cities into an economic powerhouse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Applications for booths from two publishers, Hillway Culture and One of a Kind, were rejected for the 2022 event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hillway Culture was founded by political activist Raymond Yeung Tsz-chun, who was jailed for nine months last August after he pleaded guilty to two charges of unlawful assembly over his role in the 2019 anti-government unrest.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Organiser dismisses suggestions of censorship at Hong Kong Book Fair&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;One of a Kind published books on the 2019 protests and 2014&#39;s Occupy movement, a civil disobedience campaign.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last fair featured independent publishers and bookstores such as Passiontimes, The Bookland and Bbluesky.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chong said some applications for booths were rejected this year but declined to comment on individual cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trade council updated the full exhibitor list on Thursday afternoon, and a check by the Post found the three independent publishers that took part last year were returning to the event.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>