<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[A China-brokered peace deal on the Korean peninsula would be a victory for everyone]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3225063/china-brokered-peace-deal-korean-peninsula-would-be-victory-everyone?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.26 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/48cfce65-b9fe-4b11-9e30-20f524893127_8da72840.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国可以通过促成朝鲜半岛期待已久的和平。这是北京应该与首尔密切合作开展的一个项目，意味着消除半岛上的所有核武器，促进朝韩两国的经济繁荣，并为撤走所有美军铺平道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要做到这一点，必须满足三个条件。首先，中国必须停止敌对态度，转而奉行以地区共同利益为中心的外交政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正如前苏联领导人戈尔巴乔夫曾经指出的那样，外交政策是国内政策的延续。这使得意识形态与外交政策密不可分 — — 正如中国中将景剑锋最近在新加坡香格里拉对话会上谴责拜登政府试图“将世界划分为意识形态驱动的阵营并挑起对抗”所体现的那样。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;和平、发展、公平、正义、民主、自由是习近平主席在全球文明倡议中提出的诉求。这些可能是中国外交政策的主要原则，在涉及朝鲜半岛时尤其重要。如果习近平能抓住这个机会稳定半岛局势，这将体现他的政治家风范。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二，中国必须与韩国建立战略伙伴关系，共同推出朝鲜无核化政策。这必须是包括美国在内的所有利益攸关方都会认可的提案。然后，北京在首尔、华盛顿和其他国家的支持下，可以提出平壤无法拒绝的一揽子协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议必须包括取消制裁、安全保障以及与韩国签订和平条约以及朝鲜经济现代化所需的充足资金。作为回报，金正恩政权可以实施市场导向的改革，用友好的意识形态取代敌对的意识形态。必须说服朝鲜作为无核武器国家为全球和平与发展做出贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三，朝鲜必须停止发射弹道导弹和其他此类挑衅行为，这为拜登政府提供了借口让美军在附近。一旦半岛实现持久和平稳定和经济共同繁荣，美国将不再有理由在韩国驻军。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，朝鲜半岛及其周边地区的局势正在恶化。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首先，冲突将世界主要分为两个阵营，从而加剧了地缘政治两极分化。中国拒绝谴责俄罗斯及其与莫斯科的“无限”友谊，这意味着它们被视为站在同一边，而朝鲜则热衷于鼓励与其两个邻国结成三边联盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为回应，美国巩固了其在亚太地区的伙伴关系，包括与日本和韩国的三边联盟、四边安全对话和印太经济框架。随后，许多亚洲国家的安全严重依赖美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种两极分化推动了美国的遏制中国政策，人们普遍认为这是为了阻止中国的崛起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 其次，中美两国都加大了利用经济胁迫来实现政策目标的力度。就韩国而言，中国的战略适得其反。 2017年，北京暂停了赴韩国的团体旅游，以回应首尔决定部署美国控制的萨德系统，萨德系统是一个由雷达和拦截器组成的网络，旨在拦截来袭的弹道导弹。据估计，在短短 2.5 年内，韩国的旅游收入损失就高达 240 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国现在正在远离中国，向美国和日本倾斜。它与美国定期举行军事演习，并拥有美国现代战略军事资产。去年，美国自2004年以来首次取代中国成为韩国出口的最大市场。在首尔面对共同的安全挑战寻求缓和之后，韩国与日本的关系也迅速升温。&lt;/p>;&lt;第三，日益强硬的韩国促使朝鲜宣布自己为法律上的核武器国家，并增加军事挑衅和导弹试验，包括远程洲际弹道导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这事态升级造成了严重的地区紧张局势，迫使各国考虑增加国防预算。关于韩国​​和日本发展自己的核武器计划的讨论不断扩大，这令中国感到不安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据其全球文明倡议，习近平必须扭转这些趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;朝鲜半岛和平重复失败的强硬手段不会赢得半岛胜利&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国必须坚持“人类共同价值观”，并将其应用于朝鲜半岛的外交政策指示中。只有实现半岛的永久和平、繁荣和经济共同发展，中国才能消除美军在朝鲜侵略时作为安全保障者的作用，并保持朝鲜作为中美在韩国影响力之间的缓冲区。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜无核化的伟大壮举不仅会结束美国在半岛的军事存在，还会结束美国在朝鲜半岛的军事存在。它还将为中国和平崛起为世界强国铺平道路，并在此过程中重新定义其与美国的关系。它还将为与台湾的统一创造有利的环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于习近平来说，该项目的成功意味着他将因采取如此大胆的举措而被誉为世界杰出的政治家。他将通过领导和实施一项互惠互利的朝鲜无核化一揽子协议，留下最好的遗产。如此巨大的成就只能是韩国、中国、朝鲜和美国的双赢结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 26 Jun 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Sudan’s paramilitary RSF claims it seized police camp as fighting rages in capital Khartoum]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3225342/sudans-paramilitary-rsf-claims-it-seized-police-camp-fighting-rages-capital-khartoum?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.26 02:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/26/c6a9c46b-9611-44d3-a67a-85a1fe599675_6b63f966.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;苏丹准军事快速支援部队 (RSF) 表示已占领了一支重型部队的总部周日，武装警察部队在首都喀土穆的激烈战斗中寻求与军队的战争中的优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无国界医生组织在一份声明中表示，它已经完全控制了属于中央政府的营地后备警察在喀土穆南部部署，并发布了其战士在该设施内的镜头，其中一些人从仓库中取出了弹药箱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社无法立即核实该镜头或无国界医生的声明。军队或警方没有立即发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自周六晚些时候以来，随着军队之间的冲突，构成首都的三个城市——喀土穆、巴赫里和恩图曼——的战斗激增。无国界医生组织进入第11周。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目击者还报告称，西达尔富尔地区最大城市尼亚拉的暴力事件近日急剧增加。联合国周六对西达尔富尔州埃尔朱奈纳的马萨利特社区的族裔袭击和杀害事件发出警报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;喀土穆和朱奈纳受战争影响最严重，尽管上周局势紧张达尔富尔其他地区和南部科尔多凡州的冲突升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于美国和沙特阿拉伯在吉达举行的会谈中达成的一系列停火协议未能坚持，战斗加剧。会谈于上周休会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近几周，中央后备警察已被军队部署到地面战斗中。它此前曾在多个地区被用作战斗部队，并对抗 2021 年反对政变的抗议者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它去年受到美国制裁，被指控对抗议者过度使用武力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;阿卜杜勒·法塔赫·布尔汉 (Abdel Fattah al-Burhan) 领导的军队一直在使用空袭和重型火炮，试图将穆罕默德·哈姆丹·达加洛 (Mohamed Hamdan Dagalo)（又名赫梅蒂 (Hemedti)）领导的无国界支援部队从首都各地的社区赶走。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“从清晨开始，恩图曼北部就遭到了空袭、炮击和无国界医生组织的防空火力，”47 岁的居民穆罕默德·萨马尼 (Mohamed al-Samani) 通过电话告诉路透社。 “吉达谈判在哪里，为什么世界让我们在布尔汉和赫梅蒂的战争中独自死去？”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;捐助者承诺提供 15 亿美元，以遏制苏丹滑向“死亡和毁灭”&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;2003 年之后，在达尔富尔爆发的冲突中，人们流离失所，尼亚拉因此而迅速发展。目击者称，过去几天安全局势明显恶化，居民区发生暴力冲突。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;“今天我因为战争而离开尼亚拉。该市 38 岁居民萨利赫·哈龙 (Saleh Haroun) 告诉路透社，昨天街道上发生了轰炸，子弹射入了房屋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周军队和无国界医生组织之间还发生了战斗北达尔富尔州首府法希尔周围，联合国称人道主义工作者无法进入该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在朱奈纳，近几周通信网络和援助供应几乎完全被切断，阿拉伯人发动袭击民兵和无国界部队已将数万人送往乍得。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，联合国人权事务发言人拉维娜·沙姆达萨尼 (Ravina Shamdasani) 在总结报告后呼吁为逃离朱奈纳的人们提供安全通道，并为援助人员提供通道城市和边境之间的处决以及“持续的仇恨言论”，包括呼吁杀死马萨利特人或驱逐他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在因苏丹冲突而背井离乡的人中，近 200 万人在国内流离失所，近 60 万人流离失所。根据国际移民组织的数据，逃往邻国。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 26 Jun 2023 02:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Belarus strongman Lukashenko sows future peril with Wagner PR success, say analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225339/belarus-strongman-lukashenko-sows-future-peril-wagner-pr-success-say-analysts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.26 01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/e400fd78-206e-4a39-a1a2-aebbeefdb4c1_75db1167.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;白俄罗斯领导人亚历山大·卢卡申科通过促成避免威胁的协议取得了宣传胜利观察人士称，俄罗斯爆发了内部武装冲突，但可能会对俄罗斯接待瓦格纳雇佣军首领叶夫根尼·普里戈津的协议感到遗憾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周六晚间的一份令人惊讶的声明中，卢卡申科的新闻部门表示，他已经在俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京的批准下，瓦格纳老板花了一整天的时间与普里戈任进行谈判，瓦格纳老板同意停止向莫斯科推进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一消息对卢卡申科来说是一个提振，他已经统治了一个国家与三个欧盟国家接壤近 30 年，但自 2020 年有争议的选举以来一直被西方视为贱民，现在还因为他支持俄罗斯入侵乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也是在一个棘手的时期发生的上个月，这位 68 岁的领导人在莫斯科举行的一年一度的二战胜利仪式上，由于看上去很糟糕，他的健康状况受到了重大质疑，然后就从人们的视线中消失了几天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据卢卡申科斡旋的协议克里姆林宫宣布，普里戈任未来将流亡白俄罗斯。目前尚不清楚他是否会携带瓦格纳民兵成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据白俄罗斯总统称，普京在深夜的电话中感谢卢卡申科的工作，这对白俄罗斯人来说一定是美妙的音乐&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但伦敦欧洲领导力网络的俄罗斯-西方政策研究员卡蒂亚·格洛德表示，普里戈任很可能是被普京“甩给”卢卡申科的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不认为这是卢卡申科本人的意愿。我认为他被克里姆林宫利用了。他宁愿没有普里戈任。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在白俄罗斯的存在将给这片土地带来“多重风险”，在 2020 年选举之后进行大规模选举后，安全部队的忠诚度至关重要。她说，街头抗议和残酷镇压。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“卢卡申科唯一的好处是，他可能想利用普里戈任作为私人军队来对抗任何潜在的叛乱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立陶宛总统吉塔纳斯·瑙塞达（该国下个月将主办北约峰会）警告说，“如果普里戈任或瓦格纳集团的一部分最终以不明确的计划和不明确的意图进入白俄罗斯”，该联盟将需要加强其东部边界。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;自 2020 年以来，卢卡申科越来越依赖克里姆林宫对他未来政治生存的支持，在与普京的定期会晤中总是以小伙伴的身份出现。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;冒充俄罗斯人参加乌克兰战争的中国影响者曝光欺诈&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在卢卡申科和普京达成协议后，白俄罗斯现在拥有俄罗斯战术核武器，这是政策的巨大变化，也是反对派认为白俄罗斯丧失主权的象征。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国际战略研究所 (IISS) 战略、技术和军备控制主任威廉·阿尔伯克 (William Alberque) 表示：“将核武器投入白俄罗斯领土意味着俄罗斯正在缓慢吞并白俄罗斯。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我认为卢卡申科已经感觉自己被逼到了墙角。显然，如果普京说‘帮我一个忙’，他就会这样做，希望这能为他带来某种筹码。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于白俄罗斯反对派来说，其领导人斯维特兰娜·蒂哈诺夫斯卡娅(Svetlana Tikhanovskaya)在事件发生后流亡在她声称赢得的有争议的选举中，卢卡申科对俄罗斯的完全依赖使他的举动变得危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着俄罗斯安全危机迅速展开，美国与盟友进行磋商&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“普里戈任不是一个白俄罗斯前外交官兼文化部长帕维尔·拉图什科（Pavel Latushko）现在是反对派的一员，他表示，“因为独裁者普京永远不会原谅他在普里戈任手下所遭受的羞辱，所以卢卡申科出席了会议。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这对于卢卡申科来说，这是一次小规模的、战术性的、人为的、肤浅的胜利，可能会变成独裁者本人的战略问题。”他在波兰 Nexta 反对派 Telegram 频道发布的视频评论中补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾经描述过卢卡申科被美国称为“欧洲最后一个独裁政权”，他有时会削减在白俄罗斯的反复无常的存在，经常看到在田地里割草或种植蔬菜以及进行体育运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但活动人士表示，内部镇压已经加剧据维亚斯纳人权组织称，自 2020 年抗议活动以来，目前约有 1,500 人被当作政治犯关押，其中包括蒂卡诺夫斯卡娅的同僚反对派领袖玛丽亚·科列斯尼科娃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格洛德将卢卡申科的统治描述为基于两大支柱：暴力和来自外部的支持俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他现在显然很担心，因为克里姆林宫并不像看上去那么强大，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汉娜·刘巴科娃 (Hanna Liubakova)，大西洋月刊非常驻研究员委员会表示，虽然卢卡申科的地位可以通过调解得到加强，但“从长远来看，他的政权将面临后果”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢卡申科对克里姆林宫表现出了“坚定不移的忠诚”，但下了一个“冒险的赌注” ”关于俄罗斯迅速赢得乌克兰之战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着普京权威的削弱，明斯克​​政权可能会发现自己得到俄罗斯的支持和支持减少，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 26 Jun 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Greek conservatives lead in repeat election; Mitsotakis set to clinch second term]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225341/greek-conservatives-lead-repeat-election-mitsotakis-set-clinch-second-term?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.26 01:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/26/8610d3ad-4bca-464a-b511-a5788a8ff8b6_d34fadf4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;希腊保守派新民主党在周日的议会选举（出口民意调查）中遥遥领先前总理基里亚科斯·米佐塔基斯 (Kyriakos Mitsotakis) 即将连任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新民主党以 40-44% 的得票率领先，左翼激进联盟党以 16.3-19.3% 的得票率落后，由六家民意调查公司联合为希腊电视台进行的出口民意调查显示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日的投票是过去五周内的第二次投票，因为 5 月 21 日在不同选举制度下举行的第一次民意调查未能成功。在300个席位的议会中给予单一政党绝对多数。周日民意调查中使用的系统根据选民的支持给予主要政党额外席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 5 月份的民意调查中，新民主党以 20 个百分点的两位数优势领先激进左翼联盟 (Syriza)，后者于 2015 年至 2015 年统治希腊。 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近几天的民意调查显示，新民主党以约 40% 的选票获胜，亚历克西斯·齐普拉斯 (Alexis Tsipras) 领导的激进左翼联盟 (Syriza) 获得约 20% 的选票，与 5 月 21 日的民意调查大致相似。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;米佐塔基斯自 2019 年起担任总理，直到 5 月投票结果无结果后下台，转而支持看守总理。在一场严重的债务危机重创国家之后，米佐塔基斯发誓要推进改革，重建国家的信用评级。米佐塔基斯曾担任银行家，出身于一个强大的政治家族，他承诺增加重要旅游业的收入，创造就业机会，并将工资提高到接近欧盟平均水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;希腊议员因船难后发表评论而被驱逐&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Covid-19 大流行和 2 月份致命的铁路事故也暴露了卫生和公共交通系统的缺陷。但生活成本危机和经济困难最近成为选民最关心的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我对（新政府）寄予厚望，”养老金领取者 Giorgos Katzimertzis 告诉路透社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “最重要的是卫生系统和经济，这样我们才能（体面地）生活，因为事情很困难。我是一名养老金领取者，我曾在消防队工作过，现在我一毛钱都没有了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日的选举是在本月发生的移民沉船事件的阴影下举行的，人们担心数百人会因此丧生。在希腊南部海域灭亡。这是多年来最严重的此类灾难之一，暴露了各党派在移民问题上的分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沉船灾难主导了这次选举前的竞选活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;救援人员发现了 104 个人幸存者并找到了 82 具尸体，但据信这艘摇摇欲坠的船上载有多达 750 人，该船正从利比亚开往意大利。这艘船一直受到希腊海岸警卫队的跟踪，希腊海岸警卫队表示，船上的人拒绝了所有提供的帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;米佐塔基斯政府对移民采取了强硬立场，他将这场灾难归咎于“可怜的人口贩子”，并赞扬了海岸警卫队救援人员。齐普拉斯质疑海岸警卫队为何不早点干预。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 26 Jun 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[No reason US and China can’t renew cooperation in health sciences and combating opioid misuse]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3225115/no-reason-us-and-china-cant-renew-cooperation-health-sciences-and-combating-opioid-misuse?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.26 01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/23/23b6248e-a5d7-4bed-8b13-53c0317a027d_73e08b15.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在最近举行的会议之后，并未强调恢复公共卫生合作作为可交付成果。中美外交官之间的北京合作，但值得双方共同努力，保持这一势头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯出访前几天，美国和中国药品监管部门的高级官员在北京举行了会面。北京并“就2023年及未来的合作交换了意见”。这次会议标志着两个机构之间暂停接触的结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在促进两个社会之间的公共卫生合作方面有两个问题很突出。首先是科学合作协议的命运。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去的四十年中，美国和中国的卫生科学家、大学和研究实验室之间的合作项目得到了 1979 年双边伞式科学技术协议的支持。 。随着医药和保健行业更加紧密地联系在一起，两国公民都受益匪浅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国正在讨论续签定于今年 8 月举行的协议。这场争论一直在新闻中出现，因为上一次更新是在 2018 年，但在唐纳德·特朗普政府的“极限施压”行动中却被漏掉了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，近年来，政府认可的健康科学合作已经开始发展。遭受了严重的削减。部分原因是，2000年代，美国从中国采购药品（非专利药和活性药物成分）的水平不断提高，逐渐成为一个政治问题。确定美国的依赖程度本身就是一项复杂的任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国应该加强而不是切断与中国的科学联系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;更糟糕的是，除了对供应依赖的担忧之外，还出现了担忧关于中国将药品出口武器化的声音随着2019年针锋相对的贸易关税和出口限制全面启动而愈演愈烈。不过，到目前为止，没有证据表明任何一方对待药品或医疗产品贸易作为一个国家安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，更复杂的是，国家安全已经渗透到两国卫生部门之间剩余的合作中。正如中美医疗保健二轨对话的参与者在 2022 年协议中所写，“（美国和中国）政府基于数据安全和更广泛的国家安全考虑，限制了数据和研究的交换，且定义往往模糊” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，没有理由不续签协议——考虑到所有因素，医学和医学科学的进步应该占上风。即使在两国关系高度紧张的时期，中国作为世界上人口最多的国家之一的地位也使其成为美国研究人员和开发人员的丰富的医学和医疗数据来源。这一事实违背了外交偏好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对中国同样重要的是，拜登政府将生物技术确定为“去风险”目标，不应限制与包括美国在内的任何人的合作空间。为了保护公共卫生和改善本国人民的生活，就续签协议进行善意谈判是正确的做法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个问题与美国对疫情水平的评估有关。中国采取行动帮助遏制美国的阿片类药物流行。控制芬太尼前体从中国的流入是美国政坛的标准话题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国于1996年首次制定芬太尼使用和出口法规。2015年，它涵盖了6种芬太尼类似物和110种其他医药化学品2018年，又对4种芬太尼类似物及芬太尼相关化学品实施管制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年11月，中美禁毒执法机构联合破获一起芬太尼走私案，河北省邢台市对不法分子的一审结束。这是在政府间合作水平普遍较低的背景下发生的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正如美国驻华大使尼古拉斯·伯恩斯上个月在谈到芬太尼的流动时所说，“北京政府没有做出贡献”到这个问题”。任务是加强国际合作，惩罚向美国运送非法前体化学品和产品的中国黑市公司和跨国犯罪网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;助长美国芬太尼流行的中国供应商&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这种合作并不是中国给美国的恩惠。相反，了解美国境内阿片类药物监管和治疗方面的挑战对于中国公共卫生从业者和监管者来说可能很有价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和美国人之间关注关系状况的未来讨论应该使阿片类药物 –尤其是芬太尼——医学研究、药品生产和贸易以及公共卫生方面专家的关注和参与。此类交流还应旨在就化学前体的跨境流动、止痛药物的制造以及非法跨境流动达成共识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后但并非最不重要的一点是，政府与政府之间关系的解冻。 ——中美政府接触无论多么初步，都是以保护两国人民福祉为前提的。对于两国来说，有充分理由将续签科学协议和加强解决芬太尼和其他阿片类药物滥用问题的对话作为以人民为中心的外交的体现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 26 Jun 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Airport worker dies after being sucked into passenger plane engine]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225340/airport-worker-dies-after-being-sucked-passenger-plane-engine?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.26 00:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/26/f885b0e6-9878-459a-aaee-8a2d8bbb176f_2f03a4a6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国监管机构周日表示，他们正在调查德克萨斯州机场工作人员被撞的事件被吸入客机发动机后身亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达美航空的一架航班于周五晚上从洛杉矶抵达德克萨斯州圣安东尼奥市，正在滑行至登机口，其中一台发动机还开着，“当时一名工作人员国家运输安全委员会 (NTSB) 在一份声明中告诉法新社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“NTSB 正在继续收集有关该事件的信息。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据当地媒体报道，这名工人受雇于 Unifi Aviation，该公司与该航空公司巨头签订地勤业务合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达美航空告诉圣安东尼奥广播公司 KENS 5，该公司“深感悲痛”周五晚上发生的事件，并表示“正在配合当局开始调查。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国机组人员使用套索束缚试图打开出口门的吸毒男子&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Unifi Aviation 告诉广播公司，该事件是“一场悲惨事故”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据我们的初步调查，该事件与 Unifi 的运营流程、安全程序和政策无关，”该公司表示。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;周三，支线航空公司皮埃蒙特航空公司因去年在类似事件中导致一名地勤人员死亡而被另一监管机构职业安全与健康管理局 (OSHA) 罚款 15,625 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; OSHA 官员表示：“适当的培训和执行安全程序本来可以避免这场悲剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;皮埃蒙特是美国航空公司的子公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1 killed, 7 injured in Sweden roller coaster crash, including children]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225338/1-killed-7-injured-sweden-roller-coaster-crash-including-children?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 22:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/ba396920-ee44-4e5c-a1a2-df4ca0a48e29_a348a358.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在一场过山车事故中，造成 1 人死亡、7 人受伤，其中包括儿童公园官员和警方称，周日，瑞典首都斯德哥尔摩的格罗纳隆德游乐园发生了事故。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目击者称，该公园的捷特线过山车在乘坐过程中部分脱轨，导致人们坠落到地上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“这是一场悲剧，令人震惊，令人遗憾的是，我们得知有人死亡，”格罗纳隆德发言人 Annika Troselius 告诉公共广播公司 SVT。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;救护车、消防车和一架直升机看到抵达公园，警方展开调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方表示受伤者中有儿童和成人，但拒绝就受伤程度发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grona Lund 说在一份声明中，这座拥有 140 年历史的公园已关闭，直至另行通知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与家人一起参观该公园的记者珍妮·拉格斯泰特 (Jenny Lagerstedt) 告诉 SVT，她就在附近，听到了金属噪音，并注意到了跑道事故发生时结构正在摇晃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我丈夫看到一辆过山车，里面的人掉到地上，”拉格斯泰特说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的孩子们很害怕”，她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;钢轨 Jetline 过山车的速度可达每小时 90 公里（56 英里/小时），高度为 98 英尺（30 米），每年运送超过 100 万游客，游乐园在其网站上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瑞典文化部长帕里萨·利杰斯特兰德 (Parisa Liljestrand) 表示，有关事故的消息令人难以理解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的心与受影响的人和他们的家人在一起和亲人，”利杰斯特兰德在一份声明中说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[6 Hongkongers in Russia seek immigration help after aborted mutiny by Wagner mercenaries, as tensions remain high]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3225337/6-hongkongers-russia-seek-immigration-help-after-aborted-mutiny-wagner-mercenaries-tensions-remain?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 22:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/25/fa94149a-72a6-433e-8db2-dbfcdd55594f_e85452a5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;瓦格纳雇佣兵在俄罗斯发动的叛变未遂，促使六名香港人向政府寻求帮助由于该国局势仍然高度紧张，香港保安局周日表示，目前没有计划立即升级对俄罗斯的旅行警告，但表示将密切关注事态发展，并向来自俄罗斯的旅客提供建议。入境事务处表示，到目前为止，已有六名在短暂武装叛乱后仍在香港的香港居民联系了他们，但他们不会透露讨论他们询问的性质或寻求的帮助。外交部补充说，已将案件转介至中国驻莫斯科大使馆，并提供了所要求的相关资料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“外交部驻港特派员公署将与这六名香港居民保持联系。”声明称，香港和中国大使馆将密切关注事态发展，积极跟进案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，黄色警报是该市三级旅行警告中的最低级别系统 - 对俄罗斯有效，这意味着存在“威胁迹象”，计划前往或已经在那里的香港人“应监视局势，保持谨慎并注意人身安全”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 2011年1月莫斯科多莫杰多沃机场发生致命炸弹袭击后，安全局于2011年向俄罗斯发布了黄色旅行警报。 In 2016, the bureau had also advised against “non-essential travel” to the North Caucasus and areas along the border with Ukraine, citing “unpredictable security situation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bureau on Sunday said it would closely monitor the situation in the country and asked residents who needed help to call the Immigration Department&#39;s 1868 helpline or contact the Chinese embassy in Russia at the consular protection hotline on 7-499-9518661.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russian megayacht Nord leaves Hong Kong waters for South Africa&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Travellers are also advised to register their contact details and itineraries through the government&#39;s online portal. “It will allow the Immigration Department to contact and assist them via suitable channels, including text message, when necessary,” the bureau said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Holders of Hong Kong passports are allowed visa-free stay in Russia for 14 days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the Travel Industry Council said it had not received any request for help from agencies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some local travel agencies contacted by the Post also said they had no tours operating in Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local media in the country have reported the invasion of Ukraine, and the subsequent sanctions by the West, led to a 90 per cent drop in inbound tourists on organised tours in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russian harpist stages Hong Kong concert to mark anniversary of Ukraine war&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The unprecedented challenge to Russian President Vladimir Putin was defused after Wagner Group mercenary leader Yevgeny Prigozhin agreed to go into exile in Belarus as part of a deal that guaranteed his safety and that of his troops.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the agreement appeared to end the immediate threat that Prigozhin&#39;s private army could storm Moscow, analysts said questions about Putin&#39;s grip on the country remained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apart from Russia, 21 other countries are on the Hong Kong government&#39;s amber alert list, including Britain, France, India, Myanmar, Sri Lanka, and Tunisia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Four countries are on the red travel alert list, which means there are “significant threats” and that residents should “avoid non-essential travel” or “adjust travel plans”. The four include Iran, Lebanon, Pakistan, and southeastern provinces of Turkey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government has asked residents to “avoid all travel” to Syria, which has been issued the black travel alert, indicating the presence of “severe threat” there.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese Premier Li Qiang’s Europe trip good for trade, but EU de-risking push makes matters ‘more complicated’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3225257/chinese-premier-li-qiangs-europe-trip-good-trade-eu-de-risking-push-makes-matters-more-complicated?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/24/e09b5c00-6b79-45f6-926b-1904b307fa2d_68cd717a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese Premier Li Qiang&#39;s trip to the top two European Union economies has helped to reboot trade ties with the bloc, but roadblocks remain as Brussels pushes its de-risking strategy with China, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li&#39;s visit to Germany and France last week was his first trip abroad since becoming premier in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Arriving in Germany on Sunday, he held high-level meetings with government officials including Chancellor Olaf Scholz and visited some of the biggest names in local manufacturing like BMW and Siemens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later in the week, Li was in Paris, where his itinerary included a global financing pact forum hosted by the president of France.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Senior officials accompanying Li included National Development and Reform Commission head Zheng Shanjie and Commerce Minister Wang Wentao. About a dozen cooperation agreements were signed during his six-day tour, including one on setting up a climate change and green transition dialogue mechanism with Germany and another on deeper cooperation with French aviation giant Airbus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, though his German and French hosts assured Li they would not seek decoupling with China, a recently released EU security road map emphasising a de-risking of Beijing ties still cast a shadow over his tour.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Charter flights and low-key tours mark a new approach for China&#39;s premier&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wang Yiwei, a professor of international relations at Renmin University and European studies specialist, said Li&#39;s trip would have a positive impact on putting China-EU relations “back on the right track”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With China&#39;s relations with France and Germany as the starting point, China and Europe&#39;s relationship is back on the right track. Economy and trade will gradually return to becoming the bedrock in China-EU relations,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Europe can make good use of China&#39;s huge market and its strengths in the green transformation,” Wang said. “At the same time, China can also seize [business opportunities that will become available] in Europe.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gregor Sebastian, economics analyst at the Germany-based Mercator Institute for China Studies think tank, said while the German economy could benefit from China&#39;s strengths in green tech, such as electric vehicle batteries, such cooperation could run counter to Brussels&#39; de-risking agenda.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hence, China was likely to bank on Germany – the EU&#39;s biggest economy – to help shape the bloc&#39;s de-risking strategy, with a greater emphasis on free and fair trade, according to Sebastian.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With regard to Brussels&#39; recent moves to strengthen trade defence instruments, China may seek Berlin&#39;s support in trying to maintain free trade between China and the EU,” he wrote in a note published on the think tank&#39;s website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li&#39;s visit to Europe came as the EU rolled out a plan to tighten outbound investment screening and export controls, especially on sensitive technologies, in a move seen as targeting China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While in Germany, Li discussed the idea of “de-risking” at a round table with top executives, saying the “greatest risk” was actually not to cooperate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We understand that all parties have their own security concerns, and what is important is how to reasonably define and prevent risks,” Li told the German business leaders. “Failure to cooperate is the greatest risk, and failure to develop is the greatest insecurity.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He doubled down on this idea when he met the business community in France on Wednesday, asserting that “mutual dependence” was an inevitable result of globalisation and promising a further opening up of China&#39;s market.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s Li Qiang warns of &#39;de-risking&#39; risks during Germany, France visits&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Scholz, often seen as maintaining a balancing act between China and the EU, reaffirmed that his country did not seek to decouple but would need to ensure “a level playing field” for German companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang at Renmin University said Germany was likely to still largely comply with the EU&#39;s “de-risking” strategy, but its own “smart de-risking” approach – proposed by Scholz – will play out differently across sectors. It will also allow German businesses greater flexibility in dealing with China, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But according to Ding Yifan, an expert on Europe and a senior fellow at the Beijing-based Taihe Institute think tank, Germany&#39;s de-risking approach will continue to cast a shadow over trade relations with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think it will be that easy [to reduce Germany&#39;s concerns about China],” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Although Germany did not say &#39;decoupling&#39;, in fact this is a very cunning approach … it can end its cooperation in the name of [de-risking] at any time.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ding had a more positive outlook on China&#39;s cooperation with France, given the “gentle” remarks by French President Emmanuel Macron.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron sparked a backlash during his visit to China along with European Commission chief Ursula von der Leyen in April, when he said the EU should not blindly follow the United States on its Taiwan policy, in remarks seen back home as favouring Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also objected to Nato&#39;s plans to open a liaison office in Japan, seen as an attempt to curb China&#39;s growing military presence in the Indo-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meeting Li in Paris on Thursday, Macron and French Prime Minister Elisabeth Borne spoke highly of bilateral relations and vowed to continue high-level strategic and economic dialogues with Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li and Borne witnessed the signing of multiple cooperation agreements in the aerospace and nuclear energy sectors. The Chinese premier also doubled down on his rejection of “decoupling”, while calling on the EU and France to maintain “strategic autonomy” – a term referring to policies independent of the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[France and China] are being pragmatic,” Renmin professor Wang said. “China and France will celebrate the 60th anniversary [of diplomatic relations] next year. Cultural and tourism activities are now in full swing. Economic and trade cooperation will pick up steam. I think this is a good sign.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French Finance Minister Bruno Le Maire, who attended the Sino-French business community dinner welcoming Li to Paris on Wednesday, also said he looked forward to more cooperation, while urging greater market access for French firms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Philippe Le Corre, a senior fellow at the Asia Society Policy Institute&#39;s Centre for China Analysis, said the French business community had yet to regain its confidence in the Chinese market after the country largely shut out foreign business under draconian Covid-19 control measures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think de-risking is the correct way to characterise France&#39;s China policy,” Le Corre said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, Li addressed the closing session of the two-day Summit for a New Global Financing Pact in Paris, where more than 40 world leaders and organisations gathered to discuss debts of developing countries and climate reforms – areas where China is playing an increasingly important role.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China will unequivocally reject trade protectionism and all forms of decoupling and severing of supply chains,” Li told the forum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jean-Pierre Cabestan, research fellow at the Paris-based Asia Centre think tank, said China&#39;s relationship with France and Germany had become “more complicated, contentious and competitive than before”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Issues such as Ukraine and Taiwan that have strained China-EU relations were raised in Li&#39;s meetings with both French and German officials. Li did not respond to Scholz&#39;s request for China to pressure Russia on Ukraine during a joint press conference, while none of the Chinese readouts mentioned Taiwan or human rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“De-risking … is an overarching trend that will continue to deepen”, which is what worries China, Cabestan said, adding that the push for “de-risking” rather than “decoupling” may not entirely reassure China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Li Qiang has on purpose chosen the two main economies of the EU for his first trip abroad. There is a clear diplomatic intention and message: cultivate Europe to weaken any anti-China united front led by the US,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Will it work? On the economic front, to some extent; on the security front, I doubt it.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong to host the head office of Saudi-China entrepreneurs guild, as city steps up its ‘value-added super-connector’ role amid warming ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3225334/hong-kong-host-head-office-saudi-china-entrepreneurs-guild-city-steps-its-value-added-super?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/0cd2ba23-437d-41ca-b534-dcf33693493e_f7d143f5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong will host the head office of the Saudi Arabia-China Entrepreneurs Association, as the city steps up to connect the private sectors of both nations amid warming bilateral ties, according to sources familiar with the matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The association, launched in February at the LEAP 2023 Conference during Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu&#39;s inaugural visit to Riyadh, responded to his personal invitation to set up in Hong Kong because the city is the optimal place for holding face-to-face meetings for Saudi and Chinese travelers, the sources said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong allows visa-free entry for all Saudi passport holders, a considerable convenience for visitors compared with the time, cost and effort needed to obtain business visas to enter mainland China, they said. Similarly, Chinese entrepreneurs can travel to Hong Kong for meetings more easily than going to Riyadh.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The guild is a non-profit organisation aimed at boosting private-sector collaboration to augment government-to-government bilateral ties. It is supported by the Saudi Ministry of Communications and Information Technology and the Saudi Federation for Cybersecurity, Programming, and Drones. It will be operated by eWTP Arabia Capital, according to an announcement during its February launch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are keen to support the exchanges and collaborations between Hong Kong, the Greater Bay Area and Saudi Arabia, as well as any plans by Saudi businesses to localise or develop in the Asia-Pacific region,” eWTP Arabia said in response to a query by the Post about its operational role in the guild.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are also able to help Chinese companies set up in Saudi Arabia to capitalise on the enormous opportunities available in” the kingdom&#39;s Saudi Vision 2030, the company said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chief Executive&#39;s Office did not immediately respond on a Sunday night to the Post&#39;s request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The association has more than 100 founding members, including the Saudi Telecom Company, China Mobile, Tencent Holdings, China International Capital Corp., BOC International, Alibaba Cloud&#39;s unit in the kingdom, and the delivery company J&amp;T Express.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The association will be led by a rotating chairperson, the first role being eWTP Arabia&#39;s founder and managing partner Jerry Li, the sources said. The establishment of the office is scheduled to be announced on July 2.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The association plans to organise regular events in Saudi Arabia and Hong Kong to promote people-to-people exchange, commercial relations and foster understanding, they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Saudi minister calls for people exchanges to enhance trade&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s relations with Saudi Arabia and the broader Middle East region have entered a new era, after the December 2022 visit to Riyadh by Chinese President Xi Jinping.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official Saudi Press Agency said Xi&#39;s trip “represents keenness of the leaderships of the two countries to strengthen bilateral relations and their strategic partnership and to invest their political and economic potential in serving their common interests.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two months later, Lee made his first official visit to West Asia, leading a delegation of his Cabinet members, government officials and dozens of the biggest names in Hong Kong&#39;s business community in financial services, technology and logistics to the Saudi capital. Six agreements were signed during the visit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a breakthrough, China brokered a rapprochement between Riyadh and its regional rival Tehran in March, paving the way for Saudi Arabia and Iran to resume diplomatic relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s role as China&#39;s gateway to the world can be enhanced by being a “value-added super-connector” between economies, markets and companies, Lee said last week in a keynote speech at the China Conference: Hong Kong 2023, organised by the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Total merchandise trade between Hong Kong and members of the Gulf Cooperation Council – Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates, Bahrain, Kuwait, Oman and Qatar – rose to HK$100 billion (US$13 billion) in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pope ‘breaks taboo’ with prayer for Emanuela Orlandi, missing Vatican teen]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225333/pope-breaks-taboo-prayer-emanuela-orlandi-missing-vatican-teen?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.25 21:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/25/fa18a22a-25bc-441a-b5ac-4417467782bf_ebe87b86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Pope Francis offered prayers Sunday for the family of a teenager who went missing 40 years ago this week, an intervention her brother hailed as a sign the Vatican was finally engaging seriously with its most famous cold case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Emanuela Orlandi, the 15-year-old daughter of a Vatican employee, was last seen leaving a music class in Rome on June 22, 1983.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Decades of speculation followed over what happened to her, with suggestions that mobsters, the secret services or a Vatican conspiracy were to blame, theories which sparked a hit Netflix series.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After his weekly Angelus prayer at the Vatican, Pope Francis said he wanted to use the anniversary “to once again express my closeness to the family, above all her mother, and assure them of my prayers”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I extend my remembrance to all the families who bear the pain of a loved one who has disappeared,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Orlandi&#39;s family have for years campaigned for the truth and in January the Vatican&#39;s chief prosecutor opened a file into the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday&#39;s anniversary, the Vatican revealed he had forwarded his findings to the Rome prosecutor&#39;s office, which is conducting its own probe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There had been “some lines of inquiry worthy of further investigation”, the Vatican said in a statement, without giving further details.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it said it had collected evidence from Vatican institutions and accounts from senior officials at the time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Vatican has been accused of obstructing investigation efforts over the decades, but Orlandi&#39;s brother Pietro expressed hope on Sunday that some progress might finally be made.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Emanuela Orlandi taboo has finally been broken,” he said after leading a sit-in near the Vatican and then going to listen to the pope.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The fact of praying is a sign of hope of reaching the truth.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that “these words are already a big step that we had been asking for years and years and it had never happened”, and said “we expect acts after these words”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Italy&#39;s lower chamber of parliament agreed in March to set up a commission to investigate Orlandi&#39;s case and that of another Vatican teenager, Mirella Gregori, who disappeared a few weeks earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it remains under discussion in the upper chamber, the Senate.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 25 Jun 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>