<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[From Singapore to India, Nepal and Myanmar, Asia must ‘adapt’ to heatwaves]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/health-environment/article/3229283/singapore-india-nepal-and-myanmar-asia-must-adapt-heatwaves?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/4caf673b-3ec4-4cee-8617-bc03a7948554_8175647e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新加坡居民在未来几周和几个月内每次醒来时，他们可能会在上班或上学之前，检查高温警报是他们早上例行公事的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种情况在不到十年前可能是不可想象的，但这是亚洲金融中心的人们将会遇到的事情新加坡当局也没有过于谨慎，因为气候科学家本周证实 7 月将是最热的——有史以来每个月都有记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国和欧盟监测人员表示，最近的高温可能是数千年来前所未有的，并警告说这只是未来气候的预兆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样根据莱比锡大学气候科学家 Karsten Haustein 博士的分析，温暖的气候仅在 12 万年前出现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着气候变化，包括新加坡在内的世界上许多国家的气温都在上升。因此，公众适应这一点很重要。”新加坡可持续发展部和国家环境局在最近的一份联合声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡的努力很可能很快就会以不同的形式在世界各地复制亚洲，该地区极易受到气候变化的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，印度北部发生致命洪水，而中国新疆省部分地区的气温高达 52.2 摄氏度，打破了此前创下的 50.6 摄氏度的纪录。 2017年。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着极端天气事件的增加，热浪每5年袭击中国一次：研究&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;极端天气灾难部分归因于厄尔尼诺现象，这种天气现象通常会扰乱每年的降雨模式几年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在厄尔尼诺现象期间，亚洲的气温往往会升高，通常会导致空气变得更加潮湿和温暖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，由于我们对地球的无情燃烧，这种天气现在将变得司空见惯。科学家表示，化石燃料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只要我们继续燃烧化石燃料，我们就会看到越来越多的极端现象，”格兰瑟姆气候研究所气候科学高级讲师弗里德里克·奥托说伦敦政治经济学院的变化与环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[但是]即使我们现在停止燃烧化石燃料，气温也不会下降，”她说。 “因此，我们现在看到的热浪，我们肯定必须忍受。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高温已经对那些生活在难以获得公共卫生服务的边缘化社区的人们的健康造成了严重损害， “柳叶刀”气候变化与健康倒计时执行主任玛丽娜·罗曼内洛 (Marina Romanello) 表示，自 2000 年代初以来，全球与高温相关的死亡率增加了约 70%，追踪两者之间的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;影响是巨大的，炎热的天气严重降低了农民等人每天在田地里工作长达 12 个小时的能力，就像他们几代人所做的那样.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗曼内洛表示，仅 2021 年，气温飙升就导致全球损失约 4700 亿个工作时间，造成约 7000 亿美元的经济损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约有 4.5 亿人亚太地区的小农。科学家表示，最贫穷的国家（如孟加拉国、尼泊尔、巴基斯坦和缅甸）往往首当其冲地受到气候变化的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;原因包括重建受自然灾害影响的低收入社区需要时间。 、缺乏社会福利安全网以及地理因素（例如位于脆弱的沿海地区）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高温还会造成其他危害，包括毁灭性的森林火灾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周，印度尼西亚当局表示，由于天气干燥，7 月 17 日至 23 日期间，容易发生野火的地区数量增加了一倍，这让人想起 2015 年那场毁灭性的大火，这场大火让东南亚笼罩在雾霾中达五个月之久。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; “我们将面临水危机”：马来西亚通过播种云来降雨&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国的一项研究后来将当年的雾霾与印度尼西亚、马来西亚和新加坡超过 10 万人过早死亡联系起来。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“虽然并非所有热点都会变成火灾点，但我们仍然必须保持警惕，因为我们看到火势显着增加，”印度尼西亚 BNPB 减灾机构发言人表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚气象局本月表示，预计该国下半年将出现 2019 年以来最严重的旱季，部分原因是厄尔尼诺现象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;炎热潮湿的气候也带来了更多蚊媒传播的担忧致力于减轻气候压力的非营利性亚洲创投慈善网络主题合作总监阿拉文丹·斯里尼瓦桑 (Aravindan Srinivasan) 表示，这些疾病已经在东南亚、南美洲和非洲流行。撒哈拉以南非洲地区，但现在已开始在欧洲等未知地区爆发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，人口稠密的亚洲仍然面临最大的风险。斯里尼瓦桑指出，世界上最容易受到气候变化影响的五个国家——印度、中国、孟加拉国、巴基斯坦和印度尼西亚——位于该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Srinivasan 总部位于新加坡的网络该组织的 600 名成员中有慈善家和大公司，该组织热衷于为亚洲的减排和可再生能源发电项目提供资金。过去六个月来，它一直在印度开展业务，并计划很快在中国以及东南亚开展业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的非营利网络与草根企业合作，并与不同的组织合作，斯里尼瓦桑说，与政府合作，为当地社区确定解决问题的计划，例如粉刷屋顶以减少热量，但这些计划往往缺乏资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须考虑问题的两面性他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着极端天气促使空调和风扇的电力需求激增，威胁更多的排放，缓解和适应变得越来越重要。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;最近，中国几个城市的用电量记录被打破，据报道，上海每小时燃烧数百吨煤炭以保持城市凉爽，而越南等其他国家的人们则不得不应对轮流停电。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;气候活动人士现在正关注在迪拜举行的年终联合国气候会议，希望能达成逐步淘汰化石燃料和增加可再生能源的协议。但他们表示，各国需要优先考虑环境问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;红十字会与红新月会气候中心主任 Julie Arrighi 表示，在能源需求和减少排放之间取得平衡是防止更频繁和更强烈热浪的关键。荷兰海牙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲国家经常倾向于转向燃煤发电，因为该地区燃料很容易获得，但专家表示，在气候变化的情况下，这一战略充满了风险。该研究所的战略能源财务顾问格兰特·豪伯表示，火力发电设施——那些使用蒸汽锅炉产生的能量运行的设施，通常以煤炭或天然气为燃料——在非常炎热的天气下运行效率不高。能源经济和金融分析。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，此类设施在天气非常热时往往会出现容量减少的情况。据能源智库 Ember 称，到 2021 年，全球约 62% 的电力来自化石燃料。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;亚洲终于摆脱肮脏的化石燃料，拥抱绿色能源了吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国际能源署周四表示，由于亚洲发电和工业应用的强劲增长超过了美国和欧洲的下降幅度，2022年全球煤炭消费量将升至历史新高，并将在今年保持在这一历史最高水平附近.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年煤炭使用量增长了 3.3%，达到 83 亿吨，它补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去几周，随着中国一直在增加煤炭产量，亚洲需求依然强劲澳新银行最近表示，火力发电。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但专家表示，可再生能源价格的下降意味着从长远来看，亚洲的需求可能会更多地转向绿色能源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“实际上，可再生能源可能越来越多地介入来填补这一空白，”豪伯说，他指出，上个月美国德克萨斯州燃气工厂因热源中断时，太阳能挽救了局面。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;法新社补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Post-China’s rise, India emerges as global investors’ new destination of choice: ‘India’s time has come’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3229434/post-chinas-rise-india-emerges-global-investors-new-destination-choice-indias-time-has-come?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/df7fd5af-3992-47ed-8984-0a9e80d64ba3_1ee250dc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;过去几十年来，中国崛起为经济强国，一些最大的经济体商界和投资界的知名人士现在将另一个亚洲国家视为下一个大型投资目的地：印度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亿万富翁投资者雷·达里奥 (Ray Dalio) 表示，该国已做好快速增长的准备，而埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 则强调了印度的前景特斯拉在那里建工厂。苹果公司首席执行官蒂姆·库克也表达了对印度的乐观态度，而高盛则预测南亚经济规模将在 2075 年超过美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;未来几年有利于印度经济的因素包括大规模和大规模的经济增长。专家表示，印度拥有相对年轻的人口、充满活力的股市以及强大的科技产业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度最近超过中国，成为世界上人口最多的国家。该国基准股指 Sensex 和 Nifty 50 本月创下历史新高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从亿万富翁企业家到华尔街银行，所有人的目光都集中在印度。以下是他们的评论、预测和计划的详细信息：&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;马斯克关注印度已有两年多了。早在 2021 年，这位特斯拉首席执行官就表示，他“很有可能”在该国建立一家电动汽车工厂，但前提是政府官员降低整车的进口费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果特斯拉能够马斯克当时在推特上表示：“如果进口汽车取得成功，那么很有可能在印度建工厂。”他补充道：“我们希望这样做，但进口关税是迄今为止世界上所有大国中最高的！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;快进到 2023 年，马斯克开始看到这些愿景越来越接近现实。这位亿万富翁企业家上个月会见印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪后表示，这家电动汽车制造商将“尽快”在印度建立业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉正在考虑在这个南亚国家建立一家工厂据路透社上周报道，该公司生产了一款售价 24,000 美元的首发汽车。消息人士告诉媒体，马斯克将于本月与印度政府代表会面，讨论特斯拉新工厂的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据这位亿万富翁投资者称，印度已准备好成为下一个大国全球投资机会，特别是在华盛顿和北京之间的紧张局势恶化的情况下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我很高兴能够帮助莫迪总理，因为他的时代已经到来，而印度的时代也已经到来，”达里奥说在推文中。 “他和印度的处境与 20 世纪 80 年代初的邓小平和中国类似，即处于世界上最快的增长率和最大的转型的边缘，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“挑战中美两国之间以及两国内部的合作都使莫迪总理处于独特的地位，可以通过影响不结盟世界与这两个世界领先大国的交往来影响世界秩序的格局。”这位 Bridgewater Associates 创始人继续说道。 &lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;传奇新兴市场投资者马克·莫比乌斯 (Mark Mobius) 最近称赞印度是“真正的未来”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫比乌斯提到印度的高增长率 - 国内生产总值 (GDP) 预计将增长3 月 31 日结束的财政年度增长 7.2%，这是出于他的乐观态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经验法则是，如果国家的增长率为 7%，那么一家相当优秀的公司应该能够他告诉彭博社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华尔街银行高盛最近引起了广泛关注，因为它预测印度经济将在 2075 年超过美国，成为仅次于中国的世界第二大经济体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;高盛预计，到那时，南亚国家的 GDP 将从 2022 年底的 3.4 万亿美元飙升至 52.5 万亿美元。相比之下，中国和美国的预测分别为 57 万亿美元和 51.5 万亿美元。这要归功于蓬勃发展的科技行业、不断增加的资本投资和不断增长的人口。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;印度的经济潜力也吸引了大型科技公司的兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苹果首席执行官蒂姆·库克 (Tim Cook) 此前曾表达过对印度的信心，曾在 2017 年告诉投资者他“对印度非常非常看好、非常非常乐观”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他对印度的乐观态度让苹果公司在印度开设了前两家公司今年早些时候在该国开设了商店。他还指出，印度的年轻人口和不断壮大的中产阶级意味着对先进和昂贵技术的更高需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文最初由 &lt;/p>; 发表</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s manufacturing activity contracts for fourth straight month in July despite uptick]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3229436/chinas-manufacturing-activity-contracts-fourth-straight-month-july-despite-uptick?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/2302d7c0-8b15-44cf-9f69-08b0de5e2376_e9706451.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;7 月份中国工厂活动有所回升，但连续第四个月处于收缩状态周一公布的数据显示，在经济复苏总体放缓的情况下，本月非制造业扩张放缓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月份官方制造业采购经理人指数 (PMI) 升至 49.3，高于根据国家统计局 (NBS) 的数据，6 月份为 49，但连续第四个月保持收缩。 50 关口将月度增长与收缩区分开来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;衡量服务业和建筑业商业信心的官方非制造业 PMI 从 6 月的 53.2 降至 7 月的 51.5。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;官方制造业 PMI 中，7 月新订单分类指数从 6 月的 48.6 升至 49.5，而新出口订单分类指数则从 47.2 下降至 46.3。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方综合 PMI，其中包括制造业和服务业活动，7 月份从 6 月份的 52.3 下降至 51.1。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非制造业指标中，服务业分类指数从 6 月份的 52.8 下降到 7 月份的 51.5，而建筑业分类指数则从 6 月份的 52.8 下降至 51.5。从 55.7 降至 51.2。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;季思琪的补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更多内容敬请关注……&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Given a second life’: home-alone toddler in China tumbles from third floor flat, caught by man among dozen of passers-by who rushed to rescue]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3229106/given-second-life-home-alone-toddler-china-tumbles-3rd-floor-flat-caught-man-among-dozen-passers-who?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/25a43e21-77e3-4384-bd80-c8d6a7bb742b_f3e409c5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;大陆社交媒体上的人们蜂拥而至，观看一段病毒视频，该视频捕捉到了这一瞬间一群路人本能地、戏剧性地营救了一名从大楼三楼阳台坠落的幼儿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月24日的监控录像显示，一群路人一致反应，跑向位于中国西北部陕西省的一栋大楼里，张开双臂，试图接住从三楼摔下来的孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;令人惊讶的是，19个月大的幼儿辰辰竟然落到了一个人的怀里。据新闻媒体华商新闻报道，其中一人仅腿部受了轻微擦伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抓到他的男子王晶是一名公交车司机，也是两个孩子的父亲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王某称，他骑着电动车上班途中，突然看到晨晨在三楼公寓外的阳台上行走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，他立即把自行车放在一边，冲向公寓。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说，直到看到监控后，他才意识到自己并不是唯一一个看到男孩困境后做出反应的人。视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他唯一记得的就是在他抓住孩子后跪在他面前，急切地想看看他是否还好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频还显示，王被绊倒了在接住辰辰的过程中，他采取了一些步骤，缓冲了男孩落地时对他怀里的冲击力，否则他和孩子可能会受到更严重的伤害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说，他只受了轻微的拉伤。王补充说，他的行为是出于“一个父亲的本能”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我想，既然我胖了，我什至可以让孩子落在我身上来接住他。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;获救第二天，辰辰的父母带着孩子到公交车站向王表示感谢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;父亲紧紧地拥抱着王，哭着说：“我不敢想象会发生什么。”我的孩子没有你。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说辰辰的奶奶出去买药，让他一个人睡，没想到他这么快就醒了。凸窗和阳台之间的门也没有锁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“感谢路人的救援，不仅让这个小孩获得了第二次生命，也拯救了一个家庭。” ”一位网友表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很难想象如果没有台阶的缓冲作用，公交车司机会发生什么。家长们真的应该更加小心。”另一个人说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“大家都看上面，没有注意到下面的步骤。真是一群无私的人。”第三位网友说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，十几个邻居用被子接住了从四号楼掉下来的40天大的婴儿，感动了大陆的社交媒体。 -中国东部浙江省，其母亲在燃烧的公寓的落地窗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;母亲后来被消防员救出。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why the hunt for Hong Kong schools is ‘miserable’ for some mainland Chinese arriving through talent pass scheme with children]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3229199/why-hunt-hong-kong-schools-miserable-some-mainland-chinese-arriving-through-talent-pass-scheme?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/1fd082ae-35ba-49cd-b865-4b4df7ce093f_97538e93.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;根据新计划吸引到香港的中国内地人才已开始定居香港，一些人抱怨孩子很难进入城里的学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接受《华盛顿邮报》采访的家长表示，入学考试很难，孩子的英语和广东话不熟练也是一个问题。一些人表示，他们送孩子去上两种语言的课程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位校长表示，他必须拒绝那些不会说粤语（学校中文课的教学语言）的申请者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;比借书卡更方便？内地人通过香港签证寻求新的出路&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年12月推出的顶尖人才通行证计划为成功申请者提供了两年签证。候选人在过去 12 个月的收入必须不少于 250 万港元（320,500 美元），或者是世界排名前 100 的大学之一的毕业生，并且在过去五年中工作了三年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毕业生过去5年世界排名前100的大学，工作经验少于3年的也可申请，但每年名额上限为10,000人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非这些大学的毕业生也有资格申请，只要申请前一年年薪达250万港元或以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;成功申请者可携配偶及子女来港定居。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据移民局称，截至 6 月，共有 25,961 名主申请人成功，并签发了 22,751 份家属签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《华盛顿邮报》早些时候报道，迄今为止，超过 95% 的批准申请都是针对大陆人士的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;32 岁的信息和技术行业专业人士 Jessica Liu 表示，她将与丈夫以及两个分别为 8 岁和 1.5 岁的女儿搬到香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为长辈寻找一所学校女孩被证明是一个挑战。她说，她申请了近20所小学，但名额不多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校的入学评估是一个障碍。 “香港学校对英语的要求比内地学校更高，”她说。 “面试时，有些学校强调粤语熟练程度。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说家人不会说粤语。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港7天批准1,400份新人才计划申请&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;教育局表示，并无通过顶尖人才通行证计划来港学生的数字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华仁书院校长陈伟伦，香港一所精英学校表示，今年来自内地的申请人数大幅上升，其中有一些是尖子生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有一个男孩，一直是班上第一名，从未掉队”他说：“他在大陆同年级的大约 300 名学生中排名第二。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他没有接受那个男孩，因为没有更多的学校名额，并补充说，由于其他原因，他不得不拒绝其他男孩。粤语不流利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因为我们用粤语教授中文，所以我们不会接受不懂粤语的申请者。目前用普通话教授这门课程还没有列入我们的议程。”陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从长远来看，我们可能需要考虑为学生提供选择用普通话学习汉语的选择。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈说，一些以前在香港学习并在Covid-19大流行期间返回大陆的跨境学生也已返回香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;收紧规则中国生物物理学家传奇事件后的香港人才签证计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;来自广州的Cindy Xu获得了在金融领域工作的顶尖人才签证，但她表示，为她找到中学是一次“悲惨”的经历12 岁的儿子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于对 7 月份分配给他的学校感到失望，男孩开始直接接近他喜欢的学校，这种做法在香港被称为“敲门”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;他联系过的八所中学，只有一所邀请他去面试，却被拒绝了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐说，她的儿子是广州的尖子生，课外活动也很活跃，但香港学校不承认他在内地的成绩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他最终就读于九龙塘的一所学校，徐称这所学校“对内地人友好”，但他需要 40 分钟才能从他们的学校到达那里。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为新来港的徐先生表示，一家人对西营盘的教育体系知之甚少，也因为没有全面的信息而不知所措。&lt;/p>;&lt; “我们所能做的就是在互联网上搜索或询问其他新来的人，”她说。 “我建议政府设立热线或提供电子邮件来处理新来港人士的询问。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;大陆人士被告知不要滥用香港人才签证在城市生孩子&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; 35 岁的内地夫妇王文曦和雷江雷在与两个分别为 7.5 岁和 1.5 岁的儿子安顿下来后感到更加幸福。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇都是中文大学毕业生，他们表示很欣赏这里的教育&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大男孩威廉在香港九龙塘的一所小学学习三个月后，已经很好地适应了他的班级。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;王先生说，3月份开学时，他受到了热烈的欢迎，尽管他不会说粤语。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“老师让一位普通话说得很好的学生照顾他” 1月2日几天之内就获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说语言，尤其是英语，是她儿子面临的最大挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当William第一次来香港时，他甚至不会拼写一个字。当他完成第一个听写作业时，我们感到绝望。”王说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不得不在校外花更多时间学习他的英语，最终我们看到了进步。威廉第三次听写得了满分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周末全家人都去上粤语课。王很高兴威廉学得很快，甚至可以用粤语回答老师的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇的小儿子伊森 (Ethan) 与祖父母住在深圳。家人打算带他来香港上幼儿园。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港在人才引进上撒下“比新加坡大得多的网”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;深圳会计师王静雯，说五岁女儿入屯门幼儿园的过程很顺利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只申请了一次就成功了，而且老师人很好，普通话也很好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;目前，一家人仍住在深圳，女孩每天都要过境去幼儿园。王女士表示，如果女儿继续在香港读小学，他们一家人就会搬到香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还表示，她并不担心女儿在幼儿园遭遇文化冲击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “沉浸在粤语环境中，像她这样的小女孩很快就能学会粤语，”王说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“英语可能是一个挑战，为了让她为九月份的新学期做好准备，我给她报了外教辅导班。”王补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What the Niger coup means for China’s presence in the Sahel region]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229399/what-niger-coup-means-chinas-presence-sahel-region?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/92cbc04a-1247-4b08-8450-a093252f0654_80e1a216.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;上周尼日尔的军事政变加剧了中国在尼日尔投资的阵痛。萨赫勒地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，总统卫队的一群士兵以安全和经济形势恶化为由拘留了尼日尔总统穆罕默德·巴祖姆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去三年里，尼日尔总统穆罕默德·巴祖姆也被拘留。布基纳法索、几内亚、马里、乍得和苏丹发生政变，中国在这些国家拥有广泛的经济利益，特别是在采矿和石油行业，并寻求扩大其数十亿美元的贸易和投资计划，即“一带一路”倡议。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;巴祖姆于 2021 年 3 月当选，这是该国自 1960 年脱离法国独立以来的首次和平、民主过渡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部表示，北京正在密切关注尼日尔局势，并呼吁有关方面荷兰莱顿大学非洲研究中心高级研究员拉赫曼·伊德里萨表示，军方正在利用这一优势，以维护国家和人民的利益，通过对话和平解决分歧。看起来国际气候对政变更加宽容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊德里萨表示，政变对法尼关系乃至尼日尔与西方的关系来说都是一场灾难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他瓦格纳集团——一家在非洲拥有广泛利益的俄罗斯雇佣军公司——表示，“这不是一个因素，但克里姆林宫肯定对此感到高兴，不是因为它帮助了尼日尔人，而是因为它可能有助于他们进入西非，这已经受到马里和布基纳法索军政府的青睐”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着欧盟在政变中切断对尼日尔的援助，美国的重要支持受到威胁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他表示，中国在尼日尔的存在是作为一个经济体该国东部地区石油开采的合作伙伴。 “该协议不会受到政变的影响，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴祖姆是法国和其他西方国家的亲密盟友，但北京一直在进军尼日尔，就像它与其他国家一样。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中国商务部称，中国国有的中国石油天然气集团公司和中国核工业集团公司分别在石油和铀工业上投资了 46 亿美元和 4.8 亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该国的铀工业供应了世界上约 5% 的最高品位铀矿石。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月 27 日，巴祖姆会见了中国铀业总公司 (CNUC) 的代表团，讨论了收购Société des Mines d&#39;Azelik（索米纳），CNUC和尼日尔政府为大股东。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNUC近期正在尼日尔北部地区开展重启生产的研究。该项目九年前因全球市场状况而被放弃，现在由于有利的铀价而被重新考虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了尼日尔主要出口到法国、加拿大和韩国的铀之外，该国还出口黄金根据经济复杂性观察站的数据，本月初，中国驻尼日尔大使江峰会见巴祖姆，表示中国将在首都尼亚美建设一个工业园区，这将对尼日尔经济产生重大影响。会议期间，江泽民还向总统介绍了他访问阿加德姆的有关情况。阿加德姆是中国石油天然气集团公司开发的尼日尔-贝宁出口管道所在地。启动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该管道全长近 2,000 公里（1,200 英里），预计将提高尼日尔的原油产量，并通过贝宁海岸的一个码头促进国际贸易。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;枪手绑架了 4 名中国人尼日利亚矿山工人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;华盛顿中东研究所所长穆罕默德·索利曼表示，尼日尔政变加剧了萨赫勒地区的不稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尼日尔拥有重要的铀矿以及黄金等其他宝贵资源，引发了人们对全球经济潜在深远影响的担忧，”索利曼说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;索利曼表示，如果萨赫勒地区的局势进一步升级，可能会这对中国在尼日尔及其邻国的经济利益和投资产生了相当大的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不稳定可能会扰乱中国投资的基础设施项目、采掘业和其他企业，对其在该地区的经济利益构成风险， ” Soliman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What could Niger coup and new military leader mean for West Africa stability?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Moreover, Soliman said prolonged instability and conflicts in the Sahel could impact China&#39;s broader strategic objectives and influence in Africa, prompting a re-evaluation of its engagement and presence on the continent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;John Calabrese, a professor at American University in Washington, said it would be worth watching whether the new leadership of Niger followed through with the discussions Beijing held with Bazoum&#39;s administration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gyude Moore, a senior policy fellow at the Washington-based Centre for Global Development, and a former public works minister in Liberia, said Niger was one of the last bastions of French support in francophone Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moore said China has no preference regarding regime type, so if Western governments withdrew, China&#39;s influence would grow, by default.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moore said China&#39;s contribution to Sahel security stabilisation, which includes troops joining a UN peacekeeping mission in Mali, had been tied to China&#39;s own growing economic interests in the region. “Those interests mean that China will be focused on stability, regardless of regime type,” Moore said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong needs banking talent with Arabic, Islamic finance skills to woo Middle East wealth, expert says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3229410/hong-kong-needs-banking-talent-arabic-islamic-finance-skills-woo-middle-east-wealth-expert-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/30/3574c979-1da6-4f9e-848a-623a0cb0fa17_a0cb5591.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong will have to create a talent pool with expertise in the Middle East and Islamic finance if it wants to attract wealthy families and companies from the region to invest in the city, according to a veteran banker.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong needs to have a long-term training programme or import talent to bring Middle East investors to the city,” said Derrick Tan, a private banker who has been servicing wealthy clients in Asia for more than two decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong will also have to make it convenient for Middle Eastern customers to open bank accounts so that they can invest here, Tan said in an interview with the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have come across some individual Middle East clients who have had difficulty in opening personal accounts with banks in Hong Kong,” said Tan, the chairman of Wrise Group Holdings, a wealth management platform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The global Islamic finance industry, which is guided by sharia Islamic law, principles and rules, currently boasts assets of around US$2.2 trillion and is anticipated to grow to US$4.94 trillion by 2025, according to a report by Standard Chartered in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The demand for Islamic products such as sukuk (bonds) and takaful (insurance) could be fuelled by a combination of Islamic banks together with sharia-compliant sovereign wealth funds, asset management companies, pension funds and family offices, Standard Chartered said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu, Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po and Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) CEO Eddie Yue Wai-man have led separate delegations to various Middle East countries this year to attract investments and forge closer ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June, the HKMA and the central bank of the United Arab Emirates said they would work together to promote cross-border payments and investments between the two sides. On Wednesday, HKMA CEO Yue signed an agreement with the central bank of Saudi Arabia to jointly promote fintech projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bourse operator Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing CEO Nicolas Aguzin and chairwoman Laura Cha Shih May-lung have also undertaken trips to Middle East this year to attract investments and to entice Gulf firms to list here.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The roadshows by Hong Kong government officials and bankers in the Middle East to build relationships is a good start,” Tan said. “Now, they need talent who know how to follow up.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When it comes to China, Hong Kong&#39;s financial sector has a big pool of talent who are well-versed with the culture and language and have the network to serve customers on the mainland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s active capital market and backup from China will attract Middle Eastern investors, Tan said. “However, Hong Kong does not have many people who can speak Arabic, understand Islamic finance requirements, or fully understand the background of the different countries in the Middle East,” Tan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This makes it hard for local financial firms to serve Middle East tycoons.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Tan started off as an investment banker 23 years ago, banks in Hong Kong had different teams to serve wealthy clients in Muslim-majority countries Malaysia and Indonesia, who understood sharia rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But with banks turning their focus on the mainland Chinese market, most of them no longer have such teams and many local bankers do not know Islamic finance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To solve the problem, Hong Kong can offer incentives to attract talent with experience in handling Middle East clients, or the local firms can send Hong Kong youth to learn in these countries,” Tan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tan is an example of how Singaporean companies nurture talent to tap the Middle East market. Born and brought up in Singapore, Tan worked in several banks including HSBC, UBS and Bank of Singapore – the private bank unit of OCBC. He was in charge of Bank of Singapore&#39;s Middle East operations from 2014 to 2017, where he built the bank&#39;s network and client base.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After his stint as the Bank of Singapore&#39;s Hong Kong CEO in 2021, he set up Wrise to serve ultra-high net worth customers in Hong Kong, China and Dubai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without experience in managing Dubai and other Middle East markets, I would not be able to serve Middle East clients,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Saudi minister calls for people exchanges to enhance trade&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Many Middle Eastern wealthy individuals and families want to diversify their investments, and Hong Kong can capture those opportunities by attracting them to set up family offices here, said Nelson Chow, chairman of the Hong Kong Investment Funds Association, the funds industry guild.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong can introduce more policies to attract these Middle East family offices to set up here to invest,” Chow said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Once they have a good experience investing in Hong Kong, the city can expand to offer other fund products or investment vehicles for investors from the region.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Yuan Valley: Hong Kong tech start-ups break into mainland Chinese market with help from HKU Business School’s Shenzhen campus]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3229347/yuan-valley-hong-kong-tech-start-ups-break-mainland-chinese-market-help-hku-business-schools?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/1bb89dac-67bc-400b-83c7-3b41737ae834_723c98c7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong entrepreneur Terry Lam Wa-kit recalls that he had no clue how to reach out to mainland Chinese companies to tell them about a new green product from his company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 39-year-old director and co-founder of Envicome, a Singapore-based start-up, said he received the cold shoulder when he tried to approach prospective clients last year in the hope of breaking into the massive mainland market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His company&#39;s environmentally friendly product, Envi-Gel, was an insulation coating material made from recycled plastic bottles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Describing what he learned from failing to connect with mainland businesses, he said: “No matter how good your product is, if nobody knows you, they don&#39;t trust you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong elderly health care scheme extended to HKU-Shenzhen hospital under new deal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Things changed dramatically after his firm joined Yuan Valley, a networking base for entrepreneurs set up at the University of Hong Kong (HKU) Business School-Shenzhen Campus which opened last November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The centre, which has room for 16 enterprises, aims to provide a full range of incubation services for hi-tech start-ups and help them commercialise their research and development (R&amp;D) results with financing, marketing and networking support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam&#39;s company is one of 10 firms that have moved in so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since we joined the Valley, we have been taken care of and put in touch with mainland firms. Now their attitude has changed significantly and they have become willing to talk business, knowing we are from HKU,” Lam said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They trust HKU and its reputation, and we can capitalise on that to develop our business.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the HKU centre&#39;s help, the start-ups hope to gain a foothold in the Greater Bay Area, Beijing&#39;s ambitious plan to link nine cities in Guangdong province with Hong Kong and Macau to create an economic powerhouse by 2035.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new campus is a partnership with the Futian government in Shenzhen and provides a place for HKU staff and alumni to carry out education, research and entrepreneurial activities under the model of “one university, two campuses”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the partnership, both sides will work towards growing the campus into a first-class comprehensive research university with a global vision, rooted in Shenzhen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Orange Ju Ziqian, director of the HKU Business School&#39;s Shenzhen centre, said the Valley was an important incubation site for the mainland city, and HKU would help to seek funding support from authorities there for the start-ups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We will line up cooperation between our start-ups and Hong Kong corporations, such as the Science Park and Cyberport, and help them explore international markets,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong hi-tech start-up&#39;s faster, cheaper test to pinpoint cause of fevers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Two start-ups at the Valley said they hoped to grow their business by tapping HKU&#39;s connections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tyler Lu Jiheng, CEO of Carrymen Dynamics (Shenzhen) Company Ltd, which produces a conveying system to transport small components such as smartphone parts and semiconductors, said the Valley helped him engage investors, generate new R&amp;D ideas and market his products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang Guobiao, CEO of Hong Kong Kairuipu Medical Technology, hoped his start-up would get more customers for its smart sleep monitor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Costing HK$5,000 (US$640) per set, it can help prevent sudden heart failure by continuously monitoring patients&#39; vital signs, such as their heart and breathing rates. It is being used by Hong Kong&#39;s Correctional Services Department and some hospitals in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“By being in the Valley, our clinical reports will be sent by HKU to different medical institutions in Hong Kong and overseas and help tap the market in the Middle East and Europe,” Huang said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why not allow Hongkongers to air their views on Chinese University council reform?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3229350/why-not-allow-hongkongers-air-their-views-chinese-university-council-reform?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/f806e28b-7981-407a-90ee-c14b5f5e5099_5462cb2f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Chinese University of Hong Kong has been making headlines, but not for good reasons, regrettably. As the saying goes, academic politics is the most vicious because the stakes are so small.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until recently, the effort to reform the university&#39;s governing council has made the news only occasionally. But now, its internal fight that once took place behind the scenes, has erupted into public view, with political heavyweights such as former Hong Kong chief executive Leung Chun-ying and other public figures weighing in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Punches and jabs are being thrown from all corners. For those of us who have not been following collegiate politics and are not used to this sort of a slug fest, it&#39;s a little off-putting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The storm in the college tea cup has become quite a political headache for the government and Legislative Council. At the centre of the controversy is the Chinese University of Hong Kong (Amendment) Bill 2023, a private members&#39; bill initiated by three lawmakers – Edward Lau Kwok-fan, Tommy Cheung Yu-yan and Bill Tang Ka-piu – who sit on the university council.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who oppose the move to restructure Chinese University&#39;s governing body have launched a petition against the bill, even taking out front-page ads in three newspapers last Thursday. More than 1,400 people have signed the petition, including notable public figures such as a former CEO of the Airport Authority, the director of the Hong Kong Palace Museum and a former undersecretary for commerce and economic development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deputy head of the Chief Executive&#39;s Policy Unit, Nicholas Kwan Ka-ming, was also a signatory, but he has since withdrawn his support, citing concern that the expression of his personal opinion might be seen as reflecting the government&#39;s position.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What is actually at stake? The size and composition of the council&#39;s membership, mainly. The proposal seeks to bring the number down from 55 to 34. But, more importantly, it wants to increase the proportion of external representation sitting on the council.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bill also seeks to raise the council&#39;s voting threshold for deciding the university&#39;s vice-chancellor, to three-quarters instead of a simple majority.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the city&#39;s former leader Leung, who supports the bill, the issue is about personnel. Leung has in previous Facebook posts singled out the university&#39;s vice-chancellor and president Rocky Tuan Sung-chi for criticism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Institutional autonomy and academic freedom have been abused after the 2019 black violence,” Leung said in one post, referring to the anti-government protests that year. “This exactly explains the need to reform the Chinese University council and remove Rocky Tuan.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The controversy would appear to stem from the reappointment of Professor Tuan as university president until 2026, not necessarily over the bill itself.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, opponents of the bill have been vocal about their objection to the reforms being pushed through Legco.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Members&#39; bills do not relate to public expenditure, political structure or the operation of the government. Such bills were almost unheard of before the Legco revamp, since the chief executive has to sign off on them before they can be introduced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year, apart from the Chinese University bill, two other members&#39; bills have also been introduced – over technical updates to the Lingnan University Ordinance and The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Ordinance, separately.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In today&#39;s improved political system, where the executive and legislative branches enjoy friendly cooperation, we can expect to see more such members&#39; bills being introduced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet, it is surprising that today&#39;s improved Legco has apparently developed an aversion to public hearings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A request for a public hearing over the Chinese University bill was turned down. Tang acknowledged that the “reform of Chinese University&#39;s governance, and even its school members, have always been of great concern in society and are quite political”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As “a great concern in society”, is it not deserving of a public hearing? Tang said: “If there is a public hearing, I&#39;m afraid people will attack individuals or things they don&#39;t like, rather than reviewing whether the provisions are satisfactory or what needs to be changed.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a legislator, Tang should not be afraid of people&#39;s opinions on what he himself believes to be a great concern for society. It is precisely the openness and transparency a public hearing offers that would reveal to the public whether objections to his bill are valid and whether arguments against it are sound.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now that our lawmakers have heightened the stakes of collegiate politics, there&#39;s no shying away from defending their bill to the public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s property problems appear poised to improve, but can ‘much more risky’ real estate still drive economic growth?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3229305/chinas-property-problems-appear-poised-improve-can-much-more-risky-real-estate-still-drive-economic?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/53917ab0-2ed1-43ea-aa12-8971328dd897_db635dda.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;This is the second part in a series on how Beijing&#39;s recent policy shifts have triggered debate over the potential economic risks and benefits for China, including from changes in its property sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A long-held notion among China&#39;s private entrepreneurs was that the best way to offset business losses – or to fund an expansion – was to simply sell off a bit of real estate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To that end, Steve Wang and his elder brother bought up high-end office space and residences in southern China&#39;s Guangzhou over the past few years. They saw these properties as not only an investment, but also as sort of a rainy-day fund that could be liquidated if times got tough.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This speculative mentality helped China&#39;s property market soar to previously unseen heights over the past two decades, underpinning the entire nation&#39;s economic growth while bolstering the middle class.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Real estate also became a major source of local government revenue, and it sent private property tycoons to the top of China&#39;s rich lists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And all the while, soaring property prices made homes less affordable to the average person.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Interesting signal&#39;: China&#39;s property stocks jump as Beijing softens tone&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But in recent years, the feast came to an abrupt end. Out of concerns that the property market was overheating, President Xi Jinping declared in 2017, that “houses are for living in, not for speculation”, and that oft-repeated sentiment served to shape policy in the years that followed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And in late 2020, relatively early in the pandemic, Beijing took drastic steps to limit the property sector&#39;s high leverage – restricting how much developers could borrow annually by capping their debt.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The policy shift served to choke the liquidity of many private developers, led to snowballing bond defaults, and pushed some developers to the brink of collapse, with Evergrande Group at the centre of the crisis. Property development ground to a halt, and local governments struggled to cope with a sharp drop in revenue due to weak land sales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The crisis also compounded the risks of bad loans in banks and fuelled concerns among millions of buyers that developers would not be able to deliver flats. This became a major source of financial risks and social instability – even dampening the nation&#39;s post-Covid recovery and pushing Beijing to loosen its grip over the property sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Before the pandemic, Chinese companies, especially listed ones, held a lot of properties. They were not only high-value fixed assets that enabled us to get loans for business expansion, but they could also bring more profits than our main business,” said Wang, who made his fortune by investing heavily in large photovoltaic projects across the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Housing prices have fallen back to the level of 2018 and 2019,” he added. “We will not sell the real estate we have on hand, because we still need them as fixed assets … But we also have no plans to invest in new properties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Profits in our industry are becoming flat … and investing in real estate is even becoming less profitable [and] much more risky.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Private businesses – the backbone of growth, job creation and innovation in China, as well as major players in the real estate sector – were hit hardest during the pandemic. Beijing implemented large-scale lockdowns of major urban areas, cracked down on tech companies, upended the nation&#39;s tutoring industry, and squeezed the property market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Confidence rapidly waned among consumers, investors and businesspeople. And it has yet to substantially rebound in a post-Covid climate, as the private sector has lagged behind state-owned enterprises in terms of growth this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Worries about a hard landing were further stoked this month as Evergrande said it lost a combined US$81 billion in 2021 and 2022, and as commercial property developers Dalian Wanda and Country Garden faced headwinds in paying off debt.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With bank property loans billed as the “biggest grey rhino risk” in the financial system by former top banking regulator Guo Shuqing in 2020, economic officials have been walking a fine line between lifting economic recovery and mitigating the impact of a prolonged property crisis on the financial system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The biggest issue for economic policy, however, is the speed of the retreat in the old growth drivers – mainly property,” said Wei He, an analyst with Gavekal Dragonomics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2022, real estate and related industries accounted for 13-14 per cent of China&#39;s overall economy. Property investment, which accounts for at least one-fifth of all fixed-asset investment, dropped 10 per cent last year, dragging down the overall investment total by 2.7 percentage points.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fixed-asset investment, a major gauge of economic activities, rose by 3.8 per cent in the first six months of this year, compared with the same period in 2022, while property investment fell by 7.9 per cent. Private developers account for 80 per cent of all property investment in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Private-sector investment contracted by 0.2 per cent during the same period, as the private sector&#39;s share of fixed-asset investment hit a record-low 52.9 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many analysts blamed the beleaguered property market for China&#39;s disappointing economic performance in the second quarter. And some have warned that a prolonged property crisis would threaten Beijing&#39;s economic-growth target of “around 5 per cent” this year, which had been widely viewed in March as modest and easy for China&#39;s new leadership line-up to achieve in the first year of Xi&#39;s third presidential term.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But what a difference a few months have made. Beijing&#39;s growth outlook has become increasingly murky amid geopolitical strife and uncertainties, with US-led tech-containment measures and more vocal calls to “de-risk” from China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is facing pressure to realise economic growth at 5 per cent,” said Mao Zhenghua, director of the Institute of Economic Research at Renmin University. “同时，还要承受国内外的双重冲击。扭转中长期经济增长下滑趋势，需要艰苦努力。 We are going to face a more complicated economic situation over the long run.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are paying the price for the property bubble, which saw persistent price hikes over the years, and this is the only way for China to reduce its reliance on real estate. I do not think any measures are available to remake it as a pillar of the economy,” Mao said at a seminar held by Renmin University earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why China&#39;s latest support measures won&#39;t revive its property sector&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Second- or lower-tier cities have been loosening years-long home-purchasing restrictions since late last year.监管机构还放松了对房地产开发商的融资监管。 And the central bank has said there is “marginal room to optimise” property policies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On July 19, Beijing unveiled a 31-point action plan and promised political backing for the private sector in a bid to reinvigorate the private economy and stem downward risks of overall economic growth. It also introduced measures to stimulate household consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the strongest signal for course correction in the property sector came last week from the Politburo – the prime decision-making body of the Communist Party. In a quarterly economic assessment meeting last Monday, it noted that there had been “a major change in the supply-demand situation” in the real estate market, and indicated that restrictive policies would be further relaxed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Viewing China&#39;s economic recovery as a process of “waves and zigzags”, the Politburo noted that domestic demand was insufficient, with “many hidden risks in key areas”, and that the country was facing “a complex and serious external environment”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhong Zhengsheng, chief economist with Ping An Securities, noted how it was “critical to revitalise confidence in the private sector”, particularly in terms of advanced manufacturing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And an increase in private investment is highly correlated with the adjustment in property policies and measures to address risks in the real estate sector,” he said. “But fundamentally, a revival of private-sector confidence lies in expanding domestic demand.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, most analysts expect that regulators will continue to refrain from strong stimulus measures, amid concerns that these could further inflate the property bubble.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The government does not want to solve today&#39;s problems by just creating a bigger bubble to deflate in the future,” said Wei at Gavekal Dragonomics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By digging into its monetary toolbox, Beijing could further cut mortgage rates and further relax purchase restrictions in cities.它还可以选择在大城市实施另一轮涉及“城中村”或棚户区的改造。 The last such around was in 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China must adjust its economic structure to reduce its dependency on real estate and expand consumption, as it is facing a rapidly ageing society and lower economic growth potential, Li Xunlei, chief economist of Zhongtai Securities, said at a seminar this month in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A turning point in the property cycle is looming, and the return on infrastructure investment is declining,” Li said. “地方政府债务压力巨大，而对卖地的依赖是不可持续的。 China urgently needs to transform its economy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma Guangyuan, an independent economist and deputy director of the Central Economic Committee of the China National Democratic Construction Association, said the property market will continue to be a pillar of China&#39;s economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It will remain a main investment channel for wealth portfolios,” Ma said in an article posted to his Weixin account earlier this month, adding that the property market&#39;s “role as an important force for China&#39;s economic growth will not change”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong hotels: cash-rich investors can find bargains of up to 30 per cent in ‘hot asset class’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3229403/hong-kong-hotels-cash-rich-investors-can-find-bargains-30-cent-hot-asset-class?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/30/c99bb055-ee9b-4c76-a88f-83021810ef57_de76c8ad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Cash-rich investors are looking to snap up hotels in Hong Kong, taking advantage of discounts of as much as 30 per cent, as a rapid recovery in tourism allows property owners to exit or trim their borrowing costs, according to industry observers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hotels, especially near the city&#39;s business districts, are high on the priority of investors after retail, amid limited supply due in the next few years, said Thomas Chak, co-head of capital markets and investment services at Colliers Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We see a good future for hotels,” Chak said, citing the return of tourists and the rise in the average daily rates of hotels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is a good time for cash-rich investors to [hunt for] bargains because we are in a period of high interest rates,” Chak said. Investors are increasingly eyeing hotels as a “hot asset class”, with some owners keen to offload some of their assets to lower their interest-rate burden, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week, the Hong Kong Monetary Authority, the de facto central bank, raised the city&#39;s base rate for the 11th time in 17 months, pushing the base rate to 5.75 per cent, the highest since December 2007.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, tourist arrivals in Hong Kong are on the rise, reaching nearly 13 million in the first half of the year, putting the city on track to achieve its target of 30 million for the year, according to figures from the Hong Kong Tourism Board. However, the arrivals amount to only 37 per cent seen in the same period of 2019, before the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s Far East Consortium seeks buyers for Ritz-Carlton hotels in Australia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;De Fenwick Service Apartment, a 15-storey property with 56 units, on Lockhart Road, Wan Chai, is about to be sold to China Tourism Group Hotel Holdings (CTG Hotel) for HK$900 million (US$115.4 million), according to sources familiar with the matter. The seller acquired it in 2005 for HK$392 million, according to data from the Land Registry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, CTG Hotel bought the 546-room Kimberly Hotel in Tsim Sha Tsui for HK$3.4 billion from China Cinda Asset Management, which paid HK$4.3 billion in 2019, a discount of more than 20 per cent, according to a Colliers report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Owners are also taking the advantage of the recovery in tourism to offload holdings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family of the late “shop king” Tang Shing-bor is offloading two hotels. Since Tang&#39;s death in May 2021, the family has sold dozens of real estate assets, ranging from en bloc properties and shops, to offices and parking spaces, some of them at huge losses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Tang family put the 199-room Hotel Ease Mong Kok on sale for HK$730 million this month, according to Colliers, the sole agent for the sale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It works out to a discount of more than 30 per cent to the acquisition price of HK$1.1 billion in 2018, according to government records.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family is also looking for buyers for the 119-room Hotel Ease Lai Chi Kok, which put it on the market in June. The 21-storey property, which was refurbished last year, is estimated to be worth HK$410 million, according to JLL, the sole agent for the sale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 16 hotels deals worth more than HK$15 billion were transacted since the coronavirus pandemic started in 2020 to the second quarter of this year, according to Colliers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The supply of new hotels in the coming few years will be very limited because during Covid no one wanted to build hotels,” Chak said, adding that over the past couple of years, some of the investors who bought hotels had converted them into other uses like student accommodation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of the 3,599 rooms transacted between 2020 and the second quarter of this year, almost 60 per cent were converted or expected to be converted into student accommodation or co-living facilities, according to Colliers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the tourists coming back, demand for hotel rooms is soon expected to exceed supply.根据酒店行业数据提供商CoStar（由STR更名而来）的数据，上半年酒店入住率为73.8%，而2019年同期为87.2%。 The average daily rate during the same period was about HK$1,350, close to the level of HK$1,410 in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Rising rates hit Asia-Pacific hotel deal-making in first half: JLL&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Hotels that have undergone conversion were mainly three and four-star hotels, so we are seeing keen competition among hotels [in this segment] particularly in the daily room rates, which is already very competitive,” said Lucia Leung, director of research and consultancy for Greater China at Knight Frank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Tourist arrivals are slower than expected, but we expect it will recover steadily in the second half of the year due to some major events in Hong Kong,” Leung said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seven new hotels with about 1,300 rooms are set to open this year and another two with 600 rooms are due next year, she said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>