<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Palestinian leader Abbas to visit China as Beijing expands regional engagement]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223600/palestinian-leader-abbas-visit-china-beijing-expands-regional-engagement?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 21:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/645c0ab0-8bac-4fec-9a52-2aa155c52bc2_a5ba7492.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦权力机构主席马哈茂德·阿巴斯下周将访问中国，北京将继续加强与中国的联系&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交部发言人华春莹周五表示，阿巴斯的访问将于 6 月 13 日至 16 日举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次访问正值中国加大对中东的批评之际。以色列在联合国安理会。&lt;/​​p>;&lt;p>;随着华盛顿将注意力重新集中在印太地区和乌克兰，北京加强了在中东的调解努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3 月，在北京主持秘密谈判后，中国帮助促成伊朗和沙特阿拉伯重建外交关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，中国驻联合国大使耿爽谴责以色列最近在该地区扩大定居点约旦河西岸，以及一名高级官员访问耶路撒冷的一个敏感圣地，这加剧了冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国中东特使誓言在约旦河西岸的暴力事件中与联合国合作&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“中国耿说：“将继续坚定支持巴勒斯坦人民及其恢复民族合法权利的正义事业。”在阿拉伯联盟或当时的伊斯兰会议组织之外，1988 年承认巴勒斯坦国。作为联合国安理会成员，中国一直向巴勒斯坦人提供外交和人道主义支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国建立外交1992 年与以色列建立关系，并通过“创新的全面伙伴关系”保持密切关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在过去十年中，北京一直寻求扩大其在中东的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 2013年，中国国家主席习近平分别邀请阿巴斯和以色列总理内塔尼亚胡来北京，提出基于1967年边界的“两国解决方案”寻求两国和平解决的四点计划，以东耶路撒冷为拥有完全主权的独立巴勒斯坦国的首都。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平还呼吁停止在被占领土上的定居点活动，协调解决冲突的国际努力，并更多地关注巴勒斯坦问题&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后，巴以和平举行了几次会谈，北京中东问题特使加大斡旋力度，但没有取得实质性成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿巴斯&#39; 上次访问中国是在 2017 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国的铁路计划能否吸引中东国家远离中国的“一带一路”？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;习近平向阿巴斯承诺，他将鼓励中国企业投资于并在工业区建设、人力资源培训、太阳能电站项目等方面开展合作，促进其发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国视巴以两国为‘一带一路’沿线的重要合作伙伴路线，”习说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Challenges abound if Binance seeks haven in Hong Kong amid US crackdown, analysts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3223562/challenges-abound-if-binance-seeks-haven-hong-kong-amid-us-crackdown-analysts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/391bf81c-2e2f-48b4-8f9d-a62b1902b844_755de96c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;全球最大的加密货币交易所币安可能会面临一场艰苦的战斗，如果它由于亚洲金融中心本月对运营商制定了新的许可要求，因此在美国的打击行动中寻求在香港寻求庇护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然在香港建立合法立足点可能是有益的分析师表示，对 Binance 来说，该公司可能会因为在该市获得许可而必须进行的一系列运营调整而望而却步，而美国证券交易委员会 (SEC) 本周提出的指控可能会带来更多挑战。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“Binance 将热衷于在任何具有明确的加密监管框架的市场中建立有意义的存在，而这只会因为他们在美国面临的压力而加速，”区块链负责人 Carlton Lai 和Daiwa Capital Markets 的加密货币研究。 “如果香港的制度进展顺利，如果币安不考虑获得 [virtual asset service provider] 许可证，我会感到惊讶。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但申请“在短期内肯定不会容易”对于币安来说，Lai 说，并指出美国证券交易委员会的诉讼“可能是个问题”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加密公司，包括 OKX 和火币等中国根源的公司，正在争夺香港市场的一块份额，最近推出了新规则，要求集中式加密货币交易所寻求向该市散户投资者销售和营销的许可证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，同样在中国起步的币安尚未公开表示有兴趣寻求尽管首席执行官赵长鹏最近努力谈论香港的新加密货币监管制度和中国对 Web3 行业的支持，但仍获得了该市的许可证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们欢迎该行业的监管更加明确，我们正在审查本周早些时候，币安发言人在回应邮报询问时表示：“谨慎制定规则，并考虑我们的选择，以最好地鼓励采用加密货币，以支持香港成为虚拟资产中心，同时优先保护我们的用户。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我们会定期审查和更新我们的合规政策和程序，以确保我们遵守每个司法管辖区的法律法规和合规要求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司拒绝就是否会申请香港上市公司发表评论虚拟资产牌照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 6 月 1 日生效的香港最新法规，已经在该市开展业务的交易所现在有一年的时间继续运营，同时他们准备遵守新规则或退出市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些希望留在这座城市的人将必须遵守广泛的要求，涵盖用户入职、资产托管、网络安全和公司治理等领域。根据香港证券及期货事务监察委员会 (SFC) 的规定，他们还需要对他们承认的加密代币进行尽职调查，并且只提供那些具有大市值和高流动性的代币。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这样的要求可能会带来Xapo Bank 法律和监管事务主管乔伊·加西亚 (Joey Garcia) 说，对于像币安这样大的全球实体来说，这是一项独特的挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果币安集团在香港受到监管，假设用户将受到不同的入职流程和适用性评估”，尽管该城市的用户可以使用 Binance 面向全球的实体提供的服务，而无需进行相同的入职培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Binance 也将是Garcia 说，限制其使用其现有的全球托管基础设施，并被要求在香港建立另一个托管基础设施，这可能会增加复杂性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这不一定是负面的，但它大大超过了币安集团需要遵守什么才能在世界其他司法管辖区受到监管，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于大型全球交易所，从商业角度来看，在香港获得许可并不一定有意义， FTI Capital Advisors 亚洲区负责人 Jason Ho 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“其中一些公司最不想做的就是来香港，因为他们需要披露和限制一些现有业务，这是为了赚钱，”何说。 “从商业风险的角度来看，他们可能只想保持现状而不是来这里。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加密数据提供商 Kaiko 的亚太区负责人肖恩劳伦斯也表示，其中的几个关键要素香港牌照制度将对数字资产市场参与者升级其运营模式提出“直接挑战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括要求在香港拥有一个人员齐备的法人实体，需要提高透明度最终实益拥有人，以及通过关键和高级员工“适当人选”测试的要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些对于传统金融业务来说都是相当大的挑战，更不用说那些从事数字资产业务的人了，”劳伦斯说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，海外的法律和监管问题可能会使在香港的申请复杂化，并指出证监会上个月在结论文件中表示，平台运营商“应确保其运营符合当地法律法规在他们或其关联公司运营的所有司法管辖区，因为任何违反这些要求的行为都会影响平台运营商继续在香港提供服务的适当人选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国的执法程序对 Binance 的起诉似乎是民事而非犯罪行为，”香港律师事务所 Tanner De Witt 的合伙人 Pádraig Walsh 说。 “但尽管如此，在已公布的声明中，存在一些指控，即使它只是与 Binance.US 有关，也会引起其他地方关联企业的任何监管机构的注意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt; hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese and Russian armed forces agree to hold more joint drills]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3223602/chinese-and-russian-armed-forces-agree-hold-more-joint-drills?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/77d926e1-820b-4940-83ac-b4df78a2fa18_154267b1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;两国军事领导人宣布，中俄军队将举行联合演习周五，在其东部邻国附近的联合空中巡逻加剧了与韩国和日本的紧张局势三天后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周五的视频通话中，中国联合参谋部负责人刘振利和俄罗斯国防部长瓦列里·格拉西莫夫 (Valery Gerasimov)俄罗斯军方总参谋长证实莫斯科将参加“北方联合 2023”演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;演习时间和地点尚未公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据俄罗斯国防部称，格拉西莫夫告诉刘，北京和莫斯科之间的合作“对世界局势产生了稳定作用”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我相信今天的会谈将有助于进一步加强俄中在国防领域的战略伙伴关系”格拉西莫夫说，并补充说两国的联合作战和作战训练将“继续成为优先事项”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格拉西莫夫还表示，中国国防部长李尚福 4 月份的莫斯科之行“具有重要意义” 促进中俄防务合作的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国家主席习近平 3 月访问莫斯科后，北京表示愿意参加更多的联合演习和巡逻，并与俄罗斯合作&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和俄罗斯军队近年来举行了更多的联合演习，包括“东方 2018”等大型演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，四名中国人和四名俄罗斯人军用飞机在东海和日本海（韩国称为东海）上空进行战略巡逻。据北京国防部称，这是自 2019 年以来两军年度合作计划下的第六次此类演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这架飞机进入了韩国的“防空识别区”——一个比一米宽的区域中国出于安全原因试图控制飞机的领空，但不受国际规则约束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3 月，中国与俄罗斯和伊朗在阿曼湾进行了飞行。据国家广播公司中央电视台报道，为期五天的活动包括实弹压制和打击练习以及夜间通信演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾国防部周四还报道说，中国人民解放军的飞机，包括 J-11 和 J -16 架战斗机，出动 37 架次进入该岛的防空识别区，飞行路线表明它们正在飞往西太平洋。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Cyberbullying: China looks at ‘severe penalties’ in proposed new rules to fight online violence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3223605/cyberbullying-china-looks-severe-penalties-proposed-new-rules-fight-online-violence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 21:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/0c4556b6-034a-40ca-b345-94a5a27cb4cd_7408b999.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国正计划推出一项针对猖獗网络欺凌的指令，包括与性相关的&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最高人民法院、最高人民检察院和公安部——中国三大法律机构——于周五联合发布了一套指导方针草案，公开征求意见直到 6 月 25 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该文件阐明了根据不同的现行法律如何惩罚网络暴力，但没有说明该指令何时生效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;网络暴力实例应引起注意“严厉处罚”包括欺凌未成年人和残疾人、部署付费海报、传播色情谣言、使​​用深度造假技术以及网站组织的网络欺凌。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;爆炸头发很酷&#39; : 中国女孩因爆炸头而被欺负重新引发美丽争论&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;如果网络侮辱和诽谤导致受害人精神痛苦或自杀或挑衅，执法机构将认为这些侮辱和诽谤“严重危害社会秩序”大量低俗和恶意评论”，根据拟议指令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国刑法，此类罪名最高可处以三年有期徒刑或剥夺政治权利。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;此外，如果网络暴力延伸到现实生活中，施虐者将面临刑事指控。 “人肉搜索”——或网络搜捕——如果被认为是严重的，也将被视为犯罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国没有针对网络暴力的法律，政府高级部门已经呼吁加强监管以打击此类滥用行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11 月，中国最高互联网监管机构国家互联网信息办公室发布通知，要求网站建立防止网络暴力的机制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;并且在4 月，最高人民检察院 - 中国检察院 - 发布关于“依法治网”的通知，呼吁有关部门“严惩网络暴力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来发生的多起网络欺凌事件在中国引发了悲痛和愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月，一名 23 岁的女孩因染成粉红色的头发而在网络上与抑郁症作斗争数月后自杀。她的死引发了广泛的同情和一波网上抗议浪潮。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;粉红色的力量团结女性共同反对中国的网络欺凌&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;上个月底，中国中部省份武汉市的一位母亲湖北，6 岁儿子在校内车祸身亡，因穿得光鲜亮丽被喷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月 2 日，她自杀，引发网民呼吁严惩网络暴力.几家官方媒体也加入了呼吁，包括隶属于中国执政的共产党喉舌《人民日报》的微信时事评论账号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周五发布拟议的法律指令后，总部位于武汉的媒体机构集目新闻在类似 Twitter 的社交媒体平台微博上发起了一项调查，询问用户是否支持“对网络暴力进行更严厉的惩罚”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至周五晚上 8 点，4,000 名投票参与者中有多达 3,700 人——或超过 92% - 投了赞成票。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US inflation, jobs report show Fed can’t just stick to autopilot on interest rate rises]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3223370/us-inflation-jobs-report-show-fed-cant-just-stick-autopilot-interest-rate-rises?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 21:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/5b4973e1-fdad-4129-baa0-cc7f39d60aea_7f6798af.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美联储将于 6 月 13 日至 14 日召开下一次会议，讨论货币政策。自 2022 年 3 月加息周期开始以来，讨论可能首次围绕是否停止加息展开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济数据、银行业的脆弱性和美国政府债务ceiling saga 都会影响决定。美联储可以选择保持利率不变——但越来越有可能这只是暂​​停，而不是结束加息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联邦基金期货市场，反映了投资者对中央银行将在未来几个月内做什么，最近几周发生了巨大的变化。这一指标不仅改变了未来几个月是否会加息，投资者似乎也改变了他们对美联储是否会在今年晚些时候降息的看法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 5 月份的联邦公开市场委员会会议之后，期货市场在加息周期结束时定价。它预计美联储将在今年下半年开始降息，到明年 1 月将总共降息 100 个基点。然而，截至 6 月 2 日，相同的市场定价显示，到 7 月会议再次上调 25 个基点的可能性为 80%，而第一次降息将推迟到 12 月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发生了什么变化？围绕美国区域性银行的麻烦似乎已经稳定下来。这有助于平息投资者对可能发生的银行业危机的紧张情绪。此外，近期通胀和经济数据仍显示出相当强的韧性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4月个人消费支出物价指数环比上涨0.4%，表明美联储对通胀的担忧尚未结束，尤其是服务业部门。 5 月份的就业数据远强于预期，创造了 339,000 个就业岗位，而市场预期仅为 195,000 个。 4 月份的数据也被上调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这表明加息对通胀和工人需求的降温作用有限，这可能会鼓励鹰派美联储官员提倡进一步加息。美联储自己对经济的评估，即所谓的褐皮书，也描绘了一幅稳定的经济图景，尽管企业预期正变得更加谨慎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;债务上限闹剧的结束也意味着美联储可以回归它的重点是对抗通货膨胀。乔·拜登总统和众议院议长凯文·麦卡锡就一项将债务上限提高至 2025 年 1 月的法案达成一致。该法案中削减开支的经济影响可能有限，而且该立法在国会获得通过的速度将限制任何对美国经济和金融稳定造成短期损害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于银行业危机和政府违约的风险降低，以及强劲的经济数据，美联储为什么不加息？美联储需要考虑几个因素，而不是像过去 15 个月那样继续自动驾驶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政策利率在过去 15 个月已经迅速上升，几乎没有央行行长会不同意我们已经处于限制性货币政策领域。看看 3 月份的经济预测摘要，该摘要整理了美联储高级官员对经济和政策利率的预测，18 位官员中有 10 位预测政策利率将保持在当前水平，直到 2023 年底，而只有七位预测利率将结束&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然在 6 月的更新中这种情况仍可能发生变化，但这些预测表明大多数官员认为加息周期即将结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使是经济数据，尤其是就业市场和消费，仍显示出相当强韧的迹象，其他领先指标都闪烁着谨慎的迹象。特别是，银行正在整合贷款标准，要么是因为它们受到存款外流的限制，要么是因为风险管理者因经济前景而变得更加谨慎。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美联储将在今年最后一次加息。汇丰银行和香港银行会效仿吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这种始于 2022 年底的紧缩政策在过去一直是美国经济衰退的可靠指标，美联储应注意其行动不会导致经济急剧收缩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毕竟，高利率不会立即打破局面——存在时间滞后，政策制定者不仅需要考虑未来几个月，还需要考虑进一步，衡量利率的正确水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，美联储在未来的紧缩政策中更加谨慎，而不是仅仅根据当前数据自动加息是有意义的。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best &lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong protests: High Court orders magistrate to revisit acquittal of couple who taunted man later set on fire]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3223599/hong-kong-protests-high-court-orders-magistrate-revisit-acquittal-couple-who-taunted-man-later-set?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 20:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/44162576-3544-4224-bf26-20860b835e50_b4aa97c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港检察官赢得了对一对嘲弄男子的夫妇无罪释放的上诉在他于 2019 年反政府抗议活动期间被纵火之前，一名法官将案件发回审讯裁判官重审。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高等法院周五裁定，陈海云和她的丈夫 Kwong由于对法律的错误解释，耀文在公共场合扰乱治安的行为被错误地宣告无罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但法官 Judianna Barnes 没有下令重审，而是要求下级法院根据正确的法律重新审理其裁决考虑到自 2019 年 11 月 11 日事件发生以来已经过去的时间，原审期间已经确立的原则和事实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还恢复了对每名被告人 1,000 港元（127 美元）的保释金在他们被无罪释放之前被指控，并禁止他们离开香港，直到审讯裁判官再次就此事作出裁决。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港法院敦​​促复核这对嘲弄男子纵火的人的无罪释放&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A在马鞍山的一次示威活动中，一名因匿名令而无法透露身份的中年建筑工人被激进抗议者点燃。他严重烧伤但幸免于难。这名男子早些时候追赶破坏新界镇火车站的破坏者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;37 岁的陈和 42 岁的邝被指控在行人天桥上与该男子发生口头冲突对该事件“意图挑起破坏和平，或可能导致破坏和平”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东区法院在 2020 年的审判中听说，陈曾告诉受害人“回到大湾区”，这里指的是邻近广东省的城市，而 Kwong 则告诉该男子“滚开”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在澄清这对夫妇的不检点行为时，地方法官 Arthur Lam Hei- wei 对他们的嘲讽与随后的袭击之间的关联表示怀疑，并补充说他很难确定被告的行为可能会破坏治安。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;纵火&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但巴恩斯不同意，称这对夫妇的言语攻击相当于火上浇油。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“客观地看，[被告]的火爆和喧嚣行为具有挑衅性并且可能导致[受害人]和/或现场的其他人诉诸非法武力并破坏社会安宁，”法官说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地方法官的“不正当”裁决认为这对夫妇的口头对抗不太可能扰乱社会秩序，这也是因为他没有考虑到当时充满政治色彩的环境，她继续说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官驳回了辩方关于将案件移交地方法官不公平的说法&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相反，地方法官基于对法律的错误解读而认定 [被告] 无罪，这对检方司法部是不公平的，”她补充说。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;香港三人因在 2019 年反政府抗议活动期间在理大发生骚乱而入狱&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;11 月 11 日的袭击事件标志着当年社会动荡中最臭名昭著的一章，引渡法案引发了此后&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方逮捕了 18 名与该事件有关的人，他们涉嫌多项违法行为，但据信这两名年龄分别为 17 岁和 25 岁的主要嫌疑人在警方查明他们身份之前逃往了台湾.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据《公安条例》，在公共场合扰乱秩序最高可判处一年监禁。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 20:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesia’s ‘Amish of Asia’ Indigenous group wants internet blackout]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223598/indonesias-amish-asia-indigenous-group-wants-internet-blackout?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 20:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/2036b798-57dd-4077-88af-5b5053a1c174_98991253.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚的一个原住民社区要求在他们的地区中断互联网，以尽量减少“官方周五表示，“网络世界的负面影响”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爪哇岛万丹省的 Baduy 社区有 26,000 人，他们将自己分为部分采用技术的外部群体和神圣的内部群体&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据法新社看到的一封信，内部组织要求当局关闭互联网接收或转移附近的电信塔，这样信号就不会到达他们。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“这一请求是我们努力尽量减少智能手机对我们人民的负面影响的一部分，”Baduy 代表写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们认为，在他们所在地区附近建造的电信塔可能会威胁到他们的生活方式&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lebak 地区的官员告诉法新社，他们周一收到了这封信，并同意与印度尼西亚信息部交谈，以尝试遵守&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lebak 官员布迪·桑托索 (Budi Santoso) 周五告诉法新社：“基本上，我们希望始终满足巴杜伊人的需求，并需要保持他们的传统和当地智慧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;他说外来的巴杜伊人需要互联网，他们开始了在线业务，但官员们也担心访客或游客可以访问网络并向巴杜伊人展示他们认为不合适的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;我们的新地狱：土著印度尼西亚人在绿色运动中面临新的风险&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在保守的、穆斯林占多数的印度尼西亚，互联网自由是一个有争议的问题。政府已禁止赌博和色情内容，并要求互联网提供商过滤掉他们认为不合适的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管有审查制度，但托管此类内容的非法网站依然猖獗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;隐居的巴杜伊内城– 被西方媒体称为亚洲阿米什人 – 选择住在森林里，拒绝技术、金钱和传统教育。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们住在三个村庄，占地 4,000 公顷（9,900 英亩）距首都雅加达数小时车程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府于 1990 年宣布该地区为文化保护区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚是一个多元化的国家，有 1,300 多个民族分布在群岛。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan passes controversial ‘life and death’ bill to revise immigration law for refugees]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3223578/japan-passes-controversial-life-and-death-bill-revise-immigration-law-refugees?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 18:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/d116f4b6-ce3b-4d08-984b-47e70d25d0d6_15d8eb1e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本议会周五通过了一项修订移民和难民法的法案，使当局能够不顾一些反对党的反对，驱逐反复申请庇护身份的个人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该立法的反对者在雨中聚集在东京国会大楼前，要求废除该法案，而反对派立法者批评执政阵营“推翻”了该法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参议院或上议院在首相岸田文雄领导的执政自民党的支持下制定了该法律，其小联盟伙伴公明党以及其他相对保守的反对派力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然日本目前无法将正在处理难民身份申请的外国人送回本国，但移民当局怀疑许多人滥用职权&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据修订后的法律，政府将致力于减少在移民设施中的长期拘留，并鼓励驱逐不遵守驱逐出境规定的外国人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对者争辩说，修订后的立法可能会导致那些在本国面临迫害风险、危及生命的人被遣返，并导致被驱逐出境的儿童在日本出生和长大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据日本移民服务局的数据，截至去年年底，有 4,233 名外国人不顾被命令返回家园而拒绝回国。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;法律将允许政府驱逐那些在第三次请求后未能提出合理理由获得难民身份的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，批评者提出了反驳，指出一些庇护寻求者过去曾在提出三个或更多申请后获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为向来自受冲突影响地区的外国人提供帮助，修订后的法律提供了“准难民”身份，使他们能够留在日本，即使他们不符合被承认为完全授权难民的标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为防止长期拘留的努力的一部分，政府将允许申请难民身份的个人在移民局之外居住设施在家人或支持者的监督下，以避免逃跑的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但反对者对该系统的有效性表示怀疑，称这给那些监视寻求庇护者的人带来了沉重的负担。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p&lt;p>;与此同时，主要在野党立宪民主党呼吁成立第三方机构来审查目前由移民当局执行的难民承认程序，以确保程序的公正性。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;执政集团拒绝了该请求，仅对该法案进行了微小的修改，例如培训移民官员如何筛查寻求庇护者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最后一刻试图阻止the revision bill, the opposition party submitted a censure motion against Justice Minister Ken Saito, who is in charge of the legislation, which was eventually voted down in the upper house on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Outside the Diet building on Friday , dissidents held a rally, with some raising placards with phrases written in English such as “Protect refugees”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the run-up to the vote at the plenary session of the upper house, Taiga Ishikawa of the Constitutional Democratic Party of Japan lambasted the legislation, saying, “This is a matter of life and death for many people.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ishikawa also said the revised law could see asylum seekers repatriated even though they face imprisonment or torture in their home nations. The bill was finally passed, with opposition lawmakers jeering at Hidehisa Otsuji, president of the upper house.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Sanseito: the new far-right party hoping to &#39;make Japan great again&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Japan lags far behind the United States and several European countries that typically accept more than 10,000 asylum seekers annually. In 2022, the Asian nation gave refugee status to 202 people, including 147 from Afghanistan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2021, the government shelved an amendment bill for the immigration law amid a growing backlash after a 33-year-old Sri Lankan woman died while being held at an immigration facility in Nagoya, central Japan that same year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She had been complaining of stomach pain and other symptoms for a few months and ultimately died due to a lack of necessary medical care.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, the Kishida administration submitted to parliament the latest version of the bill, which largely retains the contents of the one that was previously withdrawn.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China offers South Africa help with BRICS summit security while arrest warrant out for possible attendee Putin]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223571/china-offers-south-africa-help-boost-brics-summit-security-while-arrest-warrant-out-possible?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/aea21664-9344-42aa-b005-b18f5133b861_c62acaac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s top police officer has promised South Africa that Beijing will help bolster security for the BRICS summit in August amid controversy over Russian President Vladimir Putin&#39;s possible attendance while an international warrant is out for his arrest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a meeting with South African Police Minister Bheki Cele in Beijing on Thursday, Public Security Minister Wang Xiaohong said China was willing to work with South Africa to “strengthen the security” of the BRICS summit to be held in Johannesburg on August 22-24.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BRICS is made up of members China, India, Russia, Brazil and South Africa. The possible attendance of Putin – who is the subject of a war crimes arrest warrant by the International Criminal Court – has put South Africa&#39;s handling of the warrant and summit security under the spotlight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ICC issued the warrant for Putin in March, accusing him of the unlawful deportation of children and unlawful transfer of people from the territory of Ukraine to the Russian Federation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a signatory to the ICC, South Africa would be obliged to execute the warrant if Putin visited the country for the summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, South Africa issued diplomatic immunity for attendees in late May. Its foreign ministry said it was South Africa&#39;s “standard” conferment of immunity for international conferences and summits held in the country and “the immunities are for the conference and not for specific individuals”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;BRICS meet with &#39;friends&#39; seeking closer ties amid push to expand bloc&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;South Africa has sent an invitation to Putin but neither it nor Russia have confirmed he will attend. However, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said on May 30 that “Russia will participate in the BRICS summit at an appropriate level”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin spoke with his South African counterpart Cyril Ramaphosa on the phone on Wednesday about preparations for the summit in Johannesburg, as well as the Russia-Africa summit in St Petersburg, the Kremlin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Africa declined to enforce an ICC warrant for the arrest of the Sudanese dictator Omar al-Bashir during a visit in 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has not announced whether President Xi Jinping will attend the summit, but during a phone call between Chinese Foreign Minister Qin Gang and his South African counterpart Naledi Pandoron Tuesday, Qin said Beijing was willing to “support South Africa in successfully hosting the leaders&#39; meeting, strengthen the solidarity and cooperation of BRICS countries”, according to a statement from the ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the meeting on Thursday, police chief Wang also pledged to work with South Africa to ensure the security of China&#39;s Belt and Road Initiative, crack down on transnational crime and build law enforcement capacity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Africa is among some 40 African nations with which China has signed public security and law enforcement agreements, according to a report by Africa-China security expert Paul Nantulya published in May by the Africa Centre for Strategic Studies at the National Defence University in Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Africa backtracks on quitting ICC before possible Putin visit&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In recent years, China&#39;s law enforcement cooperation with countries such as Solomon Islands has been under scrutiny.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And during a meeting between Wang Xiaohong and the Cuban Minister of Interior Lazaro Alberto Alvarez Casas in May, Wang said the two sides should strengthen cooperation to prevent “colour revolutions” and build law enforcement capacity.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s anti-corruption body expels ex-central bank deputy Fan Yifei from Communist Party for ‘serious violations’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3223572/chinas-anti-corruption-body-expels-ex-central-bank-deputy-fan-yifei-communist-party-serious?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/eb960b47-7e69-4e40-a3f4-9a80729f3bed_a302ae34.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A former deputy governor of China&#39;s central bank has been expelled from the Communist Party and dismissed from public office for “serious violation of discipline and law”, the country&#39;s top anti-corruption body said on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fan Yifei, 59, was placed under investigation by the party disciplinary organ in November when he was deputy head of the People&#39;s Bank of China (PBOC).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He is the most senior central banker to be placed under investigation as Beijing has stepped up its crackdown on corruption in the financial sector over the past two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) said that Fan had “ignored” the spirit and principle of the party and also accepted invitations to banquets, travel, golfing and private clubs against regulations, while he also took gifts and cash against the rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fan, who was found to have engaged in “superstitious activities”, also used his position to seek benefits for others, allowing his relatives to be paid without doing any work, the CCDI said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also “traded power for personal gain and sex”, interfering in law enforcement activities, the anti-corruption agency said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He relied on finance, but also fed on finance,” it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statement described Fan as “reckless” and someone who had no “bottom line” of discipline and law.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China expels ex-top official for &#39;faking&#39; economic data, taking &#39;money, gifts&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Fan was also accused of using his position within the financial industry to obtain loans for others and “illegally accepting large amounts of property”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Fan Yifei seriously violated the party&#39;s political discipline, organisational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline, and life discipline, which constituted a serious duty violation and was suspected of accepting bribes and should be dealt with seriously,” CCDI said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It added that Fan&#39;s “illegal” gains would be confiscated and that he would be prosecuted in “accordance with the law”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s corruption crackdown ensnares high-ranking PBOC official Sun Guofeng&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Fan is a veteran banker who spent most of his career with China Construction Bank before becoming a deputy governor of the central bank in 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has also been a key driver of China&#39;s digital currency transition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, Sun Guofeng, head of the PBOC&#39;s monetary policy department, was removed from office and is now subject to a disciplinary review and supervisory investigation on suspicion of “serious violations of discipline and the law” – a common euphemism for corruption.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s era? Top finance officials flex city’s offshore yuan hub muscles at Caixin summit, Shanghai’s Lujiazui Forum]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3223582/hong-kongs-era-top-finance-officials-flex-citys-offshore-yuan-hub-muscles-caixin-summit-shanghais?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.09 19:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/09/11fd6585-d45f-4e74-ae37-36581b6c942a_4ace5bcc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Paul Chan Mo-po, Julia Leung Fung-yee, Eddie Yue Wai-man and Christopher Hui Ching-yu, Hong Kong&#39;s top finance officials, have reiterated the city&#39;s unique role as China&#39;s offshore financial hub, saying the city can promote the yuan&#39;s internationalisation at a time when tensions between Beijing and Washington are showing no signs of abating.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city is prepared to roll out more financial products to absorb the offshore Chinese currency in the future, adding to the impending launch of the dual-currency trading counter model for stocks and the Swap Connect mechanism, Chan, Hong Kong&#39;s Financial Secretary, told the Caixin Summer Summit 2023 in Hong Kong on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even though the world economy has emerged out of the shadows of Covid-19, the global environment is still complicated,” Chan said. “It is in such an era that Hong Kong can play a crucial role of a platform for China and collaborations with foreign countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We will continue to reform and optimise Hong Kong&#39;s financial market, deepen interactions with the mainland&#39;s financial markets and establish links between China and the world&#39;s capitals.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s ambition to challenge the US dollar&#39;s status as the world&#39;s major reserve currency that dominates global trade and commodity trades offers Hong Kong an unprecedented opportunity to recast its image as a financial centre after three years of isolation from the rest of the world during the Covid-19 pandemic. More than 30 countries including Brazil and Saudi Arabia have now agreed to use the yuan for trade settlements, creating huge demand for more investment channels in the offshore market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong is already the world&#39;s biggest market for the offshore yuan, processing about 75 per cent of settlements involving the currency globally. It had 1 trillion yuan (US$140 billion) in offshore yuan deposits as of the end of 2022, according to central bank data, versus 718.3 billion yuan in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Dual counter to lift Hong Kong&#39;s yuan hub status, improve liquidity&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The main thing about the internationalisation of the yuan is that the US dollar keeps raising interest rates, while the yuan is cutting [rates],” Leung, CEO of Hong Kong&#39;s Securities and Futures Commission (SFC), said at the Caixin Summit. “For the first time in years, the yuan has lower financing costs than the US dollar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The other side of the coin is geopolitics, where countries are starting to experiment with local currencies and yuan payments in commodity trading.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The next product in store might be offshore futures on Chinese government bonds for hedging needs, Yue, CEO of the Hong Kong Monetary Authority, told the same conference. Meanwhile, Hui, Hong Kong&#39;s Secretary for Financial Services and the Treasury, told Shanghai&#39;s Lujiazui Forum that the yuan “is an inevitable choice” for asset allocations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“More regions including Asia are considering diversification in terms of asset allocation, when a wild swing or a spike in the US interest rate impacts the exchange rate,” Hui said. “人民币是必然的选择。 With the yuan being part of multi-asset allocations, Hong Kong can do lots of jobs in many aspects.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said the yuan currently has only a 3 per cent share of international cross-border payments and reserve currencies, a position that is not matched by China&#39;s size in foreign trade and the economy. The SFC&#39;s Leung said China&#39;s low interest rate environment might spur more companies to increasingly tap offshore markets by selling yuan bonds because of the Chinese currency&#39;s funding cost edge over the US dollar, offering a new window for internationalising the yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong is launching on June 19 the dual-currency stock trading counters, which will allow local and overseas investors to freely convert selected stocks between the yuan and the Hong Kong dollar. The scheme, which is designed to promote the use of the offshore yuan, has already approved 21 stocks, such as those of Chinese technology giants Alibaba Group Holding – this newspaper&#39;s parent firm – and Tencent Holdings, for trading.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong poised to drive yuan internationalisation, tech innovation: HKEX&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong and mainland Chinese regulators are also discussing giving onshore investors access to the dual-currency trading, a move that can save these investors exchange-rate costs and expand the pool of yuan to be deposited in the city, the SFC&#39;s Leung said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dual-currency trading counter model comes a month after the city introduced the Swap Connect, which allows foreign investors to participate in the mainland&#39;s interbank financial derivates market for the first time. Hong Kong also already has cross-border link programmes with the mainland covering stocks, bonds and wealth-management products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said Hong Kong will turn more towards Asian markets, particularly Southeast Asian and Middle Eastern countries, for trade liberalisation and investment opportunities, as their economies have shown more resilience than western countries, which are gripped by higher borrowing costs and recession threats. At the same time, bourse operator Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing will further explore listing resources in these two regions, where many companies are interested in going public in Hong Kong, the SFC&#39;s Leung said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Investors eye Hong Kong stocks without currency angst as June countdown begins&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We hope to grow with other offshore yuan centres and grasp these opportunities together,” the HKMA&#39;s Yuen told the Caixin summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We hope that we can together make good use of the infrastructure of the Hong Kong market to promote innovation and growth in the cross-border and offshore business, and create a better yuan ecosystem to further promote the process of its internationalisation.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 09 Jun 2023 19:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>