<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong tourists in Japan face flight and rail disruption caused by Typhoon Lan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3231207/hong-kong-tourists-japan-face-flight-and-rail-disruption-caused-typhoon-lan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 00:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/3fac583d-e4f6-4a81-9dca-47ff1dfc5c7c_d43809ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台风兰周二袭击日本西部后，香港人的旅游计划陷入混乱，从大阪起飞的航班仅在晚上恢复，通往该市关西机场的交通早些时候已停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当兰于周二早上抵达大阪南部时，所有通往关西的铁路服务都停止了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;52岁的托尼·吴(Tony Ng)在建筑行业工作，原计划从关西乘坐香港快运航空的航班回国。在日本西部度过了六天的家庭假期后的下午。但廉价航空公司告诉他，航班推迟到晚上 11 点 30 分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为以防万一，吴一行三人于周一提前一晚搬出位于大阪的宾馆，并在酒店预订了两晚。距关西机场一个火车站。他们还额外预订了一晚作为备用，以防进一步延误。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但当他周一晚上入住酒店时，他被迫再次改变计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“酒店接待员告诉我，如果我们现在不前往机场，我们可能会错过周二的航班。”Ng 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，他的团队抓起行李，取消了酒店预订，然后就冲了出去。前往机场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们一无所知，因为我们没有看到日本当局的消息。我们只知道航班时间改变了。”吴说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本媒体报道，周二约有 650 名乘客在机场过夜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴说，他在机场发现了其他香港人。机场餐厅和便利店全天库存充足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，在航站楼露营的乘客也得到了毯子和水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“感觉很奇怪，吴说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;旅行混乱：日本为应对台风“兰”而取消火车和航班&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港快运航空派出两架飞机周二有两班飞往大阪的航班，分别于晚上 9 时 20 分及晚上 10 时 40 分抵达，两班往香港的航班预计于周三晚上 11 时 30 分及凌晨 1 时起飞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港航空改期 3 趟大阪航班周二晚上 9.30 至午夜期间飞往关西机场的航班。该航空公司运营了两趟航班，预计在午夜后离开日本城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自韩国、台湾和澳大利亚的一系列国际航班也在当地时间晚上 9 点后降落在关西机场。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;香港快运航空的母公司国泰航空和日本廉价航空公司乐桃取消或推迟了周二至周三飞往大阪的航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关西机场的道路连接于当地时间周二下午 6 点左右重新开放，但火车当天余下时间，除一条线路在晚上 9 点后恢复运营约三个小时外，服务仍然暂停。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Peko Wong 在香港快运航空 Facebook 页面上报道称，她在大阪的酒店设法安排了一辆出租车&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是叶永佑说，他的酒店坚称乘出租车到达机场可能会遇到困难，尽管他最终到达了机场。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国在 2019 年搜寻 16 名失踪人员。西安东北部将迎来更多降雨&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港快运航空表示，建议乘客在出发前查看航空公司和机场网站的最新信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港航空向《华盛顿邮报》推荐了《华盛顿邮报》大阪运营的旅行警报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，日本各地至少有 900 趟国内航班被取消，周三取消的航班更多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本预计将在福冈和东京之间开通新干线子弹头列车从周三早上开始恢复正常服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年 9 月，日本西部遭受台风飞燕袭击时，关西机场出现混乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数千名旅客被困在人工岛上一艘重达 2,591 吨的油轮拖锚并撞上了机场的道路连接线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机场停机坪的一大片区域也被风暴潮淹没。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Afghanistan’s Taliban government marks 2 years since return to power]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3231204/afghanistans-taliban-government-marks-2-years-return-power?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 23:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/fe9112af-8285-4b74-93ad-8efeb99769e7_69fa400b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二，阿富汗塔利班政府与支持者一起庆祝其重新掌权两周年批评者谴责对妇女权利日益收紧的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿富汗伊斯兰酋长国（塔利班对该国的正式名称）的旗帜在首都喀布尔飘扬，2021 年 8 月 15 日，喀布尔坠落，美国支持的政府垮台，其领导人流亡国外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后的两年里，塔利班当局对伊斯兰教实行了严格的解释，妇女首当其冲地受到联合国称为“性别”的法律的影响。种族隔离”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局发表声明称赞这场胜利能够“为阿富汗建立伊斯兰制度铺平道路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“征服喀布尔证明了这一点声明称，“没有人可以再次控制阿富汗这个令人自豪的国家”，并且“不会允许任何入侵者威胁该国的独立和自由”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数百名塔利班支持者，其中包括老年男性聚集在废弃的美国使馆大楼附近的年轻男孩们，这是目前空置的众多使馆之一 - 塔利班政府仍未得到任何其他国家的正式承认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国制造的军用车辆，由美国制造新的塔利班统治者在经历了长达一周的混乱撤退后被国际部队抛在身后，滚过坚固的使馆围墙半开的大门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在西部的赫拉特市，一群塔利班分子支持者高呼：“欧洲人去死，西方人去死，阿富汗伊斯兰酋长国万岁，美国人去死。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坎大哈是塔利班运动的摇篮，也是隐居的最高领袖的发源地。官员告诉记者，希巴图拉·阿洪扎达 (Hibatullah Akhundzada) 根据法令进行统治，阅兵被取消，然后转移到军事大院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坎大哈居民 Agha Sahib 赞扬了阿洪扎达的领导能力，称他统一了国家。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“当他从（坎大哈）发布一项法令时，阿富汗 34 个省份都会接受该法令，”这位 24 岁的内政部工作人员说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些法令已被阿富汗 34 个省份所接受。然而，这并没有受到所有阿富汗人的平等欢迎，也没有受到国际社会的欢迎，国际社会在是否与塔利班当局接触的问题上存在分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对妇女权利的限制——被挤出公共空间、就业和教育– 一直是获得承认和援助的主要障碍，由于外国对与喀布尔的新统治者打交道持谨慎态度，承认和援助被削减。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国的经济和人道主义危机是许多阿富汗人的一个严重担忧，即使，赫拉特人力车司机阿卜杜勒瓦斯·卡德里（Abdulwase Qadri）表示，战斗结束后他们松了口气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这两年已经提供了安全保障，”35 岁的他说。 “但工作环境对年轻人不利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女性的工作途径尤其被关闭，最近全国数千家美容院被关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;非政府组织再次谴责塔利班当局对待妇女的方式来纪念这一周年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们强烈谴责塔利班持续不断且不断升级的严重侵犯人权行为，特别是针对妇女和女童的行为，以及缺乏足够的保护包括人权观察组织和国际特赦组织在内的 10 个人权组织发表的联合声明表示：“这是国际社会的有效回应。”塔利班在周年纪念前统治，敦促国际社会采取更多行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国敦促加大对阿富汗的支持，但提醒塔利班“期望”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“阿富汗已陷入深渊” ”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，在邻国巴基斯坦的首都，100 多名阿富汗妇女举着一张海报进行抗议，上面写着：“8 月 15 日黑色日&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于根据新法律不得不放弃医学研究的喀布尔居民法拉赫来说，这个周年纪念日也是一个严峻的提醒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我面临着未知的未来，被剥夺了受教育的权利，同时我看到塔利班今天庆祝他们的胜利，”她说。 “我看到自己的黑暗未来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;研究人员表示，英国士兵在从阿富汗撤军后感到内疚&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但对于她 21 岁的男性同伴来说，这是光明的一天仍在学习医学的莫尔塔扎·凯里 (Mortaza Khairi) 周二参加了喀布尔大学由高等教育部主办的庆祝活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们今天需要庆祝，”他说。 “今天标志着我们国家占领的结束。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong construction industry issues revised guidelines on heat stress alerts in bid to fix ‘confusing and impractical’ system]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231205/hong-kong-construction-industry-issues-revised-guidelines-heat-stress-alerts-bid-fix-confusing-and?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 23:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/c781628b-6b27-463f-b808-3768f5422d8c_f0121ae0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港建造业人士已达成共识，至少给予工地工人每当政府发布热应激警报时，无论工作类型如何，两次最多 30 分钟的休息时间和更长的午休时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行业领导者表示，他们希望周二生效的新指导方针能够得到落实。在当局推出工作中热应激三级预警系统三个月后，这是在更好地保护炎热天气下的员工方面向前迈出的一步。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;对香港的新高温预警系统感到炎热和烦恼吗？邮报有答案&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;行业措施由香港建造商会、工会及分包商共同草拟，并获劳工处认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会代表超过300家公司占该市建筑项目营业额的 70% 以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会执行董事梁敬国周二表示，希望这些措施能够解决政府在建筑工程中的模糊性问题。工会成员称其为“令人困惑且不切实际”的现行防暑指南。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然该部门的指南建议员工在发布高温警报时每小时停止工作 15 至 45 分钟，但由工会发布的指南周二，业界建议员工上午 10 点休息 15 分钟，下午 3 点 15 分休息 30 分钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港建筑和清洁行业放弃令人困惑的防暑规定&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当发出琥珀色警报时，午休时间将从之前的一个小时延长至一个小时十五分钟。当出现红色警报时，每次休息时间将额外增加 15 分钟。当发出黑色警告时，所有员工都必须停止工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望这些指导方针......帮助该行业切实落实工人的休息时间。建议的休息时间是工人应有的最短时间。”梁说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次修订涵盖了所有建筑工种，没有像政府规定的那样将其分为轻、中、重工。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;指南还建议为工人采取避暑措施，包括在现场提供庇护所和冷却设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梁建议现场安全人员每天早上进行风险评估，并根据情况为工人制定灵活的休息时间” &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的热应激警告“没有考虑到整个城市的气温差异”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他还强调，最新的指导方针将“符合”政府的框架和三级预警系统。政府的系统是以天文台和中文大学共同制定的香港炎热指数为基础的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港建造业总工会主席黄屏对新指引表示欢迎，并表示将给予工人休息的“合法性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“较长的休息时间不可避免地会导致一些建设项目的延误，但工人的健康应该放在第一位。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;协会副会长- 总裁冯国强表示，固定时间休息对雇主来说更“易于管理”，并将进一步改善政府的指导方针。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此前，建造业曾表示，雇员没有意识到这一点&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;如何改善对工人的热应激警告并避免出现失误&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一些工人和工会成员指出，雇主对政府的指导方针感到困惑劳工处发言人表示，从5月15日至7月31日，官员进行了8,500次现场视察，并发出了530次警告，敦促责任方进行热应激风险评估和控制措施。他说没有雇主被起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.最好&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China watching closely as US, Japan, South Korea aim for ‘de facto Asian Nato’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231201/china-watching-closely-us-japan-south-korea-aim-de-facto-asian-nato?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 23:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/a95330b2-a5b0-4b5a-9802-c79288b26919_6d9876f6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;据说，随着美国总统乔·拜登主持会议，中国处于“高度戒备”状态日本和韩国领导人本周在戴维营会晤，深化技术和防务关系 — — 在中国家门口建立一些观察家所称的“事实上的亚洲北约”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国总统尹锡烈和日本首相岸田文雄将于周五与拜登一起出席位于马里兰州乡村的美国总统度假胜地，举行首次此类三方峰会。美国高级官员告诉路透社，预计他们将宣布扩大弹道导弹防御系统和技术开发合作的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还可能同意设立一条新的三向危机热线，并每年聚集一次路透社援引官员的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国、日本、韩国联手，中国敦促中国加强防务谈判&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;外交部发言人汪文斌在北京表示，中国反对“有关国家拼凑各种小圈子”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[中国]也反对加剧对抗、危害他国战略安全的做法，”王说。 “有关国家应该顺应时代潮流，多做有利于地区和平、稳定、繁荣的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辽宁大学美国与东亚研究院院长陆超”卢说：“这实际上相当于三方军事联盟的形成。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然朝鲜预计将成为首要议程，但北京将关注预计联合声明中对台湾的具体提及中国大陆的观察人士表示，将在峰会结束时发布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京认为台湾是一个分裂的省份，最终会统一，如果需要的话可以使用武力。虽然包括美国、日本和韩国在内的大多数国家不承认自治的台湾是一个独立国家，但反对任何武力夺岛的企图。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国对此保持高度警惕卢说：“峰会，特别是如果要提到台湾问题的话。” “如果他们在峰会上公开提出台湾问题，将被视为对中国的强烈挑衅，对于亚太地区的稳定来说将是一个危险的举动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明还将包含一般性内容一位不愿透露姓名的美国官员对路透表示，双方就维护台海和平与稳定发表了意见，但具体措辞预计要到最后一刻才能协商确定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五的峰会是在拜登进行了数月的外交努力之后举行的。美国政府试图将华盛顿的条约盟友日本和韩国联合起来，作为加强亚洲军事联盟以对抗中国的行动的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国于 1951 年与日本签署了《相互合作与安全条约》 . 1953年，朝鲜战争停战后，它与韩国签署了《共同防御条约》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东京和首尔有着一段麻烦的历史，特别是在日本战时的暴行和领土问题上，但崛起的中国、俄罗斯军国主义和拥有核武器的朝鲜是拉近这两个邻国和美国关系的因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;紧张局势不时达到顶峰，直到最近几个月出现重大缓和。去年 5 月上任后，寻求修复与日本的关系，并启动了以美国为中心的战略支点，以应对来自朝鲜日益严峻的军事挑战以及与中国和俄罗斯的关系恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜试-去年，朝鲜发射了约 90 枚导弹，几乎是 2017 年高峰期 25 枚的四倍。上个月，朝鲜测试了最新的火星 18 洲际弹道导弹，称这是对美国和其他对手的警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据朝鲜中央通讯社报道，朝鲜领导人金正恩上周视察一家军工厂时呼吁增加导弹产量，以帮助确保“压倒性的军事力量”并为战争做好准备。几天前，美韩将于周一开始年度联合军事演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据北约条约第 5 条中的集体防御原则，对一个盟友的攻击被视为对一个盟友的攻击。 ”刘说：“北约国家相互之间有安全承诺，日本和韩国是安全伙伴，而不是盟友。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三个国家的战略目标也不同。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;“美国可能会从全球角度考虑[其目标]，而日本则主要针对中国……与此同时，韩国正试图加强与美国和日本的安全合作，以对朝鲜建立更大的军事威慑” 。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，他预计“针对中国的联合军事演习和三边磋商”将会继续。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周二纪念韩国摆脱日本殖民统治 78 周年的演讲中尹表示，日本将加强与美国和日本的安全合作，应对朝鲜的核威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在日本纪念二战战败 78 周年之际，岸田重申和平承诺&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;首尔西江大学国际关系教授 Kim Jae-chun 也表示，任何三边军事技术合作都将主要集中在朝鲜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然此前的讨论仍停留在共享朝鲜导弹警报上”金正恩表示，“现在它将重点进行利用雷达和导弹武器系统拦截朝鲜弹道导弹的演习。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为这对于遏制朝鲜核发展具有重大意义。然而，中国将批评韩国加入美国导弹防御系统。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金正恩表示，虽然三边峰会后的联合声明不太可能将中国视为威胁，但美中竞争已经无论三边峰会的目的如何，都已经转变为战略竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当前趋势表明，中俄朝在东北亚的合作正在加强，美韩日关系正在加强。”回应也越来越多……看来双方正在互相牵制。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Number of childless Hong Kong couples doubles in 5 years as average births drop below 1 per family for first time]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3231195/childless-hong-kong-couples-double-5-years-average-births-drop-below-1-family-first-time?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 21:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/03881c67-4fa8-4612-9654-81ff0753962f_5a03c996.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港无子女夫妇的数量已达到“惊人”水平，计划生育协会警告称，一项调查发现，没有子女的受访者比例在五年内增加了一倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二公布的调查还发现，该市夫妇的平均孩子数量下降至创出0.9的新低，打破了2012年1.2的纪录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在香港，我们面临[人口]老龄化的情况，因为我们没有足够的年轻人，”该协会名誉顾问说和研究小组委员会主席叶兆辉教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，香港面临着移民挑战、生育率低下和预期寿命不断延长的问题，并补充说：“[人口]老龄化将成为未来几年会越来越严重。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学人口专家叶先生评论该协会的《香港计划生育知识、态度和实践调查》的结果，该研究在 2022 年 9 月至 12 月期间对 1,502 名女性及其男性伴侣进行了调查。其中，1,104 名女性已婚，398 名未婚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项每五年进行一次的研究发现，无子女夫妇数量从 20.6 增加了一倍多。 2017 年，受访者中生育一孩的比例上升至 43.2%，取代了全市平均水平（27.4%）。大约四分之一的受访者（25.2%）有两个孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017年，38.3%的夫妇有一个孩子，其中33.8%的夫妇有两个孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;洪在边境重新开放和入境计划的帮助下，香港人口达到 750 万&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;叶表示，无子女夫妇数量的增加“相当惊人”，特别是根据预测，该市最新的生育率为 772 人未来两到五年可能会更低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生育率是指1000名妇女一生中平均活产婴儿的数量，该数字不包括家庭佣工。根据政府统计处的数据，这一数字较2016年的1,205人稳步下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;叶说，小家庭已成为高收入社会的常态，不仅在香港，在新加坡、东京也是如此。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，特别是在香港，结婚人数减少，导致生育率下降70%，而另外30%则是因为生育率下降。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;雇用家庭佣工的税收减免可能会提高香港的出生率：研究&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“由于结婚的延迟，受孕的窗口期”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在回答有关当局如何增加夫妇平均生育子女数量的问题时，该协会执行董事林慧祥博士表示，没有单一的解决方案问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“解决方案将是一种整体方法……仅仅[拥有]财政支持可能无法解决整个问题。我们必须[使用]不同领域的综合方法来帮助年轻夫妇。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林指出，财政支持无法解决的障碍可能包括缺乏休息时间或短缺。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查还显示，想要孩子的女性比例略有上升，从五年前的 15.3% 上升到 2022 年的 22%，而那些不想生孩子的女性比例则略有上升。孩子或其他孩子占55.2%，低于67.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚未下定决心的女性占22.8%，略高于2017年的17.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;叶说，想要成为母亲的女性人数增加是由于最新调查中的受访者年龄较小，以及居民等到晚年结婚。他指出，平均结婚年龄从五年前的 27 岁或 28 岁上升到 30 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“女性结婚越晚，受孕的时间窗口就越短，”他说。 “晚婚增加了女性生孩子的欲望。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于学生人数下降，香港学校削减了 40 多个中一班级&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他指出，这一趋势对香港有利，同时呼吁制定更多政策予以支持，包括加强托儿服务和增加育儿假，以鼓励更多女性，尤其是那些尚未决定是否要组建家庭的女性生育孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港生殖中心的妇科医生陈益诗医学中心表示，过去五年来寻求帮助的女性人数激增了 20%，其中大多数年龄超过 40 岁，远远超过了理想的怀孕年龄。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于 43-三年前，三岁的陈晓光意识到，如果自己或妻子去世，对方就没有人可以依靠，他的情感支持就变得“非常强烈”，想要孩子的愿望变得“非常强烈”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;这对夫妇的第一个孩子是通过体外受精受孕的，18个月前出生，他们预计今年12月生第二个孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果有人问我是否要孩子，我的回答是陈说：“即使孩子意味着经济负担，也是肯定的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style =&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Finless porpoise found dead on Hong Kong beach in 20th stranding case reported this year]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231200/finless-porpoise-found-dead-hong-kong-beach-20th-stranding-case-reported-year?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 22:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/bdbb7234-a745-4018-a0b0-f70759d9548f_919a4ba2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一头江豚在西贡海滩被发现死亡，标志着20日据海洋公园保育基金会称，今年香港发生了涉及海洋哺乳动物的搁浅案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该组织表示，已严重腐烂的成年江豚尸体于周二被带到海洋公园进行查明。死亡原因是在大庙湾附近的海滩上被发现的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这只江豚身长约 1.7 米（5.6 英尺），性别尚未确定。确认的。该物种在当地水域很常见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帮助政府调查所有鲸类搁浅案件的基金会发言人表示，在尸体上没有看到渔网​​，这是对该物种的常见威胁.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该基金会此前表示，在可确定死因的搁浅案例中，人类活动是造成鲸类死亡的主要原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;渔网或渔具缠绕是主要原因之一。该基金会表示，海豚在当地水域搁浅的原因较多，而船只造成的创伤和肺部感染是导致海豚死亡的常见原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港海豚保育协会副主席麦熙文 (Viena Mak Hei-man)协会表示，今年早些时候全面重新开放边境后，澳门和香港之间恢复高速渡轮将加剧江豚面临的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在香港水域发现的鲸鱼尸体引发愤怒反对观光客&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;渡轮在大屿山南部海域航行，该地区是该物种繁殖和繁殖的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她敦促政府考虑采纳该组织的建议，搬迁渡轮&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月末，一头身长超过八米的雄性幼年布氏鲸在西贡谢尔特岛附近被发现死亡，距其首次在附近水域被发现两周后。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;这只哺乳动物的死亡，其伤口疑似由船只造成，引发了有关该市保护政策的激烈讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港埋葬了早些时候在该市发现的活着的死鲸。基金会再次呼吁公众在报告任何鲸目动物、鲨鱼或鳐鱼搁浅事件中发挥积极作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它鼓励居民拨打 1823 联系该基金会，提供重要信息例如发现的日期和时间、精确位置以及任何附带的视觉证据（例如照片或视频），以便立即采取行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还建议划船者避免使用洗发水和沐浴露在船上时，这些产品中未经处理的化学物质可能会直接污染海洋。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Plastic not fantastic as Hong Kong consumer watchdog finds online stores breach mandatory HK$1 charge for throwaway bags]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231202/plastic-not-fantastic-hong-kong-consumer-watchdog-finds-online-stores-breach-mandatory-hk1-charge?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 22:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/440a4ead-8921-4d01-a712-18977058e5a4_df48b1ed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港网上杂货店不收取强制性香港费用，可能违反了环境保护法该市消费者监管机构发现，每个塑料袋收费 1 美元（13 美分），或者向顾客提供过多塑料袋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查发现，近一半的零售商没有坚持使用塑料袋。这些规定引发了消费者委员会向零售商发出的呼吁，要求他们采用更简单的包装和“无袋”选择，以减少浪费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;监管机构补充说，政府还应该为贸易商提供更明确的指导方针，以减少城市对塑料袋的使用。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该委员会研究与测试委员会主席谭凤仪教授强调，实体店的消费者可以选择不使用塑料袋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “消费者有知情权和选择权。我们可以选择在实体店购物时不使用塑料袋。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为什么我们在网上购物时不能有这样的选择呢？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tam speaking after a council report said five of the 11 online grocery stores and e-commerce platforms it had inspected did not levy the plastic bag charge, designed to protect the environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The council explained that stores and platforms used a variety of terms for extra charges, with some using “packaging fee” and “packaging handling fee” to cover paper bags or cartons, which made it tough to check whether the charge of at least HK$1 per plastic bag rule was applied correctly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also suggested that online stores and e-commerce platforms should be advised to make their charging policies and calculation rules for plastic bags and packaging clearer.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong wet markets hand out plastic bags freely despite HK$1 levy, checks show&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“To safeguard consumers&#39; rights to make environmentally friendly choices, the council also recommends the Environmental Protection Department should provide clearer guidelines,” Tam said.&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“These include stating the scope and quantity of additional plastic bags and insulated bags to be used by the traders in the course of transportation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Retailers, including online ones, are required to charge a minimum of HK$1 for each plastic bag, except where food items are unpackaged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;APITA UNY and DCH Foods gave out plastic bags without charging the levies for all food.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HKTVmall, PARKNSHOP and YATA did the same in some trial orders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The online stores were checked by council staff, who posed as consumers and carried out 69 trial orders for different types of food between June and early July.&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;The watchdog also found that 10 of the trial orders provided more plastic bags than the fees charged.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong marks Earth Day by recycling plastic waste, saving food for the poor&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; HKTVmall charged HK$2, but used six plastic bags for nine food items.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three packs of frozen meat were packed in individual flat-top plastic bags, two T-shirt plastic bags were used for canned food, a cup noodle and a bag of crisps and a head of broccoli was packed in its own insulated bag.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HKTVmall told the council that plastic bags and packaging were used to ensure accurate identification of products and delivery as part of its logistics and transport process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The firm added its collaboration with 5,800 partner shops and suppliers resulted in the use of multiple plastic bags.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DCH Foods said the packaging materials were provided by Foodpanda, which handled its deliveries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The council received 39 complaints related to plastic bag use between January and July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post has contacted the Environmental Protection Department for comment.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 22:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China semiconductor output growth slows in July as self-sufficiency drive continues]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3231168/china-semiconductor-output-growth-slows-july-self-sufficiency-drive-continues?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/0983fd53-529e-469c-8d68-9215badd1745_bb3aba65.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s integrated circuit (IC) output rose 4.1 per cent in July, a slowdown from the previous two months, as the semiconductor industry continues to struggle with economic headwinds and escalating tech rivalry between Washington and Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Production of ICs reached 29.2 billion units in July, the fourth consecutive month of positive growth this year, according to data released by the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The growth rate, however, was slower compared with that in May and June, which showed increases of 7 per cent and 5.7 per cent respectively. The data covers companies with an annual turnover above 20 million yuan (US$2.9 million).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite continued monthly growth, IC output in the first seven months of this year was down 3.9 per cent from the same period of last year, totalling 191.2 billion units, the NBS data showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China says chip output picked up in June but remains down in first half of year&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In April, China&#39;s IC output recorded 3.8 per cent year-on-year growth to 28.1 billion units, the first monthly increase in 16 months. This year&#39;s recovery comes as China&#39;s economy continues to recover from strict Covid-19 restrictions and as it weathers the US-China tech storm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The slower IC output trend in July comes as the domestic chip market struggles with weak consumer demand and high inventories. China&#39;s smartphone sales fell 4 per cent year on year in the second quarter, the lowest second-quarter sales data since 2014, according to data from research firm Counterpoint.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, Japan imposed export controls on 23 items including lithography equipment required for manufacturing advanced semiconductors, dealing another major blow to China&#39;s semiconductor industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move was just the latest in a series of export controls imposed by the US and its allies to curb China&#39;s technological progress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last October, the Biden administration tightened export controls to curb China&#39;s access to advanced chips, chip-making equipment and US talent. That was followed by a joint agreement with Japan and the Netherlands in January to coordinate export controls covering certain advanced chip-making equipment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, China has doubled down on its self-sufficiency drive to boost the domestic output of chips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first seven months of this year, China imported a total of 270.2 billion IC units, down 16.8 per cent from the same period last year, according to data published by the General Administration of Customs this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, China churned out 324.2 billion ICs, down 9.8 per cent from 2021. The biggest monthly decline was last October, when IC production volume slumped 26.7 per cent to 22.5 billion units.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UK charges 3 Bulgarians with identity fraud amid ‘suspicion of Russia links’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3231198/uk-charges-3-bulgarians-identity-fraud-amid-suspicion-russia-links?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 22:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/7e22a226-0ba1-4158-93d9-c2a07a22b243_edd525e4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Five people were arrested in the UK on suspicion of breaching the Official Secrets Act, police said on Tuesday, with reports they were detained for allegedly spying for Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;London&#39;s Metropolitan Police said four people – two men aged 31 and 42, and two women aged 29 and 32 – were detained in the British capital on February 8.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fifth – a 45-year-old man – was held at an address on the Norfolk coast in eastern England.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;None of the five was charged under the Official Secrets Act, but three of them – Orlin Roussev, 45, from Great Yarmouth in Norfolk; Biser Dzambazov，42 岁，来自伦敦西北部的哈罗； and Katrin Ivonova, 32, also of Harrow – were charged with identity fraud.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police confirmed to Agence France-Presse the three charged were Bulgarian nationals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“All five individuals were later released on police bail and are due to return in September 2023.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UK turns to AI to disrupt weapon flow to Russia, says spy chief&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The three charged appeared in court in central London on February 13 each charged with “possession of false identity documents with improper intention”, a police statement read.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trio made another court appearance on July 31, and were remanded in custody until a date to be fixed, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The BBC said the initial arrests were made because of suspicion of links to the Russian security services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But there was no immediate confirmation of the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Met is Britain&#39;s biggest police force and has national responsibility for matters involving espionage.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mainland China’s sorties around Taiwan force island to push military fuel budget up 55 per cent to US$344 million]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3231172/mainland-chinas-sorties-around-taiwan-force-island-push-military-fuel-budget-55-cent-us344-million?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/65eb3342-cc5c-45e7-be6d-60f7d1257fe6_272d9517.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Frequent People&#39;s Liberation Army operations around Taiwan have sharply increased the cost of fuel for the island&#39;s military, prompting it to increase its budget by 55 per cent for next year to tackle ever-growing challenges from across the strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The amount spent on fuel by the Taiwanese air force and navy for shadowing, patrols and other missions will go up to roughly NT$11 billion (US$344 million) for the 2024 financial year from NT$7.1 billion this year, according to the island&#39;s defence ministry on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As we expect the enemy will increase its military threats against us, we have initially asked for a [fuel] budget of NT$11 billion to deal with the severe situation,” said Rear Admiral Chen Chun-chung, head of the ministry&#39;s material readiness department, in a news conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2022, fuel spending for the military stood at NT$5.9 billion, a big increase from about NT$4 billion the year before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen&#39;s comment came after local news reports said the defence ministry had used all its NT$7.1 billion fuel budget for this year and owed government-owned petroleum and gas company CPC corporation NT$4 billion after running out of funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen admitted that there was a need to raise spending but denied that the ministry owed the oil company NT$4 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So far we have paid the bill according to the contract and we do not owe [the corporation] any money,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsai Shih-ying, a legislator of the ruling Democratic Progressive Party, said according to his information from the ministry, the military had already spent all its budget this month and was using emergency funding to pay the fuel bill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the Chinese mainland government had not intensified its harassing actions around Taiwan, there would be no need for our military to prepare for such a large budget to deal with the challenge,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsai, who sits on the legislature&#39;s foreign relations and defence committee, said the ministry was expected to send the budget proposal to the cabinet at the end of this month to review and approve.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Asia has 5 of the world&#39;s top 7 most powerful navies. Singapore ranks No 24&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, Taiwanese vice-premier Cheng Wen-tsan said the island&#39;s military had proposed NT$440 billion in overall spending for the 2024 financial year, up NT$30 billion from this financial year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsai said the PLA operations around Taiwan had not only stoked tension in the Taiwan Strait but also created instability in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since last August, the PLA has not only sent warplanes to Taiwan&#39;s southwest air defence identification zone on an almost daily basis but some of its sorties have crossed the median line separating the island and the mainland in the Taiwan Strait and even approached the less militarily fortified region in the east.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its warplane sorties have been reported by the island&#39;s military as being accompanied on many occasions by at least four PLA warships on missions around the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the same news conference, the defence ministry&#39;s spokesman Sun Li-fang said the PLA had intensified military operations around Taiwan since then-US House speaker Nancy Pelosi visited Taipei in August last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, the mainland&#39;s military held unprecedented war games surrounding Taiwan to ramp up pressure on the island, Sun said, adding that it again staged large-scale live-fire drills around the island in April in response to a meeting in California between Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen and Pelosi&#39;s successor Kevin McCarthy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing, which views Taiwan as its territory that must be brought back to its control, by force if necessary, regarded those contacts as a breach of the US one-China policy and a serious violation of its sovereignty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United States, like most other countries, does not recognise Taiwan as an independent state but it is opposed to any unilateral change to the cross-strait status quo by force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So far, we have yet to see any relatively larger scale military drills” from the PLA in response to Taiwanese vice-president and presidential hopeful William Lai Ching-te&#39;s US transit, Sun said, adding that the island&#39;s military would continue to monitor the situation through various intelligence channels and would not let down its guard.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;A &#39;waste of money&#39;? Taiwan to keep ageing Mirage jets in the air&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lai had an overnight stay in New York on Sunday on his way to Paraguay to attend the presidential inauguration. He was expected to stop in San Francisco for a transit stay on Wednesday before returning to the island on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has condemned the US for receiving Lai, whom it has described as a “troublemaker”, and accused Washington of using the island to contain the mainland.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Don’t fall for hard-sell tactics on pain relief packages, Hong Kong Consumer Council warns residents]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3231187/dont-fall-hard-sell-tactics-pain-relief-packages-hong-kong-consumer-council-warns-residents?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 21:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/83a7d2af-7f21-4d51-bea1-c5367dd3fe2a_b605aa0a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A man with early onset dementia was pressured into buying HK$1 million worth of pain relief treatments through hard-sell tactics, according to Hong Kong&#39;s consumer watchdog, which reported a surge of similar complaints this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man&#39;s case was among 101 complaints the Consumer Council received involving high-pressure sales tactics for pain relief treatments over the past three years. The number of incidents has been on the rise, increasing from five complaints in 2020 to 32 in 2022 and 38 in the first seven months this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The wife of the dementia patient told the council her husband was troubled by knee pain from an injury and bought a 60-treatment package from an unnamed centre in June last year for HK$52,800.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On subsequent visits for treatment until January this year, staff repeatedly persuaded her husband, whose dementia has affected his comprehension capacity, to buy more pain relief packages for a total cost of HK$1.07 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When his wife found out about the prepaid packages, she realised it was impossible to use them all up before their expiry dates and filed a complaint with the council. After the council intervened, the couple received a HK$350,000 refund.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The complaints are generally about poor results, unscrutinised sales tactics … and exorbitant prepaid packages,” Professor Nora Tam Fung-yee, the council&#39;s research and testing committee chairwoman, said on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;A stretch too far? No link between yoga pants&#39; price and quality: Hong Kong watchdog&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The council said complainants&#39; exposure on average was HK$60,000 worth of treatment packages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tam warned about treatments that claimed to eradicate pain, saying that some were unsupported by scientific evidence and could cause delays in recovery and harm one&#39;s health in the long run.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Council chief executive Gilly Wong Fung-han said consumers had to be prudent and first identify what was wrong with them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What is your ailment?谁将进行治疗？怎么收费？” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Without naming any companies, the watchdog revealed that one complainant shelled out HK$317,000 in four months for more than 200 treatment sessions after a hard sell by staff during each visit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The patient “experienced extreme duress” from the high-pressure sales tactics and sought help from the council. After the council&#39;s efforts, HK$90,000 was refunded.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Insect parts, parasites, hair found in Hong Kong preserved vegetables&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The council warned that if treatments were carried out by staff who claimed to be registered professionals but were not, it could constitute a criminal offence. It urged consumers to take time to verify who would be conducting the treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;d recommend consulting a doctor if you&#39;re experiencing pain,” Tam said, adding that it was often difficult to cure chronic pain entirely.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If there are treatments that claim to eradicate pain, consumers have to consider very carefully [before committing to them].”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Consumers should also avoid buying in bulk and choose service providers that offer a charge-per-session option to allow for flexibility depending on their needs. They should also check whether a refund policy is available before committing.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>