<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China and North Korea reaffirm close ties amid armistice anniversary]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229366/china-and-north-korea-reaffirm-close-ties-amid-armistice-anniversary?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 20:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/774ef897-ed72-445e-952f-e13287d583f3_6ade45ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;朝鲜领导人金正恩承诺将与中国的关系提升至“新的水平”在平壤与中国代表团举行纪念朝鲜战争结束 70 周年活动期间，双方在“高层”举行了会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周五的会议上，双方重申了对“复杂的国际局势”的立场。朝鲜朝中社援引金正恩的话称，承诺“稳步将两国友谊和友爱合作推向新的高度”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早些时候，由政治局委员和国家人民委员部率领的中国代表团全国人大常委会副委员长李鸿忠转达了中国国家主席习近平给金正恩的信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平在信中表示，中国坚定致力于发展与朝鲜的牢固关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不无论国际风云如何变幻，维护、巩固和发展中朝关系始终是中国共产党和政府坚定的政策方向。”中国官方通讯社新华社援引习近平的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;据朝中社报道，朝鲜政权的知名人士出席了中国代表团的招待会，其中包括金正恩的妹妹金与正。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新华社的报道称，李告诉金正恩，中国希望加强与朝鲜的合作，维持稳定的双边关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还提到近年来习近平和金正恩之间的五次会面，但没有透露具体时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五的会面一天前，金正恩与中国和俄罗斯官员在首都举行的阅兵式上并肩检阅朝鲜最新的核导弹和攻击无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次集会是为了纪念朝鲜1953年签署停战协定，被称为“胜利日”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和前苏联都在联合国的旗帜下支持朝鲜对美国、韩国和其他国家的军队进行战争，并且至少有18万中国军人阵亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯政府代表团由国防部长谢尔盖·绍伊古率领。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜似乎急于利用这一周年纪念日在美国及其盟国在该地区加强军事活动的情况下，突显其与中国和俄罗斯的密切关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 Covid-19 以来，这个与世隔绝的国家实施了严格的边境政策，目前尚不清楚代表团的到来预示着政策的变化。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 20:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Hong Kong airport can’t cope’: manpower crunch means delays for travellers, carriers can’t add flights, airline group warns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3229363/hong-kong-airport-cant-cope-manpower-crunch-means-delays-travellers-carriers-cant-add-flights?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 20:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/26ae26a5-066c-426c-b98d-e421a7b9522d_8547d8fe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;航空公司联盟警告香港国际机场 (HKIA) 的工作人员处理的旅客数量超出其承受能力，这种情况可能意味着旅客延误，并使航空公司无法增加服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港航空公司代表委员会 (BAR)，其中包括 70 多家航空公司表示，人力问题正在影响航空公司恢复航班和增加运力以满足旅客强劲需求的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其北美代表林汉基告诉《华盛顿邮报》，预计旅行需求将减少增加，但机场现在处理的乘客数量超出了工作人员的处理能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“连锁反应是，人们在办理登机手续时可能会遇到更长的等待时间，而我们可能无法开放加拿大航空管理层的 Lam 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机场目前有 53,000 名员工，比 Covid-19 大流行之前的 78,000 名员工减少了约三分之一。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;6 月份旅客吞吐量为 330 万人次，略高于 2019 年水平的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;向香港输入劳动力将确保“更多航班，有助于降低机票价格”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;林表示，员工短缺是全面的，影响了在机场运营的航空公司和服务提供商（例如地勤公司）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》二月份报道称，劳工问题和费用上涨已导致多家航空公司推迟恢复或增加飞往香港的航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;航空公司高管当时警告称，尽管预计会有更多人在夏季出行，但机场的瓶颈阻碍了航空公司增加航班服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“今年夏天对许多航空公司来说都是一个挑战，”林说。 “我们不想通过增加航班来过度扩张，因为我们知道我们可能无法为这些航班提供服务，这就是我们所看到的瓶颈。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;负责管理香港国际机场的香港机场管理局根据立法会文件，上个月告诉政府，其目前的人力可以有效地处理大流行前一半的乘客。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港将在 2027 年超过新冠疫情前的航空客运量，但枢纽地位受到损害：国际航空运输协会表示，到明年年底机场第三跑道系统竣工时，还需要增加 16,000 名员工才能实现拥有 69,000 名员工的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;预计到今年年底，客运量将恢复到大流行前水平的 80%，并在明年年底前完全恢复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 BAR 的数据，五分之四的客运量将恢复到大流行前水平的 80%。截至 5 月，其 72 名成员在香港开展业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它对政府放宽入境要求并引进 20,000 名外籍工人（其中包括航空业的 6,300 名外籍工人）的计划表示欢迎，但表示该计划仅解决大约一半的前线岗位是所需的，本地人也应该有足够的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;输入2万名工人会解决香港的劳工问题吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;林郑月娥表示，他希望外籍劳工该计划可以帮助及时解决圣诞节期间的工人短缺问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拿大航空目前每天都有飞往温哥华的航班。林说，在大多数日子里，它的值机柜台比大流行之前少了两个，这意味着乘客的等待时间更长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，本地航空公司大湾航空的地面服务总经理 Ambrose吴华钊告诉《华盛顿邮报》，人力问题意味着它无法尽快增加航班频率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司使用三架租赁的波音 737-800 喷气式飞机，并计划在 2017 年增加第四架。九月，到年底总共有六架飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng 表示，该航空公司必须等到负责办理登机手续的地勤代理有足够的人力来支持更多的飞机。航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;他们起飞了！香港大湾航空开通首个飞往大阪的航班&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该航空公司上周增加了第六个目的地：越南胡志明市。 6 月，该公司每周运营 60 趟航班飞往日本大阪和东京、台湾台北、韩国首尔和泰国曼谷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本机场的人员问题也阻碍了其增加服务的努力，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司计划于 8 月开通飞往菲律宾马尼拉的航班，随后于明年飞往北京和上海。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 20:50:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Niger loses vital EU aid as Western countries condemn coup]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3229367/niger-loses-vital-eu-aid-western-countries-condemn-coup?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 20:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/11d76393-2b82-461e-825b-420358474b6b_6c2a05fa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧盟已切断对尼日尔的财政支持，美国威胁要在军方领导人本周宣布推翻民选总统穆罕默德·巴祖姆后，也采取了同样的做法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日尔是世界上最贫穷的国家之一，每年获得近 20 亿美元的官方发展援助据世界银行称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它也是法国和美国等西方国家的重要安全伙伴，这些国家将其作为遏制西部和中部伊斯兰叛乱的基地非洲萨赫勒地区。尼日尔曾被视为几个不稳定邻国中最稳定的国家，也是世界第七大铀生产国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日尔的外国盟友迄今为止拒绝承认由前总统阿卜杜拉哈曼·蒂亚尼 (Abdourahamane Tiani) 将军领导的新军政府总统卫队的官员于周五宣布他为国家元首。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在叛变士兵发动政变后，被拘留的尼日尔总统反抗&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自周四早些时候巴祖姆被拘留以来，他一直没有消息。尽管欧盟、法国和其他国家表示仍然承认他是合法总统，但他被限制在总统府内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“除了立即停止预算支持外，安全领域的所有合作行动无限期暂停，立即生效，”欧盟外交政策负责人何塞普·博雷尔在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日尔是欧盟帮助遏制撒哈拉以南非洲非正常移民流动的重要合作伙伴。欧盟还在尼日尔派遣了少量部队执行军事训练任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟从其预算中拨款 5.03 亿欧元（5.54 亿美元），用于在 2021 年改善尼日尔的治理、教育和可持续增长据其网站称，-2024年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国在尼日尔拥有两个军事基地，约有1,100名士兵，并且还向该国提供数亿美元的安全和发展援助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们为尼日尔人民提供的非常重要的援助显然处于危险之中，”美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯表示。他说，美国的支持取决于民主治理的持续。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国表示，政变并未影响其人道主义援助的交付。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚军方有多少支持军政府在尼日尔人口中占有一席之地。周三一些人群出来支持巴祖姆，但第二天政变支持者也走上街头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西非国家经济共同体 (ECOWAS) 将于周日在尼日利亚举行紧急峰会讨论局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五紧急会议后，非洲联盟和平与安全理事会发表声明，要求军队在15天内返回军营并恢复宪法秩序。它没有说之后会发生什么。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange “ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 20:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China hits out at Japan’s ‘erroneous’ defence white paper]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229365/china-hits-out-japans-erroneous-defence-white-paper?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 19:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/1c703cc1-966d-4afb-b08c-101165b18074_73918766.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国指责日本在发布东京年度防务白皮书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国防部发言人谭克非周六猛烈抨击该报告，称其“粗暴”干涉中国内政，煽动地区紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谭克飞对此作出回应报告重点关注北京在台湾周边不断增加的军事行动、与莫斯科加强战略协调以及在争议水域“试图单方面通过武力改变现状”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[中国军队]从未挑战过任何人，更不用说威胁任何人了，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相反，近年来，日本方面……在军事扩张的道路上越走越远，追随某些大国结成有针对性的集团…… ……给地区和全球的和平、安全与稳定带来严重挑战。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还指责“某些国家”在“一己私利”的驱使下，对美国进行了明显的攻击。派舰机到东海、南海“炫耀武力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国海警船赴北太平洋执行渔业巡逻任务&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;白皮书中，日本将中国称为“前所未有的、最大的战略挑战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一基调与最近的日本防卫和国家安全战略文件一致，该文件升级了来自中国的军事风险，并实际上将其非正式防卫上限提高了一倍。白皮书称，“中国当前的对外立场、军事活动和其他活动已成为日本和国际社会严重关切的问题”，并呼吁与盟国和“志同道合”的国家共同应对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该文件重申东京的目标是到 2027 年将其军费开支提高到国内生产总值的 2%，并详细说明了 43.5 万亿日元的支出计划未来五年，日本将增加3100亿日元（3100亿美元），从2019-2023财年的17.2万亿日元激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加强美日同盟是实现日本防卫目标的三大途径之一，根据该文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它强调了朝鲜构成的“迫在眉睫的威胁”，并表示俄罗斯在印太地区的军事活动及其与中国的战略协调构成了“强烈的安全担忧” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“俄罗斯和中国反复进行轰炸机联合飞行和舰艇联合航行显然是为了向日本展示武力，从日本和该地区的安全角度来看，这令人严重关切。”报道称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科周五宣布，俄罗斯和中国海军的战舰已开始在太平洋进行第三次联合海上巡逻。那是在上周末这两个邻国结束在日本海举行的空中和海上演习之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国防部的谭表示，中俄之间的防务合作基于“不结盟、不对抗、不针对第三方”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谭还表示，日本介入台湾问题是“极其错误和危险的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;中国外交部发言人毛宁周五也表示，北京已就该文件向东京提出严正交涉，称台海“军事平衡”的概念“毫无根据”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文件中日本表示，中国大陆和台湾之间的总体军事平衡正在“迅速”向有利于北京的方向倾斜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，中国驻东京大使馆指责日本政府在报告中继续采取“错误态度”，试图通过夸大地区威胁来摆脱军事限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一段时间以来，日本在涉及中国的问题上持续采取消极行动，严重扰乱了双边关系，”大使馆表示。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[We Are Family no more: Hong Kong’s only LGBTQ radio show canned after 17 years, ‘a step backward for community’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3229340/we-are-family-no-more-hong-kongs-only-lgbtq-radio-show-canned-after-17-years-step-backward-community?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/0c712b5a-ea29-4f81-85bb-b9d5e62deecc_7bca676f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港公共广播公司香港电台 (RTHK) 正在终止该市第一家也是唯一一家 LGBTQ 电台节目时隔 17 年，社区中一些人称之为倒退。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于 LGBTQ 权利来说，我们将经历一个漫长的冬天，”长期主持人梁兆辉表示。深夜节目《我们是一家人》每周日从午夜到凌晨 2 点播出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;广播公司没有给出从周日开始长期播出的原因，发言人告诉《华盛顿邮报》，该节目被取消是因为“此举是在香港组织者准备于 11 月 3 日至 11 日在香港举办国际同性恋运动会之际采取的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“特殊视角”：香港LGBTQ 人生导师踏上自己的旅程&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;59 岁的资深电台 DJ Leung 表示，取消该计划将使女同性恋、男同性恋、双性恋、跨性别者和质疑群体的人们更难与圈子之外的人互动，这对于争取平等权利至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当人们在线订阅或收听 LGBTQ 内容时，你就是在向唱诗班布道，”他说。 “但是当你在公共广播电台上表演节目时，你就可以接触到更多的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梁先生的职业生涯在 1987 年赢得香港电台 DJ 比赛后开始。他还曾于 1990 年代和 2000 年代初期在其他电台工作，之后成为 2006 年推出的《我们是一家人》的主持人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当香港电台邀请我主持他们新的 LGBTQ 电台时，没有人比我更惊讶2006 年的节目。这是一个非常保守的平台，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梁说，他一直准备好节目被取消，近年来更是如此，指的是北京自 2006 年以来对香港的加强控制。 2020年实施国家安全法。LGBTQ问题在中国大陆仍然是一个禁忌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《我们是一家人》涵盖了从变性人权利到变装皇后以及社区内部故事的所有内容，并获得了《我们是一家人》大奖2010年香港年度人权新闻奖华语广播组别。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;节目嘉宾包括歌手、作曲家兼演员黄耀明和首位公开同性恋身份的陈志全&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梁振英回忆说，第一档节目引发了十几封反LGBTQ人士向广播管理局的投诉信，但除此之外，该节目很少引起投诉或批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;在描述其多年来的影响时，他说：“当你在香港漫步时，你会看到同性恋情侣手牵着手。这在 17 年前从未发生过。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港电台拒绝透露未来是否会播出任何其他 LGBTQ 节目。该发言人表示不会对“内部编辑事宜”发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梁表示，他和他的共同主持人将休息一下，然后再考虑将该节目恢复到网上。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;是时候采取行动保护香港 LGBTQ 群体的权利&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;人权律师 Peter Reading 于 2012 年至 2022 年在香港平等机会委员会工作，领导 LGBTQ 权利的倡导工作，他表示取消该广播节目传达了关于支持社区的不良信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“《We Are Family》的整体理念是提高人们对多样性、包容性和 LGBTQ 人群相关问题的认识，”他说。 “如果你消除这样做的声音，人们担心事情可能会倒退。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，该节目对于帮助香港 LGBTQ 人群接受自己的性取向也具有重要意义。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;一位要求匿名的 34 岁空乘人员表示：“我从没出柜的同性恋孩子开始听《We Are Family》。这个节目陪伴我走过了我的青少年时代，从一个自我怀疑的孩子成长为一个接受自己的男人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位香港人说，听这个节目让他了解了同性恋文化、公民权利以及有关同性恋的法律。 - 不同国家的性婚姻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双性恋电视主持人、美容博主兼模特麦慧琪，28 岁，说她开始听这个节目时才 14 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个节目帮助我了解了香港的 LGBTQ 问题，这可能很困难，因为我们在学校里没有太多关于这个问题的信息，而且人们也没有非常公开地谈论它，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年 5 月，中文大学的一项调查显示，1,551 名 18 岁及以上香港人中，60% 表示支持同性婚姻，而 17% 表示支持同性婚姻。 % 的人没有。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数人还认为，该市应该制定一项法律来防止基于性取向的歧视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017 年，只有 50.4% 的人对此表示同意。 -性婚姻。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港中文大学调查显示，香港 LGBT 群体在体育运动中争取被接受的努力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该调查由该大学的性行为研究项目、比较与公法中心联合进行香港大学法学院和美国北卡罗来纳大学法学院的人权法项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们在2013年和2017年进行了较早的调查，使其成为历史上最长的调查正在对香港同性婚姻的民意进行研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各大学表示，最新结果显示香港的民意发生了显着变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div >;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US approves US$345 million landmark military aid package for Taiwan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229361/us-approves-us345-million-landmark-military-aid-package-taiwan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/6b3343f7-1d95-4f0f-ad01-cddcaa58994b_aa4e26ad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;白宫宣布向台湾提供具有里程碑意义的 3.45 亿美元军事援助计划，允许直接从美国库存中调出武器并发往台湾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是自华盛顿于 1979 年正式承认台北转而承认北京以来的首个此类计划，并遵循国会在过去几年中的多次要求&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据我作为总统所赋予的权力……我特此授权国务卿……指示削减高达 3.45 亿美元的国防物品和服务……以及军事教育和乔·拜登周五表示，该计划是根据总统撤军授权授权的，该授权已被用来向包括乌克兰在内的美国盟友紧急提供安全援助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据《1961 年美国对外援助法》，该授权允许总统迅速从美国库存中转移物品和服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是该授权首次用于向台湾转移武器和军事援助.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为 2023 年预算的一部分，美国国会通过撤军授权授权向台湾提供最多 10 亿美元的军事援助，北京当时对这一决定进行了攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划不包括向台湾提供的 100 亿美元无息贷款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国务卿表示，这次的撤资包括“国防部的国防物品和服务以及军事教育”并进行训练，前往……台湾”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;台湾军方使用山盾的计划受到质疑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;截至周六下午，北京外交部尚未对这一决定发表评论。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;台北智库台湾国际战略研究会会长王功义表示，此举预计将进一步激怒北京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“大陆已经对美国的军售感到不安王说：“中国驻华盛顿大使馆发言人刘鹏宇周五在一份声明中表示，北京“坚定地反对“美国与台湾的军事关系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国应“停止向台湾出售武器”并“停止制造可能加剧台海紧张局势的新因素”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;台湾抱怨美国频繁拖延向台湾岛提供武器 ​​— — 台湾称这种情况可能会增加中国大陆快速军事扩张和武力威胁对这个自治岛屿造成的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国会一直在推动拜登政府加快交付速度，众议院代表 Young Kim 在 2 月份表示，华盛顿已积压了价值 210 亿美元的已同意出售台湾的国防物资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;新北市淡江大学国际关系与战略研究教授李大中表示，台湾通常需要等待数年才能让美国供应商完成订单并交付。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果交付来得太晚，台湾可能没有在两岸战争中最需要的武器来保卫自己。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，国防部副部长凯瑟琳·希克斯 (Kathleen Hicks) 表示，台湾可能没有最需要的武器来保卫自己。美国从俄罗斯入侵乌克兰中吸取的教训是，需要在台湾面临攻击之前向台湾储备武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本称北京对台湾的军事优势正在迅速增强&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京尽管它一再表示希望和平解决局势，但仍将台湾视为其领土，必须将其置于其控制之下，必要时可使用武力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它加强了对台北的军事威胁，并大幅强化了军事力量时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西 8 月访问台湾后，台湾的军事活动也有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾总统蔡英文在加州会见佩洛西的继任者凯文·麦卡锡后，4 月的军事活动也有所增加。北京认为此举严重侵犯了其主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府智库国家安全研究院高级分析师苏子云表示，由于两国之间的默契双方都没有透露包裹中的物品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这也可以避免公开美国目前库存的武器以及台湾将使用哪些物品来保卫自己，”苏说，增加这样的举动是一种战略模糊，让北京不断猜测。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据路透社报道，该计划可能包括四架非武装 MQ-9A 侦察无人机，这与四架更先进的 MQ-9B 不同台湾计划从美国购买海卫无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该援助计划与美国之前批准的军售无关，美国在 6 月下旬同意出售价值 4.4 亿美元的备件以及后勤物资帮助台湾维持其装甲车、小型武器和作战武器系统的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3月份，华盛顿还批准为台湾的F-16V战斗机机队提供价值6.19亿美元的弹药和相关设备。 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Typhoon Doksuri hammers China, bringing floods and landslides to southeastern province]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3229360/typhoon-doksuri-hammers-china-bringing-floods-and-landslides-southeastern-province?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 18:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/29/a5948fed-cd3b-4aa8-a55f-2904e99b3c6a_8fb8929e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台风“多克苏里”登陆后，在福建省东南部地区造成大面积洪水和山体滑坡据国家气象中心称，随着气旋向北移动并深入内陆，它将给北京及周边省份带来极端降雨，影响1.3亿人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;气象学家称，中国北方周六至周二的降雨强度可能达到或超过2012年北京暴雨造成的79人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“多克苏里”是自1950年有气象记录以来袭击福建的最强台风据《福建日报》报道，这也是今年登陆中国的最强台风。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;台风“多克苏里”登陆福建，华东地区进入戒备状态&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当“多克苏里”袭击福建时晋江市上午 9.55 分，中心附近的最大持续风力约为每秒 50 米（每秒 164 英尺）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它甚至比 2016 年的台风莫兰蒂还要强，当时记录的风力高达登陆时中心附近每秒48米，造成至少11人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福建84个县超过724,600人受到影响，124,400名居民被疏散。据国家通讯社新华社周五报道，约 262 公顷（647 英亩）农作物受损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六早上，多克苏里移动到东南部安徽省，并减弱为热带低气压，这是一种弱热带气旋。气旋。周五晚上，它以邻近的江西省福州市为中心，并减弱为热带风暴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Doksuri 将于 2019 年给福建和江西等中国超过 12 个省份带来强降雨。据国家气象中心称，东南部到北部的河北和辽宁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东亚上空的高压大气环流系统，即西北太平洋副热带高压和太行高压我国北方山区将减缓多克苏里的速度，使其在北方徘徊，累积降雨量增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家气象中心首席预报员方冲表示，华北地区降水特别是京津冀地区包括北京、天津和河北省在内的地区预计将出现极端天气，发生自然灾害的风险很高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，西太平洋上空的热带风暴卡努于周六进入菲律宾责任区上午，强劲的东南风将给中国北方带来充沛的湿气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在线新闻门户网站澎湃新闻援引房方的话说，“我们预计这次降水将会非常强。”&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;国家气象中心周六再次发布暴雨橙色预警，这是中国四级天气预警系统中第二高的预警。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六和周日，预计北京将有大暴雨、天津以及山东、河南、辽宁等省份。据该中心称，部分地区每小时降水量可能超过 80 毫米（三英寸）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2012 年 7 月 21 日，北京遭受强降雨袭击，造成 116 亿元人民币（16 亿美元）的经济损失并影响了超过160万人。据新华社报道，这是该地区 61 年来最大的降雨，造成 66,000 所房屋受损，约 750 公里（466 英里）的道路被毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五至少有五个福建城市打破了 24 小时降雨记录。其中，莆田市白沙县日降雨量达648毫米，打破全省日最大降雨量纪录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;省会福州——别与江西城市混淆——日降雨量达338毫米，远超台风“莫兰蒂”带来的日降雨量170毫米。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;暴雨导致全省严重洪涝、山体滑坡。周六上午，福州报告有 30 个地区被淹。据澎湃新闻报道，该市5个地下通道被淹，最高水位达2米。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国进入洪水警报，大雨迫使撤离&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;多克苏里引发山体滑坡在福建省南安市，居民被困在被洪水淹没的建筑物中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福州当局已要求居民除非必要，否则应留在家中。 Officials in Nanan reminded residents to prepare food, water and other necessities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ports, ferry routes and tourist attractions in Fujian were temporarily closed on Friday. Public transport was suspended on Saturday morning in Fuzhou after the city initiated a Level-I emergency response for rainstorms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, eight officials in Ningde, Fujian were reprimanded, according to local media. It added that those officials failed to be on duty and take initiative when the city prepared for Doksuri to make landfall.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Women’s World Cup football in New Zealand is leading the way for the LGBTQ community in sport]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3229362/how-womens-world-cup-football-new-zealand-leading-way-lgbtq-community-sport?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 18:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/1bfeaf8e-861e-4081-a598-d17bd02b8f3b_91d3423d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;New Zealand striker Hannah Wilkinson has helped create two milestones at the Women&#39;s World Cup.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With her 48th-minute goal in the tournament opener against Norway, she led the co-host Football Ferns to their first win in six trips to the Women&#39;s World Cup. She&#39;s also one of at least 95 out members of the LGBTQ community competing in this year&#39;s tournament, according to a count being kept by Outsports, a website that covers the LGBTQ sports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Ferns were greeted with a fan-made sign at their next match in Wellington: “Gay for soccer, gay for Wilkie,” it read.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 95 out participants make up roughly 13 per cent of the 736 total players at the Women&#39;s World Cup, more than doubling the 40 players and coaches Outsports counted in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 2023 tournament also is hosting the first openly trans and non-binary player in either a men&#39;s or Women&#39;s World Cup, Quinn of Canada.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Women in media set to roar at 2023 Women&#39;s World Cup&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Last World Cup was so big, especially with the visibility of the US women&#39;s national team winning and [Megan Rapinoe] fighting with [Donald] Trump. So I think that was a huge year for LGBTQ visibility,” said Lindsey Freeman, a professor of sociology and anthropology at Simon Fraser University in British Columbia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s just the ad hoc, fun culture of women&#39;s soccer that you&#39;re seeing in this World Cup,” said Freeman, who is in New Zealand conducting research on the topic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jim Buzinski, co-founder of Outsports, agreed. “在西方世界，这根本不是什么问题，根本不会被讨论”，他说。 “And I think that&#39;s in a good way”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the start of the tournament, Fifa designated eight socially conscious armbands team captains could wear throughout the Women&#39;s World Cup. The decision came after “One Love” armbands were denied to men&#39;s teams in Qatar in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The armbands being used this year include anti-discriminatory sayings and multiple colours, but the rainbow version Germany wanted to use is not allowed. None of the available options explicitly mention LGBTQ rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision has led many players to express their support in more creative ways across Australia and New Zealand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New Zealand midfielder Ali Riley was interviewed on the official Women&#39;s World Cup broadcast after her team&#39;s upset of Norway. Her painted fingernails, left hand in the colours of the pride flag and right hand as the trans flag, were clearly visible as she held her head and fought back tears.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“She&#39;s such an advocate and she&#39;s definitely someone who uses her platform in such a positive way.我们都为她以及她代表 LGBTQ 群体的方式感到自豪”，队友 CJ Bott 说道。 “对她很好。 We&#39;re all backing her, and we all back the community as well”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippines, making its Women&#39;s World Cup debut, took home its own historic win over New Zealand 1-0 thanks to the foot of Sarina Bolden. Bolden&#39;s Instagram bio reads, “i just wanna have fun nb gay.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Irish star Katie McCabe wowed fans with a goal directly from a corner kick. She&#39;s also made tabloid news for her relationships with other players.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thembi Kgatlana, who has scored in the tournament for South Africa, has a patch of her hair dyed rainbow colours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My personality is very big for me, and my hair has become a part of my personality”, Kgatlana said. “And I did this rainbow because I want to represent all the people that are part of the LGBTQ and cannot talk while in countries where they&#39;re oppressed”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Late Wang penalty keeps China&#39;s World Cup hopes alive in dramatic win over Haiti&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Kristen Pariseau and her wife started a US women&#39;s national team supporters group on Facebook ahead of travelling to this year&#39;s Women&#39;s World Cup. Aside from some hateful users she blocked, it&#39;s been “super LGBT friendly.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She and her wife did not go to Qatar for the 2022 men&#39;s World Cup to avoid referencing each other as friends and receiving questions on their sexuality. In New Zealand, she said she&#39;s met many same-sex couples at games and while travelling around the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Everywhere you turn, it&#39;s like, &#39;Oh, my wife, my girlfriend.&#39;它是如此热情和开放”，帕里索说。 “In a way, it is kind of cool to be where there&#39;s a lot of other people like you”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kelsie Bozart took her own pride flag armband to the United States&#39; second match in Wellington, along with a pride scarf.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you look back a couple years, I feel like it just wasn&#39;t really talked about or there just wasn&#39;t much of a presence,” Bozart said. “But moving forward I feel like, especially for the US, they&#39;ve done an amazing job of just incorporating pride and LGBTQ.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though this year&#39;s tournament has highlighted vast gains for the LGBTQ community in women&#39;s soccer, advocates feel there is still work to be done.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Buzinski and Outsports, there were at least 186 LGBTQ athletes at the Tokyo Olympics.女性与男性的比例为 9:1。 There also were no confirmed out players at the 2022 men&#39;s World Cup.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think women&#39;s sports have always been open,” Denmark striker Pernille Harder said, adding that there are many role models for women who want to come out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Freeman said it would be good to see men feel the same level of comfort.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What can happen in the women&#39;s game, I would love to spill over to the men&#39;s game”, she said. “Because obviously, there&#39;s way more queer players in the men&#39;s game and it&#39;s just not safe for them to come out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you want to say that you&#39;re in an inclusive space, you really have to be an inclusive space”, Freeman added. “And I think that that includes also holding the World Cup in places where it&#39;s fine to be a queer person”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese woman makes grandparents ‘take an oath’ not to complain about spending too much money on holiday, delighting social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3229025/chinese-woman-makes-grandparents-take-oath-not-complain-about-spending-too-much-money-holiday?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/d1d9087f-89f0-46ef-8d4e-abcd09d8f3e1_78c58855.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A video of a woman making her grandparents pledge not to complain about ticket and food prices when travelling with her has delighted mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the video taken at her home in Beijing and shared online on July 18, the woman, identified as A Yi, raised her fist and took an oath in front of a camera with her grandparents standing behind her, who then did the same, reported the China Women&#39;s Newspaper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gesture of standing and raising one&#39;s fist is what a Communist Party candidate does when they make a pledge to join the party at a ceremony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I pledge never to say, &#39;The ticket is too expensive.你去玩吧，我在外面等。”阿易说道。 Her grandparents then repeated the same words.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other pledges the group made included: “I will never say &#39;restaurant food is too expensive.还是在家吃饭比较好”、“我不会强迫别人凌晨四五点起床”、“我会很享受花钱的感觉。” That&#39;s it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The grandparents repeated their pledges loudly and clearly although the grandmother could not help giggling occasionally during the “oath taking”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman said she asked her grandparents to make the pledges because she had taken them travelling several times, but the couple, who live frugally, cast a pall on the trips by frequently complaining about the expense.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The newspaper reported that on the latest trip, after taking the oath, the grandparents kept their promise and ordered food they liked without complaint.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video has resonated deeply with many on social media, with many saying their parents and grandparents are also thrifty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;ve learned from this. Next time before I take my parents to travel, I will make them do the same,” one user said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This granddaughter is so sensible, and her grandparents are very cute,” another person commented.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A third online observer recalled her own experience: “Last time when I took my parents travelling and they saw the price list at a restaurant, my father said he had overeaten at breakfast, and my mother said she had a stomach ache.他们俩都没有和我一起进餐厅。 I was speechless.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This disappointing behaviour not only derives from the different concepts in consumption between young people and the older generation but also because old people cherish the money earned by the younger generation,” China Women&#39;s Newspaper said in an editorial on July 25.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stories of heartwarming relationships between grandparents and grandchildren often captivate mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, a woman in her 30s in China was filmed tying braids for her grandmother in a viral video.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, a grandmother in northern Hebei province gave her three-year-old grandson an Afro perm for the Lunar New Year, amusing internet users as they said the boy, with the new hairstyle, looked like the “bestie of his grandma”.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong doctor urges residents to become organ donors as number of kidney transplants performed this year drops to 19]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3229359/hong-kong-doctor-urges-residents-become-organ-donors-number-kidney-transplants-performed-year-drops?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 18:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/7443f254-ffee-4da6-a00d-c93c7869548f_9cf706c5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong doctors performed only 19 kidney transplants this year, according to the vice-president of the Hong Kong Academy of Medicine, who appealed for more donors to sign up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dr Philip Li Kam-tao, on Saturday, said only 19 kidney transplants had been carried out in the first half of this year, compared with about 50 per year over the past few years during the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The number has hit a new low over the past few years. The number of kidney transplants dropped because of the coronavirus restrictions,” he told a radio programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The situation about organ donation is unsatisfactory.移植的等待时间很长，大约五到六年。有些病人在等待过程中去世了。 I, therefore, call on people to extend their care to those in need by signing up as organ donors.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s organ donation rate is among the lowest in the world, at 4.99 donors per million people, down from 5.8 in 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are more than 3,000 on the waiting list for transplants, with 80 per cent being kidney patients.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong authorities have recently appealed to more than 173,000 civil servants to sign up as organ donors after a surge in withdrawals from the register, which the city leader John Lee Ka-chiu said was a bid to “sabotage” the system.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How a kidney transplant helped a Hong Kong man run his first 10km race&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Health authorities noticed an “unusual rise” in the number of people applying to be taken off the register from last December to April after the government revealed its intent to establish a donation mechanism with mainland China as a “second-tier” response which would only be used if no suitable patients could be matched with the organs locally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials said of the 5,785 withdrawal applications received during the period, more than 2,900 were found to be invalid because they were filed by people who were not on the register.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Li said the number of donors signing up with the Centralised Organ Donation Register had reached 350,000, with over 5,000 new donors in June and July, respectively.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong leader likens fake organ donor withdrawals to &#39;discord&#39; sowed in 2019&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“This has shown that an increasing number of people are unaffected by the &#39;sabotage&#39; incident and are willing to be organ donors. A deceased donor can benefit six or seven families through organ donations and help patients needing transplants to lead a normal life again,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The rate of successful organ transplants is really high in Hong Kong, reaching 96 per cent. I encourage people intending to donate their organs to indicate their wishes to their families.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s elderly suicides reach record-high, prompting calls for more healthcare staff and measures to keep younger people in city for support]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3229358/hong-kongs-elderly-suicides-reach-record-high-prompting-calls-more-healthcare-staff-and-measures?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 17:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/84600862-9bc6-41ab-8daa-d0232b1ab11a_e3676429.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s Coroner&#39;s Court handled a record number of elderly suicide cases last year, according to a concern group, which called for more healthcare staff and measures to keep younger people in the city to support the vulnerable demographic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Samaritan Befrienders Hong Kong on Saturday said there were 1,080 suicide deaths last year, a 15-year high. About 44 per cent, or 477, involved people aged 60 or above, the highest since the record began in 1973.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among these cases, 282 involved people aged 70 or above, the highest among all age groups, while 195 were recorded for people between 60 to 69 years old.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsang Chin-kwok, executive director of the suicide prevention group which analysed statistics from the Coroner&#39;s Court annually, said suicides among the elderly had risen as the demographic had grown, adding such residents were also receiving less family support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Their children generally move away after getting married.此外，现在人们的孩子数量往往较少，因此下一代人的支持不多，”他说。 “Loneliness particularly strikes when their other half passes away and they get little support from their children.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that elderly residents aged 70 or above were more prone to suicide as their health and social lives deteriorated the most.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to urging those with suicidal thoughts to seek help, Tsang said it was important to introduce measures to encourage younger people to stay in the city to support the vulnerable group given the city&#39;s ageing population.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s &#39;hidden elderly&#39;: could string of tragedies have been prevented?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The wave of emigration in Hong Kong in recent years has also resulted in families leaving their elderly relatives behind, which adds to their loneliness,” Tsang said. “The government has to consider ways to keep middle-aged and the younger people in Hong Kong.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to official population projections, residents aged 65 and above in Hong Kong will gradually increase from 20.8 per cent in mid-2022 to 25.3 per cent in 2028, before rising to 35.1 per cent in 2069.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsang also urged authorities to raise the number of healthcare workers responsible for providing support to residents who were at risk of suicide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Six per cent of the 1,080 suicides last year involved people with mental disorders. The charity has called on the government to step up public education to avoid stereotyping those with mental health issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Angela*, who was previously diagnosed with depression and bipolar affective disorder, urged residents with mental health issues to reach out for help.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There&#39;s a very high chance of making the wrong decision if we do not ask for help,” said the 28-year-old, who stayed in a public hospital for a month due to her illness two year ago. “Feeling helpless can worsen the situation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities on Thursday proposed expanding a conditional discharge scheme to include psychiatric patients voluntarily admitted to hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Perpetual fear: why discharged psychiatric patients in Hong Kong walk on eggshells&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Angela said a professional assessment used to check whether patients could be discharged was necessary, but staying at the hospital for a long period of time would not help them recover.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If they remain in hospital for a very long period of time without a normal social life, they will be anxious and nervous. The ultimate aim is to bring them back to society and so that they can live a normal life,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the proposed changes, patients admitted voluntarily but found to have violent tendencies or those who displayed aggressive behaviour in hospital could be subject to conditions when discharged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts have warned that changes may deter people from seeking help, while others have suggested expanding the scheme to people with suicidal thoughts.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Expanding Hong Kong&#39;s conditional discharge scheme &#39;could deter those seeking help&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But executive director Tsang said including this group of patients in the changes was not necessary as they could only leave the hospital after joint-assessment from doctors and social workers under existing rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that those with severe suicidal thoughts should not be discharged as they could hurt themselves after leaving the hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking on a radio programme on the same day, Undersecretary for Health Dr Libby Lee Ha-yun said the government did not intend to include such patients who did not demonstrate violent behaviour under the proposed measures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is community support for them … We know that it is difficult for them to seek medical help. It may further deter them from seeking help,” Lee said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;*Name changed based on interviewee&#39;s request*&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you have suicidal thoughts, or you know someone who is, help is available.对于香港，请拨打 +852 2896 0000 联系撒玛利亚人，或拨打 +852 2382 0000 联系预防自杀服务。 In the US, call the 988 Suicide &amp; Crisis Lifeline at 988 or +1 800 273 8255. For a list of other nations&#39; helplines, .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>