<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Fringe Club pledges to fight to keep its home in landmark Old Dairy Farm Depot as lease put out to tender by government]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/article/3231844/hong-kong-fringe-club-pledges-fight-keep-its-home-landmark-old-dairy-farm-depot-lease-put-out-tender?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/66c1b9df-d756-4dd0-81a3-bb58f5bb5021_2ee2cd21.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港首屈一指的艺术俱乐部之一发誓要尽力保住自己的家在当局征求接管这座历史建筑的管理建议后，在中环独特的红白相间的旧牛奶场仓库中进行了改造。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;艺穗会最近遭遇了法律和财务问题周一，承诺将引入更多来自中国和海外的行为，作为其保留租约的一部分，其中将包括一项确保运营商遵守国家安全法的条款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“边缘俱乐部董事会和管理层致力于尽一切努力使我们的提案在即将到来的公开招标过程中尽可能具有竞争力，”一位发言人表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为我们提案的一部分，我们设想复兴这个著名的全市范围边缘艺术节，这是俱乐部历史的一个标志。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该艺术节将成为展示本地和国际表演的平台。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他是在文化节结束后发表讲话的体育及旅游局邀请非牟利机构明年起提交下亚厘毕道大楼的营运及发展建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会所新租约，建于1892年，为寒冷的气候而建。存储并随后延期，自 2024 年 4 月 1 日起为期三年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2022 年以来，该场地的租约一次仅授予一年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A局项目简介概述了如何提交提案，并强调如果投标人参与或“合理地认为参与”威胁国家安全的活动，他们将被取消资格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;艺穗会开始组织音乐会和艺术活动1984 年，砖石和灰泥结构的受保护建筑中展示了这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港艺穗会的困境随着创始人、前行政长官的薪资竞标而加深&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;俱​​乐部目前租用部分政府的前仓库，并为当代艺术展览和表演提供免费的画廊空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;租约早些时候一次为期五年，但艺穗会只获得了每年的租约。过去两年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自2022年以来，俱乐部陷入了一系列内部和外部问题，包括清算威胁和领导层变更。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创始人Benny Chia Chun- 2022 年 9 月，郑先生和前管理人员刘锦玲就据称未支付的工资向该俱乐部的非营利母公司香港艺穗节有限公司提出法律索赔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;令状表示截至 2020 年 4 月，Chia 已经 14 年没有领到工资，Lau 有 8 年没有领到工资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两人辞去职务后不到一个月，距离第一个一年的前六个月，这场纠纷就公开了。租约到期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着运营商即将退出，香港艺穗会的未来充满不确定性&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;俱​​乐部董事会代理主席陈耀祥 (Anson Chan Yao-cheung) 向《华盛顿邮报》表示到时候，如果法律行动继续下去，俱乐部将别无选择，只能进入清算。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈补充说，俱乐部自 2008 年金融危机以来一直处于赤字状态，并表示这一决定只是为了每年的租约增加了其未来的不确定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俱​​乐部董事会于 2022 年向当时的民政事务局提交了一份提案，详细说明了计划如何在下一份租约下运营俱乐部，该租约是于 2023 年 4 月获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该局发言人表示，该场馆的未来占用者将通过“提案邀请”来选择，并表示将确定最合适的非营利组织来运营&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发言人补充，包括艺穗会在内的非牟利组织可提交提案，并承诺获选的组织将继续支持香港文化艺术的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;该局发言人补充说，申请截止日期为10月20日，新住户预计将于年底或2024年初公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS： &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In Japan, ‘desperate’ shrinking towns eye radioactive nuclear waste storage to make a fast buck: ‘it’s all about money’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/health-environment/article/3231825/japan-desperate-shrinking-towns-eye-radioactive-nuclear-waste-storage-make-fast-buck-its-all-about?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/263f4f87-c274-4c76-a4c4-89eb18d765b7_2ea4f9c6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本南部的两个社区已同意对放射性核设施所在地进行初步评估尽管遭到环保组织和当地人的反对，日本原子能工厂的废物和乏燃料仍在使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上关是山口县的一个小镇，约有 2,340 名居民，周五表示，他们将允许中国电力公司. 就在该公司提出提案 16 天后，对乏核燃料回收前储存的临时场地进行调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地官员未经投票就做出了决定，镇议会成员也同意据《读卖新闻》报道，不允许提出任何问题。闭门会议期间，约100人聚集在市政厅外反对该计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市长西哲夫在会后表示：“我们决定接受该公司的提议。调查和[垃圾场]建设是不同的问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nishi 说，该镇实际上被迫接受公用事业公司的请求，因为它需要资金。上关此前曾被指定为一座拥有两个反应堆的新核电站所在地，但该计划在 2011 年福岛第一核电站发生灾难后被叫停。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据协议，中国电力将对计划核电站所在地进行钻孔调查，以确定其地质是否稳定。在调查阶段，该镇每年将获得 1.4 亿日元（964,400 美元）。一旦研究完成并且该地点被认为可行，该公司将提出一项建造临时核废料储存场的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“海洋不仅仅是日本人的”：韩国人撕扯国旗福岛抗议&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;如果山口县知事批准该计划，上关将在两年内赚取 20 亿日元（1380 万美元），并在第一批废物交付后每年支付费用。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;该镇传统上依靠渔业作为收入来源，但随着年轻人的离开和人口的减少，维持当地产业生存的人越来越少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些靠捕鱼为生的渔民他们仍然担心涉及核储存设施的灾难会严重损害他们的声誉和生计，就像福岛县发生的那样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于日本南部九州岛之间的对马岛也存在类似的争论和朝鲜半岛。市议会成立的一个特别委员会于上周三建议该市开始建设地下场地之前所需的研究和程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果该提议被接受，该市也将符合资格获得最多 20 亿日元的补贴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管小组提出了建议，但议会和对马岛的 28,000 名居民在这个问题上仍存在严重分歧。鉴于该岛的地理位置以及韩国对日本核能记录的反感，距离对马岛北端约 50 公里的港口城市釜山的居民很可能也会反对该提案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对马岛它不仅拥有庞大的渔业，也是日本和韩国游客的主要目的地。人们担心，围绕核储存设施的负面宣传或某种事故可能会摧毁这两个行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于这些城镇来说，一切都与金钱有关，”京都府环境活动家艾琳·米奥科·史密斯 (Aileen Mioko Smith) 说道。总部位于日本绿色行动。 “几十年来，这些社区的人口和工作岗位一直在向大城市流失，因此市长们迫切需要资金。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上关居民强烈反对中国电力在他们的城镇建造核电站的计划Mioko Smith 说，当该计划在 40 多年前首次提出时，人们定期举行示威活动反对该计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，公用事业公司都很富有，并且越来越迫切地寻找废物储存地点Mioko Smith 表示，上关项目表面上是由中国电力公司实施的，尽管它并不迫切需要废物储存设施。然而，关西电力公司由于现有设施已达到容量极限，迫切需要一个存储地点。去年，它向福井政府承诺，将在 2022 年底前解决该县设施内的乏核燃料库存问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关西电力错过了这一最后期限，直到今年年底为未来的临时储存场地提供保证。两家公用事业公司正在上关核电站进行合作，显然希望大量补贴能够帮助消除当地居民的疑虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么中国、韩国仍然反对福岛污水处理计划？&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么中国、韩国仍然反对福岛污水处理计划？ h3>;&lt;p>;即使市长同意对该地点进行初步研究，居民也不太可能做出决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当地人站起来反对反应堆，然后期望施工开始福岛事故发生的任何一天，所以一切都被搁置了，尽管该公司仍然拥有这片土地，”Mioko Smith 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对我来说，真正不合理的是关西电力想要出口关西地区产生的乏核燃料，用于为那里的公司和家庭提供电力，并提供给该国其他地区不需要的社区。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China Ferrari driver only asks for US$26 from elderly tricycle rider who scratched his US$620,000 sports car causing US$14,000 damage]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3231536/china-ferrari-driver-only-asks-us26-elderly-tricycle-rider-who-scratched-his-us620000-sports-car?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/5b2b0f65-df9f-4788-a462-04d74ee12e00_3d8c6bc5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名年轻男子在一名老人的身上只索要少量赔偿三轮车刮坏了他价值450万元人民币（62万美元）的法拉利跑车，造成价值10万元人民币（14,000美元）的损失，这一结果在大陆社交媒体上得到了赞扬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意大利豪华跑车的司机姓甘。据《九拍新闻》报道，来自上海的这名男子的宽容态度以及没有让老年三轮车司机难堪的态度赢得了掌声，尽管后者最初试图逃离现场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一段事件视频中，这名男子的黄色法拉利在斑马线上停在了一辆红色三轮车旁边，发生了轻微的碰撞，这引起了网络热议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与老人简短交谈后，甘拿起智能手机拨打电话&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;甘说，事故发生在8月15日晚上8点左右，事故发生在外滩，法拉利的车身和后视镜被划伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“他要开车走，我拦住了他。”甘告诉九拍新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，豪车司机并没有对老人失去理智，当警察赶到时，电动三轮车司机被告知他应该承担全部责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;甘说，他不想让该男子为难，并补充说他得到了充分的道歉，只要求 190 元（26 美元）的赔偿。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示，这辆法拉利是一家经营豪华车租赁业务的公司的，他正在试驾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;甘补充说，修复划痕需要10万元。这笔费用他自己掏腰包。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事在大陆社交媒体上疯传，一位网上观察者说：“颜先生非常善良、体贴。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;另一人也表示同意：“很明显，甘并不是真的想向老人索要任何赔偿，他只是希望他能从错误中吸取教训。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有趣的事故故事经常被疯传。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二月份，中国西北部的一名妇女在事故中不断与一名被困在受损汽车中的司机交谈，让他保持清醒，直到救援到来，这触动了许多人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;去年年底，中国南方的一位父亲表示，他想让他三岁的儿子因刮擦邻居的汽车而道歉并支付 2000 元（270 美元），从而教会他承担责任的价值，从而受到赞扬。&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s birth rate is low because raising a child in extreme competition is exhausting]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231753/hong-kongs-birth-rate-low-because-raising-child-extreme-competition-exhausting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/9a8e7cbb-2cfc-448b-957c-cbcceaa1e50d_29224ad4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着香港的生育率创下历史新低，每名妇女生育 0.9 个孩子，立法者和学者们提出了不同的建议来应对挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;典型的解决方案包括不同形式的福利，例如减税、直接补贴和现金支付。但除非这些激励措施足够大，能够显着降低与生孩子相关的成本和压力，否则她们不会生育更多的孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平均每个女性需要生 2.1 个孩子才能维持生育能力。人口稳定。但生一个孩子就已经够挑战了，更何况生两个孩子。作为一名家长，我和许多香港家庭一样，在城市里养育孩子，承受着精神和经济压力，感到沮丧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阻碍育龄夫妇生育的一个关键因素（更多）孩子是这样做的代价。一些家庭很幸运，有家庭佣工和祖父母协助照顾孩子，从而使父母可以全职工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，其他费用 - 课外学费、兴趣班、短途旅行等等 -高昂。为什么它们是必要的？因为，要在社会中保持竞争力，孩子不仅必须在考试中取得好成绩，还必须具备各种被香港妈妈讽刺地称为“超自然技能”的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每天都在上学、各种培训和其他活动，我们的许多学生比成年人忙碌的时间更长。父母下班后赶回家指导孩子做作业已成为常态。假期更糟糕——这意味着更多的作业，以及为下学期开始时的评估做准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在与一些最近移居海外的香港家长交谈时，我发现他们之间分享了一个笑话：当他们的孩子很顽皮，他们被警告可能会被“送回香港学校”作为惩罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们喜欢比较城市和教育体系，但这种比较可能并不总是有帮助。提供教育的方式与地方和人民的社会和文化特征密切相关，有时复制或移植特定的首选模式是不现实的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，英国学校保留体育课程并要求学生在考试期间参加这些活动。学期休息是真正的假期，很少或没有作业，让学生可以探索其他事物并给自己充电。这种做法在香港是不可想象的，因为应试文化根深蒂固。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使新技术可以改善教学体验，但落后的焦虑却给成年人带来了巨大的压力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于许多家长来说，确保孩子赢在起跑线上已经不够了，更重要的是保持竞争力直到终点线。一种策略是在某个时候将孩子送到国外接受教育。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于某些工作和公司，雇主倾向于寻找具有国际视野的人。再说一次，竞争永无止境。当这些毕业生返回香港时，他们可能会发现自己与那些在新的顶尖人才计划下被吸引到香港的人竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不断加剧的竞争增加了生育成本和家庭压力。去年，香港一家银行对中产家庭进行的一项调查显示，在香港抚养一个孩子，直到他或她完成大学教育，至少需要600万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这不是一个问题。考虑到海外教育的费用，这有点夸张。鉴于香港私人物业价格高昂，部分家长也希望预留部分或全部首付给子女购买首套房。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那该怎么办呢？具有讽刺意味的是，我们今天遇到的挑战正是由促成我们成功故事的品质促成的。我们强烈的职业道德、勤奋和竞争本性导致了工作时间长、工作与生活不平衡以及教育成本上升。这些现在正威胁着这座城市的未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，香港并不孤单；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他亚洲经济体也在应对类似的危机。经济快速发展带来繁荣；几十年后才会感受到累积的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府政策和技术创新，例如进口劳动力和更广泛地采用自动化，可能会解决一些直接的瓶颈。但社会对资源和人才的竞争不断升级，将继续阻碍年轻夫妇生育更多孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden sees devastation wrought by Maui wildfire during visit to Hawaii’s Lahaina]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231854/joe-biden-sees-devastation-wrought-maui-wildfire-during-visit-hawaiis-lahaina?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 07:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/b02273e1-bdab-474c-9ae8-5a45754b46ad_d7000fba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登和第一夫人吉尔·拜登周一观看了飓风造成的破坏火焰席卷了夏威夷岛的西部地区，亲眼目睹了美国一个多世纪以来最致命的野火留下的空心房屋、建筑物和烧焦的树木。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登一家在停机坪上短暂停留抵达卡胡卢伊机场安慰夏威夷州州长乔什·格林和他的妻子杰米·格林，以及前来机场迎接的夏威夷国会代表团成员。总统和第一夫人在登上海军陆战队一号进行空中游览火灾造成的破坏之前拥抱了每位迎接者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登后来在历史悠久的城镇拉海纳近距离观察了残骸13,000 人几乎被大火烧毁。他的车队蜿蜒穿过一个又一个被掏空的房屋和建筑物的社区，棕榈树被烧成无尽的碎片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇正在与急救人员会面，并听取州和地方官员的简报&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民主党总统将发表讲话，向山火受害者致敬。自 8 月 8 日爆发以来，山火已造成 100 多人死亡。拜登父子中断了在山火中为期一周的假期。太浩湖地区，乘坐五个小时的航班飞往拉海纳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这对每个人来说都将是激动人心的一天，”白宫副新闻秘书奥利维亚·道尔顿 (Olivia Dalton) 对与拜登同行的记者表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫周一宣布，拜登已任命联邦紧急事务管理局地区领导人鲍勃·芬顿（Bob Fenton）为毛伊岛山火的首席联邦响应协调员，以确保其政府中的专人负责长期的恢复努力。重建拉海纳需要数年时间，那里几乎所有建筑物都被夷为平地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我知道损失会对一个家庭和社区产生多么深远的影响，我知道没有什么可以取代生命的损失，”拜登说在旅行前的一份声明中。 “我将尽我所能帮助毛伊岛从这场悲剧中恢复和重建。在我们的努力中，我们始终致力于尊重圣地、文化和传统。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“令人作呕”：毛伊岛当地人猛烈抨击在野火过后度假的游客&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;数十人聚集在拉海纳的街道上，观看拜登的车队蜿蜒穿过街道。一些人热情地向总统致意，但另一些人似乎对车队挥舞着中指。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登因在当选后的头几天里说得太少而面临共和党人的批评，其中包括2024年共和党领跑者唐纳德·特朗普。灾难。然而，白宫反驳了这些批评，称总统在整个危机期间与州长和其他紧急官员保持着密切联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;夏威夷参议员布赖恩·沙茨 (Brian Schatz) 表示，截至周日，约有 85 名%的受影响地区已被搜查，仍有近2 000人断电，10 000人没有电信连接。毛伊岛西部部分地区的水无法安全饮用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然水、食物和毯子等紧急援助已随时分发给居民，但沙茨表示，人们需要帮助提供手机、身份证件和其他文件格林周日在哥伦比亚广播公司的“面对国家”节目中表示，“一支由 41 名搜救队组成的军队”狗覆盖了受影响的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毛伊县市长理查德·比森 (Richard Bissen) 在周日的社交媒体帖子中表示，已确认 27 名遇难者身份，并已向 11 个家庭通报了损失情况。联邦调查局、毛伊县法医和验尸官办公室正在共同努力辨认找到的遗体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比森表示，失踪人员名单上有 850 人，初步名单包含更多人，这让我们看到了希望超过 2,000 个名字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们继续进行恢复过程的过程中，我们对这些数字感到既悲伤又松了一口气，”比森说。 “确认的人数将会增加，失踪的人数可能会减少。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;夏威夷顶级厨师通过为火灾幸存者做饭来帮助他们康复&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;仍有 1,000 多名联邦官员留下来据白宫称，他们正在实地应对夏威夷的野火。联邦应急管理局局长迪安·克里斯韦尔 (Deanne Criswell) 表示，政府已向约 8,000 个受影响家庭发放了超过 850 万美元的援助，其中包括 360 万美元的租金援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将于周一加入拜登的沙茨强调，官员们我们“仍在应对灾难”并且“我们尚未处于恢复阶段”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管情况看起来很糟糕，但实际上更糟，”他在周日的电话采访中表示。 “你看不到的是公用事业基础设施受到的损害。你看不到的是成千上万的孩子正在努力弄清楚今年秋天如何上学。你看不到的是第一批响应者不顾自身安危冲进火海，自己的家园也被烧毁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在太浩湖度假时，拜登经常打电话。白宫表示，官员们将了解野火应对措施的最新情况。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Entrepreneurs are the hope of China’s economic future, so stop making ‘capital’ a dirty word]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231782/entrepreneurs-are-hope-chinas-economic-future-so-stop-making-capital-dirty-word?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/677563d3-5837-4420-892a-df5e0c7b5730_4051e378.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;有时令人费解的是，许多从中国的经济自由化仍然对“资本”这个词抱有强烈的感情，根据上下文，它可以与“贪婪”、“剥削”或“邪恶”等术语互换使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然该国官方承认资本作为与土地、技术和数据并列的社会主义经济生产要素之一，私人资本有时仍被视为收入差距和道德腐败等社会问题的根源，而拥有资本的人却受到怀疑。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;没有人提出真正的理论来平衡那些认为中国私人资本必须受到限制、控制并最终摧毁的声音。反资本阵营认为，中国有必要在国内剪掉资本的翅膀，在国外打击资本主义势力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;资本批评者一致认为，资本在创造就业方面可能具有功利价值。并促进经济增长，但从根本上来说这是一种必要之恶，需要采取任何手段来遏制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去四十年支持中国经济繁荣并获得一定程度的意识形态中立之后一路走来，资本再次被按照卡尔·马克思的正统定义，他将其描述为“从头到脚，从每一个毛孔里滴着血和污垢”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这样的概念争论可能看似抽象，但对政策制定具有重大影响。在中国，企业是否为私营企业有时仍是决定能否赢得合同或获得银行贷款的决定性因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京多次向私营企业家保证，他们的企业将受到与私营企业主的平等对待。国有企业只会强化人们对这两者实际上不同的认识。有一个笑话是这么说的：你只要反复告诉你的教子，他是你的儿子，不需要对你的亲生儿子这么说。中国政府当然从未觉得有必要向国有企业保证它们将获得公平的政策待遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题可能会给中国经济带来真正的问题，因为私营部门才是增长的实际引擎。随着地缘政治和人口逆风的加剧，释放中国人民的创业精神变得更加重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，北京一些直言不讳的经济学家已经公开呼吁中国放弃对企业的所有权标签。国务院发展研究中心原副主任刘世锦上个月在一次讲话中表示，国家应该停止按所有制划分企业的做法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国过去 40 年的经济奇迹，在本质上，是一个破除意识形态障碍、解放增长潜力的历史过程。例如，直到1992年，“市场经济”在中国一直是一个不好的词，也是资本主义的象征，当时最高领导人邓小平告诉国家必须遵循市场，结束了不必要的争议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国寻求加入世贸组织遭到了保守派的强烈意识形态抵制，他们抨击通过世贸组织框架设定关税的协议是“放弃中国主权”，因为设定进口关税的自由被认为是中国独立自主的关键标志。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当中国前总理朱镕基在20世纪90年代末关闭效率低下的国有工厂、砸碎数千万工人的“铁饭碗”时，有人咒骂他背叛了工人阶级，它构成了国家社会主义制度的基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，中国一次又一次地继续前进，将这些争议抛在脑后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，中国的债务驱动的增长模式，依靠国有部门低效和浪费的支出已经陷入困境，国家是时候将重点转向振兴私营部门了。显然，私营企业家是国家经济的未来，吸取了所有教训，中国是时候停止将资本视为肮脏的词了。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 07:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As Indonesia pushes EV dream, car shoppers stay cautious: ‘it’s not affordable’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3231831/indonesia-pushes-ev-dream-car-shoppers-stay-cautious-its-not-affordable?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/1fbac6b0-e062-49e4-9ecc-bfef17d08498_47115f21.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚政府利用雅加达车展加大力度推动生产和销售计划东南亚最大的汽车市场上电动汽车的销量很高，但买家尚未卖出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;电动汽车 (EV) 的溢价、充电站可用性的问题以及对新品牌的怀疑是持有的理由雅加达郊区唐格朗车展的参观者表示，现在又回来了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;车展参观者多迪·哈托诺 (Dody Hartono) 计划在 2024 年购买他的第一辆电动汽车，他表示他想要一辆更好的电动汽车&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 54 岁的人士表示：“我们必须首先让人们对电动汽车感兴趣，首先价格应该便宜 60%。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;比亚迪签署协议探索电动汽车机遇，在印度尼西亚建厂&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚制定了雄心勃勃的电动汽车增长计划，它正在与泰国和印度竞争，建设电动汽车行业，以替代全球最大的生产国中国。然而，目前电动汽车占道路上汽车的比例不到 1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府已将电动汽车的增值税从 11% 削减至 1%，从而使电动汽车的起价降低最便宜的现代 Ioniq 5 在印度尼西亚的售价为 51,000 美元以上，低于 45,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hartono 表示，10,000 美元至 13,000 美元之间的价格会更有吸引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市面上只有两辆电动汽车五菱的 Air EV Lite 和 Seres Group 的 E1 的报价接近这个范​​围，约为 12,300 美元。印度尼西亚最便宜的汽油动力汽车大发 Ayla 起价低于 9,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的 Seres 集团是科技公司华为的电动汽车制造合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，中国最畅销的电动汽车比亚迪海鸥的起价略高于 10,000 美元，但其他公司（甚至中国自己的汽车制造商）很难在出口市场上匹配这种定价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比亚迪的 ATTO 3，即第一季度东南亚最畅销的电动汽车，在泰国的起价略高于 31,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;42 岁的 Hendra Pratama 是一位在车展上购买电动汽车的顾客，他表示印度尼西亚的溢价需要减少以吸引中低收入消费者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是负担不起的，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丰田及其子公司大发和本田占美国汽车销量的三分之二。印度尼西亚，但转向电动汽车的速度缓慢。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;桑迪亚加·乌诺 (Sandiaga Uno) 表示，印度尼西亚并未将中国排除在电动汽车中心计划之外&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;44 岁的亨德拉·布迪 (Hendra Budi) 表示，价格对他来说不是问题，但他希望对所提供的品牌更有信心。 “如果丰田或本田推出全电动汽车，我们将会感兴趣。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丰田表示尚未计划在印度尼西亚生产电动汽车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚的工业工信部在周日结束的车展上宣布，将向汽车制造商提供两年以上的生产激励资格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此消息公布后，中国的耐塔电动汽车品牌和日本​​三菱汽车也做出了投资承诺。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚设定了到 2030 年生产约 60 万辆电动汽车的目标。这将是印度尼西亚 2023 年上半年销量的 100 倍以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚首席经济部长表示他希望雅加达车展能够带动超过 26,000 辆汽车的销量，这是去年上一届车展上的销量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最终售出的汽车数量以及电动汽车所占的份额并未公布。从周一开始可用。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 07:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why China is targeting the corruption tumour at the heart of its ailing health system]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3231815/why-china-targeting-corruption-tumour-heart-its-ailing-health-system?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/36d3f493-460c-4875-956e-a4b4d30e9295_097dfe7a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当同事告诉他，外科医生 James Wu 表示，他“感到震惊但很高兴”中国南方省份广东省的一家医院院长已向腐败调查人员自首。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴的老板于 7 月下旬自首，成为全国被反腐败调查人员拘留的 160 多名医院院长之一since the start of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities had given senior medical staff until August to declare their illicit activities as part of a national campaign targeting a long-standing source of public grievance: soaring health costs fuelled by corruption. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this vicious cycle, hospital chiefs take kickbacks to order expensive medical equipment and pass on the cost to patients by encouraging staff to order unnecessary tests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Wu, the pressure was intense .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have been instructed to prescribe many tests for the patients so that the hospital could recoup the investment faster,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Excessive testing is just one form of corruption in the health system that is inflating medical bills and fuelling public resentment – a discontent that has at times erupted into violence against doctors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The threat is so great that now most hospitals in China require security checks to enter.&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;It also presents a risk to social stability, with affordable and equitable healthcare one of the pillars of President Xi Jinping&#39;s vision of China&#39;s development path.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Observers say the crackdown is unlikely to end any time soon and could usher in further changes to the health system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like many countries, China has been struggling to find a right formula for its national health system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hospitals are the front line in this battle and responsible for delivering the lion&#39;s share of medical care to the country&#39;s population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the 1990s, as health started to account for a bigger share of the national budget, the government started cutting back on funding while also insisting that hospitals limit prices and the mark-up on services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That forced hospitals to make up the difference with equipment or service fees – an area ripe for graft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; With inadequate government funding, public hospitals were motivated to profit from charging patients for unnecessary prescriptions and services with inflated pricing, according to a report issued by China&#39;s legislature in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The problem is exacerbated by the lack of general practitioners or family doctors operating practices outside the hospital system, pushing patients with simple ailments such as fever and headaches to hospitals, rather than community clinics where the cost of care is far lower.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a result, hospitals are overcrowded and expensive. Even though more than 95 per cent of the population has access to some form of government-backed health insurance, many still battle to afford any kind of quality healthcare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The resulting tension in the system has fostered distrust between patients and medical workers, giving rise to a phenomenon known as yinao, or hospital violence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In one case in February, a disgruntled patient shot a doctor in the head in a clinic in Shenyang, in the northeastern province of Liaoning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And the burden on the ailing system is only increasing – especially in rural areas – as Chinese society ages and people develop more serious or chronic diseases such as cancer and diabetes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On average, healthcare accounted for 8.6 per cent of personal spending last year, up from 6.5 per cent in 2016, according to the National Bureau of Statistics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, the proportion of people aged 65 and over climbed from 10.8 per cent to 14.9 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scores of retirees took to the streets in the central city of Wuhan in February to protest against cuts to their medical services.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s anti-graft drive erases US$9 billion in value from healthcare stocks&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing started to turn its attention to the problem in late 2013.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That December, the then National Health and Family Planning Commission issued three lists of activities that were off limits for health institutions and professionals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These lists regulated the procurement of medicine, medical devices and medical supplies – big-budget areas that were fertile for graft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But there were other opportunities for eye-watering corruption in the medical system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2015, Wang Tianchao, the former president of Yunnan First People&#39;s Hospital in Kunming, was ordered to spend 10 years in jail for accepting 35 million yuan in cash, 100 properties and a number of car parking spaces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate said Wang took the bribes from 2005 in return for awarding hospital construction projects, buying medical equipment and giving doctors promotions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the decade since those lists were issued, authorities have passed laws and amendments to try to stamp out corruption and rein in medical costs. These include bringing public hospital managers and businesses under “national supervision” and banning companies that engage in corruption from the industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the government is still struggling to deliver affordable health services to its population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi has made healthcare one of the livelihood issues at the centre of his “common prosperity” campaign to shore up the ruling Communist Party&#39;s legitimacy as not only the pro-development force, but also a societal protector to keep social instability in check.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his work report to the party&#39;s decision-making Central Committee at the party congress in October last year, Xi listed medical care as one of many difficulties faced by the Chinese people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the same message he delivered to the congress five years earlier when he named healthcare – along with education and housing – as the priorities for the new administration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To that end, authorities have renewed attention on corrupt activities, giving people involved in medical industry graft until the end of July to turn themselves in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After that, thousands of investigators from national anti-corruption agencies and healthcare authorities stormed the country&#39;s hospitals, public health insurance administrations and medical suppliers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bribery is the major form of medical corruption in China&#39;s health system, according to a paper published in February by a group of Chinese and American researchers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the paper published in Health Policy and Planning journal, the researchers said bribery accounted for 68.1 per cent of the cases of medical industry corruption listed on the China Judgments Online website between 2013 and 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 80 per cent of those taking bribes were healthcare providers, and most of those giving the kickbacks were suppliers of pharmaceuticals, medical equipment and consumables.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Public hospitals in China vulnerable to corruption, finds watchdog&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing chose a massive anti-corruption campaign as the “breakthrough point” of its healthcare reform because graft is central to pushing up prices and inflating claims on the national insurance system, according to Xie Maosong, a senior fellow of the Taihe Institute and a senior researcher at the National Strategy Institute at Tsinghua University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xie said the crackdown was a long-term fight that served a number of elements of Xi&#39;s economic and social agenda&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It aims to bring down the cost of healthcare by squeezing out bribes, which inflates the medical bills,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If successful, it can help ease the Chinese people&#39;s worries about rising healthcare costs and give them more confidence to spend on other things.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is also a prelude to the push for a further revamp of the national healthcare system, which will cut away the middlemen between hospitals and medical suppliers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Beijing is very serious about these objectives and it wants to achieve them in the coming five years.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The national crackdown on medical graft follows similar campaigns in the military, security and administrative systems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deng Yuwen, a former deputy editor of the Central Party School&#39;s official newspaper Study Times, said Xi&#39;s massive and tough anti-corruption apparatus had always moved in tandem with his policy objectives, because it has been “most potent tool” to spur the entire bureaucracy to achieve his political goals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deng said the initial focus of Xi&#39;s anti-corruption campaign was to “get the key pillars of the house in order” before moving on to livelihood issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You can see that Xi is very committed to fixing the problems in education, medical care and housing, because he wants to be remembered as the one who dares to deal with the most thorny problems,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Beijing believes that fixing these issues is the prerequisite for its domestic consumption, which will drive its domestic circulation as its external trade is facing pressure from the US and its allies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ultimately he wants to prove that China&#39;s model is superior to the US, especially on healthcare.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump’s bond set at US$200,000 in Georgia case over bid to overturn 2020 loss]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231852/donald-trumps-bond-set-us200000-georgia-case-over-bid-overturn-2020-loss?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 06:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/1f3e4d6a-e975-4ed5-b428-9a7e77ef4183_a1c217a8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Donald Trump&#39;s bond has been set at US$200,000 in the Georgia case accusing the former US president of illegally scheming to overturn his 2020 election loss, according to court papers filed on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump is also barred from intimidating co-defendants, witnesses or victims in the case – including on social media – according to the bond agreement signed by Fulton County District Attorney Fani Willis, Trump&#39;s defence lawyers and the judge. It explicitly includes “posts on social media or reposts of posts made by another individual on social media”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The order says the former president cannot make any “direct or indirect threat of any nature” against witnesses or co-defendants. He is also prohibited from communicating in any way about the facts of the case with any co-defendant or witness, except through lawyers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The order sets Trump&#39;s bond for the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organisations – or Rico – charge at US$80,000, and adds US$10,000 for each of the 12 other counts he is facing. Bond is the amount defendants must pay as a form of collateral to ensure they show up in court ahead of trial.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Willis has set a deadline of noon Friday for Trump and his 18 co-defendants to turn themselves in at the Fulton County Jail to be booked. The prosecutor has proposed that arraignments for the defendants follow during the week of September 5.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She has said she wants to try the defendants collectively, and bring the case to trial in March of next year, which would put it in the heat of the presidential nominating season.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Trump spokesman did not immediately respond to a request for comment. A phone message seeking comment was also left for a lawyer for the former president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump was charged last week in the case alongside a slew of allies, who prosecutors say conspired to subvert the will of voters in a desperate bid to keep the Republican in the White House after he lost to Democrat Joe Biden.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Witch hunt!&#39; says Trump, on indictment of trying to overturn election result&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Trump has denied any wrongdoing, and he characterises the case – and three others he is facing – as efforts to hurt his 2024 presidential campaign.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump has been railing against the Fulton County DA since before he was indicted, and he singled out Georgia Governor Brian Kemp, a Republican who rebuffed his efforts to overturn the election, by name in a social media post Monday morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bond was also set Monday for three lawyers who were indicted along with Trump.对于他们每个人来说，Rico 指控的保证金定为 20,000 美元，他们面临的其他指控的金额也有所不同。 John Eastman and Kenneth Chesebro each had a bond set at US$100,000, while Ray Smith&#39;s bond is US$50,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bail bondsman Scott Hall, who was accused of taking part in a breach of election equipment in rural Coffee County, had his bond set at US$10,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other defendants include former White House chief of staff Mark Meadows; Trump lawyer and former New York mayor Rudy Giuliani, and a Trump administration Justice Department official, Jeffrey Clark, who aided the then president&#39;s efforts to undo his election loss in Georgia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Georgia indictment comes just two weeks after the Justice Department special counsel charged Trump in a separate case in a vast conspiracy to overturn the election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Besides the two election-related cases, Trump faces a federal indictment accusing him of illegally hoarding classified documents as well as a New York state case charging him with falsifying business records.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s economic slump gives US a chance to gain clout with countries indebted to Beijing: analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3231853/chinas-economic-slump-gives-us-chance-gain-clout-countries-indebted-beijing-analysts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 06:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/937cc114-3d10-4835-86e6-7babcdbb848d_67d000f6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s “still widely underappreciated” economic downturn reduces the likelihood that it will overtake the US in the next 20 years and gives Washington an opportunity to gain influence over countries that have become indebted to Beijing, an influential US government advisory panel was told on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The severity of China&#39;s ongoing economic weakness is still widely underappreciated, and the United States no longer faces a growth challenge from China,” Logan Wright of risk consultancy Rhodium Group said in a US-China Economic and Security Review Commission (USCC) hearing in Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Beijing is no longer an economic pacing threat or likely to overtake the United States in any significant measure of economic power in the next two decades,” Logan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nicholas Borst of Seafarer Capital Partners, an investment advisory group, testified that the country was now “in danger of losing economic momentum” due to the government&#39;s crackdown on the private sector and lack of planning for the post-coronavirus pandemic era, among other policy missteps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese government is likely to be intensely focused on efforts to address its own internal economic challenges over the next several years,” Borst said. “The [Chinese Communist] Party&#39;s efforts to exert greater control over the private sector have damaged some of the most dynamic and innovative parts of the Chinese economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To the extent that China continues to slow in a way that many of us are predicting, it will have a direct economic impact on many of our allies in the region, who have huge economic ties to China,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Monday&#39;s testimony before the USCC followed a stream of dismal economic data for China that had many analysts trying to grapple with the extent of the problem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Exports in July, for example, fell for a third consecutive month, recording a year-on-year 14.5 per cent contraction to total US$282 billion – the steepest annual decline since February 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s most recent official figures showed its retail sales, industrial output and investment all posting weaker-than-expected growth in July. Foreign direct investment in China plummeted by 87 per cent in the second quarter of this year, according to figures from the State Administration of Foreign Exchange on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Signs of Chinese President Xi Jinping delegating more to hand-picked deputies&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Those numbers, witnesses said, suggested that China would no longer be able to finance as many infrastructure projects in Southeast Asia, Latin America and the Middle East and Africa, sometimes called the Global South.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s external lending on this front, primarily through its Belt and Road Initiative, has helped integrate economies in these regions more closely with China&#39;s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has also pushed US President Joe Biden to launch initiatives such as the Indo-Pacific Economic Forum and the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wright estimated that since 2020 about US$78 billion worth of these loans were either in default or under renegotiation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The way in which China participates in that [negotiating] process is going to be where the rubber hits the road for their external diplomacy because it reveals the constraints of their own domestic political system … and their own financial stress,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If Beijing is not going to provide meaningful debt relief … and countries are struggling with significant financial stress, then they are going to need some sort of additional marginal source of new financing,” Wright said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He urged Congress to work with private-sector lenders “to provide some sort of alternative for that which has the added benefit of … removing Beijing from the centre of that aspect of economic diplomacy”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen told lawmakers in June that the Biden administration wanted to boost involvement in the Inter-American Development Bank group&#39;s private-sector investment fund and the African Development Fund.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These investments will bolster our engagement in these regions at a time of geopolitical competition,” Yellen said during a House Financial Services Committee hearing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, the White House asked Congress for more than US$40 billion in “emergency funding” to support its foreign-policy goals, including US$2.3 billion towards International Monetary Fund investments seeking to counterbalance China&#39;s “coercive and unsustainable” lending programmes.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Biden plan to curb China investments focuses EU minds as deadline looms&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While the witnesses said China&#39;s economic challenges were deeply rooted in its policy choices of the past decade and would thus be difficult to overcome in the short term, they all rejected a suggestion from one of the USCC&#39;s commissioners, Randall Schriver, that the US government try somehow to exacerbate China&#39;s economic distress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even if you don&#39;t agree with it, and even if it&#39;s marginal, what are things we could do to kick [China] while they&#39;re down, if you will, put pressure on them?” asked Schriver, a former assistant secretary of defence for Indo-Pacific security affairs under Donald Trump.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wright countered that such an approach would make it “far more difficult” for Biden to maintain alignment with the European Union on China policy, which the US leader had worked hard to forge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s very difficult for me to come up with anything externally that would do more than what has already taken place in China over the last five to 10 years,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US-Japan-South Korea summit represents &#39;new era&#39; of cooperation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“If you were going to think about how to undermine the vitality of a robust private sector in China, you would do roughly what Beijing has done in trying to single out some [firms] … as political targets in the last couple of years.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another witness, Zongyan Zoe Liu of the Council on Foreign Relations, agreed with Wright, emphasising that moves aimed at damaging China&#39;s economy further risked undoing much of the policy coordination that Biden had managed with Japan and South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Borst, meanwhile, said “extreme measures” intended to decouple from China would ramp up pressure on China economically and that “over the long run, it will actually be damaging to US interests”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I continue to believe that an angry and isolated China is a greater danger to US interests than one that is interconnected,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How China can step up to its responsibilities in a rising Global South]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231612/how-china-can-step-its-responsibilities-rising-global-south?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.22 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/21/bff170c8-9f93-4366-af99-0733f6357caf_c6f6e3bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The prominence of this week&#39;s Brics summit, particularly as it discusses the expansion of a bloc that comprises Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa to admit more members, reflects the rise of the Global South.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February, the Munich Security Conference added a panel discussion on how the Global North can better cooperate with the Global South. At the G7 summit in May, host Japan pushed to strengthen the Group of Seven&#39;s ties with the Global South and especially invited the leaders of several developing countries to the Hiroshima meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Global South is becoming more visible – and influential – in every arena,” said Foreign Policy magazine at the start of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the Voice of Global South Summit, a virtual meeting hosted by India earlier this year, was attended by more than 100 countries, there is no universally accepted definition of which countries exactly comprise the Global South. There are, for instance, Global South countries in the geographic North, and vice versa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet this flexibility reflects the nature of the Global South, a community where states recognise in one another their similar situations.在经济上，社区正在发展并寻求改善。 Politically, it is a multilateral alliance with diversified values and interests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the escalation of the Ukraine crisis and global political divisions, most countries have chosen to neither take sides nor join the strategic suppression of Russia. Clearly, Global South countries prefer to keep an independent foreign policy and a non-aligned position.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, major powers in the Global North have introduced initiatives to strengthen their connection with the Global South, often in hope of obtaining greater geopolitical benefits. These include the US-led Build Back Better World and the EU&#39;s Global Gateway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compared to the United States, however, the European Union appears to have a more nuanced interest in the Global South.欧盟在维护前殖民地成员国利益的同时，也希望通过“去风险”来增强能源和粮食安全。 In essence, the EU sees a third path in a new global order, dominated by neither the US nor China, and needs to build common interests with the Global South.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, India and Russia play important roles in Global South countries. India positions itself as a North-South power – deeply intertwined with Global North in strategic goals and values while remaining an integral part of the Global South, seeking to become a bridge in leading the community to build a new diplomatic equilibrium.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s diplomatic focus, meanwhile, has been on former Soviet states, the Asia-Pacific, Middle East and Africa.它们对俄罗斯能源、食品、化肥和其他大宗商品的依赖使得脱钩变得困难。 Through engagement, Russia has strengthened its position and cooperation with the Global South.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the rise of the Global South comes opportunities to deepen South-South cooperation.但任何仓促举动都可能带来风险，加剧南北紧张局势，加剧全球对抗。 China, seen as a pivotal country in the Global South as far back as in 2004, should take on its due responsibilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, it should encourage and support Global South think tanks and institutions and jointly conduct research with other Global South countries to examine issues such as exchange mechanisms. Western countries have already established several Global South think tanks and research centres.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Second, a new world order aligned with the demands of the Global South should be proposed and promoted.南方国家的崛起或许是不可阻挡的趋势，但过程不会一帆风顺。 The looseness, fragility and diversity of the community means it is less able to sidestep risks and more prone to infighting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To guard against exclusion, China should embrace developing countries, keep close ties with its partners and work to enhance the cohesion of the Global South.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Third, China must work to improve relations with India and the influence of Brics. As a bloc, Brics&#39; economy has surpassed that of the G7 in purchasing parity terms, gaining in economic importance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sino-Indian relations have been stagnant for years but with India having chaired the recent Shanghai Cooperation Organisation summit and set to preside over the G20 summit in December, there is hope that relations will get better.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both China and India are in a position to work with other major developing countries and lead cooperation in the Global South to promote Brics. Expansion will only enhance the impact of the “Brics Plus” format in addressing the concerns of the Global South.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fourth, China should hold more Global South forums to enhance official and non-governmental exchanges. Existing platforms include the Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation, Forum on China-Africa Cooperation and China-CELAC Forum with the Latin American and Caribbean states.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can Brics, the emerging world&#39;s torch-bearer, challenge the established order?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China should invite high-level officials and experts from industry and academia to hold more diverse Global South forums. Regularly held, these can facilitate standards for South-South cooperation and establish inclusive and equitable rules for cooperation in areas such as the digital economy, climate change and sustainable development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finally, China should work on stronger, better coordinated North-South cooperation.对于许多人来说，中国是崛起中的南方国家的缩影。 China&#39;s economic and technological cooperation with many countries in the Global South is also greater than that of developed countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Given China&#39;s experience in cooperating with developed countries, its role as a go-between might be more appealing to the Global North. In this sense, China should consider enhancing North-South exchanges and cooperation, while avoiding an escalation of tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a country with both developing and developed elements, China could marry the interests of both communities to promote a more sustainable global development and better global governance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 22 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>