<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Amid China’s AI investment fever, a debate on whether start-ups can make money from ChatGPT-style services]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226107/amid-chinas-ai-investment-fever-debate-whether-start-ups-can-make-money-chatgpt-style-services?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/a98f3577-84de-49be-9dd9-ee27a95498fc_5056f310.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国的初创企业是否还有空间从 ChatGPT 式服务中获利？ OpenAI 聊天机器人的推出引发了人工智能 (AI) 投资热潮后，这个问题引发了中国企业家和投资者的激烈争论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ChatGPT 和谷歌的 Bard 不太可能在中国上市，因为中国的由于严格的内容监管，本土科技公司一直在竞相推出类似服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至 5 月份，中国至少有 79 个大型人工智能模型，参数超过 10 亿个（衡量模型复杂程度的指标）根据政府研究机构中国科学技术信息研究所最近发​​布的一份报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但对于初创企业是否有机会从新的人工智能技术中获利尚无定论。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;投资早期初创企业的金沙江创投管理合伙人朱啸虎在北京的一次会议上表示，ChatGPT 可能是人工智能初创企业的诅咒，因为据中国媒体报道，该服务非常强大，可以比他们现有的许多功能更好地发挥作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对此，中国著名企业家、互联网公司猎豹移动首席执行官傅盛表示Zhu 评论称，他对 ChatGPT 可以释放的商业潜力“无畏地无知”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu 和 Zhu 没有立即回应对本文发表评论的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后台 -两位行业资深人士之间的交流引起了中国科技界的关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杜克大学电气与计算机工程教授陈怡然在微博上表示，大语言模型（LLM）这一技术对于初创企业来说，构建 ChatGPT 等生成式人工智能产品的成本可能太高，但初创企业有很多机会开发基于法学硕士的应用程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;侯振宇，副总裁百度表示，初创企业不适合从头开始开发法学硕士，因为这非常昂贵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国杂志《财经》援引侯的话说：“资金、图形处理单元和数据都是挑战。” 。 “仅百度就购买了数万块GPU，这是一笔巨大的投资。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;已经有迹象表明，中国的生成式人工智能产业正在整合。中国食品配送巨头美团周四宣布收购光年，这是一家成立仅四个月的人工智能初创公司，由美团联合创始人王慧文创立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这笔交易涉及支付 2800 万美元&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;微软支持的 OpenAI 开发的尖端对话机器人 ChatGPT 去年秋天突然出现，引发了全球人工智能军备竞赛。中国公司，从科技巨头到由风险投资家支持并由科技界知名人士领导的初创企业，一直在与全球同行一起追赶这家总部位于旧金山的初创企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括社交媒体和视频游戏巨头腾讯控股等大型科技公司和电子商务巨头阿里巴巴集团控股公司（《南华早报》的所有者），以及语音识别服务提供商科大讯飞等人工智能专家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他紧跟潮流的公司包括清华大学自然语言处理项目附属的几家初创公司中的两家——Modelbest和DeepLang AI，以及搜索引擎运营商搜狗创始人兼前首席执行官王小川创立的初创公司百川。目标是在今年年底推出中国顶尖的法学硕士课程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国类似 Quora 的网站知乎首席技术官兼北京 Modelbest 首席执行官李大海在最近接受《华尔街日报》采访时表示帖子说，建立一个成功的 LLM 是资源密集型的，并且涉及很多不确定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当 [OpenAI 的] GPT-3 发布时，每个人都认为它很棒......但是并没有太多应用场景服务，”他说。 “尽管如此，OpenAI 仍然致力于花费更多资金来开发其他 GPT 模型。这是一种非常不同的投资心态。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京英诺天使基金投资人王盛表示，中国的人工智能投资机会有不同层次，从涉及芯片的底层基础设施到大型人工智能模型人工智能与其他领域交叉并带来变革的应用。但他补充说，现在进入法学硕士已经太晚了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果你去年或前年投资了[法学硕士]，那很好……但现在机会已经消失了，”他说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他专家似乎也同意这一观点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京大学人工智能研究院副院长、北京人工智能研究院研究负责人黄铁军告诉腾讯新闻，世界可能只需要三个大型人工智能模型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京金融咨询公司42资本创始人曲凯在接受《华盛顿邮报》采访时表示，未来70%的投资将流向人工智能应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1 year of Hong Kong’s John Lee: what have been some of his more controversial moves?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3226168/1-year-hong-kongs-john-lee-what-have-been-some-his-more-controversial-moves?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/a38da329-0afa-4396-93d1-26c94962e2f4_9d819052.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;去年5月行政长官选举中获得超过99%的选票今年，李家超 12 个月前上任，誓言要重振香港的国际地位，并重启因 Covid-19 大流行而长期关闭的陷入困境的经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自“轻型公共住房”为了区议会改革，《华盛顿邮报》回顾了李明博政府过去一年采取的一些引人注目的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;1.对香港国家安全法的首次解释&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;李去年11月在香港最高法院阻止伦敦大律师蒂莫西·欧文代表媒体大亨黎智英失败后，寻求北京对国家安全法的解释- 因涉嫌与外国势力勾结而受审。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北京对香港国家安全法的裁决“可能是一次性的”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;而不是禁止海外律师出现在涉及国家利​​益的审判中，中国最高立法机构裁定此事可以交由市领导和一个委员会来决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但一些法律学者对这一解释表示担忧，称其已向行政部门提供了帮助&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府后来还修改了《法律执业者条例》，现在允许地方当局禁止外国律师参与该市的国家安全案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;律政司司长林定国表示，这并非全面禁令，如果行政长官确定国家安全利益不会受到损害，海外律师仍然可以在香港处理敏感案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黎智英案已定于今年9月审理。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北京对海外律师涉港国安案件的裁决意味着什么&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;2.区议会改革&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;为了使区议会“去政治化”并将其焦点重新转向邻里问题，李在五月份宣布对市级组织进行改组，其中包括减少民主选举产生的议员人数&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据计划，18个区议会的470个议席中，只有约五分之一将由普选产生。当局将任命 179 名成员，而政府任命的三个社区委员会将决定另外 176 名成员，并为乡村领导人保留 27 个席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港区议会改革引发对直选未来的反思&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;候选人还需要三个社区委员会成员的提名，并接受政府筛选程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李说，这些变化是为了阻止反华闹事者和分裂分子操纵区议会的改革与 2019 年一样。但批评人士表示，新的架构将切断市民与议会之间的联系，而议会的大部分席位此前都是直选产生的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港区议会将如何改革改变邻里政治生活？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府表示希望立法会能在7月初通过《区议会（修订）条例草案》，为年底的下次选举铺路。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;3。输入劳工解决短缺问题&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港劳动力人口由2018年的368万人减少至2022年的346万人。政府于6月宣布将输入约2万名建造业和运输业工人，并提升禁止雇主从海外引进人员从事 26 项低技能工作的禁令，例如熨烫工、初级厨师和电话接线员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举之后，工会指责当局剥夺了劳工咨询委员会的职权。比如说审查输入工人的申请。在政府安排的 6 月 19 日简报会上，该委员会的六名工党成员举行了罢工以示抗议，称当局在宣布该计划之前没有征求他们的意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官员们表示，他们无意绕过董事会并承诺将定期就这些计划的实施情况与董事会进行协商。他们还否认这些计划会进口廉价劳动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;4。轻型公营房屋&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;为应对公屋的庞大需求，李先生去年10月宣布，将在五年内兴建3万个短期轻型公营房屋单位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划，最初的标价为 274 亿港元（35 亿美元），引发了人们对成本效益的担忧。当局其后决定不在单位内安装空调，以节省约10亿港元。政府亦分两期向立法机关寻求拨款，而非原计划的一次性拨款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在启德市区黄金商业区兴建部分住宅的决定也引发争议，居民威胁要上街抗议。政府没有退缩，但承诺临时住房的建造不会超过五年目标，并将继续该地区计划的商业开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划旨在帮助那些等待着的有需要的家庭。传统公屋三年或以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港立法会批准第一期轻型房屋计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;5。顶尖人才通行证计划于去年12月推出，旨在吸引高收入人士和海外著名大学的毕业生。截至 5 月底，已收到超过 32,000 份申请，约 21,000 份获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月份，有新闻报道称曾因非法非法入狱的颇具争议的中国大陆生物物理学家何建奎而引发争议。医疗实践，已获得签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港批准了 3 个扩大人才计划的 361 名申请人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府后来撤销了何的签证，并修改了规则，要求申请人申报任何犯罪行为信念。该要求后来扩展到其他几个人才招聘计划，并于 6 月进一步扩大到涵盖申请工作和学生签证的人，包括家庭佣工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李在 6 月表示，香港正在顺利实现其政府为吸引人才而推出的各种准入计划每年吸引的目标人数为 35,000 名工人，而该计划吸引了近两倍的人数。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;6.法院禁制《愿荣光归香港》&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;出人意料的是，政府于6月5日向法院申请禁制令，禁止被称为香港国歌的抗议歌曲《愿荣光归香港》。 2019年反政府示威。该禁令针对的是那些使用这首歌主张香港与中国分离的人，以及任何使用这首歌暗示香港独立或侮辱国歌的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“荣耀”香港抗议歌曲被禁？政府向法院提交禁令&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府寻求禁止所有形式的歌曲，引发了对言论和表达自由的担忧。当局辩称，该申请符合维护国家安全的合法目的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法院预计将于7月21日审理此案。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[France riots: State of emergency mulled by government over protest violence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226170/france-riots-state-emergency-mulled-government-over-protest-violence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/edf1dee8-fefc-495e-a043-d0ccf7893db9_7952a9cb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;法国总理伊丽莎白·博恩周五表示，政府正在考虑“所有选择”在因一名警察杀害一名青年而发生的骚乱已连续第三晚发生后，恢复秩序，包括宣布进入紧急状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被记者问及是否有可能进入紧急状态，一些右翼人士表示针对反对党的要求，博恩回答道：“我现在不会告诉你，但我们正在考虑所有选择，其中一个优先事项是：恢复全国秩序。”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正在访问的总理巴黎南部 Evry-Courcouronnes 的一个警察局将于下午 1 点参加由总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙 (Emmanuel Macron) 主持的危机安全会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;紧急状态将赋予当局更大的权力来宣布局部宵禁、禁止示威、并给予警察更多的自由来约束涉嫌暴乱者和搜查房屋。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法国骚乱：青少年被杀如何将愤怒集中在警察策略上&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;马克龙缩短了前往布鲁塞尔参加欧盟峰会的行程周五，一名助手表示，准备“无禁忌”地采取新措施，尽管已知内阁中的一些部长反对紧急状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在全国范围内的城市骚乱期间， 2005 年，当时的右翼政府在大约两周的冲突后宣布进入紧急状态，这是自 20 世纪 50 年代以来法国大陆首次采取该措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们呼吁另类右翼全国集会发言人塞巴斯蒂安·切努周五对 LCI 电视台表示：“首先实施宵禁，然后实施全面紧急状态，并动员全国所有治安力量。”他说：“现在我们正处于悬崖底部，我们需要极其强硬。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;右翼共和党领袖埃里克·西奥蒂 (Eric Ciotti) 呼吁建立一个周四宣布紧急状态，称“国家在任何情况下都不能动摇”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据内政部称，周四晚间部署了约 40,000 名安全部队，夜间逮捕了 875 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;2015 年 11 月，圣战武装分子发动恐怖袭击，造成巴塔克兰音乐厅、餐馆和国家体育场 130 人死亡，之后法国进入紧急状态长达两年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多反政府人士紧急状态法中的反恐条款，包括赋予政府关闭礼拜场所和未经审判限制民众的权力，被纳入马克龙领导下的 2017 年通过的新法律中，该法律受到公民自由团体的广泛批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙的一名助手周四淡化了实施紧急状态法的可能性，称“没有必要反应过度”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;住房和城市事务部长奥利维尔·克莱因 (Olivier Klein) 周五也公开表示反对，他表示法国国际米兰电台表示，这将是“承认失败”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为我们还有其他选择，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴黎西南部郊区克拉马尔成为周四是第一个宣布夜间宵禁的地区，而首都地区的公共巴士和电车服务于晚上 9 点停止——这项措施现在将无限期地每晚实施。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt; div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China uses laser for 10 times faster satellite-to-ground communication in major breakthrough]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3226159/china-uses-laser-10-times-faster-satellite-ground-communication-major-breakthrough?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/0a8395a3-b008-4fe0-8c5b-35df0a2a8b45_8fa8405f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国在商业卫星上成功部署基于激光的高速通信技术，增加空对地数据传输速度十倍，达到每秒 10 千兆字节 (Gbps)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“利用地面 500 毫米（19.7 英寸）孔径，研究人员接收了从吉林卫星上的发射器发出的激光信号1 MF02A04卫星，”官方科技日报本周早些时候报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近地轨道上由108颗组成的吉林一号星座是世界上最大的成像卫星网络，并发送回商业遥感数据适用于土地资源调查、城市规划和灾害监测等领域。预计最新突破将显着增强与卫星的地面通信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;传统上，卫星到地面的链路主要依赖于微波技术。然而，由于微波频率范围受到限制，数据传输速度也受到限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，激光的频谱要宽得多。因此，使用激光器作为数据载体可以帮助将更多数据打包到每次传输中，带宽可能达到数百千兆赫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自该国主要研究机构的航空航天信息研究所（AIR）的一个团队 –中国科学院 - 使用激光建立了卫星到地面的链路，正式名称为“光通信”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的系统于 12 月与吉林一号 MF02A04 一起送入轨道，周三成功测试，为更高效的数据交换打开了大门。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国空间激光攻击竞赛创造数据速度记录：论文&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;地面系统负责人李亚林AIR 将该技术与城市道路进行了比较。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“使用 375 MHz 的普通微波就像在单车道上行驶，而新兴的[技术]更高的 1.5 GHz 微波将是四通道车道，”他说。 “与此同时，激光器可以容纳数百甚至数千条通道。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过[此类]光通信，可以在一秒钟内传输一部高清电影，这是其10到1000倍比目前的微波通信方式更快。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉林一号发射机发回地球的第一批数据包括卡塔尔首都多哈的图片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是国内首次面向商业应用的超高速[10Gbps]星地光通信测试，单次通信持续时间超过100秒。”发射吉林一号MF02A04卫星的商业公司表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;激光能量高度集中，也意味着星载激光发射机的尺寸、重量和功耗明显小于微波发射机。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;激光器还具有很强的抗电磁干扰能力，可以显着提高地对卫星通信的安全性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;值得注意的是，美国宇航局已经加快了类似的研究，并联手去年 6 月，与麻省理工学院 (MIT) 研究人员合作，实现了 100 Gbps 的下行链路速度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一壮举是通过 MIT 开发的 TeraByte 红外传输 (TBIRD) 系统实现的，该系统已被纳入由美国宇航局探路者技术演示器 3 (PTD-3) 卫星送入轨道。该系统以 TB 命名，这是一种数字数据单位，相当于 1,000 GB 或约 500 小时的高清视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PTD-3 大约有两个堆叠的麦片盒大小，TBIRD据美国宇航局称，它携带的有效载荷并不比普通纸巾盒大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，美国激光链路将数据速率提高了一倍，达到破纪录的 200 Gbps 传输速度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“通过光通信，我们将尽可能地带回尽可能多的数据。这确实是一种改变游戏规则的能力。”TBIRD 项目经理 Beth Keer 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，美国宇航局的记录是在演示卫星上实现的，演示卫星通常比商业型卫星更强大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;吉林一号MF02A04是一颗实用、长寿命的商业卫星。它的重量不到 40 公斤（88 磅），但其发射器的重量尚不清楚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更快的数据传输可以推动许多领域的发展。这项技术可以促进收集有关地球气候和资源的重要数据以及天体物理发现和军事探测的任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“激光通信是实现未来科学发现的缺失环节。据报道，科尔在 5 月份表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，在该技术的商业应用方面，中国可能具有优势。吉林一号星座今年将有138颗卫星在轨运行，到2025年完成二期建设，届时卫星数量将达到300颗。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;强大的中国兆瓦级激光器“小到足以&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;届时，系统强大的遥感图像能力每天都会产生大量数据，满足日益增长的星地、星间数据传输需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;6月15日，长光卫星技术公司又成功发射了一颗代号为“02A”的吉林一号系列卫星，该卫星搭载新一代光通信有效载荷，验证了高速星间、星地及回传能力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据该公司网站介绍：“下一步，长光卫星技术公司将开展地面卫星的常态化和商业试运行。 -星地激光通信，为后续40Gbps星地激光通信有效载荷的大规模应用提供技术基础。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘No need to panic’: Hong Kong food safety experts urge residents not to worry over ‘possibly carcinogenic’ label on sweetener aspartame]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3226173/no-need-panic-hong-kong-food-safety-experts-urge-residents-not-worry-over-possibly-carcinogenic?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/d7e47bde-9f4c-459c-b40e-861cd2d24a41_f172eb73.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港食品安全专家呼吁居民不要担心食用阿斯巴甜这种人工合成的物质据报道，一些软饮料和口香糖中发现了甜味剂，世界卫生组织的癌症研究机构将宣布这些甜味剂“可能致癌”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家周五表示，一个成年人必须喝十几罐甜味剂。每天喝健怡可乐有风险，并指出可能的分类并不一定意味着该物质会致癌。但他们呼吁公众避免过量食用含有甜味剂的商品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿斯巴甜是最常见的人造甜味剂之一，由两种天然氨基酸制成，其甜度约为糖的 200 倍，但热量低。它常见于减肥软饮料和零食中，例如可口可乐的健怡可乐和箭牌的 Extra 无糖口香糖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界卫生组织下属的国际癌症研究机构有四个不同级别的分类：致癌；可能致癌；可能致癌；并且不可分类。分类是根据该物质致癌能力的证据强度，而不是其致癌的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社周四报道称，阿斯巴甜将被列为“可能致癌”，这表明有有限的证据表明其对人类致癌的能力，但在动物中有足够的证据，或者它表现出人类致癌物的关键特征。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该类别中的其他物质包括芦荟、汽油产生的发动机废气、传统亚洲泡菜和射频电磁场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港城市大学健康与科学学部主任黄韵芝博士表示，这一决定并不一定意味着阿斯巴甜会致癌。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在安全困境中，香港学校争先恐后地维持学生的食物供应&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“[分类]意味着不能100%确定该物质具有致癌性，但指出身为注册营养师的黄说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这提醒公众，他们在食用前可能需要更多地了解该物质，并应避免过度食用，但完全不必惊慌。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一罐减肥软饮料通常含有 180 毫克阿斯巴甜。根据欧洲食品安全局的数据，该物质的每日可接受摄入量为每天每公斤体重 40 毫克。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，体重 60 公斤（132 磅）的人每天必须食用 13 罐以上&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;注意到糖尿病患者和试图减肥的人可能会选择减肥软饮料来减少糖的摄入量，黄说此举并不是控制体重的长期解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“这只能作为减少对糖依赖的短期解决方案，”她说。 「如果不能减少对甜食的胃口，长远来说，可能会想吃更甜的食物和饮料，从而增加热量的摄入。」&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;食物学会主席刘乐廷教授安全联盟一致认为，居民无需过多担心分类问题，并补充说需要更多研究来证明这种联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在测试的近一半干肉样本中发现了污染物：香港监管机构&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;“但政府必须进行更多风险沟通，以缓解公众对此事的担忧并防止不必要的恐慌，特别是糖尿病患者，”刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说他相信如果更多研究证明阿斯巴甜是一种致癌物质，食品和饮料制造商可能需要开发替代品，但指出公众接受程度是一个关键因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多加工肉类产品也被发现致癌，但仍出现在亚洲饮食中。人们知道不应该吃太多，但他们并没有停止食用它们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》已联系了几家相关产品制造商，包括太古公司和玛氏公司，请其置评。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卫生署表示知悉世界卫生组织机构进行的评估，并会密切监察人造甜味剂科学评估的最新情况，以制定相应建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;食物安全中心表示它还在密切关注事态发展，包括癌症机构和世界卫生组织下的联合国际专家委员会将于7月中旬发布的评估结果，以及其他当局的评估。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt; div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China to ease economic and trade rules to aid CPTPP pact bid, amid scepticism over reform commitment]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3226158/china-ease-economic-and-trade-rules-aid-cptpp-pact-bid-amid-scepticism-over-reform-commitment?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/c579d024-e5e8-4a7d-b03b-9208573f4368_248d748b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国推出新措施，帮助其申请加入亚太贸易协定尽管一些成员认为对于世界第二大经济体来说准入门槛过高，但北京仍继续努力实现其达到 11 国协议标准的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些措施，部分国务院周四表示，将在中国部分自贸区和口岸试行开放文件，旨在与“高标准国际经济贸易规则”接轨。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;中国商务部部长助理陈春江表示，这些措施为加入《全面与进步跨太平洋伙伴关系协定》（CPTPP）和《数字经济伙伴关系协定》提供了“务实支持” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次试点将有助于中国积累经验，也展示中国加入高标准经贸协定的意愿和能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“加入CPTPP是一个明智的选择。” “这符合中国的利益，我认为这也符合所有CPTPP成员的利益，也符合亚太地区和世界经济复苏的利益。”陈周五补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈还表示，中方已对协议进行了深入研究评估，整理了加入跨太平洋贸易协定的改革措施和相关法律法规。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“下一步，我们将陈补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国于 2021 年 9 月申请加入 CPTPP 和 DEPA——它建立在现有自由贸易协定的数字或电子商务章节的基础上—— 2021年11月。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;外部压力加大，中国呼吁加入CPTPP贸易集团&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;加入CPTPP需要所有成员国的批准，即加拿大、墨西哥、秘鲁、智利、新西兰、澳大利亚、文莱、新加坡、马来西亚、越南和日本。英国于 2021 年 6 月提出申请，并于 3 月份达成协议，预计今年正式签署该协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的新措施包括禁止相关部门要求“转让或访问另一方拥有的软件的源代码，作为进口、分发、销售或使用此类软件或包含此类软件的产品的条件”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为这该文件是中国为解决加入 CPTPP 过程中的担忧所做的持续努力的一部分。我预计一路上会发生更多变化，因为[习近平主席]已将加入 CPTPP 作为他的目标之一。”新加坡管理大学法学教授高亨利表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟商会Commerce in China also said the document was “a step in the right direction”, but added that further measures are still necessary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The changes on the transfer of source codes “does not elaborate the circumstances under which this would apply, there is a level of uncertainty about its implementation and any resulting implications,” the chamber said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi has said that China is open to negotiations on industrial subsidies and state-owned firms to be accepted into CPTPP.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Member countries, including Australia and Japan, have raised concerns over China&#39;s ability to comply with reforms needed for the accession.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ultimately, China&#39;s chances would depend on the US . If the US were to come back into the CPTPP very soon, then China would not stand a chance, but if the US drags on for too long in returning to the CPTPP, then China&#39;s bid would be taken more seriously by CPTPP members,” Gao added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CPTPP emerged after former US president Donald Trump withdrew the country from its predecessor, the Trans-Pacific Partnership, in 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Biden administration has not revisited the idea, but has sought to create new frameworks, including the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China also pledged to relax temporary entry rules for business executives and their families, allowing them to enjoy the same length of stay as company representatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The measures “send a good signal for the further resumption of people-to-people exchanges”, the European chamber added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But other related challenges remain, such as the erosion of the soft infrastructure that is vital for maintaining a vibrant foreign community in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For example, with international schools and medical clinics finding themselves short of both staff and customers, their service offerings have reduced overall, which makes relocation to China a less attractive proposition, especially for senior-level talent who are more likely to bring their families.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, New Zealand publicly endorsed China&#39;s participation in both CPTPP and DEPA following a meeting between New Zealand&#39;s trade minister Damien O&#39;Connor and his Chinese counterpart, Wang Wentao, on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s CPTPP bid &#39;impossible&#39; for Australia to approve while sanctions remain&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;New Zealand will host a meeting of CPTPP members in July, when new applicants are expected to be considered, with Taiwan, Ecuador and Costa Rica having also applied to join.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New Zealand Prime Minister Chris Hipkins said all applications to join CPTPP would be considered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has previously opposed Taiwan joining “any agreement or organisation of an official nature”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Kandy Wong&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong property: plot of land for flats in Kennedy Town fetches just 6 bids as high interest rates, market gloom deter developers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226163/hong-kong-property-plot-land-flats-kennedy-town-fetches-just-6-bids-high-interest-rates-market-gloom?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 19:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/18bbd99f-af40-44e5-af9c-73d38caafa49_c4ca1c4e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The first government land tender of this financial year ended up attracting far fewer bids than expected as the prospect of further interest rate hikes and new housing supply dimmed the outlook for Hong Kong&#39;s property market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tender for the site at the junction of Sai Ning Street and Victoria Road in Kennedy Town fetched just six bids on Friday, according to the Lands Department. The land, on the western side of Hong Kong Island, is expected to yield about 450 flats, some with a sea view.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alex Leung, senior director at CHFT Advisory and Appraisal, had expected somewhere between 12 and 15 bids.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I considered the land in Kennedy Town a rare opportunity as it is an urban area. The scale is also optimal and fits medium to large-scale developers,” said Leung. “Obviously, I was over-optimistic. Developers are far more conservative than they were a few months ago.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The construction of a temporary bus terminal next to the site while the existing one on the plot is replaced by a new one will prolong the development period, and this might have deterred some potential bidders, Leung said. The high interest rate environment makes the long development time frame more unpalatable because it will increase the cost of the project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local Chinese media reported that the six bids came from CK Asset, Sun Hung Kai Properties, Wheelock Properties, a joint venture between Sino Land and China Merchants Land, K Wah International and Great Eagle Holdings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CK Asset, the flagship property developer of billionaire Li Ka-shing, confirmed to the Post it had submitted a bid, while Sino Land confirmed its joint bid with China Merchants Land.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Developers may be adopting a wait-and-see attitude for the first land sale of this financial year,” said Cyrus Fong, head of valuation and advisory at Knight Frank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Although sentiment in the property market improved slightly at the beginning of the year after all the anti-pandemic measures were scrapped and the border reopened, the market has started to slow down in the middle of the year.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another deterrent may have been the presence of a nearby public mortuary that is not due to be moved elsewhere until 2028 at the earliest, said Fong. He said this would put some people off living there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The land, being located on Hong Kong Island, is attractive and quite rare, said Quinly Wan, director of Hong Kong property development and leasing at K Wah International. She said the long development period had been reflected in K Wah&#39;s bidding price.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wheelock said the reasons for its bid included the site&#39;s proximity to another of its developments and an MTR station.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Surveyors have slashed their valuations for the parcel. Pruden Group cut its estimate by the most, from HK$9,000 (US$1,148) per square foot in February to between HK$5,000 and HK$5,300 per sq ft on Wednesday, because of high cash flow requirements and an estimated nine-year development period. That takes its valuation for the whole plot down from HK$2 billion to as little as HK$1.2 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Midland Surveyors reduced its valuation from HK$9,500 per sq ft in May to HK$8,500 per sq ft on Wednesday, or from HK$2.31 billion to HK$2.07 billion, because of cautious market sentiment, falling house prices and high interest costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A nearby parcel of land sold for around HK$9,500 per square foot in November, according to Centaline Surveyors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eddie Yue Wai-man, the CEO of the Hong Kong Monetary Authority, warned this month that the cycle of rising interest rates was far from over, despite the de facto central bank hitting pause following 10 straight increases since March 2022.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong to look into completing rail link in Northern Metropolis earlier after lawmakers voice concerns over potential jobs, housing mismatch]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3226154/hong-kong-look-completing-rail-link-northern-metropolis-earlier-after-lawmakers-voice-concerns-over?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 18:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/a7ddf3bb-4fec-4d0e-b2ec-6cbb2d69d285_76f94938.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Authorities will look into completing a major rail line in Hong Kong&#39;s New Territories earlier after lawmakers voiced concerns over a potential mismatch between housing and jobs in the Northern Metropolis megaproject.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ambitious metropolis project, described by the administration as a new driving force for economic growth and integration with mainland China, was announced in 2021 by former chief executive Carrie Lam Cheng Yuet-ngor and covers a total land area of about 300 sq km.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Located in the northern part of Hong Kong, bordering the mainland, the area is said to be capable of housing a population of 2.5 million and create 650,000 job opportunities when fully developed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a Legislative Council discussion on Friday, Secretary for Development Bernadette Linn Hon-ho said enterprises could move in by 2030, followed by residents, triggering questions from lawmakers about the plan&#39;s feasibility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They questioned whether jobs would be available for residents when the Northern Link, a major rail line serving the northern part of the New Territories, might not open until 2034, with lawmaker Jeffrey Lam Kin-fung criticising the government&#39;s planning, saying it was “not comprehensive enough”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Linn said: “We will work with the Transport and Logistics Bureau to see if the Northern Link can be opened any earlier.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Road map for Hong Kong&#39;s Northern Metropolis could be ready within this year&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The bureau would provide more concrete details of ancillary transport services during the interim period to ease public concerns, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawmakers Regina Ip Lau Suk-yee, Michael Luk Chung-hung and Edward Lau Kwok-fan also questioned the potential mismatch between housing and jobs in the Northern Metropolis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luk said the project lacked a concrete timeline on when and what kinds of job opportunities would be created.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ip said employment in the mega project would account for 20 per cent of more than 3 million jobs in Hong Kong, so consideration should be given to daily commutes to work when planning infrastructure such as roads and railways.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lau pointed to Yuen Long as an example, saying the area had a serious mismatch of 120,000 jobs and 960,000 residents. He hoped the same would not happen in the Northern Metropolis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response, Linn said the planned figures of 2.5 million residents and the creation of 650,000 job opportunities came from the previous government when the policy was announced and based on different assumptions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that while studies were under way and should be available by the end of this year or early 2024, there was flexibility in changing the figures when more data was available on different land uses.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong aims to earmark 300 hectares of land for I&amp;T purposes near border&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Linn also said it is impossible to guarantee residents could find jobs in the same area, but the government would do its best to match where homes and work opportunities were.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vic Yau Cheuk-hang, director of the Northern Metropolis Coordination Office, added that the planning of road networks in newly developed areas would take into account when residents and enterprises would move in.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Balloon saga has had ‘great impact’ on US-China relations, analyst says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3226157/balloon-saga-has-had-great-impact-us-china-relations-analyst-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 19:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/fae79289-35c0-4633-8191-b12d1bd75bb9_ace7319f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The “spy balloon” saga will continue to affect US-China relations despite the Pentagon confirming that the Chinese craft had not been collecting intelligence when it flew over the United States, an analyst says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The suspected surveillance balloon had crossed the continental United States from Alaska to the east coast before it was shot down over the Atlantic Ocean in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We believe that it did not collect while it was transiting the United States or flying over the United States,” Pentagon spokesman Brigadier General Pat Ryder told reporters on Thursday, adding that the US “took steps to mitigate” the potential collection efforts of the craft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the remarks are not expected to do much to improve the relationship between the two powers, according to Shi Yinhong, an international relations professor at Renmin University of China in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Although the Pentagon&#39;s claims may be contrary to what they used to be, the actual impact will be almost zero,” he said. “The tension between China and the US has not been removed.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shi said “the most important fact” was that the US military had shot down the Chinese balloon which it believed was being used to gather intelligence, and that the incident “has had a great impact on US-China relations”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked about Ryder&#39;s remarks on Friday, Chinese foreign ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning said Beijing had made clear that the civilian unmanned airship had flown into US airspace in an “isolated and unexpected” incident caused by force majeure. She said the claim that it was a spy balloon was an attempt to smear and attack China.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Shoot them down&#39;: Taiwan vows to destroy &#39;risky&#39; mainland Chinese balloons&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The saga worsened the mutual distrust between Beijing and Washington, sending the bilateral relationship between the two nuclear powers to its lowest point in decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington said it was a violation of its sovereignty, and US lawmakers increased pressure on the White House to take tougher action on China. Beijing insisted the balloon was an errant civilian airship used for meteorological research and said the US was overreacting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The episode put top-level engagement between the two countries – which had just started to thaw – back in the deep freeze for months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It prompted US Secretary of State Antony Blinken to postpone a China trip, while the Chinese defence ministry refused a call from US defence chief Lloyd Austin after the balloon was shot down. Blinken went ahead with his visit last week, but defence communications have still not resumed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, the Pentagon statement is the latest sign that the US is looking to move on from the balloon incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That chapter should be closed,” Blinken said on Monday last week during his rescheduled two-day trip to Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, President Joe Biden said the “silly balloon” had derailed ties during the Group of Seven summit in Hiroshima, Japan. And just last week he admitted the craft had been blown off course, noting that it “wasn&#39;t supposed to be going where it was”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US national security adviser Jake Sullivan also told China&#39;s top diplomat Wang Yi that Washington was looking to “move beyond” the incident, during talks in Vienna last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Pentagon&#39;s latest statement could set the stage for a summit between the US and Chinese leaders, according to Pang Zhongying, chair professor in international and regional political economy at Sichuan University in Chengdu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With Blinken&#39;s visit to China as a marker, I think the page has been turned on the balloon incident,” Pang said, adding that US-China relations appeared to be moving in a more positive direction.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s Communist Party reaches 98 million members but youth membership falls]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3226150/chinas-communist-party-reaches-98-million-members-youth-membership-fell-due-strict-screening?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 18:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/8acbb763-6761-4965-b56f-0605baa924f2_b29a8ff6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s ruling Communist Party has tightened the screening process for new applicants and stepped up oversight of young cadres, a party source said on Friday as the organisation revealed a surprising drop in the number of members aged under 30.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Central Organisation Department, the party&#39;s top personnel office, said the total number of party members aged under 30 dropped to 12.43 million last year – a fall of 189,000 or 1.5 per cent – from 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overall, the party still had a net increase of 1.3 million members, a 1.4 per cent growth, pushing total membership past 98 million last year. But the total growth was much slower than the 3.4 million, or 3.7 per cent, increase seen in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Party data also showed a total 2.5 million members were recruited in 2022, a big slowdown compared to 2021&#39;s 4.4 million, despite rising applications. But the number is higher than the 2.3 million and 2.1 million recruitments in 2019 and 2018 respectively.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 21 million people submitted applications to join the party but were waiting for approval, nearly 300,000 more than the previous year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An official source familiar with the tally said the party&#39;s tightening of its political screening process for new applications and disciplinary supervision of younger cadres were key contributors to the lower recruitment number.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no shortage of new applications, but we want quality people. We need to weed out those who appreciate Western values, indulge in extravagance, avoid tough duties, or have doubts with the party&#39;s directions,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The case files from the anti-corruption agency shows many corrupt officials had wrong motives when they joined the party.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How party membership, state-sector jobs became fashionable for young Chinese&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The screening and nurturing of young cadres has been one of Chinese President Xi Jinping&#39;s key priorities. In his keynote speech to the party&#39;s disciplinary apparatus in January, he told anti-corruption watchdogs to “strengthen the education, management and supervision of young cadres” and ensure they “fasten the first button in their political career right”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) – China&#39;s top anti-corruption agency – has also announced a series of high-profile crackdowns on corrupt young cadres, including the case of a person accused of accepting bribes and spending 3 million yuan (US$413,000) on online gaming.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source said the new recruitment numbers for 2021 were exceptionally high because many 2020 recruitments were counted in 2021 numbers because of delays caused by the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Covid-19 controls affected the tallying from 2020 as all party organs were called in to control the spread of pandemic,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We did not issue a separate data set for 2020 numbers because of the disruption. Many 2020 numbers were later compiled into 2021 numbers. That is why we saw a big spike in 2021.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the party has seen growth in its female demographic and members from ethnic minority groups. The number of female members increased by 871,000 in 2022, reaching a total of 29 million, accounting for almost 30 per cent of the membership. There are 7.45 million party members from ethnic minority groups, an increase of 16,000 and accounting for 7.6 per cent of membership.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ruling party of the world&#39;s second-biggest economy is also becoming more educated with 53.65 million party members – 54.7 per cent of the membership base – having a college degree or above, an increase of 2.2 million on 2021 figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The data was released a day before the party celebrates the 102nd anniversary of its founding on July 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How Xi Jinping promotes culture-Marxism mix to further &#39;Chinese dream&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Xi, who is also the party&#39;s general secretary, extended festive greetings to party members across the country on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his remarks, which were read out at the national conference on the party&#39;s personnel work held on Wednesday and Thursday, Xi urged greater effort to build “a contingent of competent key officials for governance” who are capable of shouldering the mission of national rejuvenation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also ordered the personnel apparatus to move faster to build “global hubs for talent and innovation”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 18:50:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese online travel agent Trip.com to subsidise employee newborns as country’s population crisis deepens]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226135/chinese-online-travel-agent-tripcom-subsidise-employee-newborns-countrys-population-crisis-deepens?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 18:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/5b400bea-85f5-499a-9941-27f8fb39a9a9_ebed9558.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese online travel giant Trip.com is offering 50,000 yuan (US$6,897) in subsidies to employees who give birth, a policy that puts the company at the forefront of corporate efforts to address China&#39;s declining population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a statement by the Shanghai-based company, all employees with three years of service are entitled to the programme. Starting Saturday, eligible workers who have newborns will receive 10,000 yuan on each of the first five birthdays of their child. The company said it has earmarked 1 billion yuan for the scheme so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move comes as the country is awakening to a demographic crisis after four decades of notorious birth controls imposed by the central government. China&#39;s population peaked in 2022 as the number of births fell below 10 million for the first time, a trend that is expected to continue.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Population management could be key to winning the US-China tech race&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;James Liang, co-founder and executive chairman of Trip.com, has been warning about China&#39;s demographic crisis for years, calling for the state to do more to reduce the cost of childbearing and to boost fertility rates. As early as 2015, when the Chinese government still levied hefty fines on “excessive” births, Trip.com introduced an internal policy of providing interest-free loans, up to 200,000 yuan, to employees who had to pay the fine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a statement announcing the new incentive policy, Liang said, “Enterprises should play roles within their capacity to build up … a benign atmosphere for reproduction.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a separate staff-wide email sent out on Friday, Trip.com chief executive Jane Sun said the company could relate to the financial burdens of raising a child, and believes the subsidies could help with educational and other child-raising expenses incurred by employees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, which was dethroned by India as the world&#39;s most populous country this year, has now implemented an official “three-child” policy and ended fines for excessive births.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Provincial governments in China have also moved to provide incentives, including cash subsidies, to encourage couples to have more than one child, but the policies have failed to generate any meaningful rebound in China&#39;s fertility rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing finally wakes up to demographic reality, in a case of better late than never&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In a blog post published on his personal WeChat account in January, Liang said it was “frightening” to see how fast China&#39;s birth rate had dropped, and how quickly the low fertility crisis came about in the past five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The impact of China&#39;s collapsing birth rate will manifest in the next two decades … China is likely to suffer a significant negative impact over the long-term,” Liang cautioned in his piece, adding that action must be taken immediately if China were to reverse the trend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trip.com&#39;s new policy of subsidising employees who have babies became a topic of discussion among Chinese netizens on Friday. “It&#39;s like using a cup of water to put out a cart of burning firewood, but it is a move in the right direction,” one internet user commented.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 18:50:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>