<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Kidnappers in Ecuador resort to cutting off victims’ fingers to get hefty ransoms as crime jumps]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3224427/kidnappers-ecuador-resort-cutting-victims-fingers-get-hefty-ransoms-crime-jumps?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 13:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/ed839779-a34d-49ac-953e-3051650fea2a_b609eaf7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;犯罪在厄瓜多尔变得残酷，绑架者现在经常截断他们的受害者，并发送图像向亲属施压，要求他们支付更高的赎金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几十年来，厄瓜多尔一直是夹在危险地区的和平避难所。但如今，它越来越像附近的秘鲁和哥伦比亚，这两个拥有暴力犯罪历史的可卡因生产大国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3 月，港口城市瓜亚基尔一名商人的妻子收到有人剪断两根手指的照片从她丈夫的左手上取下，威胁要进一步肢解他，除非他们得到 10 万美元的报酬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年底，警方公布了一张智利海军成员的照片，这名士兵的两根手指被砍掉了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，当一张没有手指的手的 X 光片传遍社交媒体时，他在一次绑架中受到了关注。这张照片是一名前往美国的厄瓜多尔移民在回家度假期间被绑架。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;武装袭击者在厄瓜多尔港口城市瓜亚基尔造成 10 人死亡、3 人受伤&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对于与 2022 年同期的 60 起相比，今年前五个月的绑架报告增加了两倍，达到 189 起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们仍然普遍认为这一数字未被充分报告。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;一些绑架者要求快速支付赎金，索要低至 5,000 美元的赎金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家路易斯·科尔多瓦 (Luis Cordova) 表示，一场“可怕”的袭击行动正在给深陷公共安全危机的政府施加压力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有约 300 万居民的瓜亚基尔港已成为暴力的温床，汽车炸弹、监狱大屠杀、残缺不全的尸体悬挂在桥上以及绑架事件频频发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;流血事件已经发生安全分析师卡拉·阿尔瓦雷斯 (Carla Alvarez) 表示，尚未飙升至哥伦比亚或墨西哥曾在毒品暴力高峰期达到的水平，但“我们正沿着类似的道路前行”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，绑架、敲诈勒索未遂或谋杀案增加了五倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓜亚基尔的可卡因叶被走私到开往欧洲或美国的船只上，2023 年迄今已发生 1,000 多起谋杀案... &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为什么一个与贩毒集团结盟的强大团伙会冒险与被绑架者的亲属交谈，而他们可以贩运两吨毒品？” Cordova 问道，他是国立中央大学的教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;厄瓜多尔目前存在 13 个主要犯罪团伙，政府在 4 月宣布有组织犯罪团伙成员为恐怖分子，并授权军队追捕他们更大的自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使遭受酷刑，大多数绑架受害者都能活下来，警察反绑架部门的区域负责人 Oscar Salguero 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些被勒索赎金的人通常被关在浴室里，当犯罪团伙与他们的亲人谈判时，双手被束缚，时刻处于恐惧之中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，对企业家的敲诈勒索正在增加。今年已登记了大约 2,700 起此类投诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;40 岁的米格尔要求不透露自己的姓氏，他曾因拒绝向勒索者交出 20,000 美元而受到绑架一个月的威胁。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;据调查，这名建筑商从监狱传来的手机中收到了后续照片和警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科尔多瓦说，受绑架和勒索影响最大的是中上层阶级，他们中的大多数人将在定于 8 月举行的大选中投票支持对有组织犯罪采取“强硬态度”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 13:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Defiant comedian Jocelyn Chia taunts Malaysia over MH370 joke again]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3224424/defiant-comedian-jocelyn-chia-taunts-malaysia-over-mh370-joke-again?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 12:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/2b21e155-d6af-4097-acff-3efe08989141_13b7ea94.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Jocelyn Chia，在马来西亚成为批评和公众愤怒的避雷针，正在陶醉于她新发现的恶名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位居住在纽约的单口相声演员在一段她拿 2014 年失踪的马来西亚航空公司 MH370 航班开玩笑的片段后声名狼藉，她感谢马来西亚人把她在聚光灯下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我现在在 BBC.com 的头版。接受了@CNN、@nytimes、@BBCWorld 的采访，并将在本周六出现在@FoxNews 上。所以实际上，马来西亚，你可以继续前进，”她在周三发推文说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的@netflix 特别节目是自己写的。谢谢马来西亚！”她在星期四的另一条推文中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特使说喜剧演员“不是新加坡人”，因为马来西亚对 MH370 笑话感到愤怒&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chia 没有受到公众的强烈抗议，转发了一段她笑的采访片段在主持人关于 MH370 航班遇难人数的笑话中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一位喜剧演员 Chrissie Mayr 主持的采访中，看到 Chia 在 Mayr 说 227 人死亡“不是很多”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“老实说，如果国际刑警组织对这个要求采取行动并且事情升级，你能想象这会让我出名吗？” Chia 周三在接受 BBC 采访时说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我只是希望我能看到收到请求的国际刑警组织官员的脸。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chia 还说，她社交媒体上的笑话已被断章取义，她的日常生活应该在喜剧俱乐部的环境中完整呈现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，嘲笑观众是喜剧俱乐部文化的一部分纽约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该视频片段激怒了马来西亚人和新加坡人，并从 TikTok 中删除，这被认为违反了其仇恨言论指南。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;这个笑话杀人&#39;：新加坡漫画以 MH370 恶作剧激怒马来西亚&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新加坡外交部长维维安巴拉克里希南表示谢的笑话“可怕”，新加坡驻马来西亚高级专员也表示他们不容忍此类行为，并透露谢不是新加坡人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚警察局长亚克力萨尼阿卜杜拉萨尼曾表示，警方正在寻求国际刑警组织的帮助，以查明 Chia 的完整身份和目前的下落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文首发于 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Beijing fury risk as UK security minister ‘meets Taiwanese minister’ in break with convention]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224428/beijing-fury-risk-uk-security-minister-meets-taiwanese-minister-break-convention?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 12:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/25b2e374-07b4-4851-913b-bea238172a43_a78829c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英国安全部长Tom Tugendhat周三会见台湾数码部长，有识之士会谈中的一位表示，这是一次打破英国传统外交政策的会议，并有可能激怒中国政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国与北京只有正式外交关系，但在台北设有事实上的大使馆。尽管英国初级部长与台湾同行举行会谈，但惯例是高级部长不与台湾官员会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位消息人士称，与台湾部长 Audrey Tang 的会面是为了共同的安全利益。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;本周，唐家璇对英国进行了罕见的高级别部长级访问。她的办公室表示，预计她将访问政府部门并会见一家专门从事低地球轨道卫星的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大陆认为民主治理的台湾是其领土的一部分，并强烈反对外国干涉该岛.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;图根哈特两年前因在新疆涉嫌侵犯人权而受到中国制裁，他不是正式的内阁部长，但作为安全部长出席内阁会议，他负责旨在打击恐怖主义、国内国家威胁和经济犯罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各国议会联盟中国问题联盟执行主任卢克·德普尔福德对他的政府表示，该联盟由民主国家的立法者组成，对北京的行为表示担忧知道这是参加内阁的英国部长第一次会见台湾部长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是非常受欢迎的，并发出了正确的信息，”他说。 “应该祝贺安全部长面对来自其他部门的压力并开创了一个新的先例，现在所有部长都可以效仿。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;台湾的数字事务机构转向 Web3 以防范网络攻击&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;几位在职官员和部门不愿与路透社讨论所讨论的内容，这证明了会议的敏感性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内政部的一位女发言人说：“我们不会例行发表评论&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang 的办公室拒绝置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang 周四在 Twitter 上发布了一张她阅读“新技术状态：我们的数字梦想如何成为社会噩梦”的照片– 以及我们能做些什么”，这是一本即将出版的书，其作者 Bil​​l Raduchel 表示，这本书是从 2019 年与 Tugendhat 的对话中演变而来的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“向@TomTugendhat 学习会带来红利， ”她在推文中说。 “让我们一起#FreeTheFuture！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;已知的最后一位访问英国的台湾部长是去年 6 月访问英国的台湾最高贸易谈判代表约翰·邓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11 月，当时的英国-商务部副部长 Greg Hands 访问了台湾并会见了蔡英文总统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京谴责了这次访问，就像它对所有此类互动所做的那样。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mentorship scheme for underprivileged Hong Kong students in subdivided flats may be extended to those in public housing, No 2 official says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3224430/mentorship-scheme-underprivileged-hong-kong-students-subdivided-flats-may-be-extended-those-public?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 13:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/3f409b2c-563c-4e08-bfc4-b0d1223c98a2_e3a91686.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一项旨在帮助香港的香港学生摆脱贫困的导师计划可能是该市二号官员周六表示，该计划在第二年扩大到公共住房中的学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府的“奋斗与崛起”计划于 10 月启动，招收了 2,779 名生活在众所周知的贫困地区的贫困中学生。旨在提高他们的社会流动性的微型房屋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每个年轻人都被分配了一名导师，并且在整个计划中将获得总计 10,000 港元（1,278 美元）的奖励，包括必修课程和选修课程&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政务司司长陈国基周六表示，由于该计划的现有参与者将于今年晚些时候加入“校友会”，政府正在寻求扩大参加该计划的资格下一轮招生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“学生不一定要住劏房，公屋也可以吗？我们会考虑所有这些，”他在一个电台节目中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 指出，该计划去年从商界和社区部门筹集了 1.4 亿港元后资金充足，而且不用担心找不到&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港第二家酒店及青年旅舍开放接受申请&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在邀请两组学生到他的官邸后，陈说他有当学生通过该计划接触到他们受限的社交圈之外时，他们亲自观察到变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们变得积极提问，表明他们获得了自信，”他说。 “这就是该计划的目的。他们的自信心不应因家庭情况而受到限制。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈说，只有约 20 名学生在项目开始前退学，主要是因为时间冲突，并补充说一些企业已承诺为参与者提供实习机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据最新数据，2020 年香港有 274,900 名贫困儿童。这意味着贫困率为 27%，是自 2009 年有记录以来的最高水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划是在北京强调共同富裕的概念之际制定的，在共同富裕的概念下，社会流动性应该得到加强，为更多人提供机会&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;招募 2 家公司帮助在大湾区工作的香港青年：劳工部长&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;支持有需要的家庭，Chan 在演讲中说新学年，政府还计划与选定的小学和非政府组织合作推出课后托管服务试验计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，低收入家庭的学童可以免费参加，让家长有更多时间在工作，这既可以鼓励生育，又可以解放劳动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该计划有很多好处。除了为家长腾出时间，我们还可以利用每天的两三个小时来教学生一些东西，”Chan 说，并建议诸如职业规划和财务管理等主题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约 9000 万港元已预留给该计划，使大约 3,000 名学生在为期一年的试点中受益。 Chan 表示，目标是在全市范围内扩大该计划，让所有有需要的家庭受益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着现任政府下个月将迎来上任一周年，Chan 说这是他担任该市二把手的第一年他感到非常兴奋，因为他能够专注于决策制定和交付结果，而不是处理 2019 年反政府抗议活动的后果。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk expects brain chip start-up Neuralink to start its first human trial later this year after receiving US government approval]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3224426/elon-musk-expects-brain-chip-start-neuralink-start-its-first-human-trial-later-year-after-receiving?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 12:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/ff33d3d1-f0d9-4ed4-a598-fbfbae0fb6da_d441d284.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;亿万富翁科技企业家埃隆马斯克希望他的脑芯片初创公司 Neuralink 开始他周五在法国表示，这是今年的首次人体试验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在巴黎的 VivaTech 活动上，Neuralink 联合创始人马斯克表示，该公司计划在路透社监控的网络直播中为四肢瘫痪或截瘫患者植入植入物.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然他没有具体说明他的公司将植入多少患者或植入多长时间，但“看起来第一例将在今年晚些时候出现”，马斯克说，他也是电动汽车制造商的首席执行官特斯拉和火箭发射公司 Space Exploration Technologies Corp。本月早些时候，马斯克辞去了社交媒体平台 Twitter 的负责人一职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，Neuralink 表示它获得了美国食品和药物管理局 (FDA) 的批准首次人体临床试验，这是这家初创公司的一个重要里程碑，因为它在该国面临对其动物实验处理方式的调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;FDA 在早些时候给路透社的声明中承认，该机构批准 Neuralink 使用其大脑植入物和手术机器人进行试验，但拒绝提供更多细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果 Neuralink 能够证明其设备对人体安全，则仍需要数年时间——可能超过十年- 专家早些时候告诉路透社，为了确保初创企业获得商业用途许可。该公司还与其他已经将其设备植入人体的神经技术公司展开竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，马斯克之前就 Neuralink 发表公开声明时错过了时间表。自 2019 年以来，马斯克至少四次预测 Neuralink 将很快开始人体试验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;成立于 2016 年的 Neuralink 去年初首次向 FDA 寻求许可，但该机构拒绝了该申请，理由是数十项安全问题，路透社报道。其中一些问题涉及设备的锂电池、植入物的电线在大脑内移动的可能性以及在不损坏脑​​组织的情况下安全取出设备的挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继路透社之后，Neuralink 也面临联邦审查&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，Neuralink 的员工告诉路透社，由于马斯克向员工施压要求获得 FDA 批准，该公司正在匆忙对猴子、猪和羊进行手术，导致动物死亡人数超过必要水平.消息人士称，动物实验产生的数据旨在支持该公司的人体试验申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2021 年的一个例子中，该公司给 60 头猪中的 25 头植入了错误尺寸的设备。所有的猪随后都被宰杀了——员工表示，如果做好更多的准备，这个错误本可以很容易地避免。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月，美国立法者敦促监管机构调查 Neuralink 监督动物测试的小组的组成是否有助于在路透社报道了董事会潜在的财务冲突后，匆忙进行了拙劣的实验。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Elon Musk 的 Neuralink 让中国人既兴奋又害怕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国交通部正在单独调查 Neuralink 是否在没有适当的遏制措施的情况下，非法运输从猴脑中取出的芯片上的危险病原体。一名机构代表周五表示，调查仍在进行中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neuralink 也因可能违反动物福利的行为而受到美国农业部 (USDA) 监察长办公室的调查。该调查一直在关注美国农业部对 Neuralink 的监督。一位机构代表没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，Neuralink 的估值在最近几个月飙升。据路透社本月报道，这家初创公司在两年前的一轮私募融资中估值接近 20 亿美元，根据私下进行的股票交易，目前估值约为 50 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neuralink 员工该公司的动物董事会成员因潜在的财务冲突而受到联邦审查，他将从植入物的快速开发中受益。据路透社报道，根据二级交易，部分员工持有的 Neuralink 股票价值在短短两年内上涨了约 150%。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As Indonesia’s President Joko Widodo vows to end ‘thrifting’, anxious shoppers snap up second-hand clothes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3224348/indonesias-president-joko-widodo-vows-end-thrifting-anxious-shoppers-snap-second-hand-clothes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/9002e089-6435-4ab9-ad2a-036f5cd354c3_a87cfd77.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;现在是印度尼西亚早上 6 点 30 分，今天的第一个发现 – Gucci 裤子 – 去了一位 20 多岁的女士和她的朋友一起“节俭”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;星期天早上 6 点到 9 点营业的 Tugu Pahlawan 跳蚤市场是印度尼西亚第二大城市泗水的二手购物者每周光顾的地方。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最近一个周日清晨凉爽的空气中，成千上万的讨价还价者在成堆发霉的旧衣服中筛选，这些旧衣服是从世界各地进口的，以低于商店价格的价格出售。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“节俭”在印度尼西亚是一种独特的亚文化，这个国家的收入因生活成本危机而受到压力，但随着最敏锐的主角挑选设计师品牌、成衣和高级时装，时尚占据了主导地位-从成堆的街头主食中挑选待售商品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但它们必须速度很快。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;竞争以一群相互竞争的旧货购物者的形式出现。但他们也面临来自当局的压力，为了保护当地纺织业，官方禁止二手服装销售的国家在上午 9 点关闭市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;62 岁的 Heru Setio 一直在销售2004 年，他辞去了司机的工作后，在泗水跳蚤市场购买二手牛仔裤和裤子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我平日打零工，但这是我的主要收入来源。天气好的时候，我可以在这里赚到大约 200 万卢比（134 美元），”他谈到这个市场时，当局的目光转向了为寻求优衣库等外国品牌的当地时尚达人提供服装的市场。 Gap、Nike、Converse、Burberry、Prada 和 Givenchy，以及被购物中心定价的低收入买家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;年轻的印度人转向节俭并避开“无聊”的快时尚&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是在雅加达中央政府最近发誓要发起一场新的运动，以杜绝成衣的进口和贸易之后，官员们可能很快就无法对早上宝贵的几个小时视而不见了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统佐科维多多表示，他决心结束印度尼西亚的“节俭”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我已下达指示，要找出罪魁祸首。 3 月 15 日，他在雅加达中部表示，销售二手衣服对我们的纺织业有害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，维多多正在考虑制定一项总统令，以进一步加强他反对该行业的运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;政府于 2015 年首次禁止进口成衣，但这些产品不断流入印度尼西亚。根据中央统计局 (BPS) 的数据，2019 年约有 392 吨价值 608 万美元的二手衣服进入印度尼西亚，这是该国迄今为止的最高数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/ h3>;&lt;p>;对于 Setio 来说，禁令可能会带来财务灾难，但他选择不去想它，因为他不知道自己还能做什么谋生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我听说过电视新闻中的禁令，但到目前为止还没有人告诉我停止，”他说。 “也许这是暂时强制执行的其中一项措施，”他满怀希望地补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他是印度尼西亚非正式零工部门的一员，根据世界银行的数据，该部门约占该国经济的 60%。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在印尼销售的几乎所有二手服装都来自海外，主要来自日本、澳大利亚、马来西亚、新加坡、香港、美国、英国和其他欧洲国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;YOLO on预算：二手名牌服装风潮席卷韩国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但对于据称该禁令旨在保护的纺织业而言，还有其他因素在起作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年，印度尼西亚从中国进口了 51,790 吨新成衣。相比之下，当年进口的成衣数量为66吨，不到中国进口量的1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“进口二手衣服成了方便的替罪羊”因为政府不愿意或不能限制中国的进口，”经济学家 Bhima Yudistira 质疑政府打击成衣贸易的紧迫性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与我们的进口相比，它的价值微不足道来自中国的新衣服。如果目的是保护当地的服装业，那么新衣服的进口也应该受到限制，”他指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印尼纺织协会 (API) 表示，中国产品在印尼服装市场占据主导地位80% 的数量份额和大约 50% 的价值份额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;API 主席 Jeremy Sastraatmadja 表示，鉴于进口进入一些潜在市场的有利条件，当地纺织品生产商承受着来自中国商品的巨大压力2.7 亿人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的政府对中国服装给予了优惠待遇，这些服装以零关税进入该国。相比之下，从孟加拉国进口的衣服征收 20% 的关税，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 API 也希望停止进口二手衣服，认为这也会对当地服装制造商构成威胁.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然，我们不怪罪小贩。必须受到惩罚的是进口商，”Sastraatmadja 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;泗水 JMP Plaza 一家时装批发店的老板 Chandra Budianto 声称，当地的服装厂，尤其是大型服装厂，往往不能生产出大多数印度尼西亚人真正想要的东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在服装方面，款式变化很快，我们当地的生产商跟不上中国的，因为他们无法在同样的价格，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国制造的服装因其价格实惠和款式新颖而在印度尼西亚的商店和网上商店占据主导地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年，印度尼西亚的服装和纺织品出口据 BPS 称，销售额达到 69 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“先买后付”计划在印度尼西亚的网上商店开始流行&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但大型印度尼西亚纺织品生产商迎合了专业细分市场。例如，大型纺织集团 Sritex 为 36 个国家/地区生产军装，包括澳大利亚、德国、新加坡和美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Budianto 说，专注于印度尼西亚民族设计的中小型本地生产商通常有一个利基市场&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但他们更传统的方法往往等同于产量很小，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013 年至 2022 年期间，印度尼西亚进口了 870 吨价值美国的二手衣服1109 万美元。尽管官方数量相对较小，但对节俭者的打击——曾经看似不可能——现在可能迫在眉睫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局在 3 月份关闭了全国的二手服装分销链，特别是在苏门答腊的北干巴鲁;西爪哇，东爪哇； &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“正在开展调查，以确定是谁将他们带入该国，”印度尼西亚国家警察局长 Yuldi Yusman 说。 “我可以向你保证，肇事者将受到起诉……没收的衣服已被当局妥善焚烧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贸易部官员 Veri Anggrijono 表示，不可能知道二手衣服的真实数量&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“下落不明的旧衣服经常通过海路和陆路从邻国走私到印度尼西亚，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在新加坡捐赠，在新加坡出售印度尼西亚：陶氏鞋类“回收”计划曝光&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;外国制造的二手衣服的流行表明印度尼西亚产品仍然没有竞争力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这一切归结为一个事实日惹 Gadjah Mada 大学的经济学家 Eddy Junarsin 说：“低收入群体想要买得起的优质衣服，而二手衣服正好符合要求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Tugu Pahlawan 的跳蚤市场，紧迫感笼罩着购物者随着上午 9 点截止时间的临近，公共秩序官员每个周末都像发条一样出现，准备在截止日期前停止销售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当成千上万的泗水居民漫步在连绵不断的摊位上时，这些摊位起伏不定在市场上，那些发现铺在防水油布上的裁缝宝藏的人爆发出一阵阵欢呼——这或许是一个迹象，表明节俭可能比看起来更难消除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个真正的美国 Levi&#39;s ，”一个十几岁的男孩一边检查牛仔夹克，一边对他的父母低声说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我想知道它合不合身？”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Beijing’s sabre-rattling is fuelling US doubts over commitment to peaceful reunification with Taiwan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224398/how-beijings-sabre-rattling-fuelling-us-doubts-over-commitment-peaceful-reunification-taiwan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/8e71ef22-d45c-413a-a0e8-6dca79dc971e_01ae3278.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京正在努力说服美国及其盟友相信其对和平统一的承诺分析人士警告说，由于台湾对台湾的强硬姿态以及海峡两岸舆论之间日益扩大的分歧，与台湾的关系是真实的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国政客和国防官员越来越担心中国大陆可能在未来几年内对该岛采取军事行动的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;变化，”卡内基国际和平基金会高级研究员赵彤说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，从美国的角度来看，近年来北京的做法发生了重大变化，更加强调是“大棒”而不是“胡萝卜”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“例如，中国此前的官方政策承诺让台湾在回归后保留自己的军队，但在最近的声明中撤回了这一承诺，”赵&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福建省闽南师范大学高级两岸问题专家王建民对此表示赞同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国担心我们正在加速统一，特别是通过使用武力……中国继续升级其军事行动以遏制台湾独立，这引发了美国的评估，即北京确实准备以武力统一台湾，这造成了恶性循环，”王说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;2 月，中央情报局局长威廉·伯恩斯表示，美国情报部门暗示习近平已下令军队“准备到 2027 年成功入侵”台湾，尽管他补充说这并不意味着中国国家主席承诺使用&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但赵说，这强化了人们的看法，即北京正在采取“更强硬”的立场，这与北京坚持其倾向于和平解决的立场背道而驰。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国专家加入了对台湾最近的审查模拟解放军进攻的兵棋&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;和平统一一直是北京的长期政策目标，自 2012 年上台以来，习近平在重要政策文件中一再重申这一目标。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;8 月，一份关于台湾的官方白皮书将和平统一描述为共产党的“第一选择”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但赵和王都表示，即使在大陆听众看来，这种立场也越来越空洞。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;习近平在 10 月份的党的全国代表大会上重申了和平统一的承诺，但他也重申了北京的另一个长期立场：永远不会放弃使用武力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;即使是中国学者也认为，北京的重点已经从“反对台独”转向“促进统一”，赵说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然这两个目标听起来很相似，但人们普遍认为前者更具防御性，而后者&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此外，许多中国学者承认，台湾舆论的根本变化使台湾自愿回归大陆的可能性降低了，”赵补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;倾向于独立的民进党赢得了最近两次台湾总统选举。它的支持在一定程度上是由于公众越来越反对在“一国两制”模式下统一——考虑到香港过去四年的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说：“有可能和平统一的希望越来越小。 It is natural to prepare for non-peaceful reunification.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past 12 months, the People&#39;s Liberation Army (PLA) has conducted two large-scale drills around Taiwan, triggered firstly by a visit to Taipei by former US House speaker Nancy Pelosi in August and then a meeting in California between her successor, Kevin McCarthy, and Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PLA has also sent warplanes close to the island on a near-daily basis and repeatedly entered its air defence identification zone – actions the US has characterised as “intimidation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan&#39;s KMT to send delegation to mainland China forum despite warnings&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wang was pessimistic about the prospect that US Secretary of State Antony Blinken&#39;s upcoming visit to Beijing would ease tensions in the strait, arguing “the US will not give up provocations” and will continue to “play the Taiwan card”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Taiwan issue is … the most difficult historical problem of the country, it is hard to resolve. The fierce competition between China and the US over Taiwan issues will continue for quite a long time in the future,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US does not officially recognise Taiwan as independent, but is opposed to any forcible change to the status quo and is legally committed to help the island defend itself.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump-appointed judge Aileen Cannon in a ‘tough position’ as she oversees his classified documents case]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224421/trump-appointed-judge-aileen-cannon-tough-position-she-oversees-his-classified-documents-case?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 11:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/e5b4f8e0-c3e7-441f-8062-9fde5d12b286_a16c7f7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;When Aileen Mercedes Cannon was appointed a judge by Donald Trump three years ago, she could hardly have imagined he would wind up as a defendant in her court.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Judge Cannon&#39;s assignment to preside over Trump&#39;s high-stakes trial has added another layer of controversy to the first ever federal-level criminal prosecution of a former US president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some legal experts have argued that Cannon should recuse herself because she has previously displayed bias towards Trump, who is accused of mishandling government secrets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others contend that Cannon, who was nominated to a lifetime appointment as a District Court judge by Trump in May 2020, will ensure that the former president gets a fair shake.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s impossible now for Trump to complain that he&#39;s got a judge that is biased against him,” said Edward Foley, a constitutional law professor at Ohio State University.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump&#39;s arraignment took 45 minutes, but path to trial may take a couple years&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Thomas Holbrook, a professor of political science at the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, said Cannon is in a “tough position.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Almost no matter what she does, she&#39;s going to either feed into existing concerns about her potential bias or disappoint Trump supporters,” Holbrook said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cannon was relatively young – 38 years old – when she was appointed to the bench by Trump.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was confirmed by the Senate in a 56-21 vote in November 2020, just days after Trump lost the presidential election to Democrat Joe Biden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cannon, now 42, was randomly chosen among the active judges for the Southern District of Florida to preside over the Trump case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Born in Cali, Colombia, Cannon grew up in Florida. Her mother immigrated to the United States from Cuba as a child.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cannon obtained her undergraduate degree at Duke University and her law degree from the University of Michigan, routinely ranked among the top 10 law schools in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A member of the conservative Federalist Society, Cannon worked for three years at a law firm in Washington and for seven years as an assistant US lawyer before becoming a judge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Daniel Richman, a law professor at Columbia University, said the presiding judge wields enormous power over a trial and plays a critical role in how it unfolds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even in a run of the mill case, the judge can have a significant and sometimes even dispositive effect on proceedings,” Richman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cannon will set the calendar for the trial, rule on what evidence is admissible, oversee jury selection and handle what is expected to be a barrage of pre-trial motions from Trump lawyers seeking to delay the proceedings, Richman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How much prison time could Donald Trump face?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The timing of the trial is key. If it is still ongoing and Trump wins the November 2024 presidential election he could conceivably pardon himself on taking office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Richman said it is unlikely the case will begin before next year&#39;s vote in part because it involves classified documents, raising complicated national security concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even at best, I think an experienced judge would be hard pressed to move this case before the election,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Andrew Weissmann, a former federal prosecutor, said Cannon should recuse herself from the case, but not because she was nominated by Trump.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are many judges appointed by Democrats and Republicans who do their job, and that includes judges who were appointed by Donald Trump,” he told MSNBC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cannon should step aside because of her prior involvement in the case, said Weissman, who was a member of special counsel Robert Mueller&#39;s team that investigated Russian interference in the 2016 presidential election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the FBI raided Trump&#39;s Mar-a-Lago residence in August 2022 to recover classified documents that the former president had refused to return, Cannon was assigned to hear a lawsuit filed by Trump challenging the seizure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She issued a number of rulings favourable to Trump that were reversed on appeal by the conservative 11th Circuit Court of Appeals in a severe rebuke.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the rulings was her contention that special deference should be shown to Trump because he was a former president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three-judge 11th Circuit panel, which included two Trump appointees, shot that down.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To create a special exception here would defy our Nation&#39;s foundational principle that our law applies &#39;to all, without regard to numbers, wealth, or rank,&#39;” the court said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook owner Meta Platforms wants preteens to step into virtual reality with its Quest headset]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224422/facebook-owner-meta-platforms-wants-preteens-step-virtual-reality-its-quest-headset?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 11:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/1b8aa867-15ce-44f6-acd6-0f6eebd1cb31_d8a4999e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The corporate parent of Facebook and Instagram plans to open a digital gateway for kids as young as 10 years old to enter virtual reality (VR) through the Meta Quest headset, despite rising concerns about children spending too much time on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta Platforms, which oversees a social media empire created by Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg, disclosed it will lower the minimum age for a Quest account from 13 years old to 10 years old in a Friday blog post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Menlo Park, California-based company framed the change coming later this year as a family-friendly way for more people to explore artificial realms that Zuckerberg touts as the metaverse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move to lure preteens into a virtual world filled with digital avatars and other technological fabrications comes just weeks after US Surgeon General Vivek Murthy called upon tech companies and lawmakers to take steps to protect children from the potentially harmful mental and emotional effects of too much exposure to social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both Facebook and Instagram for years have been under fire for using tactics that get kids hooked on social media at a young age, undercutting their real-life relationships with friends and families while exposing them to the risk of online bullying and abuse by sexual predators.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its blog post, Meta said that parents will retain control over their children&#39;s accounts for the Quest 2 and Quest 3 headsets and promised that preteen access will be limited to “age-appropriate” apps deploying VR.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Preteens will not be able to have a Quest account without explicit approval from their parents and all apps used on the platform will require parental consent, too, according to the company, which is recommending the younger age group be limited to a two-hour daily time limit on the headset.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other safeguards will include setting all preteen accounts to a private setting by default and a pledge not to show them any ads that generate most of Meta&#39;s revenue.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Meta unveils Quest 3 mixed reality headset ahead of Apple&#39;s VR debut&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re building this with our Responsible Innovation Principles and our commitment to building safe, positive experiences for young people at the forefront,” Meta wrote in the blog post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company is also providing parents with extensive guidance when assessing whether they should allow a 10- to -12-year-old to use a VR headset.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One section of the guide cites “a growing body of research examining the positive effects of VR in medical/clinical contexts, including interventions to support the development of social competence skills, to distract from painful or anxiety-inducing medical procedures, and to support specific skill development in specialised populations”, such as children with cerebral palsy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By expanding the potential audience for the Quest, Zuckerberg appears to be taking another significant step toward his goal of sculpting the metaverse into a sphere that eventually will be as popular as Facebook and Instagram have become since he started the company in a college dorm room nearly 20 years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s the future of computing&#39;: we try Apple&#39;s US$3,499 Vision Pro headset&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The metaverse so far has mostly been a digital ghost town, even though millions of Quest headsets have been sold. The Meta division that oversees the Quest headset and metaverse lost US$13.7 billion last year while bringing in US$2.2 billion in revenue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta is also facing formidable new competition from Apple, which last week unveiled its Vision Pro headset that is capable of thrusting users into virtual settings, too. The high-end headset, priced at US$3,499, received enthusiastic responses in carefully staged demos, but it will not be in stores until some time early next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta already has announced the next Quest headset will cost US$500 as a way to get more people to buy it before the Vision Pro is released.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Old lady hitchhiker: Chinese woman, 79, stops car on road for ride to former home shared with late husband, warming hearts online]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/social-welfare/article/3224080/old-lady-hitchhiker-chinese-woman-79-stops-car-road-ride-former-home-shared-late-husband-warming?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/15/6b98d8ad-609f-480e-ab7a-ffda56ef2896_e77084e8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A 79-year-old woman in China who hitchhiked to the home she previously shared with her late husband has touched hearts on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bailu Video reported that the unidentified woman from Jiangsu province in eastern China left her current residence and hailed a car whose driver agreed to take her to the home she used to share with her husband before his death five months ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A video posted online with the story showed the woman walking towards the car while it is stopped at a red traffic light before she tapped on the window and talked with the driver.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The driver, a man surnamed Zhu, said that the elderly woman asked him if he could give her a ride and told him she could not get a taxi or ride-hailing car.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu agreed and asked her where she wanted to go.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I want to go to my old family home,” the woman told Zhu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu then realised he knew of the woman and remembered she had lived at the address she gave for many years with her husband before his death.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following his death, she had moved out and had not returned to their former home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu said when he drove past the woman, he thought her behaviour was strange and looked back in concern to see if she needed help.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“She tapped my car windows one by one,” Zhu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu was worried she might need help but hesitated for a moment, fearing it might be a scam. Then he remembered his in-car camera for recording traffic incidents and, feeling reassured, decided to help.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I can&#39;t give up on doing good just because I&#39;m scared,” Zhu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After driving a few kilometres, they arrived at the woman&#39;s former home. When she exited the car, she gave Zhu a slice of watermelon in gratitude and said goodbye.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu gave her his phone number and told her that she could call him whenever she wanted to go to visit her old home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story has trended on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “It&#39;s a heart-rending story, but also heartwarming.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person commented: “The woman must miss her late husband very much.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese diplomat’s anti-LGBT tweet causes stir in Japan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3224418/chinese-diplomats-anti-lgbt-tweet-causes-stir-japan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 10:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/ebaf81e7-757e-411d-aa9b-da11c2f21c03_937eba4f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A tweet by Chinese consul general in Osaka Xue Jian earlier this week in which he described transgender people as being “deformed” has stirred controversy, with some commenting the post is discriminatory against sexual minorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xue tweeted in Japanese on Wednesday, “I don&#39;t mean to discriminate against sexual minorities, but tampering with gender is a deformity, not the evolution of human civilisation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The consul general also said “the absolute minority is effectively forcing us – the absolute majority” and claimed it goes against the basics of majority-rules democracy that the West has long advocated.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;7 years after Japanese student&#39;s death, has anything changed for LGBT community?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China has cracked down on sexual minorities in recent years, viewing support for the LGBT community as part of Western values and apparently fearing that their movement could challenge Communist Party rule.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Beijing LGBT Centre, an advocacy group for sexual minorities, was shut down in May “due to uncontrollable pressure” amid stricter control by the government of Chinese President Xi Jinping.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Tokyo, Japanese Chief Cabinet Secretary Hirokazu Matsuno declined at a press conference on Thursday to comment on Xue&#39;s tweet, but said the government will work toward realising a society where diversity is respected and people value each other&#39;s human rights and dignity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xue&#39;s social media post came as Japan on Friday passed a much-contested bill to promote understanding of the LGBT community amid criticism that the legislation provides no human rights guarantees and may tacitly encourage some forms of discrimination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan, the only Group of Seven (G7) nation with no legal protection for same-sex unions, had originally pledged to pass the law before hosting the G7 leaders&#39; summit from May 19 to 21.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, wrangling over the bill and its wording meant it was only submitted to parliament for consideration the day before the summit began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It passed the more powerful lower house on Tuesday even after some lawmakers in the ruling Liberal Democratic Party broke rank with party directives and either were absent altogether or left while the voting took place.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will the rest of Asia follow Hong Kong&#39;s lead on transgender rights?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The initial draft stipulated that discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity should “not be tolerated” but was changed to “there should be no unfair discrimination”, wording critics say tacitly allows bigotry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Though the original bill was not especially meaningful, I thought it was better than nothing,” said Takeharu Kato, a lawyer and member of “Marriage for all Japan,” an activist group, before the bill&#39;s passage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But now I&#39;ve begun to think it might be better to have nothing at all.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Opinion polls show a vast majority of Japanese approve of same-sex marriage. Roughly 70 per cent of the country now allows same-sex partnership agreements, although the partnership rights fall short of those guaranteed by marriage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>