<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Australian police charge man over bomb threat on Malaysia Airlines flight]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3231092/australian-police-charge-man-over-bomb-threat-malaysia-airlines-flight?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 07:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/4a74d3c3-06d1-4b49-b9a9-b2597d255583_8a592d72.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚警方周二指控一名男子，据称该男子声称船上装有爆炸物马来西亚航空公司从悉尼飞往吉隆坡的航班，迫使其返回悉尼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名 45 岁的男子被指控对威胁损坏飞机做出虚假陈述以及不遵守机组人员的安全指示”，澳大利亚联邦警察在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些罪行最高可判处 10 年监禁和超过 15,000 澳元（9,730 美元）的罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我会炸毁飞机：在从悉尼起飞的马来西亚航空航班上受到炸弹威胁后被捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;MH122 航班于周一下午从悉尼飞往马来西亚，并在大约三个小时后返回悉尼，原因是该乘客“据称在飞行期间扰乱秩序”。警方称，飞机已起飞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一旦认为飞机安全，乘客和机组人员就从飞机上撤离，该男子被平安逮捕。预计他将于周二出庭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方没有具体说明该男子的国籍，但称他是堪培拉居民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;32 个国内航班被取消悉尼机场表示，该事件导致其他国内航班延误长达 90 分钟。没有国际航班取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.最好&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Top Chinese EV maker BYD opts out of deal to use Baidu’s autonomous driving technology, sources say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3231045/top-chinese-ev-maker-byd-opts-out-deal-use-baidus-autonomous-driving-technology-sources-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/8d0c8faa-5516-4e6e-86d6-fb4767cae9e5_be05c4b5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;比亚迪放弃了为其电动汽车配备百度自动驾驶技术的交易据两位知情人士透露，作为全球最大的电动汽车制造商，比亚迪正着眼于内部开发智能汽车软件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比亚迪最初同意在汽车领域使用百度的技术，包括导航和自动代客泊车。 2022 年 3 月，该交易被视为百度自动驾驶部门 Apollo 的重大举措，该部门成立于 2013 年，旨在追求完善自动驾驶，首席执行官李彦宏 (Robin Li Yanhong) 曾关注过这一领域，然后将注意力转向类似 ChatGPT 的聊天机器人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;百度在 2022 年 11 月发布的第三季度业绩中表示，中国最大的汽车制造商之一打算使用 Apollo 技术套件，并称此次合作是“自我需求日益增长的标志” -来自汽车制造商的驾驶解决方案”。随后被曝合作伙伴是比亚迪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次交易的取消对百度的自动驾驶雄心是一个巨大的打击，也反映出中国自动驾驶行业在全自动驾驶发展过程中面临的困境。到目前为止，事实证明这很困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;百度和比亚迪没有立即回复置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，百度已在 Apollo 上投资了数十亿元人民币，但仍将自动驾驶视为优先事项。一位不愿透露姓名的消息人士透露，该消息人士是一名员工，不愿透露姓名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位因问题敏感性而拒绝透露姓名的消息人士表示，比亚迪已“暂停”与百度的合作由于该汽车制造商认为自动驾驶技术在电动汽车大众市场上的短期前景并不乐观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，百度仍拥有中国自动驾驶公司中最大的机器人出租车车队。它已在中国几个主要城市的指定区域运营和测试了一百多辆机器人出租车。今年 3 月，该公司获得了北京市政府的许可，可以在亦庄工业区经营网约车服务，车内无需司机或安全操作员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管取得了这些成就，但业内人士和投资者表示，大型机器人出租车正在兴起由于技术的缺陷、监管限制和安全问题，运营和自动卡车距离实现盈利还很远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们长期以来一直看空机器人出租车，因为成本太高且无法降低，一位风投基金云启合伙人的投资者表示，由于无权接受媒体采访，该投资者拒绝透露姓名。他补充道：“高分辨率地图和法规的不断更新构成了大规模推广的障碍。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自动驾驶汽车除了激光雷达、传感器和摄像头之外，还使用高分辨率地图进行导航.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;再加上中国的经济困境和科技投资者对 ChatGPT 等新技术的兴趣快速变化，中国的自动驾驶行业已开始通过减少员工数量来削减成本，同时通过提高技术销售来维持生计。汽车制造商，一个竞争激烈的市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个很难进入的市场，[自动驾驶]公司需要相互激烈竞争，以获得汽车制造商的自动驾驶软件解决方案订单，”王乃彦说，自动卡车开发商图森未来中国的首席技术官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市场正处于大动荡的边缘，“许多公司将消失”，他补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war will force the West to accept the liberal order is gone for good]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230839/ukraine-war-will-force-west-accept-liberal-order-gone-good?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/0e55391f-fbda-42d5-89c8-9793508076bd_b4586136.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;乌克兰的冲突正在平息。尽管自战争开始以来，美国向乌克兰输送了超过 750 亿美元（占其国内生产总值的 0.33%），说服德国等盟国交出先进的装甲，并使俄罗斯遭受前所未有的经济制裁，但前线并没有几个月内发生了重大变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯军队击退了一波又一波的北约训练营。而且，随着燃烧的豹式坦克和布拉德利车辆的视频堆积如山，全球媒体正在开始应对叙事的下滑。这不是一件坏事。政治解决已经从幻想变成了必然。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一场类似的血腥宗派冲突，即三十年战争，使欧洲精疲力竭，于 1648 年接受了威斯特伐利亚条约。该条约导致了今天的概念民族国家。它改变了国际关系的架构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰的冲突也处于同样的关键时刻。全球南方正在获得经济和政治影响力，越来越多地加入世界超级大国的谈判桌。即将到来的解决方案有望带来与威斯特伐利亚条约同等规模的国际关系架构转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰战争影响了世界各国。从能源价格飙升到非洲迫在眉睫的饥荒威胁，全球体系已经远离战前现状，无法简单地回到战前状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但必须协调三个因素威斯特伐利亚2.0实现之前，即西方希望时光倒流、新仲裁者的崛起以及战争贩子和鹰派的疲惫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自2022年2月乌克兰冲突重燃以来，联合国各国及其盟友一直在向全球南方施压，要求其选边站队。大多数经济体的不结盟是对西方失去的基于规则的秩序的公民投票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自那以后，西方以外的国家很少加入反俄联盟。主要经济体更喜欢持续增长，而不是代表所谓基于规则的秩序的冲突。例如，印度尼西亚总统佐科维多多就多次表示，东南亚国家联盟不能成为任何一方的代理人。而且，正如印度外交部长苏杰生 (Subrahmanyam Jaishankar) 去年所说：“欧洲必须摆脱这样一种心态：欧洲的问题是世界的问题，但世界的问题不是欧洲的问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一事件的转变是不奇怪。通过提议任意没收主权财产、迫使环球金融电信协会 (Swift) 金融信息系统取消俄罗斯的国际支付渠道、怂恿对绘画进行小规模的重新命名或违反体育道德的行为，西方已经失去了对其他国家的信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;战前，西方凭借软实力、经济实力和军事力量占据主导地位。现在，它的软实力正被日益不自由的南方国家所忽视，它的经济实力还没有压垮已故美国参议员约翰·麦凯恩所说的“伪装成一个国家的加油站”，而受过北约训练的军队也只取得了一点点成果。反攻已经进行了几个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近在沙特阿拉伯举行的讨论乌克兰和平的会议说明了全球趋势，尽管会议结束时没有发表联合声明。峰会不再局限于瑞士和纽约等经典目的地。而且，一个重大转变是，美国正在寻求穿梭外交来说服各国加入其事业，而不是各国排队加入美国一边。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，新时代需要一个仲裁者。西方、俄罗斯和全球南方评论家一致认为——中国应该扮演这一角色。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是一位有吸引力的主席。首先，它是乌克兰冲突之外制定合理和平计划的一个大国。其次，与西方分裂的价值观不同，北京提供了具有文明多样性的经济发展，这与新兴国家产生了共鸣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，金砖四国（巴西、俄罗斯、印度、中国和南非）、上海合作组织和东盟也可能成为决定未来国际架构的节点。重要的是，这些都是共识驱动的，考虑到了俄罗斯和中国，并且没有强行命令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管全球正在远离西方，尽管华盛顿和伦敦相信他们可以通过击败来“获胜”俄罗斯的代理人——美国即将向乌克兰提供艾布拉姆斯坦克——乌克兰的战争将继续下去。俄罗斯没有理由退缩。前线稳定，俄罗斯经济今年也将实现增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在僵局中，似乎只有经济和军事上的疲惫才能结束流血。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么中国针对乌克兰冲突的务实和平计划可能也是最好的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;全球南方国家要求解决方案。非洲和平代表团最近不顾西方压力访问基辅和莫斯科就是一个明显的迹象。但是，尽管莫斯科正在接受这些提议，但乌克兰当局仍然不屑一顾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;历史学家将回顾过去并询问为什么所谓的基于规则的秩序会崩溃。答案可能是，从根本上来说，只有每个人都同意遵守规则，规则才算是规则。西方正在抛弃自由秩序，认为自己凌驾于规则之上，否认俄罗斯的安全担忧，将其军事力量交给代理人，并在绝望的情况下实施前所未有的经济制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这不是俄罗斯中国应该谈论缓和局势。全球南方应该对西方说：受够了，没有回头路了——但如果我们从这场血腥战争中继续前进，就会有很多值得期待的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hawaii’s governor warns that scores more people could be found dead following wildfires on Maui]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231091/hawaiis-governor-warns-scores-more-people-could-be-found-dead-following-wildfires-maui?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 07:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/28c70e85-8182-4917-ab1a-41f344deea66_a1b177af.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;夏威夷州长警告说，在毛伊岛野火搜索过程中，可能会发现更多人死亡工作人员穿过街区，火势以每分钟一英里的速度蔓延，消防员们奋力控制住火势，一些官员抱怨说，供水有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大火吞噬了这座历史名镇的大部分地区。拉海纳已经是美国一个多世纪以来死亡人数最多的一次，死亡人数至少为 96 人。原因正在调查中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们已经为许多悲惨故事做好了准备，”州长乔什·格林 (Josh Green) 告诉记者哥伦比亚广播公司早间节目周一播出了一段录音采访。 “他们每天可能会找到 10 到 20 个人，直到他们完成为止。而且可能需要 10 天。真的很难猜测。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着移动电话服务慢慢恢复，失踪人数从 2,000 多人下降到 1,300 人左右，格林说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;20 具尸体狗和数十名搜索者正在穿过化为灰烬的街区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在，他们正在一条又一条街、一个街区一个街区地穿行，很快他们就会开始进入建筑物， ” 夏威夷国防部公共事务主任杰夫·希克曼 (Jeff Hickman) 周一在 NBC 的《今日》节目中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，一些州官员表示，消防员可用的水短缺，他们将此归咎于环境法院法官最近做出的裁决。这是环保主义者和私营公司之间长期斗争的一部分，这场斗争始于夏威夷甘蔗种植园时期，长达数十年，从毛伊岛东部溪流引水。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;夏威夷火灾造成的死亡人数接近 100 人，加剧了对政府不作为的批评&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在其他地方，预计撤离人员将于周一晚上开始入住酒店。格林周日表示，正在为流离失所的当地人提供 500 间酒店房间，另外还将为联邦紧急事务管理署 (FEMA) 帮助灾后恢复的工作人员预留 500 间房间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，FEMA 行政长官 Deanne Criswell 周一表示，该机构已开始向流离失所的居民提供 700 美元，用于支付食品、水、急救和医疗用品的费用。这笔钱是在居民有资格获得的用于弥补房屋和个人财产损失的金额之外的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不会放弃任何事情，而且我们将非常有创意地如何解决这一问题。我们利用我们的权力来帮助建立社区并帮助人们找到长期居住的地方，”克里斯韦尔说。据 FEMA 称，已有 3,000 多人登记寻求联邦帮助，而且这一数字预计还会增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在供水问题上，美国消防局副局长托尼娅·胡佛 (Tonya Hoover) 表示，她没有关于岛上目前供水的详细信息。她说，她的机构负责人一直在与消防员会面，其中包括一名受重伤并住院治疗的消防员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登政府正在为政府救灾基金寻求额外 120 亿美元的资金，作为其补充资金的一部分向国会提出请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约一周前，大火席卷了有着数百年历史的拉海纳，摧毁了这座拥有 13,000 人的小镇的几乎所有建筑。据该县称，火灾已得到 85% 的控制。官员们表示，另一场被称为内陆大火的大火已得到 60% 的控制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格林在周日更新的视频中谈到拉海纳时表示，“已经所剩无几”，并补充说“估计价值56 亿美元已经消失。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使火势已经消退，当局也警告说，在火焰喷出有毒烟雾后，有毒副产品可能仍然存在，包括饮用水中。许多人根本无家可归。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;夏威夷野火死亡人数攀升至 80 人，引发愤怒；居民面临灾难&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;红十字会表示，周一，575 名疏散人员分布在五个避难所，其中包括怀卢库的战争纪念体育馆。访客中包括奥普拉·温弗瑞 (Oprah Winfrey)，她告诉《夏威夷新闻》(Hawaii News Now)，最近几天她已经送去了个人卫生用品、毛巾和水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毛伊岛兼职居民奥普拉·温弗瑞 (Winfrey) 警告说，新闻工作人员最终将离开远离毁灭，世界将会继续前进。但她说，“我们仍然会在这里试图找出重建的最佳方式……我将长期留在这里，尽我所能。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为消防员在与大火作斗争的过程中，上周因用水问题向法院提起了一系列诉讼。周三早上，法官杰弗里·克拉布特里 (Jeffrey Crabtree) 发布命令，暂时中止他实施的水上限 48 小时。他还根据毛伊岛消防官员、县或州的要求授权供水，直至无法联系到法官时另行通知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这对于州总检察长办公室的律师来说还不够，该公司后来向州最高法院提交请愿书，指责克拉布特里缺乏消防用水。该州要求最高法院不要让克拉布特里改变要转移的水量或暂停他的限制，直到请愿书得到解决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官“用他的判决代替了该机构的判决”请愿书说，指的是土地和自然资源委员会。 “因此，没有足够的许可用水来扑灭野火。”塞拉俱乐部执行董事韦恩·田中 (Wayne Tanaka) 周一表示，总检察长办公室夸大了调水上限对山火的影响。消防。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是对这场可怕悲剧的无耻利用，”他说。 “毛伊岛中部水库对毛伊岛西部没有任何用处，那里的大部分破坏仍在继续。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，他担心该州愿意不遗余力地利用这场悲剧来帮助私人公司垄断了水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前甘蔗种植园土地所有者亚历山大和鲍德温以及东毛伊灌溉公司的代表没有立即回复寻求评论的电子邮件，总检察长办公室也没有立即回复。土地和自然资源委员会的发言人表示，他们不会对未决诉讼发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在干燥的夏季和经过的飓风带来的强风的推动下，毛伊岛的火焰在干燥的灌木丛中蔓延。格林表示，一场大火每分钟移动速度可达一英里（1.6 公里）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这种风和 1,000 度的高温下，最终您将看到的所有图片都将很容易被捕捉到。”明白，”州长说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Montana judge hands historic win to young plaintiffs in climate change case]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231090/montana-judge-hands-historic-win-young-plaintiffs-climate-change-case?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 06:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/53b3a408-9de2-4816-bf0d-f0957bb7487e_4cf7e0b6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;蒙大拿州禁止国家考虑气候问题的政策侵犯了年轻人的权利一名州法官周一表示，在审查煤炭开采、天然气开采和其他化石燃料项目时，会发生变化影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海伦娜法官凯西·西利 (Kathy Seeley) 的决定标志着第一个青年主导的气候变化的重大胜利此案将在美国进行审判，并可能影响全国范围内的类似案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西利在裁决中表示，蒙大拿州的温室气体排放已被证明是对蒙大拿州环境造成气候影响的“一个重要因素”，损害了年轻的原告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西利说，原告拥有“获得清洁和健康环境的基本宪法权利”。她说，禁止国家机构在批准化石燃料项目时考虑气候和排放影响的政策是违宪的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在六月的一次审判中，年轻人辩称，尽管蒙大拿州人口稀少，但其所占份额却很大全球排放量。该州是煤炭、石油和天然气的主要生产地，这些煤炭、石油和天然气被运往其他地方，也是运输这些燃料所需的管道和其他基础设施的所在地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几位年轻的原告在审判期间出庭作证。并详细说明了气候变化如何影响他们的生活。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主要原告 Rikki Held，22 岁，作证说，干旱导致她家位于蒙大拿州东部的牧场上出现“瘦牛和死牛”，而野火则导致火山灰从农场落下。天空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该州辩称气候政策不应该由法院制定，原告也没有证明全球危机可以归因于蒙大拿州相对较小的排放量。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国主要科技团体支持 TikTok 挑战蒙大拿州禁令&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;蒙大拿州总检察长办公室发言人周一称该裁决“荒谬”，西利是一位“竭尽全力让案件继续推进的意识形态法官” ”。发言人表示，该州计划上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;代表年轻人的我们儿童信托基金会的律师朱莉娅·奥尔森 (Julia Olson) 称这一决定是“蒙大拿州的巨大胜利”，并表示可能会做出类似的决定哥伦比亚法学院萨宾气候变化法中心主任迈克尔·杰拉德 (Michael Gerrard) 表示，西利的研究结果（包括气候变化对健康和环境构成严重威胁）可能“成为一种灵感”在具有类似宪法条款的州提起诉讼，并使被告更难摆脱对气候问题的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是“任何法院就气候变化做出的最强有力的裁决，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说。 >;&lt;p>;该案件是美国青年主导的几起气候案件之一。夏威夷年轻人起诉该州交通部的案件预计将于明年开庭审理，这将是该国第二起此类案件。一起针对美国政府的案件在 2020 年被美国第九巡回上诉法院驳回后，于 6 月重新启动。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 07:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The moment of reckoning looms large for China’s property market as crisis deepens]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230992/moment-reckoning-looms-large-chinas-property-market-crisis-deepens?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/09b5c1be-a7f7-4507-bdfe-324b66e8de83_f196d774.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;第四季度中国房地产市场的“金融化”和“货币化”一个世纪可能是历史上最非凡的财富创造故事之一。但有迹象表明，这场盛会即将结束，对于房地产开发商、房主和政府来说，清算的时刻即将到来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要了解困扰中国房地产行业的危机，值得一看进入它的过去。新中国成立前50年，中国并没有房地产市场，城市居民依靠国家雇主提供住房。没有私人开发商，因为根据宪法，所有城市土地都“归国家所有”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的房地产行业在 20 世纪 80 年代末开始腾飞，当时香港专业人士为深圳的中国大陆官员提供建议和上海，他们借用了当时英国殖民地的一页，将“土地使用权”出售给投资者，作为长期租赁的一部分。中国各市政府立即接受了这个想法，认为这是筹集急需资金的绝佳来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国于 1998 年正式启动全国房地产市场，当时城市家庭被允许购买和拥有住房，由于国家快速的城市化进程，房地产市场迎来了惊人的繁荣。数亿人搬进了新公寓，房地产迅速成为中国经济增长最重要的引擎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国市政当局在一夜之间意识到自己坐拥大量房产，成为了这一过程中的大赢家。财富。 “国有”土地突然变得可以卖，各个地方政府都纷纷跟风。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一开始就形成了一个良性循环：地方政府卖的土地越多，筹集的资金就越多。其自身发展，又可用于改善基础设施，进一步推高地价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在很短的时间内，中国的城市面貌发生了永久性的改变。在一些极端情况下，市政府将整个旧社区夷为平地，建设新社区，使土地“货币化”成为此类城市化项目的根本原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国城市家庭也从席卷景观的变化中受益。随着房价的急剧上涨，家庭财富不断增加，那些已经拥有城市公寓的人，无论是继承的还是国家分配的，都获得了意外之财。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国顶级开发商在等待缓解痛苦的措施时，销售呈螺旋式上升。 &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年的一项调查显示，房地产占中国“家庭财富”的70%以上。在北京、上海和深圳等中国顶级城市，拥有一套公寓的业主，无论多么破旧，至少在纸面上都是千万富翁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;房地产繁荣也支撑了中国经济的金融化。银行业蓬勃发展，房地产金融产品如雨后春笋般涌现。值得注意的是，中国许多地方政府金融工具的债券最终都是由房地产价值作为支撑的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;简单地说房地产占中国国内生产总值的30%是一种低估。在某种程度上，土地金融的复杂性是推动中国经济奇迹的核心。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;降低中国的抵押贷款利率会减轻家庭负担，释放消费能力吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;然而，繁荣是脆弱的，因为它只能靠不断上涨的房价来维持。当需求——包括改善住房条件的“实际需求”或资产升值预期的投资——枯竭时，价格将开始下跌，整个经济结构将开始崩溃。北京多年前就意识到了这一点，当时它警告房价“不能涨到天上”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国房地产市场繁荣带来的一个大问题是，它使过度借贷成为可能，而所有参与者，包括地方政府、开发商和家庭在内的债务以惊人的速度积累。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于许多地方政府来说，他们在技术上已经破产。对于家庭来说，随着经济放缓并进入通缩区间，偿债压力将变得更大。对于开发商来说，即使是最大的开发商，由于债务的原因，生存也将是一场斗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国或许可以避免房地产市场崩盘，但该行业不再是曾经推动其经济的引擎.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 07:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong police’s outgoing deputy chief urges officers to treat residents ‘like family’ but remain wary of national security threats, signs of ‘soft resistance’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3231055/hong-kong-polices-outgoing-deputy-chief-urges-officers-treat-residents-family-remain-wary-national?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/21c9c6d9-d37a-4a08-a141-a2ceb38b078e_474af469.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;即将离任的香港警务处副处长呼吁警员像对待有需要的人一样家人希望赢得民心，但警告他们要警惕国家安全威胁并应对“软抵抗”的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行动事务副专员袁玉坚 (Albert Yuen Yuk-kin)将于周二退休，希望警员在执行职务时能跳出思维定势，表现出同理心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他强调，真诚解决香港人的问题是改善警队与市民关系的关键&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法学教授表示香港不应采取强硬“软抵抗”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“在处理求助时，如果我们的同事能够富有同情心，设身处地为居民着想”鞋，也许像对待寻求帮助的家人一样对待他们，[那么]……我从心底里相信，这将使部队与公众的关系更加有效，”袁说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;57-岁还为自2019年社会动荡以来警方对示威活动采取的严格审批程序进行了辩护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他强调，只要尊重他人的权利，公众仍然享有言论自由和自由集会自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;对于反对声音，我完全理解，香港居民享有言论和集会自由。然而，任何软抵抗的迹象都会出现转折点。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袁补充说，警方将留意是否有危害国家安全的意图，以及煽动他人的行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他于 1986 年中学毕业并完成香港高级程度考试后加入警察，担任督察，而他的大多数同龄人都完成了大学课程。随后，他在警队工作了 37 年，主要从事刑事调查和情报收集。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袁说，他的职业生涯跨越了三十年的犯罪生涯，包括 20 世纪 80 年代的枪战到现代网络犯罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袁说，他的职业生涯跨越了三十年的犯罪生涯。 p>;&lt;p>;他表示，2019 年因反对后来搁置的引渡法案而发生的大规模骚乱对于警方来说是一个分水岭，并将其优先事项转向维护国家安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很明显“我们非常关注国家安全和社会安全状况。” 。我们在这件事上绝对不会放松。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;保安局发言人上个月表示，媒体、艺术、文化甚至谣言都可能构成软性抵抗，可能被用来煽动对当局和法律的仇恨&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国安警察拘捕10名与资助示威者有关的法律资金&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府镇压抗争并不是试图控制人们的思想，而是没有任何余地发言人表示，这是对国家安全的妥协。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但香港大学法学教授、前《基本法》委员会委员陈宏义警告当局不要利用该法律来遏制“软抵抗”。上个月在外国记者俱乐部举行的一次小组讨论中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈解释说，他的评论与法律原则有关，即不应仅仅因为当局反对而适用刑法来监管人们的言论或思想。他在活动中告诉《华盛顿邮报》，政府可以考虑将课堂教育和文化活动作为替代方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及自那时以来警方罕见批准公众抗议活动时，袁坚称人们仍然拥有言论和集会自由。 2019年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在大流行的社交距离限制的三年里，警方没有批准任何抗议活动。由于当地居民反对填海计划，该部队批准了三月份在将军澳举行示威的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但警方制定了前所未有的规定，要求集会参与者佩戴编号挂绳，在警戒线内不戴口罩游行。并将抗议人数控制在 100 人以下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们当然会利用现有机制考虑[抗议投标]，但我们也会考虑最近的法院判决来确定抗议的性质。 The route, number of participants and track records of the organiser are factors we take into account when processing bids,” Yuen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing backs police after force athletes targeted for abuse at Canadian games&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The veteran police officer said people who exercised freedom of assembly must not harm the rights of others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuen also reassured the public that the force was dedicated to public safety after a spate of violent crimes in recent months, including a double murder at Plaza Hollywood shopping centre in Diamond Hill that shook the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Relevant information has been spread widely across social media, sparking concerns. We understand. That&#39;s why we have done a lot of work to solve cases and, as you&#39;ve seen, most cases were solved in a short period of time,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong national security police question parents of wanted activist Anna Kwok&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Police statistics show the number of violent crimes dropped by 8.8 per cent from 2019 to 2022, as the tally fell from 9,690 to 8,830.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuen also revealed that marine police officers had been called on to help boost the number of street patrols.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuen said he had no regrets, just a sense of pride at having served during turbulent times.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I already feel honoured about my role in helping the police force and having a purpose during such a tempestuous time.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 07:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Genius’ biochemist Kunliang Guan returns to China from US to head new lab]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3231022/genius-biochemist-kunliang-guan-returns-china-us-head-new-lab?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 06:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/14/4c156f56-8347-4e17-9ad3-dbffa5727ccf_848cab05.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After working in the United States for more than 30 years, biochemist Kunliang Guan is back in China with a full-time chair professor position at Westlake University in the eastern province of Zhejiang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As one of the most cited researchers in his field and a recipient of a MacArthur “genius” award, among other prizes, Guan will head a new laboratory to continue his world-leading research on cell signalling pathways related to organ development and cancer, according to the university&#39;s website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Previously, he was a distinguished professor at University of California, San Diego&#39;s pharmacology department – and a target of investigations backed by the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the world&#39;s biggest funder of biomedical research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, Guan was banned from applying for NIH funding for two years after he was found to have violated the university&#39;s code of conduct by failing to disclose research support from foreign sources, including Fudan University in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By the time the suspension ended in 2021, the operations of Guan&#39;s lab had shrunk dramatically and he had stopped taking on new graduate students for fear that he would not be able to support them, he told Science magazine in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m one of the lucky ones. I don&#39;t know how many people that the NIH wanted to stop are able to start again. Maybe none,” Guan was quoted as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guan is among some 250 victims of the NIH&#39;s own version of the China Initiative – a Trump-era policy aimed at combating Chinese espionage – which accused the researchers of using part of their NIH grant to do work in China through an undisclosed affiliation with a Chinese institution.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unlike the China Initiative, all investigations were done behind closed doors by NIH-funded institutions and off-limits to queries from the media, according to Science. About 42 per cent of those targeted have so far lost their jobs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of those is Guan&#39;s former colleague, neuroscientist Fu Xiangdong, who was forced to resign from UCSD earlier this year due to his collaboration with Wuhan University. Fu joined Westlake University in March to carry on with his research on Parkinson&#39;s and other degenerative diseases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guan has started recruiting members for his new team in Hangzhou, and their work will focus on the Hippo pathway, a major signalling pathway in the human body that regulates cell growth, tissue stability, organ size, and is responsible for cancer development, according to the university&#39;s website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rao Yi, a neurobiologist and president of Capital Medical University in Beijing, described Guan as “a clearly marked genius”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Kunliang is an outstanding biochemist who had made major contributions to signal transduction,” Rao said. “His next breakthroughs will be even better than all previous ones.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The message in the US funding cut for China&#39;s Wuhan Institute of Virology&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Guan was born into a poor family in Tongxiang county, Zhejiang province, in 1963. A talented and hardworking student, he entered Hangzhou University to study biology at the age of 15.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1983, he was recruited through the China-United States Biochemistry Examination and Application programme to study in the US. He earned his doctorate in biochemistry from Purdue University at the age of 26.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He went on to work at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor and UCSD, receiving a series of awards and honours, including the MacArthur Fellowship and the Schering-Plough Award.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has been actively involved in scientific evaluation activities in China. He served as chair of the overseas review committee of the National Natural Science Foundation of China, and is a science committee member of the Beijing-based Future Science Prize.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 06:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China opposes UN Security Council meeting on North Korea rights]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231089/china-opposes-un-security-council-meeting-north-korea-rights?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 05:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/b2667068-0233-462b-8ad0-37b79b7a3277_7cf1b552.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China opposes a planned United Nations Security Council meeting on human rights abuses in North Korea because it will only “intensify confrontation and antagonism,” a spokesperson for China&#39;s UN mission in New York said on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United States, Albania and Japan requested the meeting, which will be held on Thursday. It will be the first formal public meeting of the 15-member council on the issue since 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;North backs Russia&#39;s &#39;battle for justice&#39; as Kim shows off missiles to minister&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“China sees no added value for the council to have such a meeting and will be against it,” said China&#39;s UN mission representative, adding that the council&#39;s mandate was “maintenance of international peace and security, not human rights.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A council meeting on human rights in the DPRK falls outside the council&#39;s mandate, politicises human rights issues, and only serves to intensify confrontation and antagonism,” said the spokesperson, referring to the country&#39;s formal name - the Democratic People&#39;s Republic of Korea (DPRK).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;North Korean leader Kim Jong-un called for an increase in missile production to help secure “overwhelming military power” and be ready for war, state media KCNA said on Monday, as South Korea and the United States gear up for annual military drills.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was not immediately clear if China would call a procedural vote on Thursday to try to block the Security Council meeting on rights abuses, but a senior US official has said they were confident they have the minimum nine votes needed to move ahead. Vetoes do not apply on procedural issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China to G7, EU: we &#39;strictly&#39; implement UN sanctions on North Korea&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;North Korea has repeatedly rejected accusations of abuses and blames sanctions for a dire humanitarian situation. Since 2006 it has been under UN sanctions over its ballistic missiles and nuclear programmes, but there are aid exemptions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, the United States accused China of attempting to hide North Korea&#39;s atrocities from the world by blocking the webcast of an informal meeting of Security Council members on accusations of human rights abuses by Pyongyang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The council has held annual formal meetings on the issue for the past three years, but behind closed doors. Between 2014 and 2017 the council held annual public meetings on human rights abuses in North Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A landmark 2014 UN report on North Korean human rights concluded that North Korean security chiefs - and possibly leader Kim himself - should face justice for overseeing a state-controlled system of Nazi-style atrocities. The United States sanctioned Kim in 2016 for human rights abuses.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Judge in Trump’s hush-money case denies bias claim, will not step aside]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231085/judge-trumps-hush-money-case-denies-bias-claim-will-not-step-aside?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 03:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/4ee65668-63e7-4756-b109-9b8e288e8396_fba8a313.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The judge in Donald Trump&#39;s Manhattan hush-money criminal case has rejected the former US president&#39;s demand to step aside, denying defence claims that he is biased against the Republican front-runner because he has given cash to Democrats and his daughter is a party consultant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New York Judge Juan Manuel Merchan acknowledged in a ruling late on Friday that he made several small donations to Democratic causes during the 2020 campaign, including to Trump&#39;s Democratic rival President Joe Biden, but said he is certain of his “ability to be fair and impartial.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Removing himself from the case “would not be in the public interest,” Merchan wrote. His six-page ruling echoed a state court ethics panel&#39;s recent opinion that endorsed his continued involvement in the Trump case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision on recusal was entirely up to Merchan. He previously rejected a similar request when Trump&#39;s company, the Trump Organization, was on trial last year for tax fraud.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump lawyer Susan Necheles declined to comment. The Manhattan district attorney&#39;s office, which is prosecuting the case and said in court papers that it wanted Merchan to remain on the case, also declined to comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s hush-money trial – one of three pending criminal cases against him – is expected to start on March 25, overlapping with the presidential primary season as he seeks a return to the White House. A federal judge last month denied Trump&#39;s request to move the case out of Merchan&#39;s state courtroom and into federal court. Trump is appealing the ruling that he failed to meet a high legal bar for changing jurisdiction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump pleaded not guilty in April in Manhattan to 34 felony counts of falsifying business records. The charges relate to hush-money payments made during the 2016 campaign to bury allegations that he had extramarital sexual encounters. He has denied wrongdoing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Court website briefly publishes, removes document about potential Trump charges&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Separately, Trump is also charged in federal court in Florida with illegally hoarding classified documents at his Mar-a-Lago estate and impeding investigators and in federal court in Washington, in connection to efforts to overturn the results of his 2020 election loss in the run-up to the violent riot by his supporters at the US Capitol.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s lawyers wanted Merchan off the case in part because his daughter, Loren, is a political consultant whose firm has worked for some of Trump&#39;s Democratic rivals and because, they contend, he acted inappropriately by involving himself in plea negotiations last year for Trump&#39;s long-time finance chief, Allen Weisselberg. Merchan said he previously rejected that argument when asked to exit the Trump Organization case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s lawyers also raised concerns about the political donations, asking Merchan to explain three contributions totalling US$35 that were made to Democratic causes in his name during the 2020 election cycle. Merchan, in his ruling, said the “donations at issue are self-evident and require no further clarification” and pointed to the ethics panel&#39;s conclusion that such small-dollar contributions would not require recusal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These modest political contributions made more than two years ago cannot reasonably create an impression of bias or favouritism in the case before the judge,” the panel wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Merchan, a state court judge in New York, sought input from the Advisory Committee on Judicial Ethics after Trump&#39;s April 4 arraignment, as news outlets started reporting on his political contributions and Trump – pointing to the daughter&#39;s work – complained that he is “a Trump-hating judge” with a family full of “Trump haters”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ethics panel, in its May 4 opinion, concluded that a judge in Merchan&#39;s situation “may continue to preside in the matter provided the judge believes he/she can be fair and impartial.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s lawyers sought Merchan&#39;s recusal on May 31, arguing in court papers that the hush-money case is “historic and it is important that the People of the State of New York and this nation have confidence that the jurist who presides over it is impartial.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Matthew Colangelo, a senior counsel to Manhattan District Attorney Alvin Bragg, countered that Trump&#39;s recusal motion was the latest in a “prolific history of baselessly accusing state and federal judges around the country of bias.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Merchan&#39;s daughter, Loren, is a political consultant whose firm has worked on campaigns for prominent Democrats including Biden, Vice-President Kamala Harris, House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries and California Governor Gavin Newsom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Merchan, citing the ethics panel&#39;s finding that his daughter&#39;s work had no bearing on his impartiality, said in his ruling that Trump&#39;s lawyers had “failed to demonstrate that there exists concrete, or even realistic reasons for recusal to be appropriate, much less required on these grounds.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden administration urges universities to pursue racial diversity without affirmative action]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231087/biden-administration-urges-universities-pursue-racial-diversity-without-affirmative-action?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 04:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/7fbe96a6-49fa-40fd-b496-3b1061a87578_924c1338.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;New guidance from the Biden administration on Monday urges colleges to use a range of strategies to promote racial diversity on campus after the Supreme Court struck down affirmative action in admissions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Colleges can focus their recruiting in high minority areas, for example, and take steps to retain students of colour who are already on campus, including by offering affinity clubs geared toward students of a certain race. Colleges can also consider how an applicant&#39;s race has shaped personal experience, as detailed in students&#39; application essays or letters of recommendation, according to the new guidance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also encourages them to consider ending policies known to stint racial diversity, including preferences for legacy students and the children of donors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ensuring access to higher education for students from different backgrounds is one of the most powerful tools we have to prepare graduates to lead an increasingly diverse nation and make real our country&#39;s promise of opportunity for all,” Attorney General Merrick Garland said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The guidance, from the Justice and Education departments, arrives as universities across the nation attempt to navigate a new era of admissions without the use of affirmative action. Schools are working to promote racial diversity without provoking legal action from affirmative action opponents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Students for Fair Admission, the group that brought the issue to the Supreme Court through lawsuits against Harvard and the University of North Carolina, sent a letter to 150 universities in July saying they must “take immediate steps to eliminate the use of race as a factor in admissions.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US Supreme Court guts use of race as a determinant in college admissions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In its guidance, the Biden administration offers a range of policies colleges can use “to achieve a student body that is diverse across a range of factors, including race and ethnicity.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also offers clarity on how colleges can consider race in the context of an applicant&#39;s individual experience. The court&#39;s decision bars colleges from considering race as a factor in and of itself, but nothing prohibits colleges from considering “an applicant&#39;s discussion of how race affected the applicant&#39;s life,” the court wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How to approach that line without crossing it has been a challenge for colleges as they rework admissions systems before a new wave of applications begin arriving in the autumn.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The guidance offers examples of how colleges can “provide opportunities to assess how applicants&#39; individual backgrounds and attributes – including those related to their race.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A university could consider an applicant&#39;s explanation about what it means to him to be the first Black violinist in his city&#39;s youth orchestra or an applicant&#39;s account of overcoming prejudice when she transferred to a rural high school where she was the only student of South Asian descent,” according to the guidance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Schools can also consider a letter of recommendation describing how a student “conquered her feelings of isolation as a Latina student at an overwhelmingly white high school to join the debate team,” it says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Students should feel comfortable to share “their whole selves” in the application process, the administration said. Previously, many students had expressed confusion about whether the court&#39;s decision blocked them from discussing their race in essays and interviews.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The administration clarified that colleges do not need to ignore race as they choose where to focus their recruiting efforts. The court&#39;s decision does not forbid schools from targeting recruiting efforts toward schools that predominately serve students of colour or low-income students, it says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Countering a directive from Students for Fair Admissions, the new guidance says colleges can legally collect data about the race of students and applicants, as long as it does not influence admissions decisions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Asian-Americans split as US court ruling on race-based college admissions looms&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Echoing previous comments from US President Joe Biden, the guidance urges colleges to rethink policies that tend to favour white, wealthy applicants. “Nothing in the decision prevents an institution from determining whether preferences for legacy students or children of donors, for example, run counter to efforts to promote equal opportunities for all students,” the guidance said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, the Justice and Education departments warned that they are ready to investigate if schools fail to provide equal access to students of all races, adding that the administration “will vigorously enforce civil rights protections.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The guidance arrives as colleges work to avoid the type of diversity decline that has been seen in some states that previously ended affirmative action, including in California and Michigan. Selective colleges in those states saw sharp decreases in minority student enrolment, and some have struggled for decades to recover.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>