<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk in China: Tesla CEO leaves for Texas after meeting Shanghai Communist Party boss as visit yields nothing concrete]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3222596/elon-musk-china-tesla-ceo-leaves-texas-after-meeting-shanghai-communist-party-boss-visit-yields?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 17:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/dd053f71-116e-488f-8cf1-236ceca0e658_c2927be0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;特斯拉首席执行官埃隆马斯克周四上午在与上海共产党会面后离开上海前往德克萨斯老板陈吉宁在北京与西方关系恶化的情况下结束了对中国为期三天的访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在这次访问中没有签署具体的交易或协议，尽管对特斯拉计划扩大其业务的猜测越来越多上海超级工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据两位了解他在上海的行程的消息人士透露，马斯克在上午 11 点 23 分乘坐私人飞机从虹桥国际机场离开之前与陈会面。该航班飞往该汽车制造商总部得克萨斯州奥斯汀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克与陈的谈话细节尚未披露，但当地政府官员的一位消息人士告诉《华盛顿邮报》，上海官员已确定&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京逗留两天后，马斯克于周三晚上抵达上海，会见了外交部长秦刚、商务部部长王文涛和工信部部长金壮龙。这是马斯克自 2020 年初来到中国见证首批上海制造的 Model 3 汽车在 3 号超级工厂交付给客户以来的首次访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秦告诉这位美国企业家，中国将创造“前所未有的根据外交部的一份声明，在现代化建设和实现共同富裕目标的背景下，“增长潜力和市场需求”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当晚，马斯克参观了临港自贸区的工厂，根据上海电视台应用程序上的一段视频片段，数百名员工向他致意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我非常想祝贺你所做的出色工作，”马斯克是听到剪辑中告诉特斯拉员工。 “你们能够克服这么多困难和挑战，令人印象深刻。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉在美国以外的第一家工厂 Gigafactory 3 在 2022 年向大陆客户交付了约 440,000 辆汽车，增长了 37 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括出口在内，超级工厂去年生产了约 71 万辆汽车，占特斯拉总产量 131 万辆的一半以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据估计，去年 3 月 28 日至 4 月 18 日期间，在全市范围内的 Covid-19 封锁期间，由于上海工厂的班次减少，特斯拉在生产中损失了约 50,000 辆汽车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉于 2019 年底开设了超级工厂，是中国高端电动汽车领域的领先者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于本地生产的 Model 3 和 Model Y 汽车在国内的强劲销售，该公司去年初开始制定扩建工厂的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;但据邮报 1 月 13 日报道，由于未能获得大陆当局的批准，这家汽车制造商搁置了第二条装配线的计划。新生产线预计将使上海工厂的产能翻一番，达到每年 200 万辆。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“马斯克的高调访问，特别是在与高级官员会面之后，为特斯拉的进一步投资铺平了道路，因为电动汽车行业将在未来十年内实现强劲的销售增长，”高说沉，上海独立分析师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，特斯拉宣布将在上海新建电池工厂，生产其 Megapack 大型储能单元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Megapack旨在帮助稳定电网，该公司表示每个单元可以存储足够的能量，平均可为 3,600 户家庭供电一小时。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pacific nations dismayed at Australia’s backing for fossil fuels, calls it ‘biggest security threat’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3222604/pacific-nations-dismayed-australias-backing-fossil-fuels-calls-it-biggest-security-threat?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 17:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/ee0b47f2-b7e2-4fd9-a945-e6f181c672c8_37dffd34.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;太平洋岛屿周四对澳大利亚对化石燃料的补贴表示失望，将气候问题列为邻国之间的摩擦点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两位太平洋部长出现在联合直播中，谴责澳大利亚长期以来对煤炭和天然气项目的热情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦努阿图气候变化部长 Ralph Regenvanu对澳大利亚去年承诺向可再生能源转型表示欢迎，但表示必须停止资助破坏气候的项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“看到澳大利亚继续补贴化石燃料项目，我们感到非常失望，”Regenvanu 告诉澳大利亚研究所，一家位于堪培拉的智囊团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在可再生能源领域需要资金。这就是我们经济和社会的未来所在——而不是化石燃料行业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regenvanu 质疑为什么堪培拉继续“向我们太平洋地区的化石燃料行业注入数十亿美元”同意，包括澳大利亚在内，是对我们安全的最大威胁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦努阿图是一个小群岛，与许多太平洋岛国一样，受到海平面上升的威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么澳大利亚的气候目标可能化为泡影&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;图瓦卢财政部长 Seve Paeniu 与 Regenvanu 一起发表讲话说，太平洋国家目前正在权衡使该地区无化石的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个想法Paeniu 说：“是停止化石燃料的任何进一步扩张”，并消除煤炭、石油和天然气的消耗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这事关我们的安全和生存。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;图瓦卢位于夏威夷和澳大利亚之间，是世界上最小的国家之一，面积不到 26 平方公里（10 平方英里），而且正在迅速缩小。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的土地不断被吃掉离开”，Paeniu 说。 “而且我们知道化石燃料是气候变化的原因。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚承诺到 2030 年 82% 的电力将来自可再生能源。目前的数字约为 30%。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;但它是世界上最大的煤炭和天然气出口国之一，并且一系列政府抵制了缩减该行业的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中左翼工党政府批准了一个新煤矿上个月，引发了环保组织的愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚及其盟友，包括美国，目前正与中国展开一场争夺整个太平洋影响力的战斗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚与中国的关系化石燃料是一个持续的刺激因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regenvanu 将澳大利亚描述为瓦努阿图最大的贸易伙伴，但表示两国在气候变化问题上存在紧张关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指责澳大利亚“没有认识到主要的太平洋安全威胁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦努阿图在今年遭受“几天内两次史无前例的四级气旋袭击”后仍处于紧急状态，Regenvanu 说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他估计，修复损失将花费瓦努阿图国内生产总值的 40% 以上，国际货币基金组织估计这一数字约为 10 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就像你向前迈出一步，然后迈出两步。”经济发展倒退”，Regenvanu 说。 “我们没有看到我们需要看到的减排。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[HK$30 billion in e-vouchers will be major boost for hard-pressed Hong Kong retail sector, city leader says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3222593/hk30-billion-e-vouchers-will-be-major-boost-hard-pressed-hong-kong-retail-sector-city-leader-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 16:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/a1618037-a572-433d-98d0-0eab1c050215_0801de59.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;将派发价值 300 亿港元（38 亿美元）的电子礼券香港领导人表示，今年将接近香港目前的月零售额水平，并将成为该行业的重要一剂强心剂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港录得 347 亿港元的零售额政府统计处周四公布的初步数据显示，4 月份的销售额同比增长 15%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超在香港零售管理协会的零售峰会上表示当天早些时候，这座城市有望从零售低迷中复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee 说，今年前三个月约有 730 万游客访问了这座城市，而整个全年的游客数量约为 60 万2022 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年前四个月，零售额同比反弹 21.7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们看到了良好的复苏迹象，”Lee 说。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;4 月份的销售水平意味着支出恢复到 2019 年的水平，除了 1 月份录得 360 亿港元的销售额，该销售额受到农历新年等季节性因素的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府发言人表示， 4 月份零售总额较上年同期上升，消费者信心和访港旅客人数持续改善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“展望未来，入境旅游复苏和本地消费需求应会继续帮助零售业部门表现。消费券的发放将提供进一步的支持。”复活节假期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但零售协会主席谢邱安仪指出，很多人在拿到第一轮消费券之前，已经花钱去海外旅游。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“4 月上半月的零售表现相当疲软，但由于消费券的影响，下半月情况有所好转，但增幅并不显着，”Tse 说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她表示 5 月份的涨幅更大，其中包括大陆为期五天的“黄金周”劳动节假期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港 3 月份的零售额增长了 40.9%，创历史新高&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Tse 表示，与去年同期相比，化妆品、个人护理、珠宝和手表等与旅游相关的零售类别报告了中低两位数的增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但零售类别针对香港市场，包括电器和家具在内的零售业录得个位数跌幅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢表示，五一假期期间香港零售市场并没有明显提振。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，该行业已恢复到大流行前水平的 40% 至 50%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有迹象表明，内地访港游客的消费水平普遍下降，因为他们Tse 说：“他们倾向于进行体验式旅行。”天堂可能不再是它最大的吸引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会采访了 3,700 名商家和 61,000 名行业员工，其中 60% 的人预计今年第三季度的人员短缺将达到 10% 至 20%。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;谢女士表示，她希望政府能够帮助该行业解决人员短缺问题，包括通过从大湾区输入员工。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore triples jail time for drugs possession, makes sweeping changes to anti-narcotics laws]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222585/singapore-triples-jail-time-drugs-possession-makes-sweeping-changes-anti-narcotics-laws?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 16:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/d6153c73-92e2-4e95-a480-51b53229c9db_99fac6dd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;被捕时携带大量某些 A 类管制药物，例如大麻和甲基苯丙胺新加坡内政部 (MHA) 表示，从周四开始，他们将面临更严厉的处罚——包括鞭刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此前，无论体重如何，持有任何受管制药物的最高刑罚是 10 年监禁，最高可处以 20,000 新元（14,774 美元）的罚款，或两者并罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，可以根据所持毒品的数量对违法者进行鞭刑。还设定了针对某些体重阈值的强制性最低刑罚，而最高刑罚现在将是 30 年监禁和 15 下鞭刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡主要毒品立法《滥用毒品法》的修正案，于 3 月在议会通过。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“准备辩论”：Shanmugam 关于毒品战争和其他观点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这将适用于大麻、大麻混合物的八种管制药物、大麻脂、可卡因、二氢吗啡（纯海洛因）、甲基苯丙胺、吗啡和鸦片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，持有少于 10 克二氢吗啡的人可被判最高 10 年监禁或最高 20,000 新元的罚款， 或两者。没有法定的最低限度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些因拥有至少 10 克但少于 15 克的二氢吗啡而被定罪的人将面临至少 10 年的监禁和 5 下鞭刑。最高刑期是其两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有超过 15 克重的人将被判至少 20 年监禁和 10 下鞭刑。最高刑期为 30 年监禁和 15 下鞭刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MHA 此前表示，旧的对持有毒品的量刑框架没有充分考虑到持有大量毒品的人可能造成的潜在伤害&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;之所以选择这八种药物，是因为它们“造成的危害最严重”，它补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MHA 还表示，近年来，中央禁毒局（CNB） ) 观察到，辛迪加愿意在每次交易中交易更多数量的管制药物——这种转变可能与滥用者在单次交易中购买大量药物有关，而不是多次购买较小数量的药物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年 2 月，CNB 在其年度统计报告中透露，被捕的 20 岁以下大麻滥用者人数从 2021 年的 8 人增加到 2022 年的 26 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNB 主任 Sam Tee 在去年晚些时候接受记者采访时告诉记者今年缉毒机构计划加强与家长的接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;甲基苯丙胺仍然是去年新加坡滥用最严重的药物，被捕的 1,445 名滥用者占总数的 51%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡的学校教育事件引发了对长期禁毒法的质疑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;将于周四生效的《滥用药物法》的其他修正案包括 CNB 主任能够召回任何前任吸毒者一生都需要进行尿检，以确保他们不再吸毒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNB 局长现在也有权召回因吸毒而被定罪的新加坡武装部队 (SAF) 人员根据 SAF 法案，让他们进行尿检。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNB 官员现在还可以根据合理怀疑进行扣押，使这些权力与《刑事诉讼法》规定的权力保持一致。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;3 月份还通过了新法律，以更好地应对与管制药物产生相同或相似效果的精神活性物质，这些新法律将于 2024 年上半年生效。MHA 表示，将适时公布更多细节。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hiking in hot weather: Hong Kong trekking expert warns against overestimating abilities, tells enthusiasts to ‘listen to your body’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3222522/hiking-hot-weather-hong-kong-trekking-expert-warns-against-overestimating-abilities-tells?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 15:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/f9513449-c01b-43db-abeb-29427d391bf0_3cae39ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港资深登山教练梁志豪一直建议学生坚持口头禅“听从你的心，听从你的身体”，以免在酷热的农村遇到麻烦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周他一直在重申这一建议，极端气温导致数名徒步旅行者被送往医院，其中包括一名63岁男子星期六在大埔张排屯怀疑中暑而短暂晕倒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外三名登山客在西环东涌登山时亦需住院治疗Kung 和 Tsing Yi 星期二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从事山地工艺教学已有 20 年的 Leung 说，由于长时间暴露在阳光下和高温下，徒步旅行者会患上与热有关的疾病，包括疲劳和中暑。身体未能及时调节体温。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港女子沿海远足时被卷入海中死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这种情况可能发生在体力活动和摄入不足的情况下水。与热有关的疾病的早期迹象可能包括神志不清、皮肤发烫或发红，或者体温超过 40 摄氏度（104 华氏度）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们带的水很少，以避免负重或不负重Leung 谈到因高温而屈服的徒步旅行者时说：如果气温飙升至周二和周三的记录，则需要三升，市区最高气温超过 34 度，上水气温为 37 度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung 还建议再补充 500 毫升（19 液量盎司）水随身携带作为备用。他补充说，补充电解质的饮料或茶等饮料不算在内。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;家佣在香港登山点掉进泳池身亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;炎炎夏日，他在规划路线时，教练会检查天文台报告的高温指数和湿度数据，并随时准备改变路线以避免高温风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说他不会建议继续执行计划或仅仅根据计划搁置&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方准备推出“HKSOS”应用程序以快速查明迷路的徒步旅行者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“如果气温达到 37 度，我们将改变路线以包括通风区域有树荫。海拔也会降低，”Leung 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，在如此高的温度下，海边路线和荒山小径之间会有很大差异，并指出流动性&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung 表示，近年登山死亡人数增加的一个主要原因是登山者高估了自己的身体状况，而没有充分意识到环境风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“有些人会在看到 YouTuber 的路线剪辑后就出去，但无法估计他们是否能够应付，”Leung 指出，并补充说徒步旅行者也没有携带足够的防护装备。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港发出今年首个「酷热天气」警告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;远足者应始终诚实面对自己的能力，并可随时调整计划路线并在必要时撤离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们常说‘听从你的心，听听你的身体’……但很多人只是听从他们的心，而没有听从他们的身体发出的信号。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他提醒徒步旅行者不要独自散步，因为&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;59岁的远足者在香港郊野公园小径上病倒后不治身亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;50多岁的远足爱好者Winnson Wu表示，他喜欢挑战，即使温度达到35度，也不会放弃计划或任意退出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他强调，他会休息一下，会留意身体发出的警报信号。 Wu 的基本装备包括帽子、宽松的衣服、防晒霜和足够的水——通常需要 1.5 到 2 升水来进行两小时的旅行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wu 分享了一次独自徒步旅行的经历，当时他感到轻微的体征即将中暑。他在阴凉处休息了大约 20 分钟，喝了水，并在头上放了一条湿毛巾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说他还准备在情况恶化时拨打 999，并强调徒步旅行者保持安全的重要性能够在手机应用程序的帮助下向救援人员准确报告他们的位置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我今天挑战失败，明天我可以做到。无需将生活与徒步旅行捆绑在一起，”他警告说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Despite ‘no limits’ ties, China has moved carefully on Russian energy since Ukraine invasion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222493/despite-no-limits-ties-china-has-moved-carefully-russian-energy-ukraine-invasion?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/de3345bc-9cb5-47f0-bb57-9006cedd7353_e9503b26.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;自莫斯科 2 月入侵乌克兰以来，中国仅适度扩大了与俄罗斯的能源联系2022 年，根据一项新的分析，谨慎的做法与习近平主席和弗拉基米尔·普京总统在战争开始前宣布的“无限”伙伴关系不一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯石油和天然气在中国石油和天然气中的份额到 2022 年，这些产品的总进口额从一年前的 14% 上升到 16%。根据瑞典国际事务研究所独家与邮报分享的一项全面的新分析，2023 年前四个月的增长率高达 16.9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国公司没有进行新的投资或交易自普京发动入侵以来，俄罗斯的碳氢化合物行业一直处于紧张状态，也没有就任何新的石油或天然气管道或长期进口合同达成一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然北京一直在抨击西方对俄罗斯能源行业的闪电式制裁，研究指出，中国基本上没有破坏它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国抗议美国对与俄罗斯打交道的公司实施“非法”制裁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国没有提供其国有油轮船队研究称，此举将“单枪匹马”消除俄罗斯现在被迫出售其石油的大部分折扣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它也没有在之后提供替代运输保险西方保险公司被迫与俄罗斯断绝关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它继续以高于 G7 去年 12 月规定的价格上限的价格购买俄罗斯石油，但只能通过第三方或中国私营企业购买。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;调查结果显示，北京在“支持其最重要的战略伙伴挑战西方主导的世界秩序”和“照顾其自身更以自我为中心的利益，包括与西方国家保持经济联系”之间取得平衡贸易伙伴”，该报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究所的访问学者、该报告的作者 Henrik Wachtmeister 表示，北京的克制可能是因为受到来自西方的二次制裁的威胁。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;中国可能不希望依赖俄罗斯的能源，但它也有时间：随着战争进入第 16 个月，石油和天然气将在未来一段时间内以折扣价供应.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着对莫斯科的一系列严厉制裁在 2022 年展开，许多人预计中国将填补西方买家和投资者留下的空白。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，过去15 个月加速了中俄关系的不对称——法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙上个月将这种趋势描述为“一种附庸化形式”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯仍然是中国能源结构的重要贡献者，但并非主导者，而中国在俄罗斯能源出口中的份额几乎翻了一番——从 16% 增加到 30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然中国现在是俄罗斯能源产品的第一大买家，也是俄罗斯最大的油气资产外国所有者国家，这是因为西方公司退出了，而不是中国采购的大幅升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在欧盟禁运之后，亚洲获得了大部分俄罗斯暗燃料——中国、印度是主要进口国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;眼睛- 报告称，去年俄罗斯液化天然气 (LNG) 进口价值增长 44% 和管道天然气增长 50% 主要归因于价格上涨，这也符合广泛的趋势中国在寻求减少煤炭使用的同时从世界各地吸取天然气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wachtmeister 表示，只要与西方国家（尤其是欧洲）保持相对友好的关系，中国就可能会继续保持谨慎态度。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这可能很快就会受到考验：布鲁塞尔目前正在讨论自战争开始以来针对中国运营商的首次以俄罗斯为中心的制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自中国大陆或香港的八家公司因将欧盟制造的军民两用产品再出口给与俄罗斯军方有关联的买家而受到处罚的公司名单草案。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;欧盟考虑对被控帮助俄罗斯军方的中国公司实施制裁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;此外，一项新文书正在讨论中，该文书将限制向涉及违反制裁的第三国的出口。然而，这遭到了包括德国在内的一些国家的反对，他们担心会进一步损害欧盟与中国的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然这些潜在的制裁没有能源重点，但一些人担心他们会把中国推得更近&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京驻欧盟大使傅聪警告称，中国将进行报复，而欧盟官员拒绝接受傅聪在接受新媒体采访时提出的帮助调查这八家公司的提议。政治家上周日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“规避制裁绝对是欧盟的首要任务，”欧盟委员会首席发言人埃里克·马默 (Eric Mamer) 说。 “我不能说现阶段我们是否与中国有任何具体的双边接触——我不知道这一点，但我们当然注意到你提到的评论。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wachtmeister 建议为了鼓励中国在与俄罗斯的能源贸易中保持“最初的谨慎态度”，欧洲应该谨慎行事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在在这些领域使用大棒可能还为时过早，胡萝卜方法可能在不需要升级的情况下仍然有效。或许 [Theodore] Roosevelt 的‘说话轻声细语，大棒大棒’的方法就足够了，不是使用它，而是做好必要的准备，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;制裁不太可能在本周结束。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟大使周三开会讨论委员会的一项新提案，而一些成员国继续对任何类似于美国多年来实施的域外制裁的措施犹豫不决，这对欧洲的影响很大&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“危险在于我们过于偏向治外法权，”一位欧盟高级官员在谈到针对特定国家而非公司的辩论时说。 “我们需要确保这在法庭上成立。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该官员表示，欧盟对上个月访问包括布鲁塞尔在内的欧洲各国首都的中国和平特使感到失望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们没有了解到有关中国立场的任何新信息，”他们谈到与北京欧亚事务特使李辉的会谈时说。 “我们希望和平符合国际法。这是重申我们立场的机会，希望当他向习近平汇报时，他能听到（来自所有欧洲国家首都的）同样的话。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Republican 2024 field gets crowded with Mike Pence, Chris Christie to announce bids]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222574/republican-2024-field-gets-crowded-mike-pence-chris-christie-announce-bids?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 15:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/b8137cfa-194e-4043-ae4e-fbaaef3f072d_ff925a35.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国前副总统迈克彭斯和前新泽西州州长克里斯克里斯蒂计划参加下周 2024 年共和党总统候选人提名的角逐，挑战领跑者唐纳德特朗普的主导地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里斯蒂曾在 2016 年为特朗普的竞选活动提供建议，但后来却直言不讳地批评前者一位知情人士说，总统将于 6 月 6 日正式宣布他的 2024 年竞选活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭斯因拒绝支持他推翻 2020 年大选结果的努力而招致特朗普的愤怒，他将在三位熟悉情况的消息人士告诉路透社，他将于 6 月 7 日参加与他的前任老板的竞选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据一位知情人士透露，北达科他州州长 Doug Burgum 也计划与彭斯在同一天参加竞选熟悉 Burgum 的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越来越多的共和党人关注共和党内部的许多特朗普反对者。他们担心大量挑战者会分裂反对特朗普的投票，并将党内提名交给前总统，后者可以依靠至少 30% 的共和党选民支持他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普有在共和党领域的巨大民意调查领先优势，现在有超过 10 名已宣布或几乎已宣布的候选人。最接近他的挑战者是上周参加竞选的佛罗里达州州长罗恩德桑蒂斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;德桑蒂斯在 2024 年竞选摇摆开始时抨击特朗普&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周三，彭斯在共和党领域的平均支持率低于特朗普根据 RealClearPolitics 的民调平均值，特朗普的支持率为 53%，超过 4%。克里斯蒂迄今为止几乎没有在民意调查中登记。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消息人士称，彭斯将在爱荷华州的早期提名州通过视频和演讲启动他的竞选活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个坚定的社会彭斯是特朗普在任期间一直支持他的保守派，但自从他在选举失败后，他与这位前共和党总统的关系越来越疏远，他说特朗普对 2021 年 1 月 6 日袭击美国国会大厦的骚乱者的鼓励使他和他的家人陷入困境&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭斯将于 6 月 7 日迎来 64 岁生日，他继续拥护特朗普的许多政策，同时将自己描绘成一个稳重且以共识为导向的替代者。他还更直接地向福音派基督教社区发出呼吁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他竞选活动的成功将取决于他能否吸引足够多的特朗普政策支持者，这些人对前总统的言论和行为感到厌恶，从而建立一个可行的联盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;60 岁的克里斯蒂以明显的失败者身份参加竞选，六年后，他在 2016 年总统竞选中未能在包括特朗普在内的拥挤的领域中获得牵引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有 1在 5 月 9 日至 15 日进行的路透社/益普索民意调查中，% 的共和党人表示他将成为他们首选的 2024 年候选人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里斯蒂将在早期提名州圣安瑟姆学院的市政厅正式启动他的竞选活动知情人士说，周二新罕布什尔州参选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他参加竞选的共和党人包括美国参议员蒂姆·斯科特和前南卡罗来纳州州长妮基·黑莉。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[McCarthy’s moment: US debt win secures Republican House speaker’s standing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222565/mccarthys-moment-us-debt-win-secures-republican-house-speakers-standing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 14:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/8bb0241b-92a7-48dc-ab6d-ad9904a3a540_a73d2ab9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三，凯文·麦卡锡 (Kevin McCarthy) 赢得了美国众议院共和党议长的荣誉，面对激烈的强硬派反对，通过一项包含联邦支出限制的债务上限法案，乔·拜登总统数月来誓言要抵制这一法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他为了当选议长而忍受 15 次羞辱性的全场投票六个月后，麦卡锡证明有能力dragging Biden into negotiations over spending and other Republican priorities, and then marshalling two-thirds of his often fractious House Republican majority to enact bipartisan legislation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s not how you start, it&#39;s how you finish,” McCarthy told reporters after the vote, repeating one of his comments from the January night he was finally confirmed as speaker.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The House approved by a 314-117 margin the bill, which lifts the government&#39;s US$31.4 trillion debt ceiling in exchange for cutting non-defence discretionary spending and stiffening work requirements in assistance programmes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet it was a bruising victory for McCarthy. The bill gained 165 votes from Democrats, outnumbering the 149 from members of McCarthy&#39;s own Republican Party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bill now goes to the narrowly Democratic-controlled Senate, which must enact it and get it to Biden&#39;s desk by June 5 to avoid a crippling US default.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Republican shift on Ukraine masked by Beijing&#39;s fury over Tsai&#39;s US trip&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Republican congressman Dusty Johnson, a McCarthy ally who helped craft the Republican debt-ceiling legislation that buttressed the speaker in negotiations, said the vote proved wrong Democratic predications that the 58-year-old Californian would have little chance of holding his caucus together.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They said he would never become speaker, and of course they were wrong. They said he would never be able to manage the floor effectively and we haven&#39;t had a single bill fail,” Johnson said in an interview. “They said he wouldn&#39;t be able to cut a deal with the president, and they were wrong about that.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McCarthy has so far succeeded in passing the bill without drawing direct verbal attacks from former president Donald Trump, who urged Republicans to push for a default if they were not able to extract sufficient concessions from Democrats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump, who is seeking a return to the White House in 2024, had blasted top Senate Republican Mitch McConnell for agreeing to raise the debt ceiling during Biden&#39;s first year in office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McConnell largely stayed in the background during these talks, which began to move forward after Biden agreed to one-on-one negotiations on May 9.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Avoiding Trump&#39;s ire appears to have protected McCarthy&#39;s standing with Republican voters nationally, some 44 per cent of whom told a Reuters/Ipsos poll in May that they approve of his job performance, notably higher than McConnell&#39;s 29 per cent approval rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bill approved by the House on Wednesday would suspend the debt limit – essentially meaning that it no longer applies – through January 1, 2025. That sets the stage for another showdown in the weeks following the 2024 presidential election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Republican lawmakers and analysts say McCarthy&#39;s masterstroke in getting Biden to the negotiating table was his decision to bring a debt ceiling bill to the floor and pass it in April with only the support of his own party members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Up to that point, Biden had refused McCarthy&#39;s requests to negotiate over the debt ceiling, insisting that House Republicans enact their own budget for fiscal 2024 as a prerequisite for spending talks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in getting the April measure passed, House Republicans became the only body in Washington that had acted to raise the debt ceiling.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;DeSantis bashes Trump as 2024 campaign swing begins&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Once the House passed a bill, &#39;no negotiations&#39; was a clearly unsustainable place to be,” said Rohit Kumar, a former top aide to Senate Republican leader Mitch McConnell who is now co-leader of PwC&#39;s national tax office in Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The White House, for its part, contends that the talks between Biden and McCarthy were not a negotiation on the debt ceiling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The debt ceiling had to be lifted, and it had to be lifted for a long period of time,” White House budget director Shalanda Young told a Tuesday press conference. “You see this bill lift the debt ceiling until 2025. You can call it a negotiation; I call it a declarative statement.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;House Republicans say McCarthy has succeeded as speaker, because of an inclusive leadership style, cultivating support from a majority of caucus members by working through major party caucuses, known as the “Five Families”, a reference to the warring organised crime clans of The Godfather movie.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Speaker McCarthy&#39;s done an incredible job,” said congresswoman Marjorie Taylor Greene, a member of the hardline Republican House Freedom Caucus. “And I think he&#39;s proved over and over again that he defies the odds, and he also defies people&#39;s expectations.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McCarthy also expanded his influence through trusted friends and longtime associates such as congressmen Patrick McHenry and Garret Graves, who became his lead negotiators with the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But McCarthy is not quite out of the woods. After stirring the ire of hardline conservatives who decried the compromise bill as a sellout, he could face the prospect of ouster at the hands of any single member.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the conditions he agreed to in January to win the speakership was allowing for any one member to call for a “motion to vacate the chair”, in essence a vote on whether to depose the speaker.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Senior members of the Freedom Caucus have said they would consider next steps in coming weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of their number, Ralph Norman, said McCarthy should have forced Democrats to accept the House-passed bill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think it weakens him. Whether it&#39;s permanent or temporary, I don&#39;t know,” Norman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Norman said he would not support an immediate effort to oust McCarthy as speaker, adding “To threaten to kick him out now, that&#39;s not right”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A similar threat triggered the resignation of former House Speaker John Boehner in 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is where the honeymoon can definitely end,” said Republican strategist Ron Bonjean, a one-time aide to former House Speaker Dennis Hastert.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked this week whether he expects to keep his speakership, McCarthy told a reporter: “What do you think? You guys ask me all the time, and I&#39;m still standing.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His allies say they will defend him against any potential threat to his position.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ll have to deal with the internal politics of a hard-fought fight.现在脾气暴躁，情绪低落。 But we&#39;ll deal with it,” congresswoman Kelly Armstrong, a McCarthy adviser, said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Wang Yi boosts China, Germany friendship paving way for Chinese premier Li Qiang’s Berlin visit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222564/wang-yi-boosts-china-germany-friendship-paving-way-chinese-premier-li-qiangs-berlin-visit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 14:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/01/d62878b7-3e72-433d-80cc-3ea8a1165924_3c9f2d89.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s top diplomat Wang Yi has signalled Beijing&#39;s willingness to join hands with Berlin in the face of global uncertainties, in a meeting on Wednesday aimed at preparing the way for a widely expected visit to Germany by Premier Li Qiang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China and Germany should work together to make the seventh China-Germany intergovernmental consultation a success, and send a positive signal to Europe and the world”, Wang told Jens Plotner, the German foreign and security policy adviser.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Chinese foreign ministry, Plotner said Germany is also “very much looking forward” to the consultation and will work with China to speed up the preparatory work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pair also “exchanged views” on the war in Ukraine, the foreign ministry said. Germany was among the stops on Chinese special envoy Li Hui&#39;s recent peace mission, which included visits to Ukraine, Russia, France, Poland and Brussels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There has been little evidence that Li&#39;s visit turned around widely held suspicions in Europe about China&#39;s close relations with Russia, which Chinese President Xi Jinping and his Russian counterpart Vladimir Putin have hailed as a “no limits” friendship.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before his meeting on Wednesday with Wang – the most senior diplomat in China&#39;s party system – Plotner had talks with foreign minister Qin Gang, as part of the planning for Li Qiang&#39;s visit to Berlin.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China looks to reboot Germany, Europe relations, amid Ukraine war fallout&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Neither side has confirmed a date for the visit, but multiple meetings have been held to pave the way for one of Li&#39;s first trips to a major developed economy since his promotion to premier in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to German Chancellor Olaf Scholz on the sidelines of the Munich Security Conference in February, Wang said the proposed meeting would help to “chart the blueprint for the development of bilateral relations to keep China-Germany cooperation in the forefront of the world”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EU member states&#39; approach to China has been fragmented, with French President Emmanuel Macron warning against becoming a “vassal” of the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese envoy&#39;s Europe trip a &#39;search for common ground&#39; on Ukraine: analysts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Brussels, on the other hand, has suggested “de-risking” instead of “decoupling” from China – an approach echoed by the G7 powers including the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China – which has been looking to reboot ties with Europe, especially close economic partners like Germany and France – has raised concerns about the de-risking strategy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Qin met his German counterpart in Berlin last month, he said the strategy could become a “de-sinicisation” of Europe and the real risk to European countries comes from “a certain country” waging a “new cold war”. The US was not named.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia court rules decorated soldier Ben Roberts-Smith committed war crimes, dismisses defamation suit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3222569/australia-court-rules-decorated-soldier-ben-roberts-smith-committed-war-crimes-dismisses-defamation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 14:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/01/c4409ba1-9715-4737-ace5-261a96443746_7623a8fe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;One of Australia&#39;s most decorated soldiers lost a landmark defamation case against major newspapers Thursday after a bruising trial that saw accusations of murder, domestic violence, witness intimidation and war crimes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ben Roberts-Smith, a former member of Australia&#39;s elite Special Air Services regiment, sued three newspapers after 2018 reports alleged he was involved in the murder of six unarmed prisoners in Afghanistan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roberts-Smith denied the allegations and launched a multimillion-dollar defamation case in response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Justice Anthony Beskano said the papers had proven many of their allegations were “substantially true” and dismissed the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia&#39;s war crimes in Afghanistan show cost of celebrating military&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The verdict was hailed as a major victory for Australian media freedom, with journalist and defendant Nick McKenzie tweeting: “Justice.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the trial, Perth-born Roberts-Smith was Australia&#39;s most famous and distinguished soldier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He won the Victoria Cross – Australia&#39;s highest military honour – for “conspicuous gallantry” in Afghanistan, where his unit was hunting for a senior Taliban commander.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He met then Queen Elizabeth and his image hung in the Australian War Memorial in Canberra.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But The Age, The Sydney Morning Herald and The Canberra Times alleged that behind Roberts-Smith&#39;s lauded public persona lay a pattern of criminal behaviour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The paper said Roberts-Smith had kicked an unarmed Afghan civilian off a cliff and ordered subordinates to shoot him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was also said to have taken part in the machine-gunning of a man with a prosthetic leg, later bringing the leg back to Australia and using it as a drinking vessel with other soldiers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The towering veteran was also accused of domestic violence against a woman in a Canberra hotel – something the ruling said had not been completely proven – and of engaging “in a campaign of bullying” against a fellow soldier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roberts-Smith and his lawyers had claimed that five of the killings took place in combat, while the sixth was entirely fictitious.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The newspapers and their journalists had backed their reporting throughout the trial, primarily relying on the defence of truth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The case became one of Australia&#39;s longest-running defamation trials, with 40 witnesses providing often harrowing evidence about the behaviour of Australia&#39;s special forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local media has estimated the legal costs have run to US$16 million, making it one of the costliest defamation cases in the country&#39;s history.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawyers for the media indicated they would be seeking “indemnity costs against the applicant” at a later date.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roberts-Smith&#39;s defence was partially bankrolled by the boss of Seven West Media, a rival to the three newspapers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was photographed holidaying in Bali ahead of the ruling and did not attend court.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘I’m an example of speaking up’: how one woman helped change the way Asian-Americans see themselves]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222571/im-example-speaking-how-one-woman-helped-change-way-asian-americans-see-themselves?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 14:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/01/346783dc-a394-4ea8-8e66-67a765da6b5a_1ece570d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Helen Zia fought with her father to go to university.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She went on to become one of the first American women to graduate from Princeton in 1973. While there, she successfully lobbied to start an Asian American Students Association.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few years later, she demanded that authorities in Detroit handle the slaying of a Chinese-American man, Vincent Chin, as a hate crime. She succeeded. Later, her books and articles would showcase the violence and discrimination faced by Asian-Americans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It seems Zia has always been fighting – and the reasons to fight never cease. “Asian Americans have been slammed as cartoon characters,” she said. “We&#39;ve been called gooks, geeks, geishas. Moving beyond racial slurs to communities of strength and influence is a battle that doesn&#39;t die.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indeed, even after all the battles she has fought, current conditions present unusually fraught challenges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This time feels different,” Zia said at a leadership workshop in Oakland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When people started blaming China for the Covid-19 pandemic, it seemed certain Asian-Americans would feel blowback too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I see you nodding your heads,” she told the crowd. “You went, &#39;Oh, s***.&#39;”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No one laughed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Where we are today is a consequence of so many things that we, some of us, have been predicting for some time,” Zia said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among those changes is the growing diversity in the US, which some members of society find threatening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though hardly a household name to the general public, the 70-year-old activist and author is a trailblazer among those who care about Asian-American issues and civil rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Known for her hard-hitting talk and fierce intelligence as well as her warmth, Zia speaks with such energy and conviction that she leaves her audiences inspired and often in awe.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;In US, Yelp sees sharp increase in racist anti-Asian business reviews&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Most men or women might have given up by now,” said Mary Yu Danico, professor of sociology and director of the Asian American Transnational Research Initiative at Cal Poly Pomona. “Racism – bias against Asian Americans – has flourished for a long time and it still exists in public and in private. Helen could have gone on to do something lucrative or with less stress. But you continue to hear her reasoning and her passion day after day.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zia was an early proponent of what was once a novel idea: that Americans with roots in China, Japan, Vietnam and other Asian countries could unite as Asian-Americans to organise, and when necessary, agitate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The group identity would expand to more parts of Asia, such as India, and later include Pacific Islanders. Some believe it&#39;s not far-fetched to say that without Zia, May would not now be observed as Asian-American and Pacific Islander Island Month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To her, the important thing is her work, not herself. “I&#39;m an example of speaking up,” she said. “Never a role model.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But to many, that is exactly what she is, and her life has been marked by a devotion to duty – duty she developed young.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Born in New Jersey to parents from Shanghai, Zia was five when she began helping in her parents&#39; floral novelty business, doing her share along with five siblings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her father was convinced that instead of giving flowers to new mothers, consumers might buy something more creative. The elder Zia combined blue and pink duckies with a lamp shade, or a carousel with a music box, both items sporting cups for holding blooms. He trained his kids how to carefully assemble them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was an educated man who wrote poetry, plays and a novel – and fiercely proud of his Chinese heritage. He taught his children to be the same. “Just remember, when Europeans were naked in caves, we were wearing silk,” he would say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zia&#39;s mum barely knew English, while her dad spoke with a heavy accent, making him a target for mockery and racism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese – we have always been regarded as perpetual foreigners,” younger brother Hoyt Zia recalled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the 1960s unfolded, the Zias lived in a mostly-white New Jersey community near Philadelphia, but Hoyt and Helen Zia remember being increasingly exposed to a multiracial society and this prompted her interest in social justice campaigns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In “Asian American Dreams”, her groundbreaking book that is part memoir, part social history, she recounts a life-changing incident in secondary school when she discussed civil rights with two friends – Rose, who was black, and Julie who was white:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As I offered my thoughts, Rose abruptly turned to me and said: &#39;Helen, you&#39;ve got to decide if you&#39;re black or white&#39;. Stunned, I was unable to say that I was neither, that I had an identity of my own. I didn&#39;t know the words &#39;Asian-American&#39;. It was a concept yet to be articulated.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zia, who was her school&#39;s valedictorian, was determined to learn more about outside communities. But her father forbade her from pursuing higher learning.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;I had to hide my ethnicity&#39;: Asian-American actor Michael Tow on his youth&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“She was accepted at every school she applied to and had a drag-out battle with him. He finally relented and let her pick Princeton, the closest of the schools she got in,” said Hoyt Zia, a retired lawyer. “Dad said Chinese girls didn&#39;t need an education, but my sister always had a fighting spirit. She knew she wouldn&#39;t get anywhere without getting educated.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After launching the Asian American Students Association, a group that has grown into a thriving presence on hundreds of campuses, Zia found a voice protesting US involvement in the Vietnam war while joining causes pushing for racial unity among low-income minority groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, while enrolled in medical school in greater Boston, she detoured – heading to Detroit in 1976 to work in construction because she believed women were under-represented in the field.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her move brought her to the same city as Vincent Chin, who in 1982 was beaten to death by two white men with a baseball bat. At the time, Japanese carmakers were increasingly competing with US companies, and the men blamed the 27-year-old Chin for the loss of their jobs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zia, who had added journalism to her repertoire, wrote about all aspects of the killing. Chin was not Japanese but he was Asian, and for his killers that was enough. Her work galvanised Asians-Americans in Michigan and across the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By 1987, when filmmakers released the documentary “Who Killed Vincent Chin?” the intensity of the Asian-American movement rose to a new level – amassing unprecedented attention. Supporters marched on the streets with Zia, and in a first, the protesters included cooks and laundromat owners, along with engineers and lawyers, carrying signs demanding their civil rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thus, a generation of activists was born. And she continues to draw new supporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I had no idea that any of these events happened – that violence against Asians had blown up and continues to be out of control – until I tuned into a Zoom [call] and heard her emotional voice sharing this history,” said Sue Chao, a store clerk from China who relocated to Los Angeles in 2019. “I&#39;ve been researching that history, and I see Helen Zia&#39;s name a lot. Thanks to her, I now realise how our cultural reality is shaped by the past.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australian lecturer&#39;s &#39;anti-China&#39; remarks spark discrimination concerns&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But the concept of a pan-Asian community is not universally embraced. A 2022 study by the Pew Research Center into Asian identity found that “many participants felt that neither &#39;Asian&#39; nor &#39;Asian-American&#39; truly captures how they view themselves and their identity. They argue that these labels are too broad or too ambiguous, as there are so many different groups included within these labels”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, the concept Zia helped launch decades ago remains strong and she remains in demand as a speaker at universities nationwide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Publicly, Zia has also been a force for LGBTQ rights, not hesitating to spotlight the intersection of being a lesbian with Chinese-American roots. She and her wife, Lia Shigemura, tied the knot in 2008 after California began issuing same-sex marriage licences to couples.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One morning in Oakland, where Zia has made her home for more than two decades, the crowd at a conference hosted by the Center for Asian Pacific American Women would not stop clapping – even before she spoke – for their keynote speaker.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mood in the room, sombre as observers listened to her life story, turned electric – with most spectators recording her on their phones, scribbling notes or asking for a photo with the guest of honour afterward, including moderator Gia Vang, an NBC Bay Area TV news anchor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Initially, when asked to appear with Zia, Vang remembered thinking: “Wow. The Helen Zia, someone at the forefront of all the issues we care about. She&#39;s a real-life person advocating for us, not a myth.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One woman working with Asian elders asked about the health of Zia&#39;s parents. Two others wanted her autograph.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zia was quick to respond, whipping out a fine-point pen, joking: “And what do you do? It&#39;s probably me who needs your signature on my book.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On what keeps her going, Zia said: “Always have something to offer. Never think you&#39;re alone.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then she was off to San Francisco – to the next scheduled talk, another chance to educate, to inspire others to action.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>