<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Social anxiety and wanderlust are among Covid-19 pandemic’s lingering impact on Hong Kong]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227654/social-anxiety-and-wanderlust-are-among-covid-19-pandemics-lingering-impact-hong-kong?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 13:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_coronavirus_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/d00e4454-9c1c-49f8-ad61-4339ef32b8c4_992baab3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;最近在泰国度假让我反思了 Covid-19 造成的损害有多大大流行对我们所有人都造成了影响。一系列研究和调查显示了伤害有多深，以及对许多人的影响如何持续存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次访问的直接目的是看望我住在曼谷的三个孙子。当然，在国际旅行基本关闭期间，我们仍然通过电话保持联系。但是在小屏幕上看到远处的面孔与亲眼看到那个人并有机会自发拥抱并不一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过护照印章检查上次访问的日期，我意识到一种恐惧感，我们已经三年多没有近距离接触过。在此期间，其中两个孩子已成为青少年，第三个孩子的年龄已达到两位数。我错过了他们最重要的一些成长岁月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这不仅仅是我，也不仅仅是泰国。我们的生命中都曾经历过三年的时光。那是我们永远无法挽回的时刻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最终的损失是数以百万计的死亡者所承受的，我们应该哀悼他们的去世。但死者的直系亲属和亲密朋友也遭受了损失，他们的悲痛非常严重，如果国际旅行的障碍消除了最后告别的机会，他们的悲痛尤其严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些患者还报告说，他们的悲痛已经持续很长时间了。长期感觉疲劳和记忆力减退。毫无疑问，所谓的“长期新冠”现象将在未来数月乃至数年内得到研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对年轻人教育的不利长期影响已经显现。孩子们来上课时无法社交。由于多次停课，高年级学生的教育受到严重干扰，Zoom 课程并不能替代面对面教学。最糟糕的日子已经过去，一切正在恢复正常，但负面影响需要时间才能消退。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那么我们现在在哪里？环顾四周，最引人注目的事情肯定是戴口罩的人仍然占多数。 3月初的谨慎或许可以理解，但在解除授权四个多月后呢？从个人观察来看，我估计公共交通上大约一半的乘客继续戴口罩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在拥挤的火车上可以采取更保守的做法，但我们该怎么办私家车司机独自坐在车里，还是独自行人走在空荡荡的人行道上？我什至看到人们在健身房里蒙着脸做剧烈运动，这与世界卫生组织的建议完全相反。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在半山区，我们周围都是中学，每天都在中间夏季气温远高于 30 摄氏度，屋顶湿度很大，数百名孩子艰难地去上课，呼吸急促。一些人已经开始不戴口罩，但大多数人仍然戴着口罩。我们必须问为什么。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福音派路德教会社会服务处进行的一项研究可能会给出部分答案。超过80%的接受调查的学生继续佩戴口罩，其中最大的原因是健康问题。父母的影响是另一个重要因素，但第二个最常见的原因是令人担忧：对自己的个人外表缺乏信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们的许多年轻人由于社交焦虑而继续戴着面具。当只能看到眼睛的时候，每个人都是平等的。但当摘下面具后，人们可以而且将会在外表吸引力方面与同龄人进行比较。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高等教育学院和中文大学进行的另一项研究发现，超过一半的人接受调查的中小学生有中度至重度抑郁或压力问题。该研究旨在寻找心理健康与在线玩视频游戏之间可能存在的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在线旅行社 Klook 进行的另一项调查也得出了有趣的结果。当被问及成年人未来 12 个月的旅行计划时，96% 的人表示他们计划搬到某个地方。他们也准备花更多钱，旅行时间也在增加。此外，计划旅行的准备时间越来越短：当香港人想去旅行时，他们就想立即出发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将所有这些拼图拼凑在一起，我们开始了解香港人的情况。疫情对香港人心态的影响。他们很担心。他们重新认识到生命的无常，刚刚失去了三年的生命，并感到没有时间可以浪费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们每个人都会从大流行的经历中吸取不同的教训。我会对那些继续表现出焦虑或抑郁迹象的人更加同情。我计划花更多的时间陪伴家人，不管花多少钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Importance of US-India ties shown with Janet Yellen’s latest trip amid China tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3227875/importance-us-india-ties-shown-janet-yellens-latest-trip-amid-china-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 13:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/16/3676f473-5dc1-4ae4-9f5d-cf3ea710888d_0194aac0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦结束北京之行返回美国这是九个月内第三次与印度会面，这次是与二十国集团财长会面，讨论全球经济挑战，例如低收入国家面临的债务违约威胁加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦将利用在甘地讷格尔的时间试图促进美国和印度之间的关系升温。她还计划在越南河内停留，以解决供应链可靠性、清洁能源转型和其他经济弹性问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦在印度的目标：推动发展中国家经济债务重组推动全球开发银行现代化，使其更加注重气候变化，并深化不断发展的美印关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦频繁访问该国表明了在紧张时期这种关系的重要性&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管美国及其盟国努力制裁俄罗斯经济并在经济上打击俄罗斯经济，但随着克里姆林宫继续入侵乌克兰，印度与俄罗斯的长期关系也将受到影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尽管七国集团商定了俄罗斯石油价格上限，并在减缓俄罗斯经济增长方面取得了一些成功，但今年担任 G20 主席国的俄罗斯并未参与惩罚俄罗斯的行动，也没有维持与该国的能源贸易。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;尽管如此，美国越来越依赖印度，并向印度领导人示好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登 (JoeBiden) 于 6 月主持白宫国事访问，向印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪 (Narendra Modi) 致意，旨在强调和促进两国关系。两位领导人宣布美印关系从未如此牢固，并在两国之间推出了新的商业协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;战略与国际研究中心美印关系政策专家小雷蒙德·维克里 (Raymond Vickery Jr.)耶伦在访问中国后不久就来到印度是有意义的，因为印度官员“将想详细了解与中国同行会面时发生的情况，看看这与他们对与中国经济关系的看法是否相符。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“他们想知道美国是否认真地将其部分采购活动从中国转移到印度。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位财政部高级官员表示，条件是匿名预览耶伦的行程，表示希望在会议上讨论并迅速完成加纳和斯里兰卡的债务处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯里兰卡和加纳去年拖欠了国际债务，大约两年了赞比亚违约后。超过一半的低收入国家面临债务困境，这损害了它们的长期运作和发展能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，赞比亚与其包括中国在内的政府债权人达成了重组协议在巴黎举行的全球金融峰会期间，贷款金额达 63 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议涵盖来自法国、英国、南非、以色列和印度等国家以及赞比亚最大的经济体中国的贷款债权人的债务总额为 41 亿美元。该协议可能为中国如何处理与其他陷入债务困境的国家的重组交易提供路线图。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦在中国待了一周，与中国财政部会面并讨论相互贸易限制后不久就开始了此行。哈德逊研究所高级研究员 Harold W. Furchtgott-Roth 表示，耶伦的印度之行“反映了自然发展的联盟关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “印度与中国的关系非常紧张——他们的边界争端不断。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度希望发展并已经发展成为印度洋海军强国，这也是印度洋海军强国的一个特点。”中国想要发展的地区。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[El Nino and climate change will combine to shatter more records this year as world bakes in heatwaves, scientists say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3227729/el-nino-and-climate-change-will-combine-shatter-more-records-year-world-bakes-heatwaves-scientists?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 12:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/c5e029a1-29de-41af-b49b-bc91056cf8d0_359f204f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;自 4 月初以来让许多国家感到闷热的热浪将继续推动气温创纪录- 根据气候科学家的说法，由于温室气体排放增加导致的变暖与周期性厄尔尼诺天气现象的发生同时发生，今年剩余时间的气温将达到突破水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，很难破译与气候变化的影响相比，厄尔尼诺现象在历史上加剧了陆地和海洋的极端热浪，而造成的影响有多大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正处于未知领域，我们可以期待更多随着厄尔尼诺现象进一步发展，记录将会下降，”世界气象组织（WMO）气候服务主任克里斯托弗·休伊特（Christopher Hewitt）周一在一份声明中表示。 “这些影响将持续到 2024 年。这对地球来说是令人担忧的消息。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国气候变化会议 (COP28) 候任主席本周发布了四大支柱，强调了紧迫性在 11 月迪拜年会之前，计划将“快速过渡”作为首要任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，截至 7 月 9 日的一周是有记录以来全球最热的一周由卫星、陆地站和船舶收集并由世界气象组织分析。随后迎来了有史以来最热的六月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本气象厅的数据显示，7 月 7 日，全球平均气温为 17.24 摄氏度，打破了 2016 年 8 月 16 日创下的 16.94 摄氏度的纪录。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;世界气象组织指出，南极海冰处于卫星监测开始以来 6 月份的最低水平，比平均水平低 17%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;厄尔尼诺现象是太平洋的一种自然气候模式这会带来海洋表面温度升高，通常会导致世界各地的热浪、干旱和洪水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据美国国家气象局称，这种现象平均每两到七年发生一次，每次持续九到十二个月。海洋和大气管理局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“全球变暖已被证明会增加极端温度事件的可能性，”中国大学地球系统科学副教授弗朗西斯·谭（Francis Tam）和博士生曹定瑞说。香港。 “厄尔尼诺现象会进一步加剧一些地区严重热浪的发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然而，准确量化人为引起的全球变暖和厄尔尼诺现象对炎热事件的单独贡献在科学上仍然具有挑战性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“近年来，热浪已成为经常发生的事情。今年，南亚和东南亚早在 4 月中旬就受到了影响，印度、孟加拉国、中国西南部、老挝、泰国、缅甸、新加坡和越南的气温都创下了历史新高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月，华北地区遭遇高温天气。北京本月有 16 天每日高温至少达到 35 度，6 月 22 日达到最高气温，创下 41.1 度的 6 月最高气温。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;持续的热浪烧焦了南欧大片地区，造成白天最高气温上周气温在 30 多岁到 40 多岁之间，预计将持续到本月底。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国南部德克萨斯州，停滞的高压系统导致气温飙升预计上个月大部分时间的气温比平均水平高出五度或以上，预计将持续到本月底。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港，到 7 月 15 日为止，7 月有 10 天非常炎热，最高气温超过 33 度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;随着全球气温上升，城市能否承受极端高温？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;从今年到 2027 年，全球年平均气温将比工业化前高出 1.5 度以上，有三分之二的可能性WMO 在 5 月表示，五年内至少有一年的气温保持在较低水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 2016 年近 200 个国家签署的《巴黎协定》，全球领导人承诺将全球变暖控制在远低于 2 度的范围内，并且通过实施脱碳政策，努力将气温升高控制在 1.5 度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，根据气候行动追踪，截至去年 11 月全球实施的政策将导致气温升高 2.7 度。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;21世纪的技术为中国冰川融化提供帮助&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;今年最不寻常的热浪之一正在大西洋东北部发生，上个月海面温度创下历史新高：比本月平均气温高出 1.36 度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据欧盟支持的研究机构哥白尼气候变化服务中心称，大气中的短期异常环流和海洋的长期变化导致了气温激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港中文大学名誉教授刘雅昌表示，这种海洋热浪可能会对夏季飓风的轨迹和强度以及冬季中纬度气旋产生严重影响。地理和资源管理部门。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着高温和洪水风险的上升，中国对农作物和电网的损害保持警惕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;它们还可能对海洋生态系统造成严重和持久的影响，例如英国埃克塞特大学气候影响系主任理查德·贝茨 (Richard Betts) 表示，随着浮游植物大量繁殖、有毒藻类大量繁殖和鱼类捕捞量下降，这些变化正在发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，在东亚，起源点向东南方向移动Tam 和 Cao 表示，在典型的厄尔尼诺年中，预计热带气旋的数量会比正常年份晚，而且台风季节的到来会比正常情况晚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;厄尔尼诺通常会导致更强烈和更持久的现象。台风，贝茨说。他补充说，更多的飓风将在中国东北部、韩国和日本等高纬度地区登陆，而较少的飓风会登陆更南部的菲律宾、中国南部和越南。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China appears to be readying 2 advanced warships for launch, adding muscle to aircraft carrier group]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3227841/china-appears-be-readying-2-advanced-warships-launch-adding-muscle-aircraft-carrier-group?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/15/1ed930d4-3a0b-43d2-a2d3-9223eebd88c8_3e27085d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国预计将推出两艘多用途护卫舰，为其新一代增添力量根据网上军事爱好者流传的照片，可以看到航母打击群的样子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位追踪中国海军新闻的大陆微博用户分享的几张照片显示了一艘054B型护卫舰的船体——这是一艘更大的护卫舰054A 型的更快版本现已投入使用，因为它准备从造船厂的干船坞下水。超过一半的船体可见，这表明该船很快就会被下水到附近的水池中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;干船坞两侧悬挂的横幅表明，这些照片是在子公司黄埔文冲船厂拍摄的。位于广州的中国船舶工业集团公司 (CSSC) 是中国海军的主要承包商之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;卫星图像显示，中国在先进护卫舰方面取得进展&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“台湾高雄海军学院前教官卢立石表示，“从舱壁板和岛屿控制塔来看，这艘船是迷你版的 055 型驱逐舰。”他指的是仁海级隐形导弹驱逐舰，排水量超过12000吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一艘全新的护卫舰——不仅比054A型更快、更大，而且还采用了055型巡洋舰的一些新的先进技术。”&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;055型驱逐舰是世界上第二强大的驱逐舰，仅次于美国海军的DDG-1000（或朱姆沃尔特级）。它配备了综合桅杆和强大的雷达系统，被称为中国航母的“保镖”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国计划在今年年底前下水两艘054B型护卫舰。除了广州正在建造的一艘外，另一艘正在中船集团旗下另一家上海沪东中华造船厂建造。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;054B型的船体尺寸约为147吨，预计排水量约为6,000吨。根据前美国潜艇艇员汤姆·舒加特 (Tom Shugart) 在其 Twitter 帐户上发布的信息，该船长 18 米（482 英尺），宽 18 米。舒加特根据上海造船厂的卫星图像进行估计，该新船比 051A 型长了 10 多米。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月在上海造船厂拍摄的照片显示，舾装工作已完成尚未开工，说明该舰的建造速度没有广州快。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在广州，一艘为中国海警建造的4000吨054A型护卫舰就坐落在054B型护卫舰旁边&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“054B型排水量比054A型更大，将配备更强大的武器，”卢说。 “我预计它将配备先进的舰载旋转相控阵雷达系统和高功率微波，甚至舰载无人机，以及055型巡洋舰使用的其他新技术。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;去年4月，广州造船厂发布军用船体级钢材公开招标，054B型的建造情况首次曝光。招标公告称，排水量超过 5,000 吨的 054B 型舰将于 2022 年 5 月开始建造，预计今年年底下水。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;台湾将建造轻型护卫舰以降低成本周晨鸣表示，054B型将能够携带两架Z-20反潜直升机，并将与055型和052D型驱逐舰配合进行反潜行动。北京远望军事科技智库研究员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“原来的054型和054A型比较老旧，速度太慢，无法赶上新航母打击群中的其他随行军舰，”周说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“两艘054B型预计将于今年年底下水，”他说。 “如果海试顺利，那么解放军海军可能会订购更多。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;解放军计划到2030年建造至少4个航母战斗群，成为世界第二大现代化蓝水海军在美国之后。 054B型护卫舰、052D型驱逐舰和强大的055型巡洋舰是其航母的关键护航舰艇。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan’s Kishida steps up energy diplomacy with Middle East tour in push for ‘stable’ ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227803/japans-kishida-steps-energy-diplomacy-middle-east-tour-push-stable-ties?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/15/61d6e274-700b-4c43-945c-06170899703b_3dc3d701.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本首相岸田文雄本周末访问中东预计将加强碳氢化合物分析人士表示，日本与该地区之间的脱碳，以及确保东京稳定的能源供应，以区别于包括中国在内的其他大国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在访问沙特阿拉伯期间，阿拉伯联合酋长国(从周日开始，岸田预计将与沙特王储穆罕默德·本·萨勒曼、阿联酋总统穆罕默德·本·扎耶德·阿勒纳哈扬和卡塔尔埃米尔谢赫·塔米姆·本·哈马德·阿勒萨尼会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领导人将讨论广泛的问题据日本外务省称，双方讨论了一系列主题，包括地区和国际问题以及双边关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内阁官房长官松野博和周四表示，岸田的访问还旨在帮助日本企业扩大业务该地区的机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本的大部分能源依赖于从中东进口，包括原油和液化天然气。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;亚洲终于摆脱肮脏了吗？化石燃料拥抱绿色能源？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;神户大学中东问题国际关系教授中村悟表示，成功举办七国集团峰会后，岸田正带着“外交信心”前往阿拉伯湾&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，鉴于日本在碳氢化合物技术和脱碳领域的先进地位，日本希望加强与海湾国家在这些领域的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，日本表示计划投资未来 15 年斥资 1075 亿美元向该国供应氢气，加速利用天然气向低碳经济转型的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界各国都在开发氢气作为一种方式减少钢铁生产和化学制造等一些最难脱碳行业的排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本约 80% 的原油供应依赖沙特阿拉伯和阿联酋，吉冈明子 (Akiko Yoshioka) 表示日本能源经济研究所执行分析师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与这两个国家建立稳定的关系对于日本的能源安全极其重要，”她说，并补充说日本对与石油合作特别感兴趣吉冈表示，卡塔尔传统上一直是日本液化天然气（LNG）的重要供应国，但在 2021 年，一家日本电力公司没有续签长期协议。由于日本人口减少导致能源需求萎缩，日本与该国签订了定期合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然而，次年乌克兰危机爆发，日本在确保液化天然气供应方面开始面临困难，”吉冈说并补充说，正因为如此，岸田希望与多哈重建更紧密的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年，日本液化天然气进口商 JERA（东京电力公司和中部电力公司的合资企业）决定不再续签 25与卡塔尔签订了每年购买 500 万吨液化天然气的合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;全球油价上涨会成为亚洲绿色能源增长的催化剂吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;次年，中国签署了 27与卡塔尔达成的为期一年的协议，向中国石化供应液化天然气，这是迄今为止最长的此类协议，因为波动性促使买家寻求长期供应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;穆罕默德·索利曼，总部位于华盛顿的战略技术和网络安全项目总监中东研究所表示，岸田的访问是对海湾地区以技术转型和全球供应链为重点的经济多元化努力的认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“岸田打算将日本定位为海湾地区增长和发展的合作伙伴。”他说，并补充说，岸田正在继承前首相安倍晋三的遗产，安倍晋三极大地提升了日本作为中东战略伙伴的地区地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年被暗杀的安倍晋三与埃及、以色列、沙特阿拉伯和阿联酋领导人建立了个人关系，据说这使他成为该地区最值得信赖的七国集团领导人之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中东国家正在积极寻求与各国建立伙伴关系索利曼表示，日本、韩国和印度等国家“旨在淡化中东作为地缘政治舞台的权力结构”，从而限制中国和俄罗斯在该地区的“地缘政治活动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;据说，美伊关系的恶化以及阿拉伯国家对华盛顿作为盟友的可靠性日益担忧，使得俄罗斯和中国扩大了在该地区的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3月份，北京促成了一项协议沙特阿拉伯和伊朗恢复外交关系，这被广泛视为中国在该地区战略重要性日益增强的标志。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚会将向新加坡的能源出口置于其绿色经济计划之前吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3 >;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;神户大学的中村表示，中国经济预测的不确定性及其与美国的竞争预计将为其进一步参与该地区注入更大的不确定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本则相反，中村说，日本在投资发展中国家和转让先进技术方面拥有较长的经验，并指出日本今年 5 月签署的向阿联酋转让国防设备和技术的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“沙特阿拉伯和卡塔尔中村说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于中国消费者和房地产市场信心疲弱，以及青年失业率居高不下，大多数全球投资银行都修正了对中国第二季度经济增长的预测，从平均 4% 以上下调至 1% 左右或低于 1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉冈表示，虽然日本作为能源进口国的重要性在 2019 年可能不如中国那么大。从数量上看，东京致力于支持中东国家的碳转型努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岸田访华期间，日本将加强在新环保能源技术方面的合作，包括氢和氨的使用。吉冈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在中东，日本正试图通过在其伙伴国家需要的领域提供技术支持，并将自己展现为长期可靠的合作伙伴，从而与中国区分开来，”她补充道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;索利曼表示，由于日本在该地区基础设施、能源和技术方面的大量投资，日本因其可靠、平衡的外交和技术专长而在中东获得认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然日本的影响力可能不会盖过中国，但仍然可以在推动中东经济发展和促进合作方面发挥有意义的作用。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong raises No 3 typhoon warning signal as Tropical Storm Talim intensifies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227874/hong-kong-raises-no-3-typhoon-warning-signal-tropical-storm-talim-intensifies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 10:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/16/13b90158-24fe-4285-83fd-4b62aab1dfb7_48cfec1b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;此故事已作为公共服务免费提供给我们的读者。请考虑支持《南华早报》的新闻报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着热带风暴塔利姆持续增强，香港天文台于周日上午发布三号台风警告信号，并表示该警告将在全天大部分时间保持有效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;热带风暴距离香港足够近，引发时速 41 公里至 62 公里（25 英里至 38 英里）的强风以及超过 110 公里/小时的阵风，促使香港预报员将信号从“否”升级。上午 5 点 1 分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Talim 在他加禄语中意为“锐利”，截至上午 10 点位于香港东南偏南约 400 公里（248 英里）处。预计将以每小时约15公里的速度向西北偏西移动，大致方​​向为广东省西部及海南岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;热带风暴塔利姆逼近，香港提升三号台风警告信号&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;天文台的热带气旋追踪器显示，该风暴将于午夜时分经过香港以南约250公里处，然后在向海南岛移动时增强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“需要发出更高级别的热带气旋”此后的警告信号取决于塔里木强度的变化以及相关大风与珠江口之间的距离，”预报员说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“海面波涛汹涌，汹涌澎湃。市民应远离海岸线，切勿进行水上活动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;天文台又警告，在塔里木带来的风暴潮及大潮的共同影响下，周一沿海低洼地区可能会出现水浸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港旅游发展局取消周六铜锣湾海滨两场音乐汇演及幻彩咏香江烟火表演出于安全考虑，周日举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月 16 日音乐表演的门票持有者将有资格参加 7 月 22 日至 8 月 6 日期间安排的其他场次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;计划举行该委员会补充说，该市海港寒冷嘉年华的其他活动将取决于最新的天气情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;台风塔利姆席卷日本，造成两人死亡，三人失踪&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港迪士尼乐园表示，其娱乐活动公园周日将继续开放，但会进行有限度的运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主题公园海洋公园已暂停所有户外机械游乐设施，政府每日在湾仔金紫荆广场举行的升旗仪式也被取消。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;连接东涌与宝莲禅寺和该地区天坛大佛的昂坪360缆车也于周日暂停运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中国中央气象台称，塔林将加强为周日下午 5 点左右出现台风，周一下午发展为强台风。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New mode of transport: able-bodied young people in China swap e-bikes for electric wheelchairs to dodge tightened road rules]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3227595/new-mode-transport-able-bodied-young-people-china-swap-e-bikes-electric-wheelchairs-dodge-tightened?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/7466ab0e-bd72-400f-b4e4-4ccc3dae56de_564e791b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;广州的年轻人似乎找到了一种独特的方式来抗议更严格的电子管制规定-自行车——改用电动轮椅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国南方城市的年轻人使用电动轮椅上下班的古怪视频最近在网上疯传。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是这段视频在社交媒体上也引起了意见分歧，许多人对选择这种本质上是残疾人交通方式的想法感到厌烦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有能力的年轻人乘坐专为患者设计的电动轮椅上下班或者残疾人本来应该是有趣的，但我感到更多的是愤怒和悲伤——是人有病还是社会有病？”一位人士评论道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;广州将实施几项新规定，以打击电动自行车的泛滥。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到 2021 年，这些车辆在该市一直是非法的。 -bike number plate registration was first allowed, according to Chinese online outlet Dingduan News.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since then, the number of e-bikes has exploded to an estimated five million in the city of 18.7 million meaning that one in nearly four people rides one.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They are also a major means of transport for the city&#39;s tens of thousands of delivery riders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the number of road violations related to e-bikes have also been on the rise, with Guangzhou traffic police reporting over one million cases in 2021 and 1.6 million last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The proposed regulations, some of which are still under public consultation, include banning e-bikes in certain areas during rush hour or even all day, and a ban on any refits, including adding rear-view mirrors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A resident, surnamed Yang, told Dingduan News that outdated urban design in many areas meant there was less road space for bike riders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The handful of video clips going viral included those of abled people commuting in electric wheelchairs, and another showing a Guangzhou delivery rider carrying an e-bike on his shoulder.&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Official news outlet The Paper claimed that the clips were “gimmicks”, uploaded by online influencers and wheelchair sellers to piggyback on the city&#39;s most trending topic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A medical apparatus shop owner in Guangzhou said a powerchair commute was “unrealistic”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They are slower than normal bikes, and cannot be taken on subway trains or buses easily,” the shop owner, surnamed Liao, told a local TV station.&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;The best-selling electric wheelchair online can only reach speeds of up to 6km/h.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But then, they are not subject to traffic regulations for either motorised or non-motorised vehicles.&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;While some social media users were appalled at the idea, others posted in support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the city&#39;s accessibility can be improved when more people choose to travel by electric wheelchair, then it will also benefit those who actually need them,” said one commenter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another slammed the upcoming tighter e-bike regulations for having triggered the farce: “I don&#39;t support the regulations. People need e-bikes to make a living.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lu Chih-ying, associate professor at the Fujian University of Technology&#39;s School of Traffic and Transportation, said restricting e-bike usage would not improve urban traffic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The best way forward is to redesign the roads and assign special tracks for non-motorised vehicles, Lu told Dingduan News.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In South Korea, 6 bodies pulled from flooded tunnel, as more than 30 killed by heavy rains]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3227872/south-korea-6-bodies-pulled-flooded-tunnel-more-30-killed-heavy-rains?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 11:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/16/2be0d513-4009-4176-a146-80ff5e3dbff4_8be462a9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;South Korean rescuers pulled six bodies from vehicles trapped in a flooded tunnel, as days of heavy rain triggered flash floods and landslides and destroyed homes, leaving more than 30 people dead and forcing thousands to evacuate, officials said Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 400 rescuers, including divers, were searching the tunnel in the central city of Cheongju, where around 15 vehicles, including a bus, got swept away in a flash flood Saturday evening, Seo Jeong-il, chief of the city&#39;s fire department, said in a briefing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nine survivors were rescued from the tunnel, but the total number of passengers trapped in vehicles wasn&#39;t immediately clear, Seo said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are focusing on the search operation as there&#39;s likely more people there,” Seo told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea has been pounded by heavy rains since July 9. The rainfall had forced nearly 6,000 people to evacuate and left 27,260 households without electricity in the past several days while flooding or destroying dozens of homes, the Ministry of the Interior and Safety said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bodies pulled from the vehicles in Cheongju weren&#39;t immediately reflected in the ministry&#39;s official death toll, which was 26 as of Sunday morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea&#39;s weather agency said some parts of the country will continue to receive heavy rain. President Yoon Suk-yeol, who was visiting Ukraine on Saturday, asked Prime Minister Han Duck-soo to mobilise all available resources to respond to the disaster, according to Yoon&#39;s office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk says Twitter has lost half its advertising revenue, company carrying heavy debt]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227873/elon-musk-says-twitter-has-lost-half-its-advertising-revenue-company-carrying-heavy-debt?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 11:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/16/56069f29-70a7-4ea1-bad5-5c218fb778eb_955e3f99.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Twitter owner Elon Musk said on Saturday that the social media platform he bought for US$44 billion last October has lost roughly half of its advertising revenue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re still negative cash flow, due to ~50 per cent drop in advertising revenue plus heavy debt load,” the billionaire said in a post, responding to a user who was giving suggestions on financing for the platform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Need to reach positive cash flow before we have the luxury of anything else,” he added, without further elaboration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Insider Intelligence has reported that Twitter was set to earn less than US$3 billion in 2023, down one-third from 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Elon Musk says his new AI company aims to &#39;understand the universe&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Since he took over Twitter, Musk has tried to reassure advertisers who were concerned about the ouster of top executives, widespread lay-offs and a different approach to content moderation. Some high-profile users who had been banned were allowed back on the site.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, Musk said most of the advertisers who left had returned and that the company might become cash-flow positive in the second quarter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, he hired a new CEO, Linda Yaccarino, an NBCUniversal executive with deep ties to the advertising industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Changes instituted by Musk since his takeover of Twitter have also turned off users and advertisers alike.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, Musk announced that Twitter was limiting verified accounts to reading 10,000 tweets a day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Non-verified users – the free accounts that make up most users – are limited to reading 1,000 tweets per day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New unverified accounts would be limited to 500 tweets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few days later Twitter said TweetDeck, a popular programme that allows users to monitor several accounts at once, will be available only to “verified” users from next month.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Meta takes aim at Twitter with the launch of rival app Threads&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The changes came as Threads, an app launched by Facebook parent Meta as a rival to Twitter, signed up more than 100 million users in its first five days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Twitter is thought to have around 200 million regular users but it has suffered repeated technical failures since Musk bought the platform and sacked thousands of staff.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musk has threatened to sue Meta for stealing trade secrets and intellectual property, claims denied by the company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Associated Press&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UK formally signs up to CPTPP trading bloc as it looks beyond Europe for trade post-Brexit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227871/uk-formally-signs-cptpp-trading-bloc-it-looks-beyond-europe-trade-post-brexit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 09:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/16/ebce3f09-0146-4112-a705-c8efc69dedc3_08a4ec5d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The UK government on Sunday announced it had formally signed a treaty to join a major Indo-Pacific bloc, as it looks beyond Europe for trading opportunities post-Brexit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Business and Trade Secretary Kemi Badenoch signed the accession protocol for the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP) in New Zealand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It makes the United Kingdom the first new member and first European nation to join the bloc since it was created in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CPTPP comprises fellow G7 members Canada and Japan, plus the UK&#39;s long-standing allies Australia and New Zealand, alongside Brunei, Chile, Malaysia, Mexico, Peru, Singapore and Vietnam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has been seen as a bulwark against Chinese dominance in the region, although Beijing has applied to join.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;London has been pushing a “Global Britain” strategy since formally severing nearly 50 years of ties with its nearest neighbours in the European Union three years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sunday&#39;s signing – the formal confirmation of the agreement for UK membership of the CPTPP after nearly two years of talks – will be the UK&#39;s biggest trade deal since Brexit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government said it will cut tariffs for UK exports to CPTPP countries, which with UK membership will have a combined GDP of £12 trillion (US$15.7 trillion), and account for 15 per cent of global GDP.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agreement is expected to come into force in the second half of next year, after parliamentary scrutiny and legislation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Badenoch called the deal “a big boost for British businesses”, opening up opportunities for trade to a market of more than 500 million people and access to the wider region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are using our status as an independent trading nation to join an exciting, growing, forward-looking trade bloc, which will help grow the UK economy and build on the hundreds of thousands of jobs CPTPP-owned businesses already support up and down the country,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UK accession to the CPTPP – the successor to a previous trans-Pacific trade pact that the United States withdrew from in 2017 under president Donald Trump – has been met with a mixed reception.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What is the CPTPP and why is China eager to join?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For Brexit supporters, it has been seen as a chance for the UK to join other trading blocs with faster-growing economies than those closer to home – and boost the country&#39;s international geopolitical and economic clout.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But critics say it will struggle to compensate for the economic damage sustained by leaving the 27-member EU – the world&#39;s largest trading bloc and collective economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts estimate the eventual UK economic boost is £1.8 billion (US$2.2 billion) – a 0.08 per cent annual GDP increase.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government&#39;s spending watchdog, the Office for Budget Responsibility, in April forecast that the London&#39;s Brexit deal with Brussels will reduce long-term productivity by 4.0 per cent compared to when the UK was a member.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia’s religious tilt drives mixed-faith couples overseas to find ‘somewhere more accepting’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/lifestyle-culture/article/3227687/malaysias-religious-tilt-drives-mixed-faith-couples-overseas-find-somewhere-more-accepting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.16 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/2f9e7a07-0ac4-4a78-9323-6e9980f360cf_fddcf6b0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“We said yes!” former lawmaker Yap Soo Huey enthused last month in a joyous Facebook post announcing her engagement in Penang to her Atlanta-based partner – one of a growing number of Malaysians living overseas to enjoy same-sex relationships far from the disapproving glare of the nation&#39;s conservatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Malaysia, which has a multiethnic population with a Muslim majority, does not recognise same-sex marriages, and maintains a colonial-era law prohibiting consensual gay sex. Like neighbouring Muslim-majority nations Indonesia and Brunei, Malaysia also does not recognise civil marriages between Muslims and non-Muslims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This presents couples with a difficult choice: convert, live incognito, break up, or leave the country to stay together.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yap, a former state representative for the Pulau Tikus constituency in Penang, left Malaysia for the United States in 2018 after her term of office ended.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, her post has attracted attention as Malaysia prepares for state polls, with the Penang state government&#39;s Islamic authorities threatening legal action against the couple, and saying the law does not condone “LGBT activities” even though the body has no jurisdiction over non-Muslims and non-citizens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If it indeed happened, actions will be taken under relevant laws,” its chairman Ahmad Zakiyuddin Abdul Rahman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response, the Democratic Action Party women&#39;s wing chief Chong Eng issued a statement saying Yap was “an ordinary person with her own decisions” who left the country some time ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“She is someone independent, she made her decision. Don&#39;t link it to politics,” said Chong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The DAP is competing against the staunchly conservative Perikatan Nasional coalition, which is bolstered by Islamist party PAS and has the support of the largely conservative Malay-Muslim voter pool – about 60 per cent of the electorate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The episode has highlighted the power of political pressure from a resurgent religious lobby, which experts say is steering the country towards greater conservatism rather than more personal freedoms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim&#39;s clawing together a multicultural coalition after November&#39;s polls was seen by some as a chance to step back from a years-long journey into religious conservatism, but critics say he has continued to pander to politicians close to the Malay-Muslim base.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And with state elections set for next month, observers have suggested that Anwar&#39;s administration is sliding further to the right as it seeks Malay votes, with Islamic religious authorities seen overreaching into the lives of non-Muslim Malaysians and non-citizens alike.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a speech in June, Anwar said the role of the country&#39;s Islamic body, known as Jakim, will be expanded “to enhance the country&#39;s dignity and status,” adding the panel is there to nurture “true Islamic values”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Using pseudonyms to avoid a possible backlash, Syafiq, a 40-year-old Malay Muslim joked that his US-issued marriage certificate to Sally, a Malaysian-Chinese woman, is not only recognised worldwide but also on the Ethereum blockchain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But it is not recognised in my home country,” Syafiq told This Week in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A self-described nerd, he runs a video-content company in Kuala Lumpur while his spouse works in communications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After six years of courtship, a 20-hour flight across the globe to tie the knot was the last resort for the couple, who would otherwise have had to abandon their dreams of matrimony unless Sally, a devout Christian, renounced her faith for Syafiq&#39;s – something he could not bring himself to push on her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Malaysia has a hybrid legal system in which sharia courts overseen by individual states have jurisdiction over Muslims in matters such as divorce and inheritance and for some sharia crimes such as alcohol consumption and adultery. The sharia system is limited by the federal law, which is based on the common law system inherited from former colonial ruler Britain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marriage is recognised as a religious matter to be governed by sharia for Muslims. The Islamic legal system prohibits same-sex civil unions, let alone interfaith marriages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The issue was raised again recently by religious affairs minister Na&#39;im Mokhtar in response to a question in the Malaysian parliament.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If a Muslim was to marry someone of a different faith, their partner has to convert to Islam,” Na&#39;im told the assembly.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Bon Odori festival saga sheds light on how Malaysia governs Islam&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;His statement is backed up by the country&#39;s laws.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Islamic Family Law (Federal Territory) Act 1984 states that no man can marry a non-Muslim woman and vice versa, while the earlier Law Reform (Marriage and Divorce) Act 1976 does not apply to Muslims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Understanding the legal hurdles to gaining recognition for their union, Syafiq and Sally decided not to bother registering their marriage while still living in Malaysia, despite knowing it would lead to problems down the road, particularly when it comes to having children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are worried, but we intend to leave this country eventually for somewhere more accepting,” Syafiq said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For those who converted to marry a Muslim, divorce does not spell the end of their relationship with Islam, as requests to leave the religion are unlikely to be approved in Malaysia, where apostasy is illegal under the sharia courts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2015, four people in Sarawak who applied to leave Islam following divorces and the deaths of their spouses were denied after disputes over which of the two legal systems had jurisdiction – and the sharia court refusing to issue them a letter of release from the religion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to This Week in Asia, Maria, who is in the same predicament of wanting to exit the legal binds of her faith following a divorce, called the impact of the judicial set-up “a macabre injustice” towards her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An ethnic Chinese Christian, she converted to Islam to marry her long-time Malay-Muslim partner only to find herself unable to come to terms with being a Muslim, leading to the dissolution of the marriage after just a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Armed&#39; Islamist parade in Malaysia deepens fears of growing conservatism&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;She has since found herself in a conundrum when it comes to dating as any non-Muslim she meets in Malaysia in future will not want to commit to a relationship, knowing that they too have to convert to Islam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two competing legal systems could also cause problems after her death. Her body needs to be cleaned and prepared according to Islamic rituals and buried in a Muslim cemetery – despite her actual religious conviction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instances of what some have termed “body-snatching” by religious authorities have occurred in the past, leading to racial tension in multicultural Malaysia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There needs to be a greater conversation about this. Right now, no one dares to talk about it,” said Maria, who admits that she herself is scared to discuss her experience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moderate Muslim advocacy groups such as G25 have for years criticised Malaysia&#39;s stance on freedom of religion, arguing the matter is unconstitutional.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its 2020 report on the “Administration of Matters Pertaining to Islam in Malaysia”, the group pointed out that the constitution guarantees every person in Malaysia the right to profess, practise and propagate their religion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no constitutionally permitted ground to prohibit the mere profession of one&#39;s religion,” the report read.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the prevailing status quo, Shafiq said he and his wife hoped to be able to return to Malaysia to retire one day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is still home … I hope things change eventually,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 16 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>