<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Putin visits generals leading Ukraine offensive in south Russia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3231648/putin-visits-generals-leading-ukraine-offensive-south-russia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 17:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/19/a673a4d3-2f5b-491f-b811-7025d5ad3995_37b7409e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯总统普京在军队中会见莫斯科乌克兰攻势司令克里姆林宫周六早些时候表示，总部位于俄罗斯南部城市顿河畔罗斯托夫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科没有透露会议举行时间的详细信息，但官方媒体发布的视频显示会议是在晚上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科没有透露会议举行的具体时间。 p>;&lt;p>;在美国批准将荷兰和丹麦的 F-16 转移到基辅后，俄罗斯领导人会见了将军们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“弗拉基米尔·普京在位于基辅的特种军事行动小组总部举行了会议。顿河畔罗斯托夫，”克里姆林宫在一份声明中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国家元首听取了俄罗斯武装部队总参谋长瓦列里·格拉西莫夫、指挥员和其他高级官员的通报。俄新社发布了一段视频，视频中这位俄罗斯领导人身穿西装，在黑暗中从吉普车中走出来，受到身着军装、面带微笑的格拉西莫夫的迎接。握手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还显示普京正在主持与高级陆军参谋长的会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;前法国领导人表示乌克兰在北约中没有地位，妥协是结束战争的关键&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;顿河畔罗斯托夫 - 俄罗斯南部靠近乌克兰的一座城市 - 已成为俄罗斯军队在乌克兰的作战中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这里也是瓦格纳雇佣军发生戏剧性武装叛变的地点。六月，他们在停止叛乱之前短暂接管了罗斯托夫的军队总部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦格纳想要推翻的格拉西莫夫此后很少在公开场合露面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京很少前往俄罗斯在乌克兰攻势附近的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当普京会见他的将军时，基辅表示，在夜间的袭击中击落了十几架俄罗斯无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯军队表示，它挫败了乌克兰对克里米亚的袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2022 年 2 月开始的冲突双方均报告称，​​随着乌克兰发动反攻，夺回俄罗斯控制的领土，无人机定期入侵。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;基辅空军表示击落了 15 架俄罗斯无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯军队“使用‘Shahed-136/131’攻击无人机从北部发起攻击。空军在 Telegram 上表示，总共从库尔斯克地区发射了 17 架攻击无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，“北部、中部以及西部地区”的防空系统已启动。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自废除允许通过航运枢纽安全出口谷物的协议以来，莫斯科加大了对乌克兰在黑海和多瑙河的港口基础设施的攻击力度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯军队表示，在俄罗斯军队摧毁了针对莫斯科及其黑海舰队的乌克兰无人机的第二天，它击退了乌克兰对克里米亚的袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“8月19日晚上，基辅政权企图发动恐怖袭击俄罗斯军方在一份声明中表示，“S-200防空系统的防空导弹在克里米亚领土上变成了打击版本。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国将向乌克兰派遣F-16战斗机来自丹麦和荷兰的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;黑海半岛于 2014 年被莫斯科吞并，在俄罗斯近一年半的攻势中经常成为攻击目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在反攻过程中，基辅一再表示，其目标是解放被莫斯科夺走的领土，包括克里米亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基辅周五对美国决定允许丹麦和荷兰在飞行员完成任务后将美国 F-16 战斗机移交给乌克兰表示欢迎。训练有素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基辅几个月来一直在努力引进先进的西方战斗机，以取代其空军所遭受的严重损失，该空军主要驾驶俄罗斯飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰总统弗拉基米尔泽伦斯基宣布他周六将前往瑞典与瑞典首相、政党和王室进行会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在社交媒体上表示，他的会议将重点讨论“伙伴关系、国防合作、欧盟一体化以及共同的欧洲-大西洋安全”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan should heed fishing industry concerns about Fukushima radioactive water discharge plan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231280/japan-should-heed-fishing-industry-concerns-about-fukushima-radioactive-water-discharge-plan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/460be9bb-01b2-493e-9eb4-831798b11f01_ff045b01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本计划开始向日本排放超过 100 万吨放射性废水太平洋不久，对该地区渔业的担忧充耳不闻。太平洋地区的渔民本来就面临着气候变化和过度捕捞的压力，现在他们的食品安全声誉又面临着威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;12 年前的海啸袭击后，福岛核电站发生故障，导致放射性后果。这将持续数十年。用于冷却受损核反应堆的水不断积聚，并储存在巨大的水箱中。电厂运营商东京电力公司今年计划将这些废水排入太平洋，预计至少会持续三十年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但据报道，日本政府已承诺不会这样做，除非它有利益相关者的支持。渔业界对该计划并不满意。他们的捕获物的声誉受到威胁。消费者，尤其是日本的消费者，要求知道他们的海鲜是否安全，并且越来越意识到该地区渔业资源面临的环境压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们担心计划中的缓慢释放放射性废物的影响流入海洋的水对海洋生物和受影响海鲜的消费者造成影响。当谈到日本食品的安全和声誉时，也许政府应该采用其他人坚持的预防原则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 20 年前，当我收到一封信时，我是塔斯马尼亚政府的高级顾问日本一家主要贸易公司的负责人要求塔斯马尼亚证明其农产品不含转基因生物 (GMO)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塔斯马尼亚高质量食品出口的声誉受到威胁，政府做出了当时颇具争议的决定，即世界上第一个暂停使用转基因生物的决定。这一决定完全是为了保护市场声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科学建议褒贬不一，但基本上并不关心，就像今天关于福岛废水缓慢排放到太平洋的科学建议一样。在福岛核事故发生之前，科学观点也认为该工厂是安全的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行业利益相关者和公民需要放心，他们的食品供应是安全的。如果渔业及其客户（更不用说地区国家）不满意，那么日本政府还有更多工作要做，需要进行磋商，或许还可以找到替代解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塔斯马尼亚发现其预防立场对转基因生物的重视为其纯净、高品质的食品赢得了更大的国际认可。日本也可能会发现，对其放射性废水的排放采取预防措施将提升其作为良好地区公民的声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;核废料在太平洋地区是一个特别敏感的问题。 20世纪，美国和法国在那里测试了许多核武器，放射性尘埃的环境和社会后果至今仍挥之不去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;太平洋岛国对核试验抱有一致的担忧，对福岛核电站放射性废水排放到海洋表示担忧。太平洋岛屿论坛秘书长亨利·普纳指出日本计划中存在“严重的信息空白”，并呼吁推迟该计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;太平洋渔业已经面临许多挑战。气候变化正在引发更多的自然灾害、不规则潮汐、海平面上升和水温上升，所有这些都影响海洋生物和岛屿社区。随着时间的推移，对生物多样性的威胁可能会影响整个海洋食物链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;面对此类生存挑战，太平洋岛国领导人长期以来一直站在要求全球采取更大行动以摆脱污染能源的最前沿基础设施和工业转向更绿色的解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，大量流氓渔船非法和不受监管的过度捕捞正在严重消耗一些渔业资源，对蓝鳍金枪鱼和黄鳍金枪鱼的种群造成严重影响。该地区各国海上监视和执法不力，导致这一问题长期恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，要确保太平洋渔业的安全和可持续性，还有很多事情可以做。不仅水域应保持不受污染，各国还必须采取更多措施应对气候变化和非法、不受管制的过度捕捞的威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于太平洋发展中国家来说，渔业是其最重要的产业之一，提供岛屿社区许多人急需外汇和生计。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于该地区主要经济体的大型海鲜消费市场来说，海鲜的安全性和可持续性是人们日益关注的问题，食品安全将成为人们日益关注的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;渔业需要更大的声音——而且必须听到这种声音。首先，日本可以开始倾听。对福岛废水处理采取预防性措施将是朝着正确方向迈出的宝贵一步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fewer Hongkongers applying to buy subsidised flats could be sign of healthier market, possibly a ‘good thing’, housing minister says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3231641/fewer-hongkongers-applying-buy-subsidised-flats-could-be-sign-healthier-market-possibly-good-thing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 15:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/19/9d8af107-a5e2-414f-a864-9ab88c1fb831_e2960343.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港房屋部长周六表示，申请购买资助房屋的居民可能会减少这是市场更健康的迹象，她称这一变化可能是“好事”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;房屋局局长何永贤还透露，当局将提前让居民搬入超过 10,000 个公共住宅区的日期&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;何先生在电台节目中表示，“居民将能够提前五至八个月入住公寓”，他指的是青衣和屯门的两个地点，这两个地点将在现已从 2024 年初开始部分开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港法院推迟对当局批准高尔夫球场住房计划的判决&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;何还试图解决近期购买资助单位申请量下降的问题根据居者有其屋计划。该计划下的房屋今年超额认购了 18 倍，低于 2022 年的 27 倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着 18 倍的超额认购，这个数字只是从不正常的情况调整到更健康的情况，”她说。 “当我们的住房供应量增加时，如果这个数字缓慢调整，这可能是一件好事，情况正在朝着更理想的状态发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她解释说，减少的主要原因是公寓数量增加。最新一批出售的单位超过 9,100 套。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年约有 8,900 套单位可供出售，占市场价格的 51%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，居民以市价 62% 的价格在启德、观塘、屯门和元朗等地区的六处地点提供房屋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于最受欢迎地段的两栋楼的启悦阁综合大楼启德的住宅区有超过 2,000 个单位在售，而观塘北的三个发展项目则提供超过 3,500 个住宅单位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;何还提供了政府计划的最新信息，以提前让符合资格的居民搬进公屋的时间表出租单位竣工后立即出租。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“提高香港公屋租户免申报资产的年龄限制”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;房屋部长表示居民可以入住青青区的2,000个单位预计于 2024 年初在宜及屯门进行勘察，较原计划提早约五至八个月，并指出屋村内的大厦已部分完工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计约 10,000 个单位可于 2025 年期间准备好供居民入住&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超在首份施政报告中宣布提前入伙的计划，作为解决香港公营房屋短缺的措施之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net NET&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/分区>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Japanese Schindler’ likely to have saved fewer Jews in WWII than Tokyo claimed: academics]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3231495/japanese-schindler-likely-have-saved-fewer-jews-wwii-tokyo-claimed-academics?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/0adf9429-5983-4a88-932d-3938e01d9d7f_404cf498.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;东京夸大了一位被称为“日本人”的外交官 1940 年在立陶宛的活动一些以色列和日本学者表示，“辛德勒”是为了赢得以色列和美国犹太人利益的青睐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还声称，日本政府宣扬杉原千亩是一位民族英雄的说法，发放签证以从纳粹手中拯救数千名犹太人，以改变国内和国际上关于日本是 1930 年代至 1940 年代侵略者、被指控实施南京大屠杀、慰安妇和强迫劳工的军国主义国家的说法以及对盟军战俘的普遍虐待。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海法大学教授 Rotem Kowner 三月份在《美国历史评论》上发表的一篇论文称，杉原“已成为日本的民族英雄”在许多其他国家被认为是美德的典范”，但这种英雄主义已被日本的动机“操纵”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥斯卡·辛德勒 – 因 1993 年史蒂文·斯皮尔伯格获奖影片《辛德勒的名单》而闻名– 是一位德国实业家和纳粹党成员，尽管如此，他还是拯救了至少 1,200 名犹太人的生命，这些犹太人在被占领的波兰的搪瓷器和军火工厂工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 20 世纪 90 年代中期以来，杉原就出现在日本学校的历史书中记载，这名外交官利用自己的职务，向逃离的犹太人发放了 6,000 多份签证，让他们穿越西伯利亚前往安全的日本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些记录称，他每天工作 20 个小时，直到被迫工作1941 年 9 月 4 日离开考纳斯领事馆。当时，立陶宛是苏联的一部分，苏联于 1941 年 6 月 22 日被纳粹德国（与日本和其他国家一起属于轴心国的成员）入侵。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;电影中对杉原故事的描述显示，他在火车离开车站时将签证从窗户扔了出去，而且据称他在离开前将官方签证印章交给了犹太人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;杉原自己的儿子 Nobuki 于 2019 年在明斯克接受《以色列时报》采访时表示，这两起事件都没有发生，而且他父亲的故事有许多额外的修饰，该故事是根据他母亲 Yukiko 出版的书改编的。 1995 年，也就是他去世九年后，享年 86 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nobuki 说他的母亲当时不在立陶宛，想写一部“小说，而不是纪录片”，但杉原的故事很快就成为了现实。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kowner 和其他学者，包括名古屋名城大学的 Chiharu Inaba 和耶路撒冷希伯来大学亚洲研究系的 Meron Medzini，都指出了日本政府对杉原的描述中的漏洞。据《以色列时报》报道，这些差异包括忽视了驻考纳斯的荷兰外交官 Jan Zwartendijk 可以说更为关键的作用，他通过签发前往日本和旅行的证件帮助拯救了数千名犹太人的生命。最终荷兰人占领了库拉索岛，并且实际上已经从日本的故事中消失了；以及声称杉原在战后最终返回日本时因不服从命令而被外务省解雇的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更平淡的事实是，随着外务省的大幅精简，没有他的位置了学者们坚持认为，日本投降后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们指出，杉原在他的祖国其他地方仍在继续抬升。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国将日本战犯的骨灰撒入大海，以防止其死亡。崇拜：解密文件&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;八百津镇自称是杉原的出生地，拥有一座纪念馆和博物馆，每年吸引约 20,000 人前来瞻仰“日本辛德勒”。博物馆工作人员坚称年长的居民记得杉原。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，杉原信树告诉《泰晤士报》，他的父亲出生在约 40 公里外的美浓市，从未在八百津市居住过。他说，整个小说都是为了吸引游客而创作的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个非常困难的问题，很难得出准确的结论，但毫无疑问，在我看来，已经有东京国士馆大学国际关系学教授雅科夫·津伯格 (Yakov Zinberg) 表示：“这个故事的基本内容是事实，”来自圣彼得堡的犹太人津伯格说。杉原无疑拯救了生命，但细节更难以确定，而且现代的说法“非常有问题”，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在 20 世纪 80 年代之前，没有人谈论过杉原，当时日本与美国的关系还很糟糕。”非常好，”津伯格说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一个暗示的动机是，日本相信犹太人在媒体上很强大，尤其是在美国，所以他们提出了杉原的问题，以便在媒体上得到积极的反映，这突然使他受欢迎。这是在首相安倍晋三领导下发生的，此举背后有明确的政治考虑。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“另一个动机是恢复日本在西方的声誉，”津伯格补充道。 “在中国发生的事情以及日本皇军犯下的暴行对东京来说是可耻的，因此日本能够选出一个真正拯救了很多犹太人的人是有帮助的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本政府长达 16 年的竞选活动 — — 科纳尔表示，之所以推迟，是因为人们怀疑他冒着生命或职业地位的危险来援助犹太人 — — 1985 年，以色列因杉原在立陶宛的行为而将其授予“国际义人”之一。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;吉田明夫是一名新教神父，也是距离广岛约 60 公里的福山镇大屠杀教育中心主任，他承认，对杉原行为不加批判的叙述中的一些内容并不完全相符。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“目前尚不清楚有多少人能够使用他的签证逃离立陶宛，”他说。 “他妻子书中的数字是6000多，但现在我们认为可能会更少。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在学术界公认的数字在2000到3000之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “重要的是要记住，他是一位人道主义者，毫无疑问他拯救了生命，”吉田补充道。 “即使这个数字被夸大了，但这也不会改变。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How has Hong Kong’s West Kowloon arts hub landed in financial woes? The big picture behind price cuts, real estate rejigs and a 2025 deadline]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3231639/how-has-hong-kongs-west-kowloon-arts-hub-landed-financial-woes-big-picture-behind-price-cuts-real?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/19/bf727a10-72d9-444b-92b8-e51b46deefaf_7533613f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港用了数十年的时间来规划和建设其艺术中心，并将其设想为区域文化中心镶嵌在维多利亚港九龙一侧的宝石。但在最后一个主要景点故宫博物院开张仅一年后，这个雄心勃勃的项目就陷入了财务困境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西九龙文化区管理局主席唐英年表示。本周，当 216 亿港元（28 亿美元）的政府种子基金预计将于 2025 年 3 月用完时，该中心可能被迫停止在​​其两个博物馆和剧院举办活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此处，《华盛顿邮报》解开争议并解释了这个大型项目如何陷入危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;唐警告说，2025 年文化区三大地标的表演和展览“将无法继续进行”如果没有找到新的收入来源，M+当代艺术博物馆、香港故宫博物院和戏曲中心等场馆的成本将大幅削减。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;管理层已“大幅削减”成本，再削减就如同“血脉喷张”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》周五的检查显示，这三个场馆正在举办约 20 场表演和展览，其中包括日本艺术家草间弥生 (Yayoi Kusama) 作品的画廊展示和关于宋怀贵，20世纪80年代和1990年代的中国时尚偶像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构首席执行官冯程淑仪最近也向《华盛顿邮报》表示，经过一系列紧缩措施，该中心2022年的赤字- 23 日的预算被削减三分之一，至 7.18 亿港元，低于之前预估的 10.7 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“单腿跳跃”：香港西九龙艺术中心首席执行官描述资金困境&lt;/h3>;&lt; h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2008年，政府向该机构拨款216亿港元，但不到十年后，这家艺术中心运营商就已陷入财务困难。政府于 2017 年 1 月作出回应，采取了“强化财务安排”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然没有提供直接资金，但当局获得了面积 366,620 平方米（390 万平方英尺）的酒店、办公室和住房的开发权。 ）的总建筑面积。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府表示，通过在商业和住宅项目的建设、运营和转让模式下与私人开发商建立收入分享安排，该机构可以获得稳定的经常性收入来源.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017年的安排要求当局保留对商业空间的完整所有权，包括占建筑面积20%的公寓。但据消息人士透露，管理机构目前正在寻求改变这些限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然该机构尚未公布其向政府提交的融资计划的详细信息，但两位消息人士接近向机构暗示正在考虑出售住宅单位。一位消息人士称，所得款项将用于“再投资”，以产生长期投资收益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但一位资深房地产开发商对此想法表示担忧，称这将影响附近已有项目的开发商的投资计划.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“开发商肯定对市场上任何新的地块都感兴趣，”这位要求匿名的开发商表示。 “但政府过去说西九龙不卖，只租。附近的房产可能会受到影响。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于香港房地产市场疲软，公寓销售的收入可能并不乐观。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;对香港艺术中心土地使用建议的财务吸引力提出疑问&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;九龙站上方邻近的住宅区是香港最昂贵的住宅区之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学者们也对该计划泼了一盆冷水，指出出售资产的一次性收益将浸会大学经济学家 Billy Mak Sui-choi 表示，当局可以选择通过发行债券来筹集资金。但政府可能必须为该债券提供担保，这违背了邓小平为该中心做出的自力更生的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会议员林兆劳同意发行债券不会为该中心提供长期解决方案。中心的财务困境。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该艺术中心在 Covid-19 大流行期间开设了当代视觉艺术博物馆 M+ 和故宫博物院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据该机构称，尽管这两家博物馆的成本回收率达到了 40% 左右，在全球博物馆中属于最高水平，但它们尚未实现财务自给自足。费率是指一个机构对其运营成本的贡献程度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，故宫博物院宣布从9月27日起提高门票价格，以期改善其财务状况。 M+从7月29日起将门票价格下调四分之一，促销活动将持续到9月30日，以吸引夏季游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2015年，时任行政长官时任行政长官时，故宫博物院出人意料地被纳入该地区。林郑月娥绕过公众咨询，安排香港赛马会出资兴建。此举使当局产生了未包含在该区原始捐赠中的额外费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港西九龙艺术中心提交了重组财务的计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;开发商建造的写字楼和酒店的收入原本是为了支付M+和其他艺术设施的运营费用，但该地块商业项目的招标恰逢疫情和房地产市场疲软，导致开发商的投资兴趣减弱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当局不得不将商业项目的建设、运营和转让模式的运营期限延长至48年，以吸引更多的兴趣。新鸿基地产于去年11月经过第二轮竞标后中标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦经济学家表示，建设商业空间是一项昂贵的资本投资，且投资回收期较长。租赁物业——尤其是零售空间——在第一个十年的回报率也往往较低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;疫情还意外地引发了建筑成本的上升，并阻止了游客在边境重新开放之前在艺术中心消费，他说。补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mak 指出了该学区最初的目标是了解政府是否应该介入以承担更多费用。 “我们到底想在西九龙实现什么目标？不就是为了吸引更多游客来旅游消费，强化香港国际城市的形象吗？”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Underperforming civil servants in Hong Kong to be sacked ‘in a few months’ rather than current 2 years under new mechanism]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3231638/underperforming-civil-servants-hong-kong-be-sacked-few-months-rather-current-2-years-under-new?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 14:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/19/6eee86b5-a253-49f9-ac19-ff915b3e8c09_75a8f1f9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港持续表现不佳的公务员可能会在“几个月内”被解雇该市公务员事务主管表示，建议采用精简机制，而不是目前平均两年多的时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公务员事务局局长杨何佩恩周六还表示，将需要公务员在新的行为守则下保持政治中立的精神，尽管确切的措辞可能会更新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港公务员事务局本月早些时候向工会通报了一项计划，该计划将加快对持续表现不佳的员工强制退休的计划公共工资单上的 174,000 名工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然公务员工会担心该机制会损害士气，但公务员部长为该提议辩护，称严格纪律表现不佳者反而会对辛勤工作的同事有好处&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“公务员工作从来都不是‘铁饭碗’，”杨在周六的一个电台节目中说道，指的是中国关于有保障的工作保障的说法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去五年，当局按照现有机制处理了16起案件。在这 13 起结案中，有 4 名公务员保住了工作，7 名自行离职，只有 2 名被迫退休。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她表示，自 2005 年以来实施的现行程序不会采取任何措施。平均不到 24 个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于流程冗长，部门负责人不愿解决该问题，因此经常将工人调到其他职位。但如果一名工人一直表现不佳，这样的调动并不能解决问题。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港对表现不佳的公务员的打压可能会损害工会的士气&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据该计划最快将于今年生效，面临强制退休的公务员将有两个而不是四个窗口提出申诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“独立小组”的审查将被取消&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨表示，根据建议的修改，该流程可能会在“几个月内”完成，并预计会略有改善。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨女士表示，经常考评分数最低的政府工作人员，会在强制退休机制启动前接受辅导和培训，她认为这种情况很少见&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，涉及个人偏见的案件将被高级官员和公务员事务局以及公共服务委员会的外部成员清除。公务员还将有充足的机会解释他们的不良记录并反驳不公平的指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;根据新建议，香港公务员将需要宣布逮捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“通过简化机制“我们希望表明，我们将严肃处理工作表现不达标的同事，并希望同事‘醒悟’自己，做得更好。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，她裁定提出立法者关于建立奖金制度以鼓励积极表现的建议，并警告这种激励措施可能会阻碍负责执法或申请人审查的官员正确履行职责，因为他们可能会试图避免投诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首席执行官李家超在去年十月的首次施政报告中承诺“及时”解雇表现不佳的公务员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李家超还承诺在今年第一季度推出修订后的《公务员守则》年，但杨周六表示，修订后的守则仍处于草案阶段，不再有明确的时间表。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港公务员解聘机制早就应该进行重组&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;杨解释说，公务员事务局在收到公众和立法会议员的大量意见后，正在重新审议守则的第二稿。她补充说，一些建议提到了官员必须研究的“历史文件”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她曾表示，修订后的守则中公务员将不再受到政治中立的约束。她在节目中表示，该要求的精神将保留在未来的守则中，但当局尚未决定是否采用新的措辞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公务员事务局局长去年10月曾表示，新的守则是根据rising geopolitical tensions and “incidents in recent years”, a possible reference to the anti-government protests that rocked the city in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Old man style’ trend sees young women in China seek comfort over style with oversized men’s clothes to avoid body-shaming]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3231179/old-man-style-trend-sees-young-women-china-seek-comfort-over-style-oversized-mens-clothes-avoid-body?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/5bf2f2dd-f909-4688-a31b-b9a5079f490f_0d6fe096.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A new fashion trend dubbed “old man style” is now taking over young Chinese women&#39;s wardrobes as they increasingly seek comfort over beauty with oversized men&#39;s clothes to combat body-shaming.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese Gen Z May said she struggles to fit into women&#39;s clothes in any size lower than an XXL despite weighing only 50kg.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like many women in China, May has recently discovered a whole new world;就她而言，那是在和父亲一起购买男装时。 She told Chinese media outlet Sanlian Lifelab that men&#39;s clothes fit her quite well, and she had begun wearing them to “feel respected again”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a revealing anecdote about how women&#39;s clothes are being labelled as larger than they really are, user @Waayikou on mainland social media platform Xiaohongshu said an XL size camisole top she recently bought from an online shop would only have “fitted the three-year-old me”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many women in China with similar experiences have said no to what they see as the body-shaming sizing of women&#39;s clothes and turned to oversized menswear as part of the old man style movement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Xiaohongshu, the #laotoufeng, or #oldmanstyle in English, had attracted 66,000 views at the time of writing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Female social media users have summarised various advantages men&#39;s clothes have over those designed for women.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some said the comfortable style of men&#39;s clothes that are “designed to accommodate a man&#39;s beer belly” can prevent wardrobe malfunctions and liberate them from worrying about gaining weight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For many, the palette of men&#39;s wardrobes features classic colours such as black, white, beige, grey and navy blue, reducing fears about an outfit quickly going out of fashion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others have linked the style trend to the popular genderless fashion movement in the West. One woman commented: “Widen your horizons, you will realise men&#39;s clothes at Zara are the same as women&#39;s clothes at Balenciaga.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some female office workers have also opted for men&#39;s clothes to appear “professional and mature”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A woman from Shanghai identified as Azaki told Sanlian Lifelab that she only wears “old man style” clothes to “work easily and not feel bad when they get dirty”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another primary motivation for many women is that men&#39;s clothes are often cheaper. On China&#39;s largest e-commerce site Taobao, a men&#39;s vest is priced at around 20 yuan (US$3) whereas a women&#39;s camisole is usually triple this, with some priced at more than 100 yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taobao is an affiliate of Alibaba Group Holding that owns the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Chinese women consumers have increasingly protested against the “pink tax”, referring to the gender discrimination of products marketed to women being more expensive than identical products for men.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nepal’s older LGBTQ people feel ‘invisible’ – alienated from society, activist community]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3231557/nepals-older-lgbtq-people-feel-invisible-alienated-society-activist-community?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/8f0c993c-a9c4-488d-bbb8-9778da324e00_828b045d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;At age 11, Sapana Chaudhary knew she was not like the other boys. 17岁时，她因女性化而受到欺负，但仍被父母强迫嫁给一个同龄的女孩。 Now 55 and a parent-of-three who identifies as a transgender woman, Chaudhary reflects on a life shaped by prejudice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Identity struggles in Nepal have been amplified by the difficulty of family life, she said, with three children relentlessly urging her not to dress as a woman, while her son and daughter-in-law have asked her to move out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My son tore all my women&#39;s clothing and said I bring shame to the family,” said Chaudhary, who now lives alone in eastern Nepal. “但是我该怎么办呢？ This is who I am.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chaudhary is one of many LGBTQ Nepalis over the age of 50, some of whom have been married against their will or to meet social norms, struggling to share in the gains made in law and social recognition in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 2022 survey of 100 LGBTQ individuals aged 50 to 75 by Mitini Nepal – a charity promoting lesbian, bisexual, and transgender rights – found that 15 per cent were in heterosexual relationships, with some married due to pressure to hide their sexuality or being forced to by family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sixty-five per cent of those surveyed said they lived under emotional and psychological pressure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nepal is touted for its progressive LGBTQ laws in a conservative region. A new republican constitution enacted in 2015 was hailed for granting equal protection to LGBTQ citizens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a landmark order in June, Nepal&#39;s Supreme Court allowed LGBTQ couples to register to get married under a temporary provision – another first in South Asia – until the country passed a marriage equality law.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Milestone&#39;: LGBTQ Nepalis welcome top court&#39;s marriage decision&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;However, a district court in Kathmandu has refused to register a transgender woman and a heterosexual man – citing the law that only allows marriage between a man and a woman.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rights activists say marriage equality has fallen to the wayside due to unwilling conservative lawmakers and bureaucratic hurdles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nepal&#39;s LGBTQ community is estimated to number more than 900,000 people, among a population of around 30 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 2021 census, however, showed only 2,928 people in the country identifying as “other”, rather than male or female. Rights activists say this is a gross underestimation, with many people uncomfortable disclosing their true selves or not wanting to be identified as “other”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;As the authorities and legal system drag their feet, the painful outcomes for many are multiplying, advocates say. Sukumaya Magar lived with her lesbian partner for nearly three decades until she sadly died three years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since then, the 52-year-old Magar has had more than her grief to cope with. As the relationship was not legally recognised by the state, she&#39;s unable to receive a monthly allowance of 2,660 rupees (US$20) provided to widows by the government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Magar is also too young to be eligible for a state social security allowance of around US$32 a month that&#39;s reserved solely for single women over the age of 60. As a result, she says she has virtually no source of income.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If I were married to a man and widowed, I would have received the government allowance [for widows] without any issue,” she said. “It&#39;s very sad to be discriminated against because I loved and lived with another woman, when the law says we are equal.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Employment and income disparities afflict Nepal&#39;s LGBTQ community, especially those who are older.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Mitini Nepal survey showed that 86 per cent of the respondents did not receive state benefits – including the single woman allowance and social security allowance – with their age, gender identity and sexual orientation believed to be the reason.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chaudhary commutes for over an hour to the border with India for work, carrying luggage for travellers and working ad hoc at nearby shops.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But even though she dresses as a man, she often receives less than the wage agreed upon and believes this is discrimination – by both travellers and shop owners – because of her appearance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Kathmandu, 55-year-old Kanchi Maya Tamang, a transgender woman, said her appearance restricted any employment opportunities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A daily wage worker in shops, restaurants and on construction sites, she said she “feels like a woman” but often must “dress like a man” to avoid harassment from her landlord, neighbours and prospective employers, a situation exacerbated by her age.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They don&#39;t want to give us work because we are old,” Tamang said, adding this marginalisation even extended to the activist community. “I feel we are invisible and even left behind by the same activists fighting for [LGBTQ] rights.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Malaysia&#39;s religious tilt drives mixed-faith couples to &#39;more accepting&#39; places&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sarita KC, the executive director of Mitni Nepal, who identifies as bisexual, acknowledged that the country&#39;s LGBTQ movement had previously overlooked older individuals and their specific needs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We need to document their struggles because we&#39;ll also get there some day. We&#39;re also gradually advocating for their rights and well-being with the authorities, as many officials are almost unaware about their existence.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many older LGBTQ Nepalis had lower literacy rates limiting their access to information, jobs and better pay, KC added, while prejudice from relatives had contributed to their vulnerability to physical and emotional abuse, resulting in loneliness and poor mental health for many.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These older people “need to be heard and recognised”, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Tamang, who does not have a partner, said her isolation drove her to seek solace in alcohol and cigarettes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet, she said: “I don&#39;t regret not marrying for the sake of society.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Some older people have learned to navigate a pathway between their identities and relationships.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ram Chandra Chaudhary, a 52-year-old gay man from the far-western Kailai district, said he had married at 14 and only discovered his sexual orientation much later on in life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said his wife and children were aware of his identity, but “don&#39;t say anything”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hundreds of miles away, on the other side of the country in Saptari district, a 65-year-old transgender woman known to many as Budhiya – a derogatory term often used for older women – said she married “for society&#39;s sake”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She still lives with her wife and while most of their five children are married and largely accepting of her, she often still dresses as a man due to discrimination and name-calling in her village, despite growing awareness of the LGBTQ community.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family had accepted her partner, a 57-year-old openly gay man from the same area, whom she has known for most of her life and been involved with for many years, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;ve made my family and my community aware,” she added. “I did what needed to be done – took care of the family and educated my children.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Coronavirus: New Covid variant with ‘high number of mutations’ found in Britain, ‘significant community transmission’ likely]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3231632/coronavirus-new-covid-variant-high-number-mutations-found-britain-significant-community-transmission?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 13:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_coronavirus_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/19/7c81b137-29f3-4975-a334-3ee5620a1075_95abe66b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A new coronavirus variant with a “high number of mutations” has been detected in Britain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The BA.2.86 mutation was identified in the UK on Friday in someone with no recent travel history, the British Health Security Agency said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This means there could already be “significant community transmission” among Britons, the agency added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The strain was first detected in Denmark on July 24 and was also found in that country on July 31, the same day it was discovered in Israel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A case in the US was detected earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The variant is said to be gnomically distant from its likely ancestor the BA.2 variant, nicknamed “stealth Omicron”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That variant gained its nickname from the fact it is more transmissible than the original Omicron strain, which originated in southern Africa and was first detected in the UK in late 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The UKHSA said there is “insufficient data” to assess the new strain&#39;s relative severity or how likely it is to evade the protection offered by vaccines compared to other currently-circulating variants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agency said it would continue to monitor the spread of the variant closely while checks to determine the risks it may pose continue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Francois Balloux, Professor of computational systems biology and director of the UCL Genetics Institute at University College London, said the new strain is “the most striking Sars-CoV-2 strain the world has witnessed since the emergence of Omicron” with more than 30 mutations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However it is unlikely to cause a fresh wave of severe disease and deaths, or prompt fresh restrictions on people&#39;s daily lives, because most people have some immunity to the illness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: “Even in the worst-case scenario where BA.2.86 caused a major new wave of cases, we are not expecting to witness comparable levels of severe disease and death than we did earlier in the pandemic when the Alpha, Delta or Omicron variants spread.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Most people on Earth have now been vaccinated and/or infected by the virus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even if people get reinfected by BA.2.86, immune memory will still allow their immune system to kick in and control the infection far more effectively.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It remains that a large wave of infection by BA.2.86, or any future comparable variant, would be an unwelcome event.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The strain is likely to have emerged in an immunocompromised person who later spread it, the professor added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UKHSA deputy director Dr Meera Chand said: “V-23AUG-01 was designated as a variant on August 18 2023 on the basis of international transmission and significant mutation of the viral genome.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This designation allows us to monitor it through our routine surveillance processes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are aware of one confirmed case in the UK. UKHSA is currently undertaking detailed assessment and will provide further information in due course.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 13:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Smooth Hong Kong arrival for cruise ship as passengers use new transport set-up; tourism chief expects terminal operators to share costs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3231634/smooth-hong-kong-arrival-cruise-ship-passengers-use-new-transport-set-tourism-chief-expects-terminal?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 13:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/19/b7dc983f-84b9-4849-a51f-d344f9cbdc65_e5685e7e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;More than 4,500 cruise ship passengers had a smooth arrival in Hong Kong on Saturday morning under new transport and logistics measures, with the tourism chief saying he expected costs to be shared with terminal operators.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Spectrum of the Seas ship docked at Kai Tak Cruise Terminal at 7am, two weeks after returning to the city following a nearly two-year absence. Secretary for Culture, Sports and Tourism Kevin Yeung Yun-hung said logistics were largely “smooth” in the morning, unlike earlier this month when passengers overloaded bus and taxi stops at the facility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With the government highly involved in solving the problem this time, we have learned from this experience and will embed it in the daily operations at the terminal. We will support the operators and work out how to share the additional costs with them,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thousands of passengers made their way through the terminal sporadically, with staff present to provide transport information, according to observations by the Post in the morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Citybus put on two additional bus routes, 20R and 25R, to take passengers between the cruise terminal and Tsim Sha Tsui and Kwun Tong. Bus 22R heading to Kai Tak MTR station was less popular among passengers in the morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No queues were spotted at the bus stops as of 9am.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Canadian couple on the cruise had booked a tour for sightseeing around the city.这位只透露姓名的丈夫表示，他已经了解到该船上次来访时的交通安排“混乱”，但他发现早上的经历“非常顺利”。 It took the couple about 5 to 7 minutes to get to the coach.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Cruise control? Hong Kong&#39;s measures for tourist ships to avoid terminal jam&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A woman from Japan, who declined to give her name, was travelling with her father on the 7th day of the cruise trip. She said she had done some research and planned to visit The Peak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The notice boards at the terminal ... were helpful to [point us in the right] direction,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A bazaar selling local brands and signature souvenirs has also been opened on the upper floor at the terminal since Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Newton Ng, commercial director for Citybus, said the service heading to Tsim Sha Tsui had carried more than 1,000 passengers from 7am to around 10am. Buses were scheduled for every eight minutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities also introduced a HK$50 (US$6.40) coupon for petrol to incentivise taxis to head to the terminal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong, the last driver in the queue, expected to wait for at least 30 minutes as dozens of cars were ahead of him. He said the lack of a notice board indicating the wait time at the terminal was a “poor arrangement”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now that I have already driven all the way here, leaving would just be double loss,” he said, adding the petrol subsidy would not help much.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Sea change for passengers as free buses cut queues at Hong Kong cruise terminal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yeung earlier said the government had “learned a lesson” from the chaos in which the terminal&#39;s transport options were swamped with thousands of passengers. Hundreds had been forced to wait in line for taxis or buses, in some cases for as long as 45 minutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following the hiccups, deputy chief secretary Warner Cheuk Wing-hing met tourism authorities, transport officials and the terminal operators to devise plans for traffic arrangements, including disembarking the passengers in batches and providing options on board ahead of time.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thailand’s ex-PM Thaksin Shinawatra to return from exile on Tuesday, same day as political stand-off vote: daughter]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3231630/thailands-ex-pm-thaksin-shinawatra-return-tuesday-same-day-political-stand-vote-daughter?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 12:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/19/2e9feb6d-dbe8-48aa-8c73-fcbf7ea32c54_d47db652.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Thailand&#39;s former prime minister Thaksin Shinawatra is set to return to the kingdom on Tuesday, the same day as a key parliamentary vote that could end a political deadlock, his daughter said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 74-year-old billionaire was ousted in a 2006 military coup and has spent 15 years in self-exile.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thaksin has long said he wished to return home, but faces multiple criminal charges that he says are politically motivated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On Tuesday, August 22, 9am I will pick up my father Thaksin at Don Muang Airport,” his daughter Paetongtarn Shinawatra, who was one of the Pheu Thai party&#39;s candidates for prime minister, said on Instagram.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His return will coincide with an afternoon vote on whether to approve Srettha Thavisin – from Thaksin&#39;s Pheu Thai Party – as prime minister and end three months of political deadlock since a May general election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To become premier, Srettha needs a majority across the lower house of 500 elected MPs, and the 250-member senate that was hand-picked by the kingdom&#39;s last junta.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The progressive Move Forward Party (MFP) won the most parliamentary seats in the election but the military-dominated senate blocked its leader from becoming prime minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Thaksin-backed Pheu Thai party came second and has been trying to form a government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parties linked to Thaksin have dominated Thai politics since 2001 but lost two prime ministers to military coups and another to a court ruling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A bogeyman for Thailand&#39;s pro-military and royalist establishment, Thaksin&#39;s return has the potential to inflame an already tense political situation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thaksin said on social media days before the May election, that he would return to Thailand “before my birthday” in July because he was getting old and wanted to spend time with his grandchildren.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;A dream to be back&#39;: second son of Thailand&#39;s king returns after 27 years away&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He has lived in self-exile, mostly in Dubai, since 2008 but regularly addresses supporters on the Clubhouse social media platform using the alias Tony Woodsome.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thaksin was convicted during his time abroad in four criminal cases, one of which has now passed the statute of limitations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His sentences for the other three total 10 years, while he is still under investigation in another case, and in his May message he said he was ready to face justice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has long maintained the cases were politically motivated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On arrival, he is likely to be taken to the Supreme Court and then to a special detention centre before being sent to prison.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He previously slated an August 10 return to Bangkok but postponed citing a medical appointment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Political analyst Yuttaporn Issarachai said there had long been rumours about his return and still no guarantees it would happen this time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I give it a 50-50 chance,” Yuttaporn said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“His return on August 22 which is the same day as the PM vote in the parliament, might facilitate the vote for Srettha among the lower house MPs, but might cause distress among the senators.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>