<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s long-awaited plan to charge residents for waste delayed to next year]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227225/hong-kongs-long-awaited-plan-charge-residents-waste-delayed-next-year?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 22:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/86f3a4cb-181b-45db-9dc1-b69c18497d23_853dd6d7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一项向香港居民每扔一袋垃圾收费的计划推迟到明年，再次推迟了近 20 年前首次提出的城市垃圾管理改革计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环境局表示，收费将于 4 月 1 日开始，而不是年底。周一告诉立法者，承认在垃圾收集者对寒假期间垃圾数量预计激增表示担忧后，需要更多时间来制定该计划的后勤工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一些行业，例如清洁服务考虑到圣诞节和农历新年期间预计将产生大量废物，以及农历新年期间人手短缺，该局一直呼吁推迟实施。”该局在提交的文件中表示。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，我们建议于2024年4月1日起实施都市固体废物收费，这标志着香港废物管理的一个重要里程碑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平均三件- 假设每个家庭每天产生 13 升垃圾，预计每个家庭每月需支付 33 港元（4.20 美元）购买政府批准的垃圾袋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但许多居民将幸免于难。该计划前六个月的费用。当局将向105万个居住在公屋、乡郊及没有业主立案法团的住宅小区的家庭派发20袋15公升的物品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;房委会则协助派发至公屋住户方面，该局尚未与民政事务总署敲定其他受免费垃圾袋计划覆盖的家庭将如何接收这些垃圾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将在乡郊地区设立更多垃圾收集点，并设立大型垃圾收集箱设立在免费袋子计划覆盖的私人住宅小区附近。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每个袋子售价为11港仙，六个月后，居民如使用非政府指定的袋子，将面临1,500港元的罚款。无法放入垃圾袋的大型废物需要贴上特殊标签，费用为港币11元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相关废物接收点的前线工作人员会目视检查交给他们的废物是否已妥善包装。环保局表示，将拒绝任何不合规废物。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;14年后，香港将强制实施废物收费计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“针对严重黑点&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府亦会向每名综合社会保障援助受助人或综合社会保障援助受助人提供每月港币 10 元的资助。老年生活津贴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局目前正在建立一个由超市、便利店、药店、家居用品店和在线平台组成的全市网络，以方便购买这些包。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环境生态局表示，当局已收到 19 家零售连锁店和网上零售商出售这些袋子和标签的要求，覆盖 2,000 个网点和 11 个数字平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2021 年发布的《香港 2035 年废物蓝图》中，政府制定了计划，逐步将人均处理率降低45%，并将回收率提高到55%左右。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;415万吨市政垃圾中，只有30%左右2021 年，该市处理的固体废物得到回收利用，其余的则送往垃圾填埋场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台北自 2000 年起开始对城市垃圾收费，首尔自 1995 年起开始征收城市垃圾收费。这两个城市的垃圾量均减少了至少 30% .&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港“应将废物收费计划推迟到春季，以防止垃圾堆积”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港征收垃圾税的想法于 2004 年首次提出，当时政府详细阐述了未来十年将如何处理废物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;时任行政长官曾荫权的政府提议利用经济激励措施鼓励居民多回收、少处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随后的主管部门采纳了对处置收费的想法。一项法案于 2018 年起草，并于 2021 年由立法者通过，但当局有 18 个月的时间来准备这一转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划原定于今年年底生效，但上周代表们表示垃圾收集部门警告称，该市在寒假期间扔出的垃圾将超出其处理能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港“应将垃圾收费计划推迟到春季，以防止垃圾堆积”&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;代表七个商业集团和约 200 家清洁服务公司的环境服务承包商联盟称推迟对行业来说是个好消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在是行业学习新知识的理想时机。劳动力最充裕时的废物管理模式，”联盟发言人邱佩林说。 “垃圾量在10月至3月期间达到峰值，但在4月至6月期间达到最低点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还呼吁当局举办更多研讨会，以便业界更好地了解新系统。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;但环保组织绿领行动的高级公共事务官员Beatrice Siu Wing-yin对这一拖延表示失望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们已经讨论垃圾税十多年了，”她说。 “香港平均每日废物处置量已达11,300吨。如果当局再拖下去，每天的处理量还会继续增加。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong justice chief lodges professional misconduct complaints against two activist lawyers on police wanted list]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3227226/hong-kong-justice-chief-lodges-professional-misconduct-complaints-against-two-activist-lawyers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 22:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/0b4d0dba-cf5f-416e-8cb9-947c2d988141_a3aff804.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港律政司司长向警方提出针对两名反对派维权律师的专业不当行为投诉因涉嫌危害国家安全罪被列入通缉名单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;律政司司长林定国举报大律师兼前立法会议员郭永亨和律师任建峰涉嫌涉嫌犯有国家安全罪。损害了律师行业的声誉，削弱了外界对香港法治的信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们利用大律师、律师的身份，意图增加自己的公信力和权威，抹黑律师。”林郑月娥周一表示，“破坏香港的司法制度和法治，诽谤香港法官和检察官，推动和支持外国势力对中国和香港特别是香港法官和检察官实施制裁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;他们的行为损害了香港的司法制度和整体利益，也违反了大律师和律师的基本行为准则……作为公众利益的保护者，我必须维护香港的法治和正义。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两人是被通缉的八人之一，被悬赏 100 万港元（127,725 美元），被指控违反北京 2020 年实施的国家安全法，该法旨在惩罚分裂国家行为， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林郑月娥还指责任和郭对香港司法系统进行毫无根据的指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“郭甚至主张破坏香港金融体系，林说，“他们试图干涉法官处理国家安全案件。”林说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“而任则煽动和支持制裁法官和检察官，并支持制裁他们的家人，以胁迫他们。这种行为是公开践踏正义。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;8 香港通缉活动人士应被视为“街上的老鼠”：李约翰&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;任志强，于 2022 年移居澳大利亚据称，他去年曾会见海外官员，要求对香港政府实施制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称，他还曾于5月份要求外国政府对香港法官和检察官实施处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;郭先生是前反对派议员，于 2020 年前往加拿大，涉嫌支持 2021 年针对中国大陆和香港实施制裁和其他敌对行动的呼吁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称，他曾去年再次呼吁对香港进行经济制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;律师管理机构香港律师会表示无法对个别案件发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但它证实该协会周一收到针对一名会员的专业不当行为投诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;奖励纠纷不应阻止香港讲述其好故事&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该协会主席陈泽明表示： “我想强调……律师会非常重视我们会员的行为……并严格处理所有投诉，并以公平、公正和客观的方式处理。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;律师公会监管大律师的机构已被要求置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两个专业团体上周表示，他们已收到有关成员因涉嫌违反国家安全法而被警方通缉的投诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;香港警方上周一宣布悬赏 100 万港元，以提供线索逮捕这八人，他们都在海外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人是前立法会议员罗冠聪和许志峰，工会成员蒙少达和活动人士刘祖迪、郭凤仪和袁恭仪。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国家安全法：警方悬赏100万港元逮捕8名&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;悬赏提议引发了北京与八名活动人士所居住国家政府之间的争执，其中包括英国和澳大利亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中一名通缉犯居住在美国，称此举威胁人民的人权和自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国驻香港外事办公室早些时候警告“外国势力”停止窝藏犯罪分子和支持“走卒”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ant Group’s IPO plan under the spotlight after regulatory fine, share buy-back]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3227211/ant-groups-ipo-plan-under-spotlight-after-regulatory-fine-share-buy-back?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/fdc2a3a0-107a-4441-a17c-ba3c7991e840_cd2e9b76.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;亿万富翁杰克创立的金融科技巨头蚂蚁集团的上市计划和修订后的估值在北京以近 10 亿美元的罚款结束了为期两年半的监管调查后，马云成为了人们关注的焦点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管蚂蚁金服对恢复计划守口如瓶，在马云在2020年底发表批评中国金融监管的有争议的演讲后，蚂蚁金服的上市在最后一刻被取消，北京方面承诺对蚂蚁金服和其他金融科技公司进行“常态化”管理，引发了蚂蚁金服IPO障碍已被解除的猜测&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“打击行动结束后，蚂蚁金服可能会重新考虑上市计划，”IPG中国首席经济学家白文曦表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，即使蚂蚁金服重回上市轨道，如果在香港或上海上市，其估值将显着低于 2020 年 10 月，当时阿里巴巴集团控股分拆公司的目标是 370 亿美元 IPO，预计估值为 3000 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;阿里巴巴物流部门推出快递服务，提高电商效率&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在最新的回购股份计划中，蚂蚁金服的发行价较其总股本高达7.6%折让近75%。估值3000亿美元。拥有《南华早报》并持有蚂蚁金服 33% 股权的阿里巴巴表示，正在考虑是否参与回购计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，蚂蚁金服的金融科技业务以及蚂蚁金服等竞争对手腾讯控股的金融科技部门受到更严格的监管，这使得发展利润丰厚的信贷业务和赚取高利润变得更加困难。蚂蚁金服也在数据共享、管理和人员等方面与阿里巴巴渐行渐远，以符合北京的要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“蚂蚁金服和腾讯的金融科技业务似乎有可能分别在资本市场上市上海协赢律师事务所证券律师董约翰表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马云在 2023 年初宣布的公司重组中放弃了对蚂蚁金服的最终控制权，结束了代理蚂蚁金服的行为。与公司董事长井贤栋、前首席执行官胡晓明和阿里巴巴集团资深人士蒋芳签署一致协议。蚂蚁集团 1 月份表示，此次重组意味着马云放弃了 53.46% 的投票权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海汉盛律师事务所高级合伙人李敏表示，此次处罚是“严厉打击&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，对蚂蚁金服处以的 71.23 亿元人民币（9.8433 亿美元）罚款低于 28 亿美元的反垄断罚款2021 年 4 月，国家市场监管总局对阿里巴巴进行了处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;咨询公司博通易观的财务分析师王鹏博表示，罚款将加快蚂蚁金服的上市进程，尽管 IPO 可能不会发生。短期内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为不可能快速上市。 [蚂蚁]需要恢复。”王说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据阿里巴巴的数据，蚂蚁金服的最新市值约为 5671 亿元人民币，分析师表示，一定程度的监管仍将笼罩该公司，这使得蚂蚁金服的市值受到限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“金融监管永远存在，”证券律师董说。 “对于整个平台经济来说，合规要求非常高，这必然导致合规成本的增加。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s mothballed monorail catches attention of second mainland Chinese company, months after scheme revival floated to city leader]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3227224/hong-kongs-mothballed-monorail-catches-attention-second-mainland-chinese-company-months-after-scheme?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 22:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/86195775-93ce-40f8-9fb5-dab77b4de2ed_e10be0c9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港九龙东的一个封存的单轨铁路项目吸引了第二家公司的兴趣在中国大陆，几个月前，该市领导人表示，他愿意使用一家电动汽车制造商的公共交通系统来恢复该计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中唐高铁集团国际业务部总监 Eleanor Jane Mak 表示周一表示，该市搁置的交通计划引起了这家四川公司的注意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司早些时候与阿拉伯联合酋长国迪拜当局签署了一份谅解备忘录，探讨开发悬挂式单轨铁路网络。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港在2020年取消了自己建造连接启德、观塘和九龙湾的单轨铁路的计划。当局当时估计该项目将耗资 120 亿港元（15 亿美元），并认为成本太高。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港领导人对使用大陆制造的交通线路恢复单轨铁路计划持开放态度&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;今年 4 月，行政长官李家超表示，政府对使用深圳比亚迪汽车开发的 SkyShuttle 电动火车系统持开放态度，有关该计划的讨论随后又重新展开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一想法是由立法会议员提出的，他们与李光耀和其他高级官员一起进行了为期四天的大湾区之旅，这是北京将香港、澳门和九个内地城市整合为经济强国的雄心勃勃的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法者张新宇曾估计，在启德安装这条铁路线的成本约为 70 亿港元，即每公里 5 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦周一表示，该公司迄今为止仅派遣工程师前往香港，以解决该问题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然她没有透露中唐愿意为九龙东复兴的铁路项目投资多少，但她表示安装轻轨系统的成本在1亿至1亿港元之间。每公里1.5亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每节火车车厢由三个车厢组成，每小时可搭载10,000至20,000名乘客，高于比亚迪汽车交通系统可运送的6,000至10,000名乘客，她补充道。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;中唐的空中列车也依赖于悬挂单轨系统，而SkyShuttle则使用安装在高架轨道上的自动锂动力车辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mak表示，轨道系统上方的表面可能是用作自行车道或留作其他用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的系统是模块化构建的，因此可以节省大量劳动力成本，因此我们不需要在香港花费额外的时间和人力从头开始，”她说。 “我们只需要运送它们并组装它们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公司代表还与香港路政署会面，并将在未来几个月与其他利益相关者讨论可能的合作领域，她补充道。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;为什么香港启德单轨铁路计划需要重启&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;发展局局长林汉豪上周表示，政府将研究绿色和智能集体交通的最新技术发展运输及物流局亦正在探讨为港铁公司的东九龙线开发高架无轨快速运输系统，她表示，这是恢复搁置的单轨铁路计划的一部分。林恩补充说，一项研究将于今年完成，并将考虑居民对铁路可能路线的看法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》已联系运输和物流部门交通局和路政署征求意见。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Is China’s Fujian aircraft carrier counting down to a catapult take-off test?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3227218/chinas-fujian-aircraft-carrier-counting-down-catapult-take-test?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/0eb96709-aee0-456b-8432-0442aa0052f5_750203bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;覆盖该国最新航空母舰上先进飞机发射系统部分的避难所出现据军事分析人士称，该舰上的弹射起飞测试已被删除，这表明该舰的弹射起飞测试可能很快就会开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位军事爱好者周一在微博（相当于中国的推特）上发布的照片​​也显示了一系列台湾海军学院前教官卢立时表示，电磁弹射系统的安装已于几个月前完成， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“下一步应该是对歼15T战斗机进行测试。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示，舰上的雷达系统照片中包括先进的有源电子扫描阵列（AESA）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这与055型巡洋舰和052D型驱逐舰上使用的相同，这意味着海试可能随时开始，”陆说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;J-15T 是 J-15 战斗机的更新版本，并配备了新的弹射系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该飞机是该国唯一现役舰载机战斗机，并已部署在中国另外两艘航母辽宁舰和山东舰上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2021 年该飞机的照片开始在中国社交媒体平台上流传以来，军事爱好者一直关注 J-15T 的发展。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据了解，J-15T 的地面飞行测试多年前就在位于辽宁省兴城的中国人民解放军海军训练基地开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周晨明，北京远望军事科技智库研究员表示，电磁弹射系统自一年前推出以来，中国工程师不断对其进行修改。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经过一年多的校准，现在是时候确保歼15T的飞行试验能够在今年年底前完成了。”周说，并补充说时间表可能在8月至10月之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“确保安全仍然是首要任务对于如此高度复杂的武器系统来说，这是当务之急，如果到 8 月还没有准备好，那么 [PLA] 可以瞄准 10 月 1 日 [国庆]。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国军人傅前哨航空分析师表示，只有福建舰首次海试顺利，歼15T飞行试验才会进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福建舰是中国第三艘航母，也是迄今为止最先进的航母。卢表示，如果美国干预台湾问题的冲突，预计它将在解放军的反介入和区域拒止战略中发挥关键作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为中国的一部分，并已不排除使用武力将其收回。包括美国在内的大多数国家都不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对使用武力改变现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陆说，福建事件的进展可能表明解放军正在加紧努力到2027年建军一百周年，实现“全面现代化军队”的短期目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外两个目标是到2035年完成军队现代化，成为“世界一流”军队到本世纪中叶，军事力量将与美国平起平坐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福建号是中国人民解放军海军 003 型航母中的第一艘，也是继美国杰拉尔德·福特级之后唯一的第二艘航母级航母。使用电磁弹射系统从甲板上发射飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计它将成为中国成为一支能够在远海作战的蓝水海军计划的核心。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Was China’s ‘rainbow reception’ for Janet Yellen warmer than Antony Blinken’s ‘snub’?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227203/was-chinas-rainbow-reception-janet-yellen-warmer-antony-blinkens-snub?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/11779b7e-468d-431e-8c4c-85faea1e3f9d_121b91a4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国财长耶伦访华时没有走红地毯，但对许多人来说，与几周前访问中国的同事、美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯相比，她确实受到了非常热烈的欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在为期四天的访问中，耶伦可以说是最鸽派的拜登政府官员会见了许多高级经济和金融官员，包括中国国务院总理李强、财政部长刘昆、央行行长易纲和副总理何立峰。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美中经济竞争不存在耶伦称“赢家通吃”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她还会见了退休的经济重量级人物刘鹤，但没有见到正在江苏视察的习近平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦在紧张的日程中举行的高层接待被视为一个信号，表明尽管台湾、乌克兰战争和美国主导的技术限制等多条战线的摩擦不断加剧，中国仍决心稳定双边关系并深化合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周五，当耶伦在北京走下飞机时，中国财政部代表杨英明在机场迎接她，杨英明微笑着指着彩虹与她握手了约 20 秒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在与总理会面时再次提到这个天象，总理告诉耶伦：“我认为这也适用于美中关系：经历一轮风雨之后，我们一定能看到彩虹。” ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自中国媒体的会议视频片段显示，耶伦坐在李克强旁边，贺对面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三周前，布林肯——确实会见了习近平——被显示坐在会议的一侧。两张长桌在做笔记，习近平在一张桌子的最前面发表演讲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些图像与三天前习近平和微软联合创始人比尔·盖茨的会面形成鲜明对比。照片中两人并排坐着，习近平偶尔会向盖茨倾斜。习近平称盖茨为“老朋友”——这是一个外交术语，专指那些被视为对中国发展做出贡献的外国实体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国社交媒体平台上，网络用户似乎普遍对耶伦的访问感到满意。一些人将其与布林肯的招待会进行比较，发现礼节很相似，没有红地毯或鲜花。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多人认为机场友好的“彩虹接待”、耶伦与中国女经济学家的晚宴以及会议高级官员称之为“高层接待”，因此是双边关系改善的希望迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们很有诚意。这次耶伦来了，我们对她的接待“超出标准”。”一位微博用户写道，他认为美国的要求不应该太霸道，不能让中国人民接受。这篇帖子在中国类似推特的平台上获得了数千个点赞。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在不确定的阴云中，中国以彩虹欢迎美国财政部长&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;希拉里·克林顿担任国务卿时，用红地毯欢迎来到中国。西方观察家称接待布林肯的礼节——他受到了一名中层官员的欢迎，没有鲜花或红地毯——是北京“羞辱”布林肯的计划，作为其“外交冷落”的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但对布林肯的欢迎并没有完全不同于以往的招待会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;礼节——甚至会议室——与时任美国贸易代表罗伯特·莱特希泽(Robert Lighthizer)和时任财政部长史蒂文·姆努钦(Steven Mnuchin)访问中国时相同。 2019年2月，他们会见习近平进行经贸磋商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去的会面都比较轻松。 2013年，习近平就任中国国家主席几天后，习近平在人民大会堂会见了时任美国财政部长雅各布·卢。这是卢以此角色首次出国。官方媒体显示，这些人坐在扶手椅上聊天，中间放着一个花篮。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tencent’s WeChat to skip Australian social media hearing on ‘political interference’ amid backlash]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3227207/tencents-wechat-skip-australian-social-media-hearing-political-interference-amid-backlash?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/cca14969-bad3-4cbd-848e-672e8f045114_4f80d887.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国社交媒体应用微信不会派代表参加澳大利亚议会听证会澳大利亚自由党参议员詹姆斯·帕特森 (James Paterson) 写的一封信，他是著名的对华鹰派，已警告微信在该国的影响力，这家中国社交媒体平台已拒绝出席澳大利亚参议院通过社交媒体进行外国干涉问题特别委员会听证会的多次邀请。该听证会将于周二开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次会议旨在强调通过社交媒体“外国干预”澳大利亚政治的潜力，来自北京字节跳动旗下社交媒体巨头 TikTok 以及西方平台 Twitter 和 LinkedIn 的高管将出席此次会议。 p>;&lt;p>;由于微信在澳大利亚没有常驻员工，该国议会不能强迫腾讯总部所在地中国南方城市深圳的高管出席听证会。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;腾讯为对高校微信支付费用较高的“误解”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“微信在我们运营的所有市场中都非常重视合规性。我们期待继续与澳大利亚的利益相关者进行接触。”腾讯发言人周一表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;微信因涉嫌对澳大利亚华人产生影响而在澳大利亚受到批评。根据悉尼智库洛伊研究所 4 月份的一项调查，微信是澳大利亚华人日常使用的第三大社交媒体平台，仅次于 YouTube 和 Facebook。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 76% 1% 在中国​​出生的澳大利亚人表示，他们每天都使用微信，根据受访者的说法，该应用程序作为澳大利亚华人的新闻来源发挥着核心作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至年底，澳大利亚用户数量已达到 690,000 人2020 年，微信已成为世界各地华人侨民的重要沟通工具，他们依靠该应用程序与家人和朋友进行交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，该应用程序作为新闻和观点文章平台的功能已经受到人们的关注。在北京和堪培拉关系恶化之际，该法案受到了澳大利亚政界人士的密切关注。微信因国家安全问题而面临禁止的呼声，包括国防部在内的政府机构也限制其工作人员使用该应用程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;微信并不是唯一引起担忧的中国应用程序。澳大利亚。 4 月，澳大利亚宣布将从所有联邦政府拥有的设备中删除 TikTok，此前其他西方国家在所谓的五眼情报共享网络中也采取了类似举措。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TikTok 和微信也是目标美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普在 2020 年提出的一项禁令，但微信用户团体对此举提起诉讼，并在法院阻止该禁令后胜诉。该命令于 2021 年被美国总统乔·拜登正式撤回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;微信（中国称为微信）是中国和海外华人社区中非常流行的社交媒体工具，每月有 12.5 亿活跃用户全球范围内，其中绝大多数位于中国。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Surprise move as Erdogan links Sweden’s Nato membership to Turkey’s EU accession]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227222/surprise-move-erdogan-links-swedens-nato-membership-turkeys-eu-accession?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 22:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/10/c7983491-e0b6-4491-8c76-b2950658fc7f_26690390.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;土耳其总统塔伊普·埃尔多安周一出人意料地表示，欧盟应该会在土耳其议会批准瑞典加入北约军事联盟的申请之前为安卡拉加入欧盟开辟道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2005 年在埃尔多安的领导下启动入盟谈判以来，土耳其加入欧盟的申请已被冻结多年。作为总理的第一任期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几年前，安卡拉与欧盟成员国之间的关系恶化，特别是在 2016 年土耳其政变失败之后，但此后有所改善。该集团依赖于北约盟友安卡拉的帮助，尤其是在移民方面的帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃尔多安周一出人意料地改变了策略，将安卡拉批准瑞典加入北约与土耳其最终加入欧盟联系在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;拜登在与土耳其埃尔多安通话时表示支持瑞典加入北约&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我在这里向这些让土耳其在欧盟门口等待了 50 多年的国家发出呼吁， ”埃尔多安在出发前往维尔纽斯参加北约峰会之前说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“首先，来为土耳其在欧盟打开道路，然后我们将为瑞典打开道路，就像我们一样did for Finland,” he said, adding that he would repeat his call during the summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A European Commission spokesperson said Nato and EU enlargement were “separate processes” and that “The accession process for each candidate country is based on the merits of each country”, adding that the two processes cannot be linked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked about Erdogan&#39;s comments, Nato Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg said while he backs Ankara&#39;s membership of the EU, as far as he was concerned Sweden had already met the conditions required to join Nato.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is still possible to have a positive decision on Sweden in Vilnius,” Stoltenberg told a news conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sweden and Finland applied for Nato membership last year, abandoning policies of military non-alignment that had lasted through the decades of the Cold War in response to Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Finland&#39;s Nato membership was green-lighted in April, Turkey and Hungary have yet to clear Sweden&#39;s bid. Stockholm has been working to join the bloc at the summit in Vilnius.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan said Sweden&#39;s accession hinged on the implementation of a deal reached last summer during the alliance&#39;s summit in Madrid, adding that no one should expect compromises from Ankara.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ankara says Sweden has not done enough against people Turkey sees as terrorists, mainly members of the outlawed Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) that is considered a terrorist organisation by Turkey, the EU and the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;No Nato for Sweden if Koran burning is allowed, says Turkey&#39;s Erdogan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sinan Ulgen, former diplomat and director of the Istanbul-based Centre for Economic and Foreign Policy Studies, said Erdogan&#39;s move would not strengthen Turkey&#39;s hand at the Vilnius summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The positive side of this surprise move is that it showed Turkey still has an EU membership perspective. But it is hard to say it would help any progress on Turkey&#39;s EU membership bid,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan also said that an end to the war between Ukraine and Russia would ease Kyiv&#39;s Nato membership process.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s Xi Jinping pledges economic, tech aid for Solomon Islands as ‘strategic partnership’ takes off]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227221/chinas-xi-jinping-pledges-economic-tech-aid-solomon-islands-strategic-partnership-takes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 22:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/0b0302a1-1e7e-43d1-9775-05f6e319c1e5_779cf721.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese President Xi Jinping has pledged economic and technological aid with “no political preconditions” for Solomon Islands – Beijing&#39;s first close security partner in the strategically important South Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meeting Solomons&#39; Prime Minister Manasseh Sogavare in Beijing on Monday, Xi said: “Although our friendship arrived belatedly, it has come to the forefront of relations between China and the Pacific Islands.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China supports more Chinese enterprises to invest in Solomon Islands and will continue to provide assistance and technologies with no political preconditions,” state broadcaster CCTV quoted Xi as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said China was willing to share in the development of the Pacific nation and in the opportunities brought by modernisation, “expand cooperation in all sectors … and assist Solomon Islands to revive development and achieve long-term stability”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi and Sogavare also announced the setting up of a “comprehensive strategic partnership” and signed a joint statement for “mutual respect and co-development”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Developing diplomatic ties was the right choice … China has become the largest infrastructure partner of Solomon Islands and a reliable partner for development,” CCTV reported Sogavare as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Soon after Solomon Islands switched diplomatic recognition from Taiwan to Beijing four years ago, it joined the Belt and Road Initiative – Beijing&#39;s flagship multinational infrastructure strategy under which it offers loans and invests in projects like railways, highways and ports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sogavare, who led the switch soon after coming to power in April 2019, will also open his country&#39;s embassy in Beijing later this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is Sogavare&#39;s second visit to China, but the first since the signing of a landmark bilateral security deal last year that had provoked strong rebukes from the United States and its South Pacific allies, Australia and New Zealand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He arrived on Sunday for a weeklong, Chinese-funded trip aimed at “further strengthening bilateral ties”, an official statement from his government said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After meetings with senior officials, Sogavare will visit Chinese enterprises in Beijing and later travel with his delegation to the economically powerful coastal provinces of Jiangsu and Guangdong. Guangdong set up a sister-province relationship with Guadalcanal, an island in the Solomons, in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The state visit is also the latest sign of closer bilateral economic and trade cooperation, after last year&#39;s security pact paved the way for Chinese police to take an increasing role in training and equipping the Royal Solomon Islands Police Force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US and its allies reacted strongly to the deal over concerns about Beijing&#39;s naval ambitions in the strategically located region with decades of strong American military presence, especially given the secrecy over the details of the agreement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “lack of transparency”, as the US put it, has added to worries that China might be able to station military equipment or personnel, or even set up a military base, in the Pacific Islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The China-Solomon Islands security pact and why it has raised alarm&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Honiara has sought to dispel those fears, saying last year it would not allow a Chinese military base on its soil and was “conscious of security ramifications”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Days before Sogavare&#39;s trip to China, Australian deputy prime minister and defence minister Richard Marles visited the Solomons for security talks, and emphasised “the deepening partnership between our two countries”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia has been the Solomons&#39; largest aid donor and the two countries also have a decades-old security relationship, including a mechanism for Australian police and defence personnel to deploy rapidly if need be.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has continued to invest financially in Solomon Islands, prompting the United States to rekindle its engagement with the region, including reopening its embassy in Honiara and boosting investment efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Sogavare last visited China in October 2019, a month after the switching of ties, state-held China Railway promised help to build facilities for this year&#39;s Pacific Games, to be hosted by the Solomons over November and December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Huawei Technologies and contractor China Harbour Engineering are also building 161 mobile telecoms towers in the islands under a deal last year involving a loan of US$66 million from Beijing.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Germany wants to deepen China agricultural trade ties by combating climate change suffering, eyes lifting of pork ban]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3227191/germany-wants-deepen-china-agricultural-trade-ties-combating-climate-change-suffering-eyes-lifting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/259cbb34-e63f-46e4-9f73-f7aa203d1663_edfacea9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China and Germany should deepen agricultural collaboration amid worsening climate change issues and global supply chain disruptions, said German diplomats, who are also hoping Beijing will relax its pork import ban.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Germany has the social responsibility to share the experiences and expertise of its highly-digitised agriculture sector, while China plays an important role due to its size and population, said Hendrik Barkeling, head of the economic department and minister counsellor at the German embassy in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no industry suffering [from climate change] as much as agriculture,” said Barkeling during the China (Gansu)-German AgriFuture Cooperation Conference in the northwestern city of Lanzhou, Gansu province, on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Every country has a particular responsibility to combat these challenges to further increase efficiency in agricultural production, and at the same time to ensure the conservation of natural resources,” he added during the event co-hosted by the German Agricultural Society, German embassy in China and China Council for the Promotion of International Trade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese representatives from more than a dozen German companies in the agricultural sector attended the conference, which was held in tandem with the annual Lanzhou Investment and Trade Fair, together with numerous firms from across Gansu province and local officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Such exchanges are] especially important as the Covid pandemic in the past three years has blocked human exchanges and disrupted supply chains. And because of Russian aggression in Ukraine, one of the world&#39;s biggest grain exporters is cut off from the world,” said Barkeling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There have been no direct Western sanctions on the Russian grain trade, but restrictions on banks and other logistical hurdles caused by the war have made it harder for exporters to ship agricultural products and also arrange payments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And that&#39;s why in Germany there is increasing discussion about de-risking, there is the same discussion in Europe,” Barkeling said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;No more declines&#39;: China&#39;s crop crackdown targets critical grains, oilseeds&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said China&#39;s rising focus on security and self-sufficiency – which is not limited to the agricultural sector – shares similar logic, and the key is to raise the reliability of future economic relations between the two countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This could include the resumption of Chinese imports of German pork, which were banned in September 2020 due to African swine fever.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Germany has been trying to persuade China to accept the “regionalisation concept”, which stops imports only from the region where the disease has been detected instead of a blanket ban on the whole country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Germany would like to export to China again,” Barkeling added. “The outbreak has been successfully contained.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Friederike Dorfler, agriculture and food counsellor at the German embassy in Beijing, said that China is one of the most important countries for German exports outside the European Union.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Germany exports around a third of its agricultural products, while China faces the challenge of feeding almost 20 per cent of the world&#39;s population with less than 10 per cent of the arable land, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This shows us that trade is important, that we have to share our resources, share our work and trade goods,” she also said during the conference in Lanzhou.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping has repeatedly made strong calls for China&#39;s food self-sufficiency in recent years, especially after the Ukraine war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the annual central rural work conference in December, Xi said agriculture was the foundation of national security and that weak links – including low productivity – must be addressed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi said that, since the start of the Ukraine war in 2022, over 30 countries have limited food exports, and some have experienced social turmoil or even regime change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Containment from the rest of the world has escalated, and there&#39;s an obvious increase in all kinds of uncertainty and unpredictability,” he said, according to a full transcript of his speech released in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Once something&#39;s wrong with agriculture, our bowls will be held in someone else&#39;s hands and we&#39;ll have to depend on others for food. How can we achieve modernisation in that case?”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mainland China running ‘more subtle’ campaign to sway 2024 vote, Taipei says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3227214/mainland-china-running-more-subtle-campaign-sway-2024-vote-taipei-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.10 21:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/10/7af97a6b-9a74-439c-a9f3-f7d48c66ff59_24b77db9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing is trying a “more subtle approach” to influence Taiwanese voters ahead of presidential and legislative elections in January, a security source in Taipei has warned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An exaggerated spectre of cross-strait war combined with soft concessions like lifting certain import bans were in play this time around, the source with the National Security Bureau, Taiwan&#39;s top intelligence agency, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Previous election years saw Beijing unleash hostile rhetoric against the independence-leaning Democratic Progressive Party, in the hope that voters would choose the candidates of mainland-friendly parties like the Kuomintang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, it appears to be toning down the criticism after previous efforts to hit out at the DPP backfired, choosing instead to highlight the greater risk of war if the ruling party remained in power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In addition to nonstop military threats, the Chinese Communists have tried to generate fear within Taiwan by creating an atmosphere of imminent war and the feeling that people risk losing their homes and families if they continue to support the DPP or the pro-independence camp,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwanese presidential hopeful William Lai stresses cross-strait status quo&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Using platforms like TikTok and other social media, Beijing had been trying to impress upon Taiwanese that the DPP government and its “hostile” mainland policy were to blame for bringing Taiwan to the brink of war, the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to more frequent warplane fly-bys, the People&#39;s Liberation Army has carried out massive live-fire drills around Taiwan in recent months as the DPP&#39;s ties with the US have grown closer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Beijing] has also tried to create the impression that our foreign friends, including the United States, are not trustworthy, as they are unlikely to send forces to Taiwan&#39;s rescue in the event of a cross-strait war,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing claims sovereignty over Taiwan under the “one-China principle” and views its exchanges with overseas governments as a violation. It has also warned the self-ruled island that any declaration of independence would warrant an attack.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United States, like most countries, does not recognise Taiwan as an independent state but is opposed to any unilateral change to the cross-strait status quo by force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is also bound by domestic law to help defend Taiwan, which has included weapons sales and military exchanges, but has yet to directly declare that US troops would be sent to help deter any attack from Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Debate over whether the island faces a potential cross-strait attack has dominated the headlines in recent years, and Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine sparked renewed speculation about Beijing&#39;s military intentions concerning Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an article in April 2021, The Economist described Taiwan as being seen as the most dangerous flashpoint for war in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This came two months after former US officials and academics at a US congressional hearing ranked the island as the No 1 flashpoint in US-China relations, with the potential to trigger a military conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indo-Pacific commander Philip Davidson and US Air Force commander General Mike Minihan are among US officials who have predicted conflict with Beijing over Taiwan between 2025 and 2027.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source said Taiwan believed that, in addition to playing up the risk of war, Beijing had also tried to portray the string of visits by foreign delegations as focused on personal or business gains rather than support for the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is to confuse the Taiwanese public and to stir their resentment towards the government for inviting foreign visitors regardless.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another gimmick was to “first suspend the import of certain Taiwanese products, only to resume shipments as the elections approached”, the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing banned the import of more than 2,000 Taiwanese food products shortly after then US House speaker Nancy Pelosi visited Taipei in August, a move that also triggered days of unprecedented PLA live-fire drills around the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This was followed in December by an extension of the bans on 11 beer and distillery items from Taiwan. However, imports of some products were gradually resumed from January, including certain fish, farm and alcoholic items.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Beijing lifted the ban on sugar apples from Taiwan on June 20, the main opposition party KMT claimed it to be the result of its persistent efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Disinformation had been another major part of the influence campaign launched by Beijing as it tried to sway the elections, the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Between January and June, we uncovered more than 1,800 pieces of disinformation with the purpose of painting the [DPP] government as unsuitable to continue its rule,” the source said, adding this was only expected to increase as the elections drew closer.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 10 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>