<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[World Economic Forum: Premier Li Qiang plays up China’s economic prospects, hits out at West over ‘de-risking’ calls]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3225600/world-economic-forum-premier-li-qiang-plays-chinas-economic-prospects-hits-out-west-over-de-risking?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/c00575a1-f71c-4a17-a11d-f4b9c586993c_78777c81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;李强总理夸大中国经济前景，指责“西方”呼吁在全球对中国经济增长前景的担忧之际，周二世界经济论坛第一天“去风险化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李克强在周二上午作为为期三天的“夏季达沃斯论坛”发表了主题演讲。 ” 论坛在北方城市天津拉开帷幕，表示中国经济正在实现既定目标，并承诺将推出“务实有效的政策”来促进增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国经济复苏势头良好今年以来，国际形势明显向好。”李克强在以“创业精神：世界经济的驱动力”为主题的论坛开始时对1500名外交政策制定者和企业高管表示。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“我们预计第二季度的增长速度将快于第一季度 4.5% 的 [国内生产总值] 增长速度。我们有希望实现今年设定的 5% 的增长目标。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李克强试图安抚投资者之际，正值市场密切关注北京方面推出更多刺激措施以促进疫情后复苏的计划。最新的经济数据已显示出失去动力的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，北京对“较长期经济周期”的稳定增长“充满信心”，这将导致市场持续扩张，创造合作机会，为各国投资者创造机会，促进世界经济复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李承认中国国内发展尚未“平衡”，但指责外部因素造成“巨大破坏” ”，影响世界发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一些人煽动意识形态对立，煽动仇恨、遏制。偶尔的地区冲突和战争仍在发生。”李说，但没有点名具体国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，李克强对“西方”日益高涨的“去风险化”呼声进行了直接反驳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“我们知道西方有人呼吁‘去风险’和‘减少依赖’，我认为这两个短语都是伪命题，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“即使某个行业面临供应链风险，不应该由政府或任何组织来决定做什么。企业对经济风险和产业挑战最敏感，理应有发言权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府或任何相关组织不应阻挠、将风险扩大化、政治化或将风险转化为风险。”意识形态斗争。这会带来很多问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李特别强调了他最近对德国和法国进行的为期六天的访问，他说政策制定者和企业高管一致认为应该有更多的合作心态，而不是“零和游戏”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京在指责美国想要遏制中国发展时采用了这句话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李克强的信息是在中美之间经济和技术竞争日益加剧的背景下发出的。美国和中国，美国总统乔·拜登及其欧洲盟友在 5 月份的七国集团会议上强调，他们希望“降低风险”，而不是与中国经济“脱钩”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“明确的信息是向企业家表明，看到风险和竞争是正常的……公司不应被误导，认为“脱钩”和“去风险”之间存在差异，因为两者将被视为具有相同的性质参加周二开幕式的中国人民大学国际关系教授王义伟表示：“针对中国的做法会增加全球经济的风险。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;从中国经济数据中得出的六点结论创新高&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;同样在周二的论坛上，国务院国资委主任张玉琢表示，外部和内部因素将继续对企业发展构成挑战。中国经济复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[在]对外贸易方面，增长低于我们的预期，因为从全球范围来看，前五个月的增长相当温和，”他说，并补充说“贸易壁垒”给全球贸易带来了新的壁垒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们经常听到脱钩和相关做法的说法，这也肯定会阻碍国际贸易合作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在国内，张说。 ，中国需要打造新的“增长点”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“消费方面，消费增速也低于我们的预期。一些新兴行业仍需扩大规模，以产生更大的影响。”张补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市场预期中国经济将在第二季度实现增长，部分原因是与去年相比基数较低。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于中国严格的Covid-19限制措施和房地产市场低迷，去年4月至6月中国的经济增长跌至近半个世纪以来最糟糕的水平之一。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;去年 4 月至 5 月，李克强在经济重镇上海担任市委书记，直到今年 3 月晋升，该市经历了为期两个月的封锁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些限制导致了冲击- 对经济的下行影响，包括去年 4 月上海的汽车销量为零。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，随着全国零售额的回升，中国后新冠疫情反弹的强劲势头令经济学家和投资者感到失望。投资和工业生产增长放缓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新西兰总理克里斯·希普金斯周二在论坛的另一个小组中表示，世界的“不确定性”促使一些国家在讨论中“更加内向”关于当前的地缘政治局势如何导致新的关税和保护主义，以及中美之间的脱节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为我们希望看到一个继续开放和外向的世界， ”希普金斯说，并补充说，气候变化和人口结构的变化将成为常见问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“全世界都必须应对这一问题。因此，我认为任何国家的内向型关注都无法挽救他们的长期利益。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Huawei and Chinese state telecoms operators tout 5G’s ability to change lives at MWC Shanghai]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225612/huawei-and-chinese-state-telecoms-operators-tout-5gs-ability-change-lives-mwc-shanghai?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/49111935-fe8c-495c-a476-0deb765f3ec2_a5c34c90.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国电信行业的巨头们承诺支持中国的 5G 发展在今年的 MWC 上海上，周二，高管们宣扬高速移动互联网标准改变生活的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然今天看起来很正常……（四年前）追求 5G 影响了许多电信公司的利益并带来了很多额外的工作。”中国通信标准化协会理事长库闻在当地举行的世界移动通信大会上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2019 年开始广泛部署以来，5G文说，改变了用户的日常生活，也改变了电信行业本身。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们的网络覆盖到农田时，农民只需一个手机就可以[直播]并将他们的产品推广到全国。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国有电信运营商中国移动、中国电信和中国联通以及设备制造商华为技术有限公司是此次会议的主要参与者。美国半导体设计公司高通和中国人工智能 (AI) 公司科大讯飞也出席了会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他加入的组织包括中国信息通信研究院 (CAICT) 和中国通信标准化协会。标准制定机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自四年前成为首批推出 5G 覆盖的主要经济体之一以来，中国的覆盖范围不断扩大。根据工业和信息化部 (MIIT) 和 CAIAT 的数据，截至 5 月，中国已拥有超过 280 万个 5G 基站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为设备一直是该网络的主要贡献者。这家总部位于深圳的科技巨头最近获得了中国移动 2023 年至 2024 年 52% 的 5G 基站工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;MWC 上海在疫情中断两年后以现场活动形式回归&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;根据中国信息通信研究院 1 月份发布的报告，截至 2022 年 9 月，中国拥有 5 亿 5G 用户，约占总人口的 35%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在内地以外的人口稠密的香港，有 480 万人使用 5G 网络。当地通信管理局监管办公室主任 Lee Shun 表示，约 65% 的人口正在使用 5G。李说，市政府正在鼓励更广泛地应用5G，以使某些类型的活动和地点变得更加智能，例如建筑、物业管理和校园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为无线网络产品总裁曹明，表示，5G在中国只用了三年时间就达到了4G花了六年的水平。曹在演讲中表示，华为目前正在研发所谓的 5.5G，并将其描述为下一代技术，其速度比现有网络提高十倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“5G 改变了人们的生活，曹说：“数字经济正在成为数字经济发展的重要引擎，使运营商获得商业成功。” “华为将与业界合作，加速创新，将5.5G变为现实。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国移动还一直致力于建设全国计算网络，旨在共享全国各地的资源。中国移动互联网副总经理李斌表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在人工智能时代，此类网络变得越来越重要，因为人工智能时代依赖于大数据模型的资源密集型训练。 ChatGPT 引发了人工智能行业的一系列活动，李说这凸显了计算能力对生产力的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，将此类技术带给世界各地的每个人仍然需要时间。温家宝指出，中国5G覆盖仍有一些领域有待提高。他说，例如在高铁上使用5G并不是一种顺利的体验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MWC是全球最大的移动通信行业贸易展，每年的主要活动都在巴塞罗那举行。由于 Covid-19 大流行导致中国严格旅行限制，其上海地区展会今年自 2021 年以来首次以现场活动形式回归。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的活动将于 6 月 28 日开始至30日在上海新国际博览中心举行。它在周三开幕式之前于周二举行了预演。这家总部位于伦敦的组织者表示，今年 MWC 上海的主题是“速度”，重点关注 5G 转型、物联网 (IoT) 和增强现实。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Baidu says latest version of Ernie Bot has surpassed ChatGPT 3.5, and outperforms ChatGPT 4 in Chinese language]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3225616/baidu-says-latest-version-ernie-bot-has-surpassed-chatgpt-35-and-outperforms-chatgpt-4-chinese?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/9fe47a92-2ad4-4188-bea4-2ea375798909_027eff7d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;百度曾表示，采用人工智能驱动的大语言模型（LLM）随着与美国和当地竞争对手的竞争日益激烈，其聊天机器人 Ernie Bot 在关键指标上的表现超过了 OpenAI 的突破性 ChatGPT。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周二的一份声明中，这家中国搜索和人工智能巨头引用了国家的一项测试 - 《中国科学报》的报道显示，该公司最新的法学硕士Ernie 3.5在综合能力测试中超越了ChatGPT 3.5，在多项中文能力测试中超越了更先进的ChatGPT 4。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“短短三个月在基于 Ernie 3.0 构建的 Ernie Bot 测试版发布后，Ernie 3.5 在功效、功能和性能方面实现了广泛的增强。”百度首席技术官王海峰在声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国网络空间负责人对生成式人工智能的力量提出了担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;王补充道，厄尼的法学硕士最近在创意写作、问答、推理和代码生成方面的改进已经很明显。最新的Ernie Bot还允许通过插件扩展机器人的功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;已经集成了“百度搜索”插件，使Ernie Bot具备了实时生成的能力和准确的信息。该公司计划添加更多来自百度和第三方的插件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《中国科学报》的测试基于旨在测试 AI 语言模型的基准，例如 AGIEval，它通过“人类”来测试模型的性能”，以及 C-Eval，这是一个中国评估套件，可测试涵盖 52 个学科的数千个多项选择题的模型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Badui 的声明是在首席执行官兼联合创始人李彦宏在一次会议上发表讲话之后做出的。一天前的会议上，他表示，自 3 月份发布 3.0 版本进行 Beta 测试以来，Ernie Bot 的“模型性能累计改进”超过 50%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li 补充说，训练性能提高了一倍，并且推理性能提高了 17 倍，使公司能够更快、更便宜地迭代和升级到未来版本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着美国对用于训练大型语言模型的世界上最先进的图形处理单元实施制裁，去年年底，效率的提升对于国家人工智能发展尤为重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;百度Ernie Bot荣登新华社中文大语言模型排行榜&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Ernie基金会模型3.5版不仅李说，这可能反映了北京为解决日益增长的内容安全担忧而采取的举措。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国一直在鼓励和规划之间徘徊。执行和管理技术的感知风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李认为，生成式人工智能带来了许多治理挑战，该领域的健康发展需要建立健全的法律法规、制度体系、道德、 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司于 3 月份发布的 Ernie Bot 3.0 代表了中国对 ChatGPT 的首次重大回应，促使阿里巴巴集团控股和腾讯控股等公司推出了自己的模型。阿里巴巴旗下拥有《南华早报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据新华社附属智库新华社研究所 6 月份的调查显示，百度的 Ernie Bot 在中国科技公司提供的 ChatGPT 替代品中名列前茅。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;百度已推动将 Ernie Bot 整合到其其他产品中，并于 5 月份宣布设立 10 亿元人民币（1.39 亿美元）的风险基金，投资中国的生成式人工智能初创企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可以预见的是，大型[语言]模型将渗透到越来越多的领域，成为推动数字经济及其与实体经济融合进一步发展的关键因素。”李说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 22:50:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China, New Zealand should be ‘partners, not adversaries’, Xi Jinping tells visiting prime minister]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3225625/china-new-zealand-should-be-partners-not-adversaries-xi-jinping-tells-visiting-prime-minister?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 22:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/8e516b0c-081f-45e6-9d62-687c28a5f001_39e1e330.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国国家主席习近平告诉来访的新西兰总理克里斯·希普金斯，他们的国家应该双方将彼此视为伙伴而不是对手，并补充说北京随时准备推动稳定的全面战略伙伴关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新西兰工党领袖希普金斯正在对中国进行为期六天的访问 - 他的这是自 1 月份宣誓就职以来的首次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他随行的贸易代表团由 29 人组成，其中包括一些新西兰最大的公司，包括游戏应用开发商 PikPok 和健身运动设计师 Les Mills International。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;习近平周二在北京会见希普金斯时表示，两国关系“长期走在中国同发达国家关系的前列”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方要加强全面战略伙伴关系，继续将彼此视为“伙伴而不是对手，视为机遇而不是威胁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[我们需要]相互尊重、平等相待、开放包容、和谐相处习近平表示，两国要为营商投资环境提供更好的环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方要加强教育、文化、旅游等领域民间交流与合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;希普金斯后来表示，这次会议“热情且富有建设性”，双边经济关系是议程上的首要项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，还讨论了国际问题，包括“共同努力支持基于规则的国际秩序的重要性”，以及中国在应对气候变化和乌克兰战争方面可以发挥的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们还致力于以下领域：我们的文化和政治制度不同，我重申，我们将始终以尊重但一致的方式倡导反映新西兰独立外交政策或利益和价值观的方法和结果，”希普金斯在一份声明中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;忘掉英国和北美吧——民意调查发现，亚洲对新西兰人来说是最重要的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在此次旅行之前，希普金斯曾表示，他决心“使我们的出口产品多元化”，超越传统的新西兰商品乳制品、肉类和木材，通过支持游戏、健康和保健等新兴行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013 年，中国超越澳大利亚成为新西兰最大的出口市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二早些时候，希普金斯在邻近的天津参加世界经济论坛新领军者年会或夏季达沃斯，中国总理试图在会上就中国经济复苏发出令人放心的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，中国贸易部长新西兰达米安·奥康纳 (Damien O&#39;Connor) 在北京会见了中国外长王文涛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥康纳称此次会谈“非常积极”，北京有可能参与《跨太平洋全面进步协议》伙伴关系 (CPTPP) 提上议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CPTPP 是 11 个签署国（澳大利亚、文莱、加拿大、智利、日本、马来西亚、墨西哥、新西兰、秘鲁、新加坡和越南）之间的贸易协定。这些国家的经济总量占全球国内生产总值的 13.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国外交部长纳纳亚·马胡塔和秦刚在 3 月份会晤，为希普金斯的访问奠定了基础。秦当时表示，中国愿与新西兰共同努力，“延续高层交往的良好势头，增进政治互信”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，希普金斯表示，他不同意美国总统乔的观点。拜登将习近平称为“独裁者”，这与二月份在美国领空涉嫌中国间谍气球的争吵有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国的政府形式是中国人的事人们，”希普金斯说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 22:50:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Jeffrey Epstein suicide blamed on jail guard negligence and misconduct: Justice Department watchdog]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225629/jeffrey-epstein-suicide-blamed-jail-guard-negligence-and-misconduct-justice-department-watchdog?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 22:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/719c5de0-31b2-475b-a3da-f3bacac10fad_4351df44.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;司法部监管机构周二表示，“疏忽和不当行为相结合”金融家杰弗里·爱泼斯坦 (Jeffrey Epstein) 在等待性贩运指控审判期间在纽约市的联邦监狱结束了自己的生命。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;监察长迈克尔·霍洛维茨 (Michael Horowitz) 援引联邦监狱局未能为爱泼斯坦分配一名狱友为例霍洛维茨还表示，爱泼斯坦的牢房里留下了太多床单，这是一个安全问题，并在他自杀时使用了这些床单。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;监察长发布了一份报告，详细介绍了他对爱泼斯坦 2019 年 8 月死亡事件的调查结果，这是对此事进行的几项官方调查中的最后一项。他重申了其他调查的结果，即没有任何谋杀迹象，驳斥了围绕这起备受瞩目的死亡事件的阴谋论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;霍洛维茨呼应了之前的调查结果，即参与看守爱泼斯坦的监狱工作人员的一些工作人员过度劳累。 。他发现了 13 名表现不佳的员工，并建议对 6 名员工提出指控。只有两名负责看守爱泼斯坦的工作人员受到指控，在承认伪造日志后通过认罪协议避免了牢狱之灾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这份报告是在爱泼斯坦在大都会惩教中心自杀四年多后发布的。正在等待性贩运和共谋指控的审判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几周前，美联社获得了数千页详细记录爱泼斯坦的拘留和死亡及其混乱后果的记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;吉斯莱恩·麦克斯韦尔致电普林斯安德鲁在接受采访时说，她的“亲爱的朋友”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;检方称，被分配看守爱泼斯坦的工作人员正在睡觉和网上购物，而不是按照要求每 30 分钟检查一次他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;诺瓦·诺埃尔 (Nova Noel) 和迈克尔·托马斯承认在监狱记录上撒谎，让他们看起来好像已经做过检查，但根据与检察官的协议，避免了入狱。该机构发言人本杰明·奥科恩 (Benjamin O&#39;Cone) 表示，他们于 2022 年 4 月离开监狱局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是霍洛维茨六个月内第二次将一名知名囚犯的死亡归咎于监狱局的失误。去年 12 月，监察长发现，管理失误、政策缺陷和普遍无能是臭名昭著的黑帮成员詹姆斯·“怀蒂”·巴尔杰 (James “Whitey” Bulger) 2018 年在陷入困境的西弗吉尼亚州监狱中死里逃生的因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联社获得了 4,000 多页的信息根据《信息自由法》，联邦监狱局提供了与爱泼斯坦之死有关的文件。这些文件包括对导致爱泼斯坦自杀的事件的重建、内部报告、电子邮件、备忘录和其他记录，强调了人员短缺和偷工减料是如何导致爱泼斯坦死亡的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;安德鲁王子不会穿军装在伊丽莎白女王的葬礼上&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;爱泼斯坦在现已关闭的曼哈顿大都会惩教中心度过了 36 天。在他去世前两周，监狱官员称他是自杀未遂，导致他的脖子瘀青和擦伤，因此对他进行了 31 小时的自杀监视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在爱泼斯坦去世当晚负责看守的工作人员是加班。其中一名通常不被分配看守囚犯的人已经连续第五天加班。另一个人则强制加班，这意味着一天内第二次轮班八小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，爱泼斯坦的狱友在前一天的法庭听证会后没有回来，监狱官员也未能为另一名囚犯配对和他在一起，留下他一个人。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 22:50:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong court fines Leighton Contractors HK$40,000 over shoddy work at Hung Hom MTR station]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3225630/hong-kong-court-fines-leighton-contractors-hk40000-over-shoddy-work-hung-hom-mtr-station?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 22:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/232b6ec4-1550-4aab-b3e7-9f2e9a5f71f0_2b02efea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港一家领先的建筑公司因以下原因被罚款 40,000 港元（5,100 美元）：在建造香港最昂贵的铁路线时偷工减料，由于工程质量低劣而超出了预算。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;礼顿承包商（亚洲）的律师周二在九龙城法院承认违反《建筑物条例》。该公司未能遵守已批准的计划，在红磡港铁站建造一个 1,410 平方英尺的空间，该站是沙田至中环线的一部分，耗资近 1,000 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但礼顿和参与该项目的其他人因对丑闻进行独立调查期间发现的其他问题而受到指控，例如车站平台的偷工减料、未经授权的更改支撑连续墙的设计以及缺少检查文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;沙田至中环线分包商起诉主公司索赔2,400万港元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;裁判官林子康表示，该公司有社会责任，必须按照建筑指引完成新连接线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但他同意该案涉及的不合格工程涉及有限区域，并未造成人员伤亡或大型结构出现裂缝等进一步缺陷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该项目的安全性在 2018 年中期受到质疑。据透露，一些用于加固的钢筋在安装过程中被剪短，导致它们无法拧入车站下方新站台上的车钩中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一丑闻导致铁路运营商高层管理人员进行全面整顿政府委托的独立调查于 2020 年中期裁定，该车站安全且适合使用，但猛烈抨击礼顿公司和港铁公司该项目的监管存在“严重缺陷”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该项目的总成本据信已从 971 亿港元增加到至少 991 亿港元，部分原因是红磡站的加固工程，推迟了线路的全面开通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;礼顿的起诉涉及在车站马厩侧线（火车停放的侧轨）可变制冷剂容量房间的地板上固定钢筋。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;检方案件摘要称，2017 年 6 月 30 日，港铁公司的两名工程师检查现场时，铁杆并未完全固定在车钩上。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港港铁公司耗资 650 亿港元的维护计划可能会受到影响。出轨了。这就是为什么&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;铁路运营商要求 Leighton 在将混凝土浇筑到板中之前纠正这种情况，但工人们仍然在当天晚些时候继续进行该程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;错误仅发生在2019年5月，一名港铁公司员工向建筑事务监督举报车站施工违规行为，引起政府关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名政府工程师发现，由于施工不当，车钩无法充分履行其指定功能。工作，但空间的稳定性仍然良好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在没有事先咨询和接受的情况下使用耦合器，构成了对已接受计划的实质性偏离，”检察官Jasmine Ching Wai-ming在她的书面文件中说&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;身陷争议的香港基础设施核心承包商&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;辩护律师 Adrian Halkes 表示，此次违规涉及小范围内的“技术”错误，并补充说这是 Leighton &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;林法官以 60,000 港元罚款为起点，随后将罚款减少三分之一，以反映该公司认罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;法院最初记录了 Leighton 根据《建筑物条例》第 40(2A)(a)(ii) 条提出的无罪抗辩，指控该公司允许或授权合并未正确固定的材料。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;该公司最终根据该条例第 40(2A)(b) 条承认了类似的违法行为，该条文称该公司“严重偏离了建筑事务监督批准的图则所示的工程”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;两项指控均最高罚款 100 万港元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 22:50:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: strong demand in China for advanced chips used on AI projects creates growing market for smuggled Nvidia GPUs, despite US ban]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3225594/tech-war-strong-demand-china-advanced-chips-used-ai-projects-creates-growing-market-smuggled-nvidia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/e72db326-43f4-4e50-9b91-8bbd1df00326_adf1b817.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国对先进半导体的巨大需求推动了新的人工智能 (AI) 开发项目据业内人士称，这为走私图形处理单元 (GPU)（例如 Nvidia 公司的 A100 和 H100 设备）创造了一个快速增长的市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是一种场外交易，显然已经尽管美国政府去年 8 月禁止芯片供应商超微半导体 (AMD) 和英伟达 (Nvidia) 向中国出口某些产品，但该公司仍然蓬勃发展，后者在用于训练人工智能系统的 GPU 方面几乎处于垄断地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海一位唐姓半导体工程师表示，由于国内对英伟达 A100 和 H100 GPU 的强劲需求，采购走私 GPU 已成为一项赚钱大业。他是数千家采购 Nvidia 高端 GPU 的非官方中间商之一，以满足目前正在开发类似 ChatGPT 服务的各家中国科技公司的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在社交媒体平台抖音（中国版 TikTok）上，许多人的供应商正在提供 Nvidia GPU，尽管很难验证他们是否能够获得广受欢迎的 A100 和 H100 产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深圳华强北街道的一家供应商，这里是全球最大的电子产品批发市场，声称他能够采购 Nvidia 的 A100，售价为 128,000 元人民币（17,709 美元），这高于制造商建议零售价约 10,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;某些改装的 A100 GPU 的价格范围为 80,000 美元据一位不愿透露姓名的华强北供应商称，价格从 10 元到 9 万元不等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，该供应商表示，获得一套 8 颗原装 A100 GPU“即使不是不可能，也是非常困难的”用于高性能服务器系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 Nvidia 网站，A100 Tensor Core GPU 为用于人工智能、数据分析和高性能计算应用程序的世界领先数据中心提供支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在电商巨头京东平台上，英伟达授权经销商以88999元的价格列出了该公司的80G A800 GPU，而80G A100的售价为99999元，但已经缺货。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nvidia的A800被允许出口到中国，因为它减少了原始A100的一些功能。 H100 的改良版中国出口版本称为 H800。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地对走私 GPU 的高需求凸显出中国缺乏强大的替代供应商来提供与 Nvidia 的产品相抗衡的产品。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;总部位于上海的 Iluvatar Corex 去年 9 月声称拥有唯一量产的国产 GPU 天盖 100，用于云计算应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，中国的主要科技公司仍然关注获取 Nvidia 产品。例如，据报道，TikTok 和抖音的所有者字节跳动今年从 Nvidia 订购了价值 10 亿美元的 GPU。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社上周首次报道了中国蓬勃发展的 Nvidia GPU 地下市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; Nvidia tweaks flagship H100 chip for export to China as H800&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tang, the Shanghai-based intermediary for smuggled Nvidia GPUs, said the A100 can now easily sell for between 130,000 yuan and 150,000 yuan in the Yangtze River Delta, where many AI start-ups operate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Training an AI system is just a start,” Tang said. “If companies want to provide large language model-based services, they will require even more computing power.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Large language models (LLMs) are deep-learning AI algorithms that can recognise, summarise, translate, predict and generate content using very large data sets. These represent the technology used to train AI chatbots like Microsoft-backed OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nvidia&#39;s A800 chips, according to Tang, have been bought in bulk by several Chinese Big Tech companies over the past few months, which has led to a shortage in the local market. That situation, in turn, has further pushed up the prices of A100 and H100 GPUs bought from unofficial channels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang said two of his customers needed to pay more than 1 million yuan upfront to lock in their supply for the next shipment of A800 GPUs. “First paid, first served,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s ChatGPT ambitions could hinge on AI GPU chips under US sanctions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s lack of access to advanced chips from the likes of AMD and Nvidia is already expected to hinder the country&#39;s progress in various cutting-edge applications, from LLM development to autonomous driving.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At present, Nvidia&#39;s H100, A100 and A800 GPUs as well as AMD&#39;s MI250 and MI250X series are considered the mainstream products used in AI-related computing applications, according to a recent report by market research firm TrendForce. It said Nvidia now has an 80 per cent market share in server GPUs worldwide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Development of Baidu&#39;s ChatGPT-alternative Ernie Bot, which was originally created on servers using Nvidia&#39;s A100 GPUs, has switched to the A800 owing to US export controls, according to TrendForce. It projected Baidu&#39;s demand for AI servers, for Ernie Bot and its other applications, to reach around 2,000 units this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As such, demand for Nvidia&#39;s China-tailored A800 and H800 GPUs has pushed up the prices of these products “day by day”, according to a sales manager, who requested not to be named, at certified Nvidia solutions provider Sitonholy Technology.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s John Lee gears up for Asean trade trip next month to lure business, as weak global demand drags down exports]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3225620/hong-kongs-john-lee-gears-asean-trade-trip-next-month-lure-business-weak-global-demand-drags-down?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/171797cc-a55c-43a8-b792-a96b663397b2_58760005.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s leader will lead a trade delegation to Asean countries next month to drum up business for the city, according to a senior official, as fresh statistics showed weak global demand continued to drag down exports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Commerce and Economic Development Algernon Yau Ying-wah on Tuesday said Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu would travel to Singapore, Indonesia and Malaysia to foster closer economic cooperation with the 10-member Association of Southeast Asian Nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The importance of Lee&#39;s trip was underscored by the latest trade data that showed Hong Kong&#39;s exports fell by 15.6 per cent in May over a year ago, the 13th monthly decline in a row. Imports dropped by 16.7 per cent, year on year, for the 11th straight monthly contraction.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing says Hong Kong leader John Lee should be invited to Apec meeting in US&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Exports shrank to HK$327.6 billion (US$41.8 billion) in May, while imports decreased to HK$354 billion, leaving the city with a HK$26.4 billion trade deficit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yau predicted the city&#39;s exports would continue to face challenges, adding: “We hope to find a way out through cooperation with different trade blocs and overseas trade delegation for business opportunities.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He revealed the trip after meeting representatives of chambers of commerce for a cocktail reception to exchange views on measures to help them explore more opportunities in various markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The minister said Hong Kong&#39;s bid to join the 15-member Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership was pending the approval of member states.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world&#39;s largest free-trade agreement covers nearly a third of its population and about 30 per cent of its global gross domestic product.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On his exchange with business leaders, Yau said they had expressed full confidence in Hong Kong and many of them had plans to expand operations in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Business leaders at the reception included: Andrew Leung Kwan-yuen, Legislative Council president and honorary president of the Federation of Hong Kong Industries; Paul McComb, executive director of the British Chamber of Commerce; and Ursula Klingenberg, chief operating officer at German Industry and Commerce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others present were: Andrew Yao Cho-fai, vice-chairman of the Chinese General Chamber of Commerce; chamber member and lawmaker Kennedy Wong Ying-ho; and Chinese Manufacturers&#39; Association of Hong Kong president Allen Shi Lop-tak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Klingenberg said the opening of the city&#39;s borders had brought back a lot of interest from overseas companies and in-person visits by delegations were gradually returning.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s John Lee &#39;to lead delegation&#39; to Singapore, Malaysia and Indonesia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Having the borders open has definitely helped get people in and see for themselves how business in Hong Kong works and what it is really like to be in the city,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, some companies had raised questions about practical advantages of the Greater Bay Area. “A lot of companies that come to Hong Kong want to expand to mainland China as well. We all know about [the bay area], but how does it work in practice? You still need a visa, online payment for foreigners is extremely complicated.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bay area aims to link nine cities in Guangdong province, Hong Kong and Macau – an area spanning 56,000 sq km – to create an economic powerhouse by 2035.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese Manufacturers&#39; Association&#39;s Shi welcomed the news of the city leader&#39;s trip, saying the Hong Kong business sector would like to explore more opportunities in the Asean market as growth in the markets of Europe and the United States had tapered off amid geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong to enter world&#39;s largest free-trade pact in Asean partnership&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Demand in Europe is getting weak and, because of geopolitics, it is getting more difficult to get orders from the US,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many factories have moved to Asean countries, but even for those factories, the recovery was not explosive, perhaps because the economic environment is not back to 100 per cent normal yet. Orders are now down by 30 per cent when compared with pre-Covid levels but we hope it&#39;ll get better by the end of the year.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shi said he hoped the government could also help local products gain easier access to the mainland market. “We want to bring Hong Kong products, such as jewellery, food, and medication, at least to the bay area, if not the whole country.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, exports to Germany dropped 32.9 per cent year on year, the biggest decline among overseas markets that month, while those to the US slumped 17.7 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Exports to Asia dropped 18.2 per cent that month from the same time last year. In particular, exports to Malaysia tumbled 38.4 per cent year on year and India declined 30.7 per cent.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s defence chief offers to boost military ties with Vietnam, ‘unite closely’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3225609/chinas-defence-chief-offers-boost-military-ties-vietnam-unite-closely?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 21:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/f96efde2-88a1-4e77-bf8b-a68df7a6f5c6_d2554d96.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China is willing to build closer military ties with Vietnam to “safeguard common strategic interests”, Chinese Defence Minister Li Shangfu said during a meeting with his Vietnamese counterpart in Beijing on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing would coordinate with Hanoi to “strengthen high-level communication” and “deepen practical cooperation” between the two militaries, Li told Vietnamese Defence Minister Phan Van Giang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting comes as the two neighbouring countries remain at odds over the South China Sea, where they have overlapping territorial claims. The tensions have frequently boiled over into clashes and confrontations.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese navy ship in Vietnam on goodwill trip amid South China Sea tensions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Without mentioning the long-running maritime disputes, Li said China-Vietnam military relations, which were an important component of bilateral relations, had enjoyed “sound momentum of development”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At present, the international situation is intertwined with changes and turmoil, and the Asia-Pacific region still faces some security challenges,” Li said, according to a ministry statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China and Vietnam should continue to “unite closely”, safeguard the common strategic interests of the two countries, and make positive contributions to regional peace and stability, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li said a meeting last year between Chinese President Xi Jinping and Vietnamese Communist Party chief Nguyen Phu Trong – the first foreign leader to visit China since its party congress – reflected the “special friendship” between the two countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Beijing on Monday, Premier Li Qiang suggested to his Vietnamese counterpart Pham Minh Chinh that the two countries should manage their South China Sea disputes through dialogue and promote practical maritime cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has laid claim to much of the South China Sea through a “nine-dash line” that encircles most of the contested waters, while Vietnam claims the entire Paracel and Spratly islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, Chinese and Vietnamese vessels were involved in the latest confrontation near the Vanguard Bank – the westernmost reef in the resource-rich Spratly Islands – after Hanoi tried to expand oil drilling operations in the area, according to accounts on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Vietnam criticises China, Philippines over South China Sea conduct&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Phan told Li during the meeting that the Vietnamese military was willing to cooperate with China on border defence exchanges and personnel training, and strengthen bilateral military relations, according to the Chinese readout of the meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Phan also invited Li to pay an official visit to Vietnam, according to a report in Vietnam&#39;s official People&#39;s Army Newspaper on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two ministers agreed to resume bilateral defence cooperation activities and high-level visits between the two sides, and improve land and sea border management, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meetings come as Vietnam continues to seek improved security ties with the United States, with both countries expressing concerns over China&#39;s ambitions in the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, a US aircraft carrier and two guided missile cruisers visited the Vietnamese port of Da Nang, following visits to Vietnam by senior US officials, including US Secretary of State Antony Blinken early this year.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s Cathay Pacific pledges to hire more than 800 cadet pilots this year and next as it gears up to hit the heights of the industry after Covid-19]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3225623/hong-kongs-cathay-pacific-pledges-hire-more-800-cadet-pilots-year-and-next-it-gears-hit-heights?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 21:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/bfc89266-5eb3-4c50-8436-288bcfc4820c_37e58276.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Cathay Pacific Airways has committed to the recruitment of more than 800 trainee pilots from Hong Kong and mainland China over two years as the government promised to nurture home-grown aviation talent to help tackle a staff shortage in the industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cathay made the pledge as the city&#39;s flag carrier held its first cadet pilot graduation ceremony since Covid-10 hit Hong Kong in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Airline officials said they wanted to take on more than 800 cadet pilots this year and in 2024 as it battled back from the damage inflicted by the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cathay opened up cadet pilot recruitment to mainland Chinese residents earlier this year and a spokeswoman told the Post that the response had been encouraging.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Transport Secretary Lam Sai-hung said at the graduation that investment in city talent was crucial as the city navigated its way back to normality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We firmly believe that in the long run, only by enlarging the pool of local aviation talents can we sustain the development of Hong Kong&#39;s aviation industry,” Lam said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He told the audience: “The government is fully aware of the manpower challenges faced by the industry, so please rest assured that we are adopting a multipronged approach to address the issue.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aid measures include a government plan to bring in 6,300 personnel for the aviation sector, part of a wider scheme to bring in 20,000 workers for short-staffed industries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As Hong Kong&#39;s home carrier, Cathay Pacific has a very important role in helping Hong Kong to not just rebuild but also continue to grow as an international aviation hub,” Cathay&#39;s chief customer and commercial officer Lavinia Lau Hoi-zee, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added the 19 graduating pilots, 16 men and three women, would help the airline in its mission to hit the heights in the sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 19 trainees completed 55 weeks of training in Adelaide, Australia, and are expected to join the carrier as second officers next month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The airline said at present there were 400 cadet pilots under training.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Surviving in the wild&#39;: Cathay pilots as ground staff at Hong Kong&#39;s airport&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Andrew Yuen Chi-lok, from Chinese University&#39;s Aviation Policy and Research Centre, said Cathay had taken a “proactive approach” to meet post-pandemic increased demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Local hires are also crucial to the long term stability of the cadet programme,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The airline has trained around 1,000 cadet pilots from Hong Kong since the programme was launched 35 years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Paul Weatherilt, the head of the Hong Kong Aircrew Officers Association, which represents Cathay pilots, said the plan to hire 800 flight deck staff over the next two years was an ambitious target – and added it did not tackle the shortage of veteran fliers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are not short of cadets. We are short of experienced pilots. Under the Cathay system, cadets take years to become qualified,” Weatherilt said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The union has estimated that the airline has around half the number of captains and 60 per cent fewer first officers than in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the number of second officers was around 97 per cent of 2019 levels in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trainees on the Cathay programme start with classroom-based theory lectures in Hong Kong before they start flight training in Australia or the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cadets are later sent to the company headquarters at Cathay City at Tung Chung simulator training.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cathay last year signed a three-year deal with Polytechnic University to collaborate on a new cadet pilot training programme with the airline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 177 cadet pilots are expected to graduate from both programmes in 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Desmond Tsui, 32, a former civil servant and one of the new second officers, left a desk-bound job to spread his wings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A lot of people see government jobs as a stable career with benefits, whereas, as proven in previous years, the pandemic hit the aviation industry a lot … but I did not regret my decision,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsui brushed off concerns about uncertainty over a flying career, such as the potential for airlines to be grounded in another pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Perseverance is an important trait in a pilot&#39;s character,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s Cathay Pacific has lost over half its senior pilots, union says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Patricia Hwang, Cathay&#39;s director of people, admitted in a memo to staff, seen by the Post, that the results of a survey of 6,200 employees gave a poor score to questions on whether they would recommend the airline as a place to work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said that meant “there&#39;s more work needed to help our employees to become promoters of the company.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hwang admitted the airline still faced problems, but it was “committed to sharing in the future successes of our business.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Cathay Group last week said it expected to make a profit in the first half of 2023, after three years of losses caused by the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cathay and its budget arm HK Express earlier said they aimed to hit 70 per cent of pre-pandemic passenger levels by the end of the year and be back at 100 per cent by the end of 2024.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hungarian foreign minister decries EU’s ‘de-risking’ strategy towards China, warns of ‘brutal suicide’ for economy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3225624/hungarian-foreign-minister-decries-eus-de-risking-strategy-towards-china-warns-brutal-suicide?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.27 21:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/139f712e-4685-4d85-8c45-2dc8da804ee6_809da3d0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Hungarian foreign minister lashed out against Brussels&#39; “de-risking” approach to China and warned cutting off the world&#39;s second largest economy would be “a brutal suicide” for Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Warning against the risks of “bloc confrontation” and the possible consequences for the European economy, Peter Szijjarto called on the EU to fix ties with Beijing and expand bilateral economic cooperation, especially in electric vehicles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Political leaders in Europe are not too much interested in the interconnectivity between Europe and China. To the contrary, they are interested in so-called decoupling or de-risking, which, to be honest, according to our understanding, would be a suicide, a brutal suicide committed by the European economy,” he said at a panel discussion during a World Economic Forum meeting in the port city of Tianjin on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our interest is to cooperate with China, unlike others. Hungary looks at China as a country with which cooperation brings a lot of potential benefit,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;China-friendly&#39; Hungary hails Beijing&#39;s peace efforts in Ukraine&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hungary is widely seen as the most “China-friendly” member of the European Union.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since Prime Minister Viktor Orban assumed office over a decade ago, the country has strategically increased its attention towards powers such as China and Russia, notably through its involvement in the Belt and Road Initiative, Beijing&#39;s global infrastructure plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The future of relations between China and the EU “depends on whether Europe is ready to come back to rationality and common sense”, Szijjarto said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I do hope that we will be able to come back to rationality and we will be able to stand with both feet on the ground.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also opposed labelling China a systemic rival, citing differences in culture and political systems, and said Brussels should stop acting as “a teacher of the world”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Szijjarto said both sides could expand cooperation in electric cars – a “reborn industry” in which China has become a global leader, and one that could give impetus to Europe&#39;s auto sector, which has traditionally been a “backbone” of its economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Improving trade, investment and supply chains between the two sides is “a must from our perspective”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He acknowledged his country&#39;s dependence on Russian energy and that Russia had been a reliable partner. He said Hungary was “absolutely interested in a pragmatic relationship with Russia” and supported China&#39;s proposals to end the Ukraine war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Budapest has used its veto right over the bloc&#39;s foreign and security policy to block several joint statements criticising Beijing, while Brussels has subjected its China ties to closer scrutiny in the face of differences, from the war in Ukraine to concerns about Xinjiang, Hong Kong and Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Central European nation is also a member of Nato, a military alliance that China views with growing hesitation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;It&#39;s &#39;complicated&#39;: EU de-risking push casts shadow over Chinese premier&#39;s trip&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The notion of “de-risking” is shorthand for weaning the EU off Chinese supplies of critical minerals and restricting its investment in sensitive industries – including artificial intelligence, microchips and quantum computing – over fears of technology theft and strengthening Beijing&#39;s military-industrial complex.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has been the key concept in Brussels&#39; new approach towards Beijing as outlined by European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen in a speech on EU-China relations in March. The US has recently adopted the same language in an effort to cement a united front on China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week, Brussels unveiled its first economic security plan, which is aimed at shielding the bloc from risks “inherent in certain economic dependencies” while fostering its own competitiveness by making its economy and supply chains more resilient.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Multiple European leaders stressed that they were not looking to decouple from China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the claim does not sit well with Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some people in the West are hyping up the so-called reducing dependencies and de-risking,” said Chinese Premier Li Qiang at the Tianjin forum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To a certain extent, I believe that these two phrases are false propositions,” Li said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That mirrored remarks he made during his visit to Germany and France last week. The trip was the latest sign that Beijing is placing a greater emphasis on improving its relations with the EU amid growing pressure from Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 27 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>