<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China cautiously eyes defence production opportunities with Nato member Turkey]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3228264/china-cautiously-eyes-defence-production-opportunities-nato-member-turkey?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/385f1bd4-e25d-4c8b-9710-ed08985f9 253_1a551bcd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国分析人士表示，中国国防工业正在探索在土耳其建立生产基地以扩大其国际市场份额的方案，但将权衡其扩张过程中的潜在风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国防工业生产商在利用其北约成员国地位进入新市场时，将仔细考虑来自美国的压力以及与土耳其商业伙伴的不那么令人满意的记录等风险因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国防工业生产商将仔细考虑这些风险因素。据美国《防务新闻》本周初报道，一位负责组织国际国防工业博览会 (IDEF) 的未透露姓名的土耳其政府官员称，该展会将于下周二在伊斯坦布尔开幕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该官员称，将有 74 家中国防务公司参加为期四天的活动，而来自美国的只有 5 家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;土耳其媒体 TurDef 的国防分析师 Ozgur Eksi 告诉《防务新闻》，中国企业参加此次会议“主要是为了收购适合其长期目标的土耳其公司”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国卫星再次看到中国的WZ-8超音速无人机&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“收购后，[中国企业]将引入他们的技术，在土耳其享受较低的生产成本，生产北约标准系统并瞄准北约系统使用市场，”Eksi称，但没有详细说明将引入哪些类型的中国技术。 “这些将是‘北约制造’系统，面向使用‘北约制造’系统的国家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国向土耳其转让技术最有可能的候选者是无人机。北京远望军事科技智库研究员周晨明表示，安卡拉迫切希望改善和升级其无人机开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“土耳其TB2无人机的弱点在乌克兰战争中已经暴露出来。”周晨明指的是拜卡科技公司开发的土耳其小型、中空无人机，目前已被乌克兰武装部队使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“安卡拉希望中国转让其无人机技术，帮助其升级TB2，使其TB2 无人机被誉为乌克兰军队的游戏规则改变者，但其有效载荷不足 100 公斤（220 磅），巡航速度为每小时 130 公里（80 英里），最长服役时间为 27 小时，使其很容易被发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是世界领先的武装无人机出口国，拥有多种产品，包括彩虹-s前解放军教官宋忠平表示，除无人机外，中国还可以与土耳其合作生产多管火箭、战术导弹，甚至防空系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这将是双赢的合作，因为土耳其是北约成员国，中国可以利用安卡拉”宋说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但我不认为土耳其制造的武器系统会卖给北约国家，这些武器只会卖给非北约国家或第三方国家，就像土耳其向乌克兰出售无人机一样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，上海政法大学军事分析家倪乐雄对中国是否会将其核心无人机技术转让给土耳其表示怀疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“土耳其大国竞争中的好手。全世界都看到了安卡拉如何利用乌克兰正在进行的战争。”倪说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;倪说，北约国家不会购买土耳其制造的中国武器，因为担心该技术可能为中国留有“后门”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周表示，鉴于土耳其取消了 2015 年从中国购买 34 亿美元的远程导弹防御系统的协议，中国国防生产商可能会谨慎行事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“土耳其旨在使用中国与其他国家讨价还价，以达成更好的协议。”周说，他指的是在与中国取消协议两年后，土耳其于 2017 年同意支付 25 亿美元购买俄罗斯 S-400 防空系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国只有在有利可图的情况下才会达成交易，”周说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;据说中国正在与沙特阿拉伯和埃及谈判武器交易&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;担心受到北约盟国的进一步孤立和制裁，土耳其后来决定不让俄罗斯 S-400 系统投入使用。针对购买S-400，美国暂停了土耳其在建造第五代F-35战斗机的跨国财团中的成员资格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;土耳其为隐形飞机支付了14亿美元的定金，但从未收到任何飞机，而且这笔钱也没有退回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国应该谨慎，以免土耳其有自己的议程，从美国的F-35战斗机交易中获得更好的结果，”倪说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Top Beijing official in Hong Kong urges residents to ‘read and use well’ books on Xi Jinping’s philosophy and vision for city]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3228294/top-beijing-official-hong-kong-urges-residents-read-and-use-well-books-xi-jinpings-philosophy-and?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 11:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/20/a3a0c616-ee24-43df-bbe8-f4a8a9b9eb2 1_4417748b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京驻香港最高官员呼吁居民通过阅读习近平主席的哲学和对香港的愿景来抓住新机遇，他在当地书展上推荐了中国领导人的五卷本出版物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中联办主任郑雁雄罕见地强调，有关习近平思想的书籍是香港发展香港的“重要参考” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习主席高度重视香港和一国两制。周三，也就是香港书展的第一天，郑在五册出版启动仪式上说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些繁体字作品首次在本地出版。这套书包括《习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想学习提纲》和习近平在浙江、河北、福建、上海工作经历四册。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港书展商预计参观人数将反弹至100万&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;郑周四表示，呼吁市民“读好书、用好书”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港书展760家参展商敦促遵守国家安全法&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“香港人应该从书中明白自己共建振兴的使命和责任……全面准确落实中央涉港政策部署，积极把握国家现代化建设机遇，为香港作出贡献。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说。 >;&lt;p>;这些书由华联出版（控股）有限公司旗下两家公司出版发行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑先生表示，这些书的出版是香港社会政治界的一件大事，并补充说，这些书有利于增强香港人对国家的信心，鼓励他们向世界讲述中国故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“也将帮助海外读者更多地了解中国的哲学、中国的道路和施政。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在会议展览中心举行的香港书展湾仔活动将持续至7月25日。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Domino’s serves up world’s cheapest pizza in India to survive runaway inflation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3228297/dominos-serves-worlds-cheapest-pizza-india-survive-runaway-inflation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 11:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/20/6f6d72fc-e4ea-4390-9b86-ce0eb836848 b_73745713.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;问：全球最大的披萨品牌如何应对全球人口最多国家的高通胀？答：拥有世界上最便宜的达美乐披萨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度是达美乐在美国以外的第一大市场，印度的 49 卢比（0.60 美元）披萨是其对抗猖獗的通货膨胀的矛尖，据其特许经营商的首席执行官称，通货膨胀挤压了利润并使许多顾客望而却步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司希望“拥有这个价格点”，萨米尔·凯塔帕尔 (Sameer Khetarpal) 表示，他确认了精简后的 7 种披萨。 “撒上”罗勒和欧芹的 2 英寸奶酪披萨是多米诺在任何地方最便宜的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你要去商店或打开应用程序，因为有 49 卢比的电话，”他说，并补充说多米诺的全球团队支持这些计划。 “顾客会减少外出就餐，因为到处的价格都更高——我们现有的消费者不应该出去参加竞争。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，在线菜单价格显示，在上海，达美乐最便宜的咸味披萨售价约为 3.80 美元，在旧金山约为 12 美元。达美乐全球总部将有关印度的问题转交给当地特许经营商。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“一个艰难的选择”：印度人大吃速食以应对通货膨胀&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;路透社对六名高管和 12 名门店经理的采访揭示了达美乐以及必胜客和汉堡王等其他全球快餐巨头如何被迫改变策略，以应对 14 亿人口市场中猖獗的通货膨胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些公司正在努力保住自己的地位。在一个对其未来至关重要的国家，他们的市场份额经过三十年的快速增长而获得，而在这个国家，很难与街头小吃文化和低至 10 卢比的铁板萨莫萨三角饺竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khetarpal 的 Jubilant FoodWorks 经营着达美乐在该国的 1,816 家门店。 2023 年前三个月下滑 70%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他提供了多米诺骨牌转向印度及其财务收益的新细节；从 12 月开始，他的公司已经取消了商店出售的所有披萨盒的盖子，每次节省 0.6 美分。他表示，这相当于大幅节省了包装成本，因为达美乐在印度的业务有 37% 是堂食。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jubilant 的达美乐业务占其去年 6.35 亿美元收入的大部分，Khetarpal 表示，还旨在通过提供预付款从一些商店业主那里获得租金回扣，但拒绝透露有关成本效益的更多细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达美乐并不是唯一一家瞄准印度价格的公司，这是一个对价格高度敏感的市场，目前面临着比包括美国在内的许多其他市场更高的通胀。高管们表示，希望低价优惠能吸引人们到商店和应用程序订购更多附加产品或升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;必胜客去年推出的起价为 79 卢比（0.96 美元）的披萨，其印度特许经营商 Sapphire Foods 表示，这是该品牌全球价格最低的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;必胜客印度次大陆董事总经理 Merrill Pereyra 表示，该连锁店正在开发对于印度对价格敏感的消费者来说，“使品牌具有相关性且易于获取”，其廉价披萨深受年轻人欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦当劳于 6 月推出半价餐食。 Westlife Foodworld 执行董事 Akshay Jatia 表示，它们将成为未来几周促销活动的重点。该公司在印度西部和南部拥有 357 家门店。他表示，这些餐食将吸引更多顾客，提高销售额和利润。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些平价产品确实在全国范围内掀起一场数字和实体营销热潮——根据路透社对印度四个邦的商店的走访，商店甚至是豪华的新德里购物中心都贴满了横幅。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度对黄金的热爱也延伸到了快餐业，12 美元的汉堡引发了一场风暴&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;达美乐的旗舰抗通胀产品是 49 号汉堡。 -卢比披萨，2月份推出。 Khetarpal 表示，该公司通过降低价格（以及西红柿）进行了“重新设计”，其价格从之前最便宜的 59 卢比开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特许经营商 Jubilant 5 月份表示，2022-23 年间奶酪价格飙升了 40%，鸡肉和纸盒价格上涨了 30%。官方数据显示，最近几周出现了更多冲击，番茄价格上涨超过 400%，创下历史新高，而从牛奶到谷物和香料等各种商品的价格上涨，家庭都在苦苦挣扎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;业内人士描述了一个贫富差距拉大的国家中两个消费者的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多中低收入者在经济繁荣时将在外国连锁店就餐视为一种生活方式升级，但随着通货膨胀的加剧，他们开始勒紧裤腰带，而富人继续花钱购买价格更高的智能手机和销量创下新高的 SUV 汽车等产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当 Khetarpal 参观位于钦奈和其他城市的 Domino&#39;s 商店时，他说他看到顾客掏空了口袋，只能凑到 49 卢比。他补充道，相比之下，达美乐新推出的美味披萨售价高达 14 美元，在一些富裕地区的销量大幅增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于市场份额约为 12.5% 的印度快餐领军企业达美乐以及其他公司来说，今年是惨淡的一年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;必胜客旗下 Sapphire Foods 的税前利润在 3 月份季度减少了一半以上。汉堡王的印度特许经营商 Restaurant Brands Asia 的净亏损扩大了 9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，情况并非全是悲观。欧睿国际 (Euromonitor International) 估计，印度提供快餐的快餐店市场价值近 50 亿美元，而美国的 3,410 亿美元和中国的 1,370 亿美元的市场规模只是其中的一小部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由西方连锁店主导、在印度价值 21 亿美元的披萨、汉堡和鸡肉餐厅市场规模较小，将会增长，但速度较慢。 Euromonitor 预测，到 2027 年，其预计增长率约为每年 15%。相比之下，2022 年的增长率为 21%，2021 年的增长率为 43%，这主要是由于 Covid-19 后的消费激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;必胜客所有者百胜餐饮集团 (Yum Brands) 在 6 月份发出了看涨的基调，将其在美国的 17,000 家门店与印度的 2,000 多家门店进行了比较，后者认为印度存在“巨大的增长机会”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;短期内仍面临严峻挑战.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于在路边吃饭的人来说，在当前通货膨胀损害他们钱包的环境下，[新优惠]仍然偏高，”印度 Emkay 全球金融服务公司的消费者分析师 Devanshu Bansal 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多像 Kiran Raj 这样的披萨爱好者永远不会考虑预算优惠。这位 26 岁的银行员工表示，当他在钦奈当地一家餐厅 Pizza Lounge 狼吞虎咽地吃着奶酪片时，他准备多付一点钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我避免在大型连锁店经营的商店购买低于 100 卢比的披萨，因为它们通常含有较少的配料和一小层奶酪，”他补充道。 “这只是一个粗糙的外壳。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Swedish embassy in Baghdad stormed, set alight over Koran burning]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3228287/swedish-embassy-baghdad-stormed-set-alight-over-koran-burning?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 10:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/20/42b1e266-12d3-4ecc-8912-6e7aad2942 45_87b2d3ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周四凌晨，数百名抗议者冲进巴格达市中心的瑞典大使馆，翻墙并放火焚烧，以抗议瑞典可能焚烧《古兰经》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瑞典外交部新闻办公室在一份声明中表示，所有巴格达大使馆工作人员都很安全，谴责这次袭击，并强调伊拉克当局有必要保护外交使团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;周四的示威活动是由什叶派神职人员穆克塔达·萨德尔的支持者号召的，抗议数周内计划在瑞典进行的第二次焚烧《古兰经》的活动，据与这位颇具影响力的神职人员和其他亲萨德尔媒体有关的热门 Telegram 群组中的帖子显示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;瑞典焚烧古兰经激怒了穆斯林世界&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;瑞典通讯社 TT 周三报道称，瑞典警方批准了周四在斯德哥尔摩伊拉克大使馆外举行公开集会的申请。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《TT》报道，该申请称申请人试图焚烧《古兰经》和伊拉克国旗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《TT》报道，有两人参加了示威活动，其中一人与 6 月份在斯德哥尔摩一座清真寺外纵火焚烧《古兰经》的人是同一个人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Telegram 群组 One Baghdad 上发布的一系列视频显示，周四凌晨 1 点左右（格林尼治标准时间 2200 点），人们聚集在大使馆周围。星期三）高呼支持萨德尔的口号，大约一小时后冲进使馆大楼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抗议者高呼“是的，是的，遵守《古兰经》”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后的视频显示，使馆大楼内的一栋建筑冒出浓烟，抗议者站在屋顶上。路透社无法独立核实这些视频的真实性。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;伊拉克外交部也谴责了这一事件，并在一份声明中表示，伊拉克政府已指示安全部队进行迅速调查，查明肇事者并追究其责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据路透社目击者称，周四黎明时，安全部队已部署在使馆内，消防队员扑灭顽固余烬，使馆内冒出浓烟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;大多数抗议者已经撤离，有几十人在使馆外徘徊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月末，一名伊拉克男子在斯德哥尔摩焚烧《古兰经》后，萨德尔呼吁抗议瑞典并驱逐瑞典大使。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瑞典警方指控该男子煽动反对民族或民族团体。在接受报纸采访时，他将自己描述为一名伊拉克难民，试图禁止《古兰经》，这是伊斯兰教的核心宗教文本，穆斯林认为《古兰经》是上帝的启示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在《古兰经》被焚烧后，瑞典驻巴格达大使馆外发生了两起大规模抗议活动，其中一次抗议者冲破了大使馆场地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括伊拉克、土耳其、阿拉伯联合酋长国、约旦和摩洛哥在内的几个穆斯林国家的政府发出了抗议伊拉克寻求引渡该男子以在该国接受审判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国也对此表示谴责，但补充说瑞典发放许可证是为了支持言论自由，并不是对这一行动的认可&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US House panel scrutinises four venture capital firms investing in Chinese AI and semiconductors]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3228288/us-house-panel-scrutinises-four-venture-capital-firms-investing-chinese-ai-and-semiconductors?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 10:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/20/ea603afc-a3c0-42b7-9d5b-a8ec9bd2294 c_71979eb2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国会委员会正在调查四家风险投资公司对中国科技公司的投资，这是华盛顿对涉嫌帮助中国发展敏感行业的美国基金加强审查的最新迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由威斯康星州共和党人迈克尔·加拉格尔 (Michael Gallagher) 领导的众议院中国特别委员会正在对 GGV Capital、GSR Ventures、Walden International 和 Qualcomm Ventures 的投资进行调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;GGV 周三晚上拒绝置评。其他公司没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着科技前景黯淡，中国的风险投资明星推迟了赌注&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;《华尔街日报》早些时候报道了这项调查，正值华盛顿试图阻止中国开发下一代技术，官员们担心这些技术将主导安全和经济格局，特别是半导体、人工智能和量子计算。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫和国会议员都在制定政策，以跟踪并可能阻止美国在这些领域的投资他们称这些公司被用于侵犯人权和提升军事能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拉格尔周三将这四家公司称为委员会的“初步目标”，并表示调查将为委员会的政策建议提供信息，包括国会授权审查对外投资的任何要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拉格尔表示，他的两个主要担忧是，接受美国投资的中国公司可能会加剧中国新疆地区的侵犯人权行为，并帮助中国军队开发尖端技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“中国不存在真正的私营实体，”加拉格尔周三对记者说，他指的是中国所谓的军民融合战略。 “民主党人和共和党人一致认为，我们不想助长自己的毁灭。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候由众议院议长凯文·麦卡锡(Kevin McCarthy)创建的中国委员会拥有传票权，正在编写一份有关美中政策的报告，该报告将主要关注美国在中国的商业活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该委员会在给纪源资本的一封信中表示，其目标是投资人工智能开发商，包括旷视科技和半导体公司。高通创投对商汤科技的投资也被委员会提及。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旷视科技和商汤科技在 2019 年被列入所谓的实体清单，禁止它们在未经美国政府批准的情况下与美国公司开展业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华登国际因投资芯片制造商中芯国际而被提及，该公司也被列入美国黑名单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些信件均提到了最近对美国对外投资的研究乔治城大学安全与新兴技术中心要求这些公司在 8 月 1 日之前回答问题。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 10:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As India eyes a US$1 trillion digital boom, will it spawn a data-driven resource crunch?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3228203/india-eyes-us1-trillion-digital-boom-will-it-spawn-data-driven-resource-crunch?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/6b73842b-acf5-4834-9cb7-370383a35 62e_a17e58da.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度对一切数字化事物的日益接受为该国带来了一切，从移动支付的便利到在线医疗卡，但业内人士表示，这也助长了能源密集型数据中心的热潮，这些数据中心耗尽了关键的电力和水资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据商业数据，在截至 2022 年的三年内，印度数据中心所需的电量增加了一倍多，达到 722 兆瓦房地产服务公司仲量联行印度——随着政策制定者的目标是到 2026 年建立 1 万亿美元的数字经济，这一势头不太可能放缓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;仲量联行印度数据中心咨询主管 Rachit Mohan 表示：“印度的数据中心行业将持续增长。”他预测，到 2025 年，其扩张将需要额外 910 万平方英尺（85 公顷）的土地，价值约 48 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据中心网络设施的服务器、存储系统和计算基础设施使组织能够处理、存储和传播大量数据：现代经济的高科技燃料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，随着这些中心越来越多地出现在孟买、班加罗尔和印度其他主要都市区，以接近最终消费者，这给他们所需的电力和水基础设施带来了越来越大的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mohan 补充说，现有的数据中心运营商以及该行业的新进入者都在采用采取“土地储备”的做法，即购买土地作为投资并持有以供未来使用，但没有具体的开发计划，以建立新设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些数据中心消耗的大量电力以及冷却所需的大量水，引起了全球对如何减轻其环境影响的广泛关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通常，这种审查的形式是股东呼吁数据中心运营商提高能源效率和可再生能源咨询公司 Bridge to India 的首席执行官 Vinay Rustagi 表示，“随着汞的上升，气候变化会影响能源、贸易和农业吗？”与此同时，数据中心可能会发现自己依赖肮脏的化石燃料，除非他们在发展的早期阶段就确定了购买可再生能源的选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果他们[数据中心]没有可靠的备用电源，那么他们就必须使用柴油发电机[如果发生停电]，而这是高度污染的。据我所知，数据中心成本的 40-50% 仅来自电力消耗。”Rustagi 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于许多人来说，使用可再生能源为数据中心供电的唯一方法是直接与绿色能源生产商而非国营配电公司联系，Rustagi 说，“这是一个繁琐的过程，需要多次批准。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府最好为数据中心制定具体的可再生能源政策，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h 3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在数字经济需求和减少碳足迹之间取得平衡方面，印度并不是唯一一个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡在审查政策时于 2019 年暂停了新数据中心的建设，直到去年 1 月才根据能源效率和可持续性条件解除了禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“数据中心对于印度经济的数字化至关重要，政府正在努力促进其发展，”Rustagi 表示。 “我不认为限制数据中心的增长或选址是解决问题的办法。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师表示，与新加坡相比，印度落后于数字化发展曲线，而新德里无力实施类似的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据总部位于孟买的投资银行咨询公司 Anarock Capital 称，印度约有 20 个活跃的数据中心运营商，他们在过去三到四年内购买了超过 350 英亩的土地用于开发和运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“其中一些是Anarock Capital 工业物流和数据中心总裁 Devi Shankar 表示：“该项目已经在开发中，计划在未来两到三年内供应。” “其中一些地块是为了未来的可扩展性而准备的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，由于基于云的业务爆炸式增长、需要额外的存储来遵守数据隐私法以及全国性 5G 网络的推出，需求飙升，该行业正面临供应紧缩的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的电力消耗将超过美国、欧盟和印度的总和&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“在印度，需求绝对巨大，而且目前的供应量非常大，金杜律师事务所合伙人杰克·罗布森 (Jake Robson) 表示，金杜律师事务所的业务重点是南亚和东南亚，其经验涵盖资源和大宗商品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大部分发展来自数据中心运营商以及大型科技公司，他们因预期需求激增而抢购了大片土地。业界所称的小型“边缘数据中心”开发商来自较低的第三层。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，随着寻找合适土地的压力越来越大，科技公司“将越来越关注边缘数据中心，他们可以设计、制造和大量部署边缘数据中心，以创建跨地区和城市的集成网络。”Robson 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;诸如此类的网络数据中心的各个单元可以快速、廉价地安装在屋顶、停车场和其他空间有限的区域。他补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk says Tesla will spend US$1 billion on Dojo supercomputer over next year]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3228285/elon-musk-says-tesla-will-spend-us1-billion-dojo-supercomputer-over-next-year?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 09:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/20/298fdae9-ea5e-4894-a0bb-7bc9d8481a10 _457a97ed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;特斯拉公司正在不遗余力地成为超级计算领域的参与者，埃隆·马斯克表示，这家电动汽车制造商计划到 2024 年底对其所谓的 Project Dojo 投资超过 10 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首席执行官马斯克周三告诉投资者，内部超级计算机的设计目的是处理创建自动驾驶软件所需的大量数据，包括来自特斯拉汽车的视频。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;他在与分析师的电话会议上表示，明年“我们将在 Dojo 上投入远远超过 10 亿美元”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马斯克表示，中国“注重团队人性”，愿意致力于全球人工智能法规&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这一大笔支出的披露似乎吓坏了投资者，导致特斯拉股价在上市后下跌超过 4%。特斯拉首席财务官扎卡里·科克霍恩 (Zachary Kirkhorn) 在电话会议上很快澄清，这项投资分为研发支出和资本支出，这与之前公布的三年支出前景相符。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克表示，特斯拉拥有“数量惊人”的视频可供使用，这要归功于其客户使用基于摄像头的驾驶辅助软件 Autopilot 以及名为“全自动驾驶测试版”的相关功能，该功能已积累了超过 3 亿英里的数据。该公司在最新的财报中表示，它已经开始生产“Dojo 训练电脑”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Indeed a beast’: Chinese father dangles  screaming daughter upside down from flat window as pee punishment  slammed on social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/social-welfare/article/3228019/indeed-beast-chinese-father-dangles-screaming-daughter-upside-down-flat-window-pee-punishment?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/18/393bef6d-98b8-4df2-a2e4-4ec4dbec512f_0e97ba6e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A young girl is receiving psychological support after her father dangled her upside down from the window of their second-floor flat to punish her for urinating in the wrong place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unidentified man from Liaoning province in northeastern China shocked the mainland online community when a video emerged of him inflicting the terrifying punishment on his small child.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a video clip filmed by a neighbour, the bare-chested father grabs his daughter by the ankles and holds her headfirst from the window as she clutches at the wall of the building.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The girl, believed to be around two to three years old, can be heard screaming for help and crying “Daddy, daddy”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ignoring her screams, the man continues dangling her in mid-air and warns her not to make a sound: “Why don&#39;t you urinate in the bathroom?你更喜欢在自己的房间里小便，对吧？” he asks her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the girl fails to answer clearly through her screams, the father twice demands that she repeat herself as her small body sways outside the window.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He then pulls her up until the girl&#39;s knees are on the window sill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Star Video, the child&#39;s ordeal lasted two to three minutes. The neighbour said he and another resident shouted at the man to stop but he did not listen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The local women&#39;s federation said it has reprimanded the man and is providing psychological support to the child. An unnamed employee said an investigation into the incident is underway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The father&#39;s actions have caused widespread distress on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video had attracted more than 630,000 views and 17,949 comments by July 17.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many people criticised the man and expressed sympathy for his daughter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Oh Jesus, this is so scary!他不配成为一名父亲，”一位评论者写道，而另一位评论者则问道：“他真的是父亲吗？ Who would treat his child like this?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another online observer said the man was “indeed a beast” adding: “He is the one who should be punished.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unusually strict punishments for children regularly spark an outpouring of anger in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June, a woman was so incensed when her son broke his strict diet by eating a piece of cake at school that she forced him to drink a brew of olive, linseed and coconut oil until he vomited.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November last year, the topic also trended on social media when an eight-year-old boy in central China was forced by his parents to watch television all night as a punishment for watching too much TV.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[From AI to dates, China and Saudi Arabia explore new oases beyond oil, but obstacles remain]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3228218/ai-dates-china-and-saudi-arabia-explore-new-oases-beyond-oil-obstacles-remain?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/19/4d6e465f-615d-4798-b374-b17588a08da2_1ae84175.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Saudi Arabian date exporter Omar al-Refaei once again set foot in China earlier this month, this time with higher hopes than his previous visit four years ago, as he looked to sell the traditional fruit into the world&#39;s most populous market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I know, when Chinese think of Saudi Arabia, they only know [about] oil,” said Refaei, having flown over 5,500km (3,418 miles) from Riyadh to attend a trade fair in Lanzhou, the capital city of northwest China&#39;s Gansu province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But we also have a lot of dates. No country can consume all of these, except for China,” added Refaei, who last visited China in 2019 but left empty-handed after failing to find an importer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Refaei was part of a Saudi Arabian government-led delegation, which included representatives from investment and energy departments, who had been invited to the five-day Lanzhou Investment &amp; Trade Fair held at the start of July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I feel there has been more guidance, help and support from our government to help our business opportunities in China get bigger,” said Refaei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following President Xi Jinping&#39;s state visit to Riyadh in December, China and Saudi Arabia have repeatedly described bilateral relations as being at “the best stage ever” amid their respective fraying relations with the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi&#39;s state visit saw US$50 billion of investment agreements signed, and a series of government to business level visits, as China opened up earlier this year after three years of its stringent coronavirus control policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another US$10 billion of deals were also signed during June&#39;s Arab-China Business Conference in Riyadh, covering technology, renewable energy, agriculture, real estate, minerals, logistics, tourism and healthcare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By making Saudi Arabia a guest co-host, together with Thailand, for the annual Lanzhou trade fair, the Gansu government followed up on Beijing&#39;s call to boost cooperation at a provincial level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ministers from both sides added that China and Saudi Arabia could find common ground in renewable energy and combating desertification, as the two share similar arid landscapes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Saudi Arabia is enthusiastic and ready to work with Chinese businesses interested in exploring the diverse opportunities within our borders,” said Saudi Arabia&#39;s deputy investment minister, Saleh Ali Khabti, during the fair&#39;s opening ceremony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I assure you, we have started creating a supportive environment for Chinese investors and businesses. We are excited to explore and forge new pathways of cooperation, not only in Lanzhou, but across China.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khabti added that Saudi Arabia was especially interested in collaboration in technology, renewable energy, infrastructure development and mining.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We will need openness in our cooperation and we would like Chinese businesses to work with us on technology transfer and establish mutually beneficial joint ventures. We are eager to learn from Chinese expertise and learn success stories in various sectors,” he told a room of Chinese businessmen at the fair.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has been Saudi Arabia&#39;s largest trading partner for a decade due to energy shipments, while the Kingdom has been China&#39;s largest trading partner in the Middle East since 2001.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bilateral trade was worth more than US$106 billion in 2022, up by 30 per cent from the previous year, according to both governments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vincent Yan, the Greater China CEO of one of Riyadh&#39;s largest conglomerates, Ajlan &amp; Bros Group, said the surge in Chinese investment in Saudi Arabia in recent years has been unprecedented, and both sides have found new opportunities outside energy trade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Signals from the governments are very strong, and no matter private sector or state-owned companies, we are seeing soaring interests,” said Yan, who heads offices in Beijing, Shanghai, Shenzhen and Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the offices were established in 2017, Ajlan &amp; Bros Group has established nine joint-ventures in sectors ranging from artificial intelligence, fintech, healthcare, industrial manufacturing to courier services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yan said the technology industry would remain one of key focuses of their investment, as their strategy would be coherent with Riyadh&#39;s national development plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ties between China and Saudi Arabia had started to heat up during a visit by Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman in February 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the trip, the two sides agreed to “align” Xi&#39;s Belt and Road Initiative development plan with Salman&#39;s economic diversification blueprint, known as Vision 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Saudi Arabia has accumulated wealth from being a major crude oil exporter, Salman stressed the need for “innovation” and “modernisation” in his plan that would be a “transformative economic and social reform” for an economy that is heavily reliant on petroleum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For China, the world&#39;s biggest energy importer, Saudi Arabia has been one of its top suppliers, along with Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But away from oil, Chinese firms have also recently been looking for new and growing markets after three years of a stagnant domestic economy that is yet to recover.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tech companies, including Huawei Technologies and Alibaba Cloud, have also found themselves welcomed by Riyadh, in contrast to facing increased scrutiny on security issues from the West. Alibaba is the owner of the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In terms of traditional economic cooperation, riding on the growing economic links, Riyadh&#39;s state-owned Saudi Aramco, the world&#39;s top oil exporter, has announced two investment projects in China totalling 50 billion yuan (US$7 billion).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One includes a plan for Aramco and its Chinese partners to build a large refining and petrochemical plant in Panjin, Liaoning province, which was once reported to have stalled during the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The other deal will see Aramco acquire a 10 per cent share of privately controlled refinery giant Rongsheng Petrochemical for 24.6 billion yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The picture for cooperation, however, is not all rosy and bright across sectors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hesham Al-hojairi, the vice-president of Saudi Silk Road Industrial Services, said while there is a growing interest in cooperation and business, there are also challenges for firms to localise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think part of it is cultural differences, and also to get talent,” said Hojairi, whose company provides business consulting services to investors on both sides.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While we got some Chinese technology companies to set foot in Saudi Arabia, suitable local talent also needs to be recruited, and so this is also quite challenging and will require Chinese companies to do it … [supply of] raw materials for some factories would also be one of the problems faced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Yet, I think these are not really big problems, we can solve them as long as there are more visits and communication.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Saudi Arabian attendee at the fair in Lanzhou said another challenge for economic cooperation was that many projects were heavily government facilitated, meaning small- and medium-sized enterprises would likely find it difficult to enter each other&#39;s markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We understand that for China, what it takes for the companies to work with us would be a push by the government, so sometimes it is not about how much we try to lure Chinese businesses to set up a factory in our country, but whether there was a greenlight by the Chinese government, especially because many of the sectors we are interested in are state-controlled,” said the person, who asked not to be identified as they are not authorised to speak to the media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And for date exporter Refaei, who came to the trade fair with high hopes, he again left without being able to find a Chinese partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Lanzhou seems like a small city. I think that there are not many big importing companies,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Refaei&#39;s difficulty in finding partners was shared by Chinese businessman Su Han, the CEO of the Amin Bio Group, who was interested in finding opportunities in Saudi Arabia for his halal gelatin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think in the end, this was not an area that was of immediate urgent interest for them right now,” said Su, who was invited to speak to Saudi government representatives at the Lanzhou fair.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Su said he was also invited to discuss prospects with Saudi ministries in 2019 during Salman&#39;s visit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now companies across sectors want to know whether their business would work in Saudi Arabia due to the positive narrative on economic and political ties,” said a Beijing-based Chinese academic, who asked not to be identified as they are not authorised to speak to the media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And after all, there are not many markets in the world that still have a young population and have money to spend like Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beyond crude oil, is China the &#39;ideal partner&#39; for Middle East development?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Saudi Arabia, according to 2022 census data published in May by the General Authority for Statistics, 63 per cent of the 32.2 million population are aged under 30.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But in reality, this also creates a lot of confusion for both sides because very few of them had experience with each other,” the academic added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is the stage this is at right now, everyone thinks they want a piece of the cake, but they do not even know if they are suitable for it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What can Hong Kong learn from mainland China’s Fujian? Hi-tech tours for city’s lawmakers offer glimpse into model for data centre ambitions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3228275/what-can-hong-kong-learn-mainland-chinas-fujian-hi-tech-tours-citys-lawmakers-offer-glimpse-model?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/20/34fd3644-ce53-4e41-91c9-2d8c4f65dd87_067d1a4e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong should learn from cities in Fujian in its bid to become an international data centre, lawmakers have said as they wrapped up a five-day visit to the province positioned as mainland China&#39;s southeastern tech powerhouse and supercomputing hub.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But some observers warned against “copycat development”, noting Hong Kong&#39;s stricter privacy laws provided overseas businesses with confidence in data storage even though the legislation was often blamed for slowing the pace of digital transformation in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Talk of cloud computing and big data was all the buzz as the delegation of 34 lawmakers concluded their first official visit to Fujian province on Wednesday, after touring a supercomputing data centre, three industrial parks, and a number of technology and biomedicine firms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some lawmakers were quick to conclude that Hong Kong should adopt the model of Fujian cities Fuzhou, the provincial capital, and Xiamen in setting up data centres and different industries in the Northern Metropolis mega development project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After visiting the Digital Fujian Cloud Computing Data Centre in Fuzhou – a facility with a 40,000-server capacity selected as a National Green Data Centre in 2020 for its efficient power usage – Liberal Party lawmaker Michael Lee Chun-keung said Hong Kong should aim for better synergies with Greater Bay Area cities in the area of cross-border data exchanges by making good use of its strengths as a financial hub.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong lawmakers begin 5-day Fujian trip with aim to foster closer ties&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Fujian&#39;s digitalisation, especially its digital economy model … is more advanced than Hong Kong&#39;s. Work is delegated across Fujian, with data centres located in Fuzhou and Xiamen responsible for calculations and data utilisation,” Lee said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawmakers&#39; trip to Fujian came weeks after Hong Kong and central authorities signed a memorandum making cross-border data transfer easier within the Greater Bay Area. It mainly targets data flowing from the mainland to the city, with an aim of developing Hong Kong into an international information hub.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bay area refers to Beijing&#39;s ambitious scheme to integrate Hong Kong, Macau and nine cities in neighbouring Guangdong province into an economic powerhouse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong officials have stressed that facilitating cross-border data flow is an important initiative for promoting the region&#39;s integrated and high-quality development, lowering enterprises&#39; compliance costs and driving growth of the city&#39;s digital economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong explores easier cross-border travel for talent to spur I&amp;T hub growth&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong was Fujian&#39;s largest external investor in 2020, accounting for 71 per cent of the province&#39;s utilised foreign direct investment, according to Trade Development Council research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A visit to an exhibition hall detailing a development plan for Binhai New City in Fuzhou reminded some lawmakers about the Northern Metropolis scheme, under which the government hopes to create an innovation and technology-led commercial and residential hub, with up to 186,000 homes near the mainland border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Spanning an area of 188 sq km, Binhai New City is a seaside district developed to serve as a sub-centre of Fuzhou under an “industry-city integration” approach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Commercial sector lawmaker Jeffrey Lam Kin-fung, who sits on a subcommittee for the Northern Metropolis, said the government should learn from Fujian to make its development blueprint clearer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Their industrial park planning is very transparent and well-planned. Some companies have their own park area, while small firms and enterprises wishing to come could enjoy a public area,” said Lam, a member of the government&#39;s key decision-making Executive Council.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong aims to grow I&amp;T sector by doubling up on talent, start-ups and unicorns&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lam, of the Business and Professionals Alliance for Hong Kong, also said the city would need to work on industrialising its research and publicising its plans to become a top global innovation centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All three industrial parks the delegation visited had an exhibition hall that laid out the history, vision, supporting government policy measures and developmental progress of the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam also said the government should ensure that those behind innovative products got a high share of the returns once the results of their research became commodified as a way to learn from Xiamen&#39;s aggressive talent-poaching tactics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Eric Yeung Chuen-shing, honorary president of the Smart City Consortium, said it was easier said than done to develop data centres in Hong Kong, citing the high land and operating costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Hong Kong must do more to ensure technopole&#39;s success, learn from past mistakes&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said Hong Kong&#39;s strict privacy laws could make the collection of big data more difficult, and thus slow the pace of smart city development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But also because we have rather comprehensive privacy laws here to guard against abuse of personal data, overseas businesses may be more confident in storing their data in Hong Kong than elsewhere on the mainland,” Yeung said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In this sense, it is not altogether gloomy for Hong Kong to become a data centre hub in the Greater Bay Area.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;IT-sector veteran Joseph Leung Wai-fung shared similar views and said Hong Kong should seek closer cooperation with Fujian, rather than compete in hi-tech development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are not strong in hardware development due to many constraints. Our strengths are application development, making use of applications to maximise our value,” said Leung, a lecturer at Polytechnic University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But big data, Internet of Things, cloud computing all touch on data which is very sensitive.暂时要求香港开发商、用户将数据存储在中国城市并不容易。 Thus application development is likely to be an area of cooperation for both places.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese real estate tycoon Zhang Li, co-founder of Guangzhou R&F, avoids US prison in bribery charges deal]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228283/chinese-real-estate-tycoon-zhang-li-co-founder-guangzhou-rf-escapes-us-prison-bribery-charges-deal?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.20 09:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/20/a2372a17-e25c-4851-b5d5-d4c8490747df_a36a4de7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese property tycoon Zhang Li admitted bribing a top San Francisco building official to win permits for a construction project and will not face criminal charges under an agreement he reached with US prosecutors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Li, 70, of Guangzhou, China, was charged by the US in 2021 and arrested last year in the United Kingdom, prosecutors said in a statement.六个月后，他同意被引渡。 His admission stems from a larger public corruption scandal prosecuted by multiple city and federal agencies, resulting in charges against 14 people including the former head of San Francisco&#39;s Department of Public Works.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang, the co-founder of Guangzhou R&amp;F Properties Co. Ltd., will get the case dismissed in three years if all conditions of the so-called deferred prosecution agreement are met, including paying restitution, according to a filing in San Francisco federal court. If he had been convicted of the US charges, he could have faced as long as 20 years in prison.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;R&amp;F&#39;s billionaire Zhang to fight US extradition from luxury London flat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We are pleased that Mr. Zhang has returned to China and the charges against him will be dismissed pursuant to an agreement with the US government,” said his lawyer, Hartley MK West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang bribed the public works director, Mohammed Nuru, with food, drinks, luxury lodging, and transport during a trip Nuru took to China in 2018, prosecutors said. In exchange, Nuru gave Zhang and his company favourable treatment and city approvals for the development of a mixed-use project in San Francisco.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Billionaire developer Zhang Li no longer subject to electronic monitoring in London&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The criminal charges against Zhang and the agreement “send a clear message that this office will not tolerate the corruption of public officials,” including individuals “acting from outside of the United States,” First Assistant US Attorney Patrick Robbins said in the statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nuru was sentenced in August to seven years in prison after pleading guilty to defrauding the public of its right to his honest services.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 20 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>