<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[How China-Russia grain corridor can help Beijing safeguard food security and boost agricultural trade]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3223083/how-china-russia-grain-corridor-can-help-beijing-safeguard-food-security-and-boost-agricultural?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/0f1a8386-0d54-4307-b5bb-441538906a18_ccce5d15.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;上个月，俄罗斯宣布将通过新大陆增加对中国的粮食出口粮食走廊。该走廊由北京于 2012 年提出，旨在发展基础设施并增加粮食产量，将俄罗斯远东地区与中国北部的内蒙古连接起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 6 月，俄罗斯新陆粮走廊集团公司和国有的中国诚通国际投资公司签署了一项共同开展该项目的协议，重点是以本国货币结算交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在俄罗斯附近的后贝加尔斯克建设一座粮食铁路枢纽转运设施- 于 2022 年 9 月启用的中国边境解决了两国之间的轨距差异问题。以前，不可能不间断地从一个网络运行火车到另一个网络，因此俄罗斯出口的粮食必须运往中国，这需要几个月的时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;转运枢纽将运输时间减少到两到三个周，年产能高达 800 万吨，提高了俄罗斯农产品的竞争力，促进了中俄贸易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新的粮食走廊可能为中国带来多重利益，特别是在粮食方面&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首先，走廊有助于中国的农产品进口多元化战略，在国内气候冲击和与美国等主要粮食供应国关系紧张的情况下，这一战略变得至关重要。正如习近平主席最近在一篇关于农业自力更生的文章中指出的那样，俄罗斯入侵乌克兰引发的危机表明，农业是“国家安全的基础”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越来越依赖全球粮食市场，北京认为俄罗斯和中亚国家是最大的农产品出口国，具有进一步增长粮食生产和出口的潜力。随着中国允许不受限制地进口俄罗斯小麦，走廊将促进廉价俄罗斯小麦的进口增加，此外还有包括化肥在内的其他农产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其次，走廊可以吸引更多中国农业投资俄罗斯肥沃的土地东方。尽管农业合作园区和自由贸易区等联合举措已经到位，但农业运输基础设施问题和监管壁垒使中国在俄罗斯农业领域的投资变得困难。然而，粮食走廊缩短运输时间的承诺有望吸引更多中国对俄罗斯的投资，尤其是在远东地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三，该走廊可以帮助中国避免可能影响国内和国际粮食的潜在咽喉要道可用性和价格。在推动提高自给自足的过程中，北京将马六甲海峡等咽喉要道视为一个关键问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;玉米、小麦、大米和大豆贸易的集中——中国的一些主要主粮和农产品进口——在少数国家，这给该国的粮食安全造成了薄弱环节。通过利用粮食走廊进一步丰富供应路线，中国可以在压力越来越大的情况下减少对这些咽喉要道的依赖，同时确保更安全的粮食供应链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新的粮食走廊面临诸多挑战，也具有潜在的全球影响。虽然俄罗斯对中国的谷物出口在过去五年中翻了一番，但与中国的整体进口量相比仍然相对较小。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年，中国从俄罗斯进口的大豆占其总量的不到 1%大豆进口。同样，尽管中国在今年 1 月至 4 月期间大量进口小麦 600 万吨，但俄罗斯小麦的进口量仅限于 3 万吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和俄罗斯在农业合作方面也有不同的做法。俄罗斯的战略以其政府和大公司为中心，旨在渗透中国市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，中国利用自己提供机械、种子和劳动力的中小型企业进行国际发展。中国农民和小型农业企业在俄罗斯远东地区的存在越来越多，这已经成为两国关系紧张的根源。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国和俄罗斯之间的贸易、投资关系如何？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;其他障碍也阻碍了中俄农业伙伴关系，包括俄罗斯的关税政策、保护性市场战略、缺乏足够的基础设施和迟缓的通关系统。为了克服这些障碍并确保双方的进出口流程高效，中俄必须共同努力，共同制定这些领域的标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，中俄农产品贸易已经巨大的潜力。中国增加对俄罗斯农产品和化肥的进口可能导致澳大利亚和美国等主要农产品出口国输给俄罗斯。此外，新的粮食走廊不仅可以让更多的俄罗斯小麦等农产品进入中国，还可以从中国进入其他亚洲市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;粮食走廊为中国提供了加强农产品贸易、保障安全的机会粮食安全和进一步多样化供应路线，同时减轻与全球贸易瓶颈相关的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;展望未来，俄罗斯和中亚国家对中国和其他亚洲市场的谷物和化肥出口预期扩大可能会带来挑战美国和澳大利亚的长期主导地位，特别是在区域小麦和大麦市场，同时也加强了中国在全球和区域食品贸易和安全中的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China should set up US communication channels like it offered other countries, top Biden aide says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223319/china-should-set-us-communication-channels-it-offered-other-countries-top-biden-aide-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 03:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/89809682-f376-425d-804b-d4ed753b930b_887a872a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统拜登的亚洲政策最高官员呼吁北京建立与华盛顿的沟通渠道与它最近与一些邻国建立的沟通渠道相同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫印太国家安全协调员库尔特坎贝尔周三的评论是坎贝尔和其他美国官员警告称，五角大楼与中国高级国防官员之间的通信中断可能会引发军事冲突，这是一系列回应中的最新一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们仍处于相对较早的阶段[美国]和中国之间在对话和外交方面的新一轮接触，不确定它会走什么轨迹，但我可以向你保证......我们将在与盟国和坎贝尔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们认为，美中关系的主导框架确实是竞争性的，而且这种情况可能会持续下去，”他在美国战略与经济中心的一次讨论中指出。总部设在华盛顿的智库国际研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次活动以印太跨大西洋对话为主题，由布鲁塞尔自由大学安全、外交和战略中心协办。治理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我会注意到——你会在最近几周看到——中国已经包括……与包括东南亚在内的国家的磋商机制和热线电话号码，”坎贝尔说。 “我们认为，这种机制也应该与美国一起积极和真诚地建立和参与。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部长王毅和当时的越南副总理范平明去年同意建立一个热线电话处理涉及南海的海上争端，进一步促进双边关系。菲律宾总统小费迪南德·马科斯 (Ferdinand Marcos Jnr) 在 1 月份对北京进行国事访问期间同意这样做。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然拜登政府与七国集团、北约和四边安全对话等重叠联盟进行了合作坎贝尔在周三关于将日本、韩国、澳大利亚和新西兰纳入北约框架的努力的讨论中表达了对总统对抗北京的战略的谨慎态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国“利用国际法挑衅中国”之后台海事件&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;亚太四国领导人一年前在北约马德里会议期间会面，成为长达数十年的跨大西洋防务联盟的“AP4”组成部分.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在那次会议之后，日本外务省发表声明，承诺与该集团“密切沟通”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“基于对印太地区安全问题的认识，和欧洲是不可分割的，他们还一致认为，他们将密切协调和促进作为北约伙伴的合作，利用各自的优势，率先深化印太与北约之间的沟通，”它说。 /p>;&lt;p>;“四位领导人还重申，他们将继续为印太地区的和平与稳定密切沟通，”日本政府补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在被问及更大的前景时Campbell 表示，AP4 参与北约“仍处于非常非正式、偶然的阶段”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当你考虑印太地区的机构时，你必须谨慎行事，”他解释说。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“不仅在中国，整个地区都存在敏感性。东盟对东亚峰会和东盟地区论坛 [是] 太平洋地区的主要政治和安全机构非常敏感。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该地区至少目前已经确定了关于持续的公民权利的现有框架协商和讨论，”Campbell 补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[CNN ousts CEO Chris Licht after a brief, tumultuous tenure]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223317/cnn-ousts-ceo-chris-licht-after-brief-tumultuous-tenure?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 01:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/08/4f5ed5e3-6b6d-4f59-ac9d-7676cae9d840_ffca92ef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;CNN 在经历了动荡的一年领导陷入困境的新闻网络后罢免了首席执行官 Chris Licht在一份该死的杂志简介中，并且越来越多的人意识到他已经失去了该网络记者的信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一变化是在周三早上的 CNN 编辑会议上宣布的，就在 Licht 表示他将“战斗”的两天后”以赢得周围人的信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNN 母公司华纳兄弟探索频道的首席执行官大卫扎斯拉夫任命了一个四人临时领导团队，并在编辑会议上表示，他将彻底寻找 Licht 的替代者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Licht 的任务是努力让 CNN 更受该国政治分歧双方的欢迎；在美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普的多次攻击之后，共和党人对该网络越来越怀疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但该网络中的一些人认为 Licht 的变革授权是对他们过去工作的否定，以及对 Licht 的现场市政厅采访特朗普上个月招致了广泛批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，莱希特改组了该网络的早间节目，但事实证明那是不成功的，并导致长期担任主角的唐·莱蒙被解雇。建立新的黄金时段阵容的努力进展缓慢，自从克里斯·库莫 (Chris Cuomo) 于 2021 年 12 月被解雇后，凯特兰·柯林斯 (Kaitlan Collins) 最近才被任命在晚上 9 点填补空位，而没有固定主持人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Licht 负责监督裁员去年，Zaslav 决定在 CNN+ 流媒体服务启动仅数周后就将其关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾制作过 MSNBC 的早安乔、CBS 的早间新闻节目和斯蒂芬科尔伯特的深夜节目的 Licht 被任命为Zaslav 仅在一年多前接替了内部颇受欢迎的前任 Jeff Zucker。祖克因未透露与 CNN 高管的双方同意的关系而被解雇。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;CNN 首席执行官杰夫扎克在与同事发生关系后辞职&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;扎斯拉夫在给 CNN 员工的备忘录中说，这份工作“这绝非易事，尤其是在发生巨大破坏和变革的时期。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“克里斯倾注了全部心血，”他说。 “他对新闻业和这项业务有着深厚的热爱，这一点在他的整个任期内都很明显。不幸的是，事情并没有像我们希望的那样发展——最终这取决于我。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Licht 没有立即回复征求意见的消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Licht 在周五出版的《大西洋》杂志题为“深入了解 CNN 的崩溃”，事实证明这让他很尴尬，而且很可能决定了他的命运。一些记者因为 Licht 在他到达之前批评 CNN 的一些 Covid-19 报道而感到愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNN 的一些主要主持人——Jake Tapper、Anderson Cooper 和 Erin Burnett——私下表达了他们对 Licht 的保留意见据《华尔街日报》周二晚间发表的一篇文章称，领导层。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，观众正在消失。 CNN 的黄金时段收视率在 5 月份为 494,000，比 4 月份下降了 16%，还不到其最接近的新闻竞争对手 MSNBC 的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zaslav 任命了 CNN 的四位现任高管——Amy Entelis、Virginia Moseley、Eric Sherling 和 David Leavy – 在寻找替代者的同时运行网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们得到了很好的帮助，让我们能够花时间进行深思熟虑和彻底的新搜索领导者，”Zaslav 在备忘录中说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US-China relations: despite the discord in Singapore, high-level talks in Beijing offer hope]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3223219/us-china-relations-despite-discord-singapore-high-level-talks-beijing-offer-hope?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 01:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/a0fe2e31-29d0-4358-81bb-dcf502ccc65b_75ac72b6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国和中国在一年一度的香格里拉大酒店展开激烈的口水战本月在国际战略研究所的主持下在新加坡举行的对话。与近年来一样，两国国防部长相互指责对方危害地区和平与稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，双方再次交锋，发表严厉声明。鉴于活动前夕的挑衅性军事演习使美国和中国的海军舰艇和军用飞机在南海及其上空危险地接近碰撞，似乎警告灯正在闪烁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，就在新加坡的审议落下帷幕之际，美国和中国周一在北京进行了高层双边会谈。一天后，双方发表了简短的声明，其中关键词和短语的选择是相似的。在外交语言中，两个对手是对话者，这种语义重叠被认为是相当积极的。对于在新加坡可见的敌意，这是值得欢迎的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国负责东亚和太平洋事务的助理国务卿丹尼尔克里滕布林克和外交部副部长马朝旭在北京举行了会谈。会谈结束后，美国发表声明说，“双方进行了坦诚而富有成效的讨论，这是为保持开放的沟通渠道和巩固两国近期高层外交所做的持续努力的一部分”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发表的声明中国外交部回应了这一观点并指出：“双方就推动中美关系改善、妥善管控分歧进行了坦诚、建设性和富有成果的沟通”。 “卓有成效”二字值得关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国国防部长在香格里拉对话会上的发言，让我们看到了美中两国在核心问题上如何努力表达和维护各自立场正在受到争议——即台湾和南中国海的航行自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀和他的中国国防部长李尚福没有表示美中关系普遍脆弱。在新加坡直接交谈，除非在尴尬的握手过程中进行非正式交谈。早些时候，中国拒绝了美国提出的在两国将军峰会期间举行会晤的提议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥斯汀在讲话中传达的信息与他在去年香格里拉对话会上的讲话一致。在强调美国在联合国海洋法会议上阐明的对国际法和航行自由的承诺的同时，他重申华盛顿坚持其台湾政策是“维持海峡现状，符合我们长期以来的立场”。坚持一个中国政策，并履行我们在《台湾关系法》下的既定义务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在南中国海的争议声索中，奥斯汀表示美国将“继续与我们的盟友和伙伴合作维护航行和飞越自由。让我再次强调仲裁庭 2016 年裁决的重要性。这是具有法律约束力的，也是最终的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是他就任国防部长以来首次在外部论坛上露面，他在习近平主席提出的全球安全倡议的背景下阐述了自己的言论，并表示推动“共同、综合、合作、可持续的安全，探索对话而非对抗、伙伴而非结盟、共赢而非零和”的新安全之路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李继而重申了中国的承诺到台湾统一。他说：“我们将以最大的诚意和最大的努力争取和平统一的前景，但不承诺放弃使用武力。如果有人胆敢把台湾从中国分裂出去，中国军方会毫不犹豫。我们将不惧任何对手，不惜一切代价坚决捍卫国家主权和领土完整。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个棘手的问题是否会导致北京诉诸武力仍不确定，但显然不会保持沉默桌面上的那个选项。然而，乌克兰持续不断的战争应该提醒我们，曾经被认为难以想象的事情可能会迅速升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于涉及东南亚国家的地区领土争端，李说：“我们致力于促进合作，在相互尊重的基础上，我们地区的集体和共同安全。”北京首选的模板仍然是南海行为准则，但与受影响国家的共识仍然难以实现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，区域对话者的观点仍然大相径庭。在李克强讲话后的问答环节，菲律宾海岸警卫队副局长杰伊·特里斯坦·塔里埃拉准将提出了一个中肯的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你提到中国希望促进对话而不是对抗，”他说。说。 “所以我的问题是关于中国与菲律宾以及可能与该地区其他国家的海上互动的言行之间明显脱节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你们的海岸警卫队将军用级激光发射到菲律宾海岸菲律宾专属经济区内的警卫船。所以中国说的是对话，中国的行动却是对抗。因此，我的问题是，为什么中国的言行会有很大的不同？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题仍然没有答案。显然，北京必须言出必行，以表明其坚持其既定价值观和优先对话而非对抗的诚意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[4 takeaways from China’s May trade data as exports tumbled]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3223247/4-takeaways-chinas-may-trade-data-exports-tumbled?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.08 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/8f999f74-8150-4d0a-97ba-99bd7f8fa3fc_a998b2ab.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京已承诺支持贸易以支持整体经济复苏，但中国的出口由于全球需求疲软，一直在苦苦挣扎。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国的出口自年初以来首次出现下滑，5 月份同比下降 7.5% 至 283.5 美元亿美元，与 4 月份 8.5% 的增幅形成鲜明对比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 1 月份和 2 月份的总出货量下降 6.8% 之后，中国 3 月份的出口也增长了 14.8%，相比之下&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国官方制造业采购经理人指数 5 月份进一步收缩，海外需求疲软已被归咎于此。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月份的出口额也是第二位- 自 2022 年 5 月以来的最低水平，仅高于 2 月份受季节性影响的 2138 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包含高科技产品的类别造成了大部分痛苦，因为在家工作设备的购买量减少以及全球技术裁员影响了需求，”Moody&#39;s Analytics 的经济学家 Sarah Tan 说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“从好的方面来看，汽车出口增长了一倍多，其中电动汽车增长最为强劲。但这还不足以弥补其他出口类别的疲软。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月份中国对美国的出货量同比下降 18.24%，而同期为 6.5% 4 月，连续第 10 个月下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，对欧盟的出口在经历了两个月的短暂上升后，恢复负增长，与去年同期相比下降 7.03%。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;对东南亚国家联盟（东盟）国家的出货量在 5 月份下降了 15.92%，而东南亚国家联盟（东盟）国家是 3 月和 4 月中国强劲整体出口的主要推动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/ h3>;&lt;p>;中国 5 月份进口额同比下降 4.5% 至 2177 亿美元，高于 4 月份 7.9% 的降幅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这主要是由于大宗商品进口下降账单。事实上，5 月份全球能源价格同比下降 33.9%，而全球食品价格同比下降 16.3%。牛津经济研究院高级经济学家 Lloyd Chan 表示，进口下降也可能反映了与中国贸易摩擦的增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，中国在 5 月份进口了创纪录的 1202 万吨大豆，增长了 24 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国 5 月份贸易顺差 658 亿美元，较 4 月份的 902 亿美元大幅下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国贸易顺差5 月份顺差收窄，出口降幅大于进口。出口回落是在 3 月和 4 月连续强劲增长之后出现的。进口延续了 10 月份开始的回落，”穆迪分析公司的 Tan 补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月份中国对美国的贸易顺差达到 281.6 亿美元，低于 4 月份的 296.8 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;总理李强上周表示，尽管今年开局良好，但中国经济复苏尚未稳固，投资银行对增长失去动力表示担忧，他们预计中国经济将提供更多支持&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“出口疲软证实，随着全球经济放缓，中国需要依赖内需，”中点资产管理公司总裁兼首席经济学家张志伟表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“下半年全球需求可能进一步疲软，政府在今年余下时间增加国内消费的压力更大。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;统一的国内市场是否有助于解决中国经济增长问题？ &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周一，中国增加了建立统一国内市场的努力的细节——重点是通过高效的生产、分销和流通建设强大的国内经济，同时遏制市场分割问题。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;北京将修订反不正当竞争法，出台公平竞争审查制度，扩大外商投资市场准入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;积极建设国内统一市场恢复投资者信心和释放长期增长动力的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“展望未来，我们认为出口将进一步下降，然后在今年晚些时候触底反弹。 Capital Economics 的分析师表示，尽管中国以外的利率接近峰值，但大幅加息的滞后影响将在今年晚些时候削弱发达经济体的活动，在大多数情况下引发温和衰退。&lt;/p>; p>;“至于进口，我们认为它们将在未来几个季度继续复苏，因为重新开放带来的推动力将继续发挥作用。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Hospital Authority should double number of biomedical engineers to oversee equipment work, conduct its own facility repairs, expert panel says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3223313/hong-kong-hospital-authority-should-double-number-biomedical-engineers-oversee-equipment-work?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 23:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/08696ac9-b887-4e76-986d-a1aab555b8b0_c9c3c2d8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港医院管理局应将专业工程师的人数增加一倍，以监督医疗设备工程一个专家小组建议，由承包商自行维护和维修设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局周三还誓言要采取法律行动，追究承包商因涉嫌未能达到维修和维护标准而承担的责任，在今年早些时候发生了一系列涉及坠落物体的事件之后。由专家组处理的一项审查是由 2 月份在一家公立医院落下的手术灯引发的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们过去常常依靠承包商对高风险医疗设备进行维护工作 [没有生物医学工程师的监督]，但这些事件让我们意识到加强监督的重要性，”管理局行政总裁高百星博士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港医院应该使用技术来检查设施, 增加检查”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;柯还表示，目前每三年检查一次建筑物的做法并不理想。 “内部工作人员应该接管工作，并根据建筑物的年龄和状况进行更频繁的检查，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邮报已经联系了负责维护建筑物的公司 Getinge早期事件中心的手术灯，以征求意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由测量、工程和企业传播等领域的专家组成的工作组在经过三个月的审查后提供了一份包含 23 条建议的清单&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港医院管理局承认老化设施维修困难&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;委员会主席温文仪表示，管理局的生物医学工程师人数应增加一倍，以满足承包商监督设备工程的巨大需求。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前有 15 名生物医学工程师为当局工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;万说，43 家公立医院每年进行约 351,000 例维修。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“生物医学工程师全神贯注于设备采购，而无暇监督[承包商]的维修和维护工作，这并不理想。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他建议进一步集中采购工作和主要维护合同在当局总部，让工程师专注于监督任务并接受相关培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wan 将一连串事件与建筑物和设施老化以及大流行期间定期维护中断联系起来, 并补充说，医院亦应妥善记录设备的使用手册，以协助监督工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一方面，委员会建议与设备工作分开的一般楼宇维修工作，应由内部处理，不依赖&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wan 表示，当局医院共有约 740 名设施管理人员，他们应该参与大楼维修工程，理由是他们“拥有更强的主人翁意识”。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;香港当局呼吁以医院坠物为警钟&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“他们应密切留意容易漏水的地方，这会增加风险的混凝土剥落。他们还应该经常检查高风险地方，把医院当作自己的家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局管理的300座建筑物中，有一半以上是30多年前竣工的。一些建筑物的历史超过 85 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wan 补充说，与外部承包商相比，内部设施工作人员会发现更容易适应维护计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 Ko 说考虑到每个病例的独特性，将不会成为检查易受攻击设施的频率的硬性指标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，每家医院都将设立一个安全委员会，以监督维修和保养&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港医院护士因配药器故障而触电受伤&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;注意到在短期内增加生物医学工程师的数量存在困难Ko 表示，在一段时间内，技术将用于提高检测结构缺陷的效率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构的策略和规划总监程伟权博士表示，红外线扫描仪和湿度计是正在开发的工具之一用于辅助常规检查方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局正与理工大学合作，测试先进传感器和雷达在容易漏水的区域（包括厨房和洗手间）的应用，以促进及早发现混凝土剥落&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，当局还将加强其内部报告和公开披露机制，要求根据新指南向管理层报告每起事件，并评估是否需要公开披露。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 23:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s yuan seen as ‘new choice’ for RCEP, may match pound and yen in 10 years, report says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3223277/chinas-yuan-seen-new-choice-rcep-may-match-pound-and-yen-10-years-report-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/cf8a38ec-2ac4-45a9-9637-880e66312b45_baf97422.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国应通过区域贸易协定和离岸贸易进一步吸引人们对使用人民币日益增长的兴趣centres, according to a Bank of China report, as Beijing presses on to increase global use for the currency in an “orderly” manner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Members of the 15-nation Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP) accounted for 18.9 per cent of yuan-denominated remittances in China last year, compared with 15.9 per cent in 2021 and just 7.1 per cent in 2020, according to the bank&#39;s 2022 yuan internationalisation white paper released on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is also strong intention to expand the cross-border use of yuan in the China-backed RCEP that involves the 10-members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (Asean), plus China, South Korea, New Zealand, Australia and Japan, it added .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 90 per cent of domestic and foreign companies said they believe “strongly” using the yuan in cross-border payments could steady in the Asia-Pacific region when the liquidity among major currencies takes a hit, according to the state-owned bank&#39;s survey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In 2022, the US Federal Reserve continued to raise interest rates, the liquidity of the US dollar tightened, and the attractiveness of yuan financing to overseas market players rose, ” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“78.6 per cent of overseas industrial and commercial enterprises interviewed said that when the liquidity of international currencies such as the US dollar and the euro is relatively tight, they would choose yuan as a new choice of financing currency, and this ratio has increased by 7.4 percentage points compared with the survey results in 2021.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The survey, conducted between January 30 and February 27, drew data and feedback from 3,600 domestic and foreign industrial and commercial enterprises, as well as 82 overseas financial institutions. It also used data from the global financial messaging system Swift.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Almost 80 per cent also said the yuan will enjoy an international status of no weaker than the British pound and Japanese yen in 10 years, although the 79.8 per cent figure was slightly lower than 81 per cent in 2021 and 80.2 per cent in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Which 8 nations are using China&#39;s yuan more, and how will it affect US dollar?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Acknowledging the growth of yuan trading in Russia last year, the Bank of China saw potential in offshore yuan trading in Africa, highlighting that Chinese financial institutions in Zambia, South Africa, Angora, Djibouti and Mauritius can consider offering yuan deposit, lending and remittance services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the offshore yuan centres in East Asia, outstanding yuan deposits in South Korea declined by 4.8 per cent in 2022 to US$1.78 billion from a year ago, the Bank of China said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was, though, an increase of 14.4 per cent in the total amount of yuan denominated remittances and payments in South Korea compared to 2021, the report added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has been treading cautiously when it comes to further increasing the global use of the yuan, which is yet to be fully convertible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world&#39;s second-largest economy and an export powerhouse continues to keep a tight control on cross-border fund flows and manages the yuan exchange rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lu Lei, deputy director of the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, pledged to create more application scenarios during the country&#39;s opening-up and also vowed to boost its use in regional pacts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that the stability of China&#39;s economy and the prudence of its monetary policy are important fundamental factors that have been driving the “orderly” internationalisation of the yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On the premise of effectively preventing and controlling risks, we should continue to improve the facilitation level for foreign investors to invest in the domestic financial market, smooth the channels for the trading of yuan, and increase the willingness of foreign entities to hold the yuan,” Lu wrote in the latest issue of Tsinghua Financial Review published this week.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Citi CEO Jane Fraser joins likes of Elon Musk, Jamie Dimon in visiting China after its reopening]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3223307/citi-ceo-jane-fraser-joins-likes-elon-musk-jamie-dimon-visiting-china-after-its-reopening?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 21:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/07/90ca6491-5b78-40c1-ad85-8b5ca4853795_b1d63a35.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Citibank CEO Jane Fraser has followed in the footsteps of Tesla&#39;s Elon Musk and other CEOs from the West by making a beeline to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fraser met Li Yunze, director of the National Administration of Financial Regulation (NAFR), on Monday, according to a statement by China&#39;s new financial regulator on Wednesday. She expressed “full confidence in China&#39;s economic and financial development” and pledged to expand business in the country, the statement added. The Chinese regulator also added that the country&#39;s financial industry will open up further to the rest of the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Citi, which first opened for business in China in 1902, announced late last year that it would wind down its consumer banking business in the country as part of a global strategy adjustment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The long list of similar visits by CEOs from the technology, banking, fashion and manufacturing sectors indicates major western businesses with interests in the world&#39;s second-largest economy are keen to re-engage after its reopening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fraser also met the head of the Chinese People&#39;s Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries on Tuesday, the association said on Wednesday. She said the United States and China should strengthen dialogue and cooperation in areas of common interest, according to a statement by the association.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fraser&#39;s trip came on the heels of a visit to China by Musk, who last week said Tesla opposed a decoupling between the US and China. The carmaker – a runaway leader in China&#39;s premium electric vehicles segment – was willing to continue expanding its operations in the country, Musk said during his brief visit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JPMorgan CEO Jamie Dimon also said during a recent visit to China that there “won&#39;t be a decoupling” between Washington and Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roland Busch, the Siemens CEO, will be in China this month for his second visit this year, according to Chinese official media Global Times. Busch is expected to announce new plans for the Chinese market and attend a digital economy forum in Beijing, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, Busch joined a slew of CEOs such as Apple&#39;s Tim Cook, Saudi Aramco&#39;s Amin H Nasser and Mercedes-Benz&#39;s Ola Källenius at Beijing&#39;s high-profile China Development Forum, casting a vote of confidence in the Chinese market despite lingering concerns about the country&#39;s progress with economic reforms and geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;François-Henri Pinault, the CEO of French luxury group Kerry, was in China in February to gauge the market himself.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Construction work at Hong Kong public housing estate stops as emergency exit at MTR station sinks by 20mm]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3223310/construction-work-hong-kong-public-housing-estate-stops-emergency-exit-mtr-station-sinks-20mm?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 21:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/07/75b2ca6c-118b-418a-bb3b-9de4dbcab003_57cdf9f6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Part of the piling works of a Hong Kong public housing estate has been halted after it was blamed for the sinking of an emergency exit at a nearby MTR station.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A settlement monitoring checkpoint installed at an emergency exit at the MTR Sung Wong Toi station along the Tuen Ma Line found it had sunk by 20mm (0.8 inches) on Monday, triggering the suspension of piling works within 30 metres (98 feet) of the facility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Transport and Logistics Lam Sai-hung said the MTR Corporation and the Electrical and Mechanical Services Department had confirmed that rail operations at the site were safe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The [department] and MTR Corp will continue to look at the incoming data to ensure that continued rail operation would be safe,” Lam said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also pledged all relevant authorities would ensure the construction site had implemented appropriate measures to mitigate the problem before they were allowed to resume work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sinking problem was believed to be related to the foundation works of a public-housing project at Kai Tak Site 2B3, which is close to the MTR Sung Wong Toi emergency exit. Work started last September.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a separate government statement, it said authorities had reviewed the monitoring data submitted by MTR Corp and were satisfied that the condition of the railway fulfilled the operation safety requirements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The construction works concerned have not affected the structural safety of the railway facilities and safe operation of the railway,” the statement said&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Legislator Kitson Yang Wing-kit of Kowloon Central constituency, however, expressed concerns saying the incident was “quite unusual”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Besides this, in the whole Kai Tak district, there will be about six construction sites doing work nearby in the future,” Yang, also a Kowloon City district councillor, added, urging authorities to step up monitoring of those sites.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Veteran structural engineer Ngai Hok-yan said foundation works causing settlement in nearby building structures was not uncommon but added: “It is too early to say at this stage how dangerous a 20mm sinking is … We should also check if underground pipes, like water pipes, are also affected.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s Kai Tak housing plan grounds high-flying expectations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, MTR Corp confirmed the sinking problem but reassured the public that “railway safety is not affected” and that it would “continue to monitor the situation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The registered building professionals responsible for the construction project have been requested to provide work methods and mitigation measures that can effectively alleviate settlement brought by the construction works,” the MTR statement read.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Resumption of the relevant works will be considered only when it is ensured that the construction works will not have any adverse impact on railway facilities and the safe operation of the railway,” it said, adding the corporation had a set of stringent and comprehensive protection measures for any construction activities in the proximity of its premises.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Should Hong Kong look to Shenzhen&#39;s Skyshuttle to ease transport woes in Kai Tak?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A requirement of the Fire Services Department, the exit provides an escape route for passengers to flee the tunnel in case of an emergency. Commuters do not use it on normal days, according to MTR Corp.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Housing Authority installed the monitoring checkpoint to meet MTR Corp&#39;s requirements for railway protection. As a general guide, the safety area is about 30 metres from structures or fences or tracks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a reply to the Post, the Housing Authority said it hoped to complete the investigation report and have the authorities approve the recommended remedial measures in about two to three months so suspended building works could resume as soon as possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A government-subsidised housing estate is under construction at Kai Tak Site 2B3. According to the authority, It will comprise a residential block of 1,280 units and a nine-storey block housing community services.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2 Hong Kong political parties to back funding request for light housing scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The suspended work was on the foundation of the block for community services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The residential block was set to be completed in about 2026-27, and the authority did not expect a delay despite the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, the construction of a private housing estate in Kai Tak was also reported to have caused a 20.1mm sinking of a section of a nearby rail tunnel. Construction works stopped for some three months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2021, the building of a Fire Services Department complex was temporarily halted after it was believed to have sunk the rail tunnel between Kowloon and Olympic MTR stations by 20.27mm.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US accused of using international law to provoke China after latest Taiwan Strait incident]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3223278/us-accused-using-international-law-provoke-china-after-latest-taiwan-strait-incident?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/07/85885b8d-9dc7-47f9-89e0-8654df827afe_891a1136.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing believes the US is using international law as a “cover” for provocations and feels it has “no choice” but to intercept US warships in the Taiwan Strait, according to mainland Chinese observers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But US-based maritime law specialists said China&#39;s actions risked “the possibility of conflict” and were an indication Beijing was disregarding international practice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 3, a People&#39;s Liberation Army (PLA) warship came within 137 metres (150 yards) of an American destroyer during a joint Canada-US operation through the Taiwan Strait, the Pentagon said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US officials accused the PLA of making an “unsafe and unprofessional” manoeuvre, and warned that China was violating the international maritime law on safe passage and raising the risk of a military miscalculation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s foreign ministry called the manoeuvre “lawful” and “justified” in the face of US provocation, accusing Washington of “stirring up trouble” in the Taiwan Strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident coincided with the release of an analysis from the South China Sea Strategic Situation Probing Initiative , a Beijing-based defence think tank, which argued that China has the right under international law to intercept US warships sailing through the strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese paper accuses Canadian press of hyping PLA ship&#39;s &#39;very scary&#39; move&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;US forces have long cited the laws on “innocent passage” to defend their voyages through sensitive areas such as the Taiwan Strait and South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the think tank argued that coastal states such as China have the right to determine what constitutes “innocent passage” under Article 25 of the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There has never been an unrestricted right of navigation in the convention or in general international law,” its analysis read. “US warships may exercise the right of innocent passage, but at the same time must respect the coastal state&#39;s determination of whether the passage is innocent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But diplomatic analysts from both the US and China questioned this reading.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Under international law, innocent passage is only relevant within a state&#39;s 12-nautical-mile [22km] territorial sea,” said Gregory Poling, director of the Asia Maritime Transparency Initiative at the Centre for Strategic and International Studies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the strait, which is 130km (70 nautical miles) wide at its narrowest point, is “far too wide to be considered territorial waters under any circumstances”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma Jianying, director of the Centre for Maritime Security Studies at Shandong Normal University, said: “Objectively speaking, the US warships have the right to pass through the Taiwan Strait.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But according to Ma, China views US navigation exercises as a “tactic to bully China”, and sending out its own warships was a signal to deter future passage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China has no other choice,” Ma said. “It can&#39;t stop the US warships passing across the Taiwan Strait, so it has to send out its own warships.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Most Europeans would want to stay neutral in a US-China war over Taiwan: study&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China has long considered US warship passages through the strait as needlessly provocative and a challenge to its claims of sovereignty over Taiwan – which Beijing considers to be a renegade province that should be brought back to the fold, by force if necessary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Immediately following the most recent incident, Senior Colonel Shi Yi, a spokesperson for PLA Eastern Theatre Command, said US actions were undermining regional peace and stability and sent “the wrong signals to Taiwan independence forces”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;James Kraska, chairman of the Stockton Centre for International Law at the US Naval War College, said: “[Beijing] routinely exercises its right of navigation and overflight near neighbours and distant states, but creates &#39;incidents&#39; when the United States conducts the same operations at the same distance from China.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s actions increase the likelihood of further situations like we saw over the weekend and raise the possibility of conflict,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Ni Lexiong, a professor at the Shanghai University of Political Science and Law, said that the latest incident was not a matter of who was right under international law, but rather a matter of deterrence and counter-deterrence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s logic is that when countering US actions, why should it abide by international law that has become cover for Washington to intimidate and provoke Beijing?” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Poling warned that such a posture only calls into question Beijing&#39;s commitment to regional and global security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China does not want to be bound by international laws that it finds constraining or at odds with its policy preferences,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That desire for extreme exceptionalism does raise tensions between China on one hand and a growing coalition of anxious states on the other, which includes all of the G7, Europe, and most of China&#39;s neighbours in East and Southeast Asia.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesia President Joko Widodo reassures Singapore investors of returns on beleaguered new capital city Nusantara]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223289/indonesia-president-joko-widodo-reassures-singapore-investors-returns-beleaguered-new-capital-city?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 21:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/07/0eba734a-512f-498c-ae64-58dc8f95cdbb_e0980c9e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Indonesian President Joko Widodo on Wednesday made a renewed pitch for his country&#39;s new US$32-billion capital city to investors in Singapore, the latest attempt to lure funds into a project that has so far failed to attract big-ticket investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking at a sustainability-focused conference hosted by Singapore&#39;s Temasek Holdings, the president offered 300 development packages worth US$2.6 billion to investors interested in building the city, Nusantara, amid the jungles of Borneo Island, and promised high returns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Everything will be fine, no need to worry, your investment in Indonesia will continue to be safe and [there will be] continuity in the development of Nusantara capital city,” said Jokowi, as he is popularly known, while presenting images of the planned futuristic city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So far, not a single investment deal has been signed as investors worry about the project&#39;s feasibility and future given an expected transition of power in the next year&#39;s general and presidential elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nusantara is set to become the capital of Southeast Asia&#39;s biggest economy from next year, replacing the congested yet beating commercial and political heart of the country, Jakarta. Jokowi, who made infrastructure development a priority during his two terms in office, considers the project part of his legacy as he prepares to leave office next year after a decade in power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has said he expects most the city to be funded by the private sector and the government in March introduced a set of incentives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bambang Susantono, chair of the Nusantara authority, told the same forum that funding the project will be profitable, citing a 11 per cent to 13 per cent potential return on investing in the city&#39;s power system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Investors from South Korea, Japan, China, Germany and the United Arab Emirates are conducting due diligence and about 100 more visited Nusantara last week, he said, without elaborating.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some 16,000 civil servants, military and police officers are expected to move to Nusantara by next year. Construction of government buildings is under way but only temporary settlements for workers were seen at the site as of March.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>