<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Australia hits out at Hong Kong bounty for national security law suspects: ‘it’s just unacceptable’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3226580/australia-hits-out-hong-kong-bounty-national-security-law-suspects-its-just-unacceptable?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 10:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/1ad89f29-c686-4348-8b21-cdd1d4746495_d73c672e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚总理安东尼·阿尔巴内斯周三表示，香港的做法“不可接受”对两名澳大利亚居民悬赏，他们是根据国家安全法通缉的八名海外民主活动人士之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港行政长官李家超周二表示，八名海外香港活动人士被悬赏因涉嫌危害国家安全而被发出逮捕令的人将被“终身追捕”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港警方悬赏 100 万港元（127,700 美元），奖励提供线索逮捕包括墨尔本律师在内的 8 人。以及澳大利亚公民任嘉伦，以及自 2021 年以来一直居住在澳大利亚的前香港立法会议员许泰德。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿尔巴尼斯在接受九号台电视采访时谈到香港的声明时表示，“这是不可接受的”。 “我们将继续在力所能及的范围内与中国合作，但在必须的地方我们会提出不同意见。我们在人权问题上确实存在分歧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港活动人士被指控要求外国势力对香港和中国大陆实施制裁，并根据北京对香港实施的国家安全法进行通缉。 2020 年，前英国殖民地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤表示，澳大利亚对广泛适用国家安全法来逮捕或向民主人士和民间社会施压感到担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大陆和香港当局表示，该法律恢复了维护亚洲金融中心经济成功所需的稳定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他被指控的活动人士包括罗冠聪 (Nathan Law)、郭安娜 (Anna Kwok) 和刘芬 (Finn Lau)，前郭丹尼斯 (Dennis Kwok) 律师，工会成员 Christopher Mung 和在线评论员 Elmer Yuen。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港悬赏 8 名国安法嫌疑人，向世界发出“强烈信息”：李&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“结束他们被囚禁的命运的唯一方法李周二对记者表示：“如果潜逃者会被终身追捕，那就是自首。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;活动人士分布在多个国家，包括美国、英国和澳大利亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球警察机构国际刑警组织在一份声明中表示，截至周二，尚未收到对上述八人发布红色通缉令或通缉人员的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构表示，成员国可以要求国际刑警组织发布红色通缉令。向持有有效国家逮捕令的个人发出通知，但会审查附加请求是否符合国际刑警组织规则和人权，并评估有关个人是否是难民或政治活动家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A美国国务院发言人表示，香港此举开创了“一个危险的先例，威胁到全世界人民的人权和基本自由。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国外交大臣詹姆斯·克莱维利表示，他的政府“不会容忍任何中国试图对英国和海外个人进行恐吓和噤声”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部发言人毛宁表示，这八人是“外部反华势力干预香港事务的先锋队” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还表示“坚决反对个别国家公然抹黑香港国安法、干涉香港法律制度。”&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;警方国家安全“通缉”名单上有“数十名香港居民”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;目前居住在美国首都华盛顿的活动人士之一郭安娜在接受采访时表示宣布她将继续强调中国对香港自由和法治的镇压。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我相信我们所争取的价值观是正确的。这就是为什么我永远不会停止，也永远不会退缩，即使我的人头悬赏，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李行政长官表示，当局将继续“监控”这八人在海外的行动和行为，但没有具体说明当局将如何做到这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望他们知道我们不会袖手旁观，”李说，他还呼吁公众提供有关活动人士的资料。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Monday was the hottest day ever recorded as global temperatures rise]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3226581/monday-was-hottest-day-ever-recorded-global-temperatures-rise?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 10:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/d7bfe68c-d313-4ce9-99a5-d7300210a5e3_14f2790f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周一全球气温创下历史新高，凸显了温室气体不断增加的危险燃烧化石燃料产生的排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据国家环境预测中心的数据，全球平均气温为 17 摄氏度（63 华氏度），略高于 2016 年 8 月创下的 16.9 度的历史记录.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新高凸显了北半球 2023 年夏季已进入尾声，并让人们关注全球减排进展缓慢的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这不是我们认为的里程碑。格兰瑟姆气候变化与环境研究所高级讲师弗里德里克·奥托说：“我们应该庆祝，这对人类和生态系统来说都是死刑。” “令人担忧的是，很长一段时间不会是最热的一天。”她说，厄尔尼诺天气现象将导致全球气温升高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年夏天的炎热天气已经让全球数百万人面临危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国正在经历一场严峻的气候变化。北京气温突破纪录不到两周后，又迎来新一轮热浪。上个月印度的极端高温已导致一些最贫困地区的死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;越南农民通过在黑暗中种植水稻来抵御 37 度的高温&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;上周危险的热穹覆盖了德克萨斯州和墨西哥北部，而英国则迎来了有记录以来最热的六月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;热带太平洋七年来首次出现厄尔尼诺现象，并将引发厄尔尼诺现象的激增据世界气象组织称，“厄尔尼诺现象的出现将大大增加打破气温记录的可能性，”世界气象组织秘书长佩特里·塔拉斯在周二的声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;政府间气候变化专门委员会在 3 月份的一份总结其五年研究的报告中表示，由于气候行动的努力仍然不足，“短期内”世界升温可能会超过 1.5 度。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;该报告称，到 2035 年，全球温室气体排放量需要比 2019 年的水平减少 60%，而且随着变暖的每一次加剧，与气候相关的风险也在增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的世界需要在所有方面采取气候行动——一切、各地、同时，”联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯当时在一份声明中表示。古特雷斯敦促各国迅速加快计划，逐步淘汰化石燃料的使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着各国齐聚迪拜，参加今年晚些时候在迪拜举行的 COP28 年度联合国气候峰会，人们的注意力将集中在限制全球变暖的努力上。上个月在德国举行的 COP28 会议上，外交官们离开了为期两周的筹备会议，他们对国家间的争吵以及一些人所说的缺乏雄心感到失望。阿拉伯联合酋长国，今年的东道国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果未能取得显着提高将全球平均气温升高 1.5 度以下的前景的进展，一些国家，特别是脆弱的小岛屿国家，可能会开始质疑多边气候进程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s services activity softens in June as recovery falters, expands at slowest pace in 5 months]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3226578/chinas-services-activity-softens-june-recovery-falters-expands-slowest-pace-5-months?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 09:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/c81f7576-ceea-4f82-bfbb-b9b8a30ae9ce_2010ad37.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;6 月份中国服务业活动增速为五个月以来最慢，私营企业周三的行业调查显示，需求疲软打压了疫情后的复苏势头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财新/标普全球服务业采购经理人指数 (PMI) 从 5 月份的 57.1 降至 6 月份的最低值 53.9自一月份当局放弃防病毒限制后，冠状病毒席卷全国以来。 50 点的大关区分了活动的扩张和收缩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该数据大致追踪了上周发布的政府官方采购经理人指数 (PMI)，并显示，由于现场服务需求减弱，服务业活动放缓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;继第一季度增速快于预期之后，全球第二大经济体在 4 月至 6 月间因通货紧缩加剧、青年失业率高企和外国需求疲软而失去动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财新 PMI 显示，上月商业活动和新订单增速均明显低于 5 月。新出口业务增长也有所放缓，但保持了较快的步伐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;服务公司表示二季度末投入成本稳步上升，通胀率较5月份变化不大，而价格上涨6 月份服务提供商的增长略有上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;令人惊讶的是，企业对 12 个月前景的乐观情绪有所增强，企业预计经济状况会更强劲，新工作量也会增加以支持增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;服务业的就业创造率也小幅升至三个月高位，但总体仍温和。大约一半的中国就业人员在该行业工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财新/标准普尔综合 PMI（包括制造业和服务业活动）从 5 月份的 55.6 降至 52.5，连续第六个月扩张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“制造业就业萎缩，通货紧缩压力加大，乐观情绪减弱，”财新智库高级经济学家王哲表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与此同时，服务业在后疫情时期继续保持景气。野村证券首席中国经济学家陆挺周一表示，随着下半年的开始，有更多证据表明经济将出现二次探底。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;中国将于7月中旬发布第二季度国内生产总值数据和6月经济活动指标。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US under pressure from businesses, EU to avoid ‘unnecessary conflict’ with China, but ‘much could still go wrong’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3226517/us-under-pressure-businesses-eu-avoid-unnecessary-conflict-china-much-could-still-go-wrong?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/ddde896b-e9be-49ec-aa83-9ed2c3de2fb5_3ef9acaf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;华盛顿面临美国企业的压力，要求其调整对华政策，因为美国寻求这样做消息人士和分析师表示，尽管不确定性仍然存在，甚至在今年晚些时候可能举行的领导人峰会之前可能会进一步恶化，但仍将恢复与北京的经济接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦 (Janet Yellen) 将前往北京周四，在期待已久的四天访问中会见了中国负责经济和贸易的新任同行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯结束了备受关注的为期两天的访问，其中包括上个月与习近平主席会面后，人们还期望商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多和气候特使约翰·克里也将访问中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯原本预计早些时候访问中国，但在二月份推迟了行程当一个疑似中国间谍气球飞越美国领土时。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;从 GDP 到人民币：7 月中国经济值得关注的 4 件事&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;参与经济和贸易，以防止双边关系免遭脱轨，但近年来，技术竞争愈演愈烈，北京方面也带头开展本土创新，以打破美国主导的遏制措施，中国将其视为中国经济增长的生存危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，据因问题敏感性而拒绝透露姓名的消息人士透露，一些美国公司一直在游说华盛顿缓和紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“欧洲公司也在各自的领域做同样的事情。一位消息人士称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是他们在欧盟委员会主席 [Ursula von der Leyen] 最近访问中国时向她传达的信息。”&lt;/p>;&lt;另一位消息人士称，一些欧洲高管对美国的做法表示不满，因为这似乎正在将他们的国家和公司拖入一场“不必要的冲突”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我想这就是一些欧盟政府也有同样的感觉，因为我们听说美国现在试图缩小其做法的主要原因之一是欧盟的压力，”该消息人士补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国商界存在分歧关于华盛顿是否应该软化态度或对中国采取更强硬态度，但分析人士表示，保持沟通渠道畅通是缓和整体紧张局势的关键。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，仍然存在不确定性，并且“很大可能”在习近平可能于 11 月访问美国之前“出问题”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国应提高可支配收入、买家信任度以支撑经济：美国报告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国国家元首韩林咨询公司亚洲集团表示，美国企业可以“感到安慰”，因为美国和中国领导人正在寻求缓解紧张局势的方法，并减轻脱钩带来的紧缩和通胀后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这让企业他补充道：“这为他们在规划 2024 年预算时提供了关注中国经济基本面的喘息空间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国官员也寄希望于美国企业积极发挥斡旋和弥合差距的作用，他们借机发出反对脱钩的强烈信号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国证监会副主席方星海在6月初的金融论坛上表示，中国永远不会寻求与外界脱钩，而是主动与外界对接&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉首席执行官埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 在 5 月底旋风般访华期间受到中国外交部长秦刚和常务副总理丁薛祥的迎接。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两周后，习近平在北京迎接比尔·盖茨，并在近年来首次会见外国商界领袖时称这位微软联合创始人为“老朋友”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国官员可能会见马斯克和盖茨，以提供帮助经济学人智库全球贸易首席分析师尼克·马罗表示： .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月初，美国研究公司凯盛的办公室遭到中国当局突击搜查，工作人员受到国家安全和市场监管部门的询问，据报道，他们检查了在上海办公室发现的物品，北京、苏州和深圳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然马斯克和盖茨出于不同的原因来到中国，但他们和其他来访的首席执行官都强调了人文交流的重要性——布林肯访问的一个不起眼但重要的成果– 可以缓和中美之间的误解，”亚洲集团的林补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管如此，中美紧张局势可能暂时平静，但进入明年的选举季，华盛顿可能会变得喧闹起来。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国商业服务局前官员道格·巴里 (Doug Barry) 表示，尽管人们对整体关系实质性改善的期望较低，但“通过更多的高层对话，最终可能会找到一条前进的道路”习主席可能于 11 月访问美国”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但从现在到那时，可能会出现很多问题，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位商业内部人士表示，虽然他们尽管美国公司仍然看到中国市场的潜力，但由于担心双方可能实施制裁，美国公司在采取行动方面犹豫不决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“关于公司可以投资的白名单可能有助于双边合作，”表示由于问题的敏感性，该知情人士不愿透露姓名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界大型企业联合会中国经济与商业中心主任阿尔弗雷多·蒙图法尔-埃鲁 (Alfredo Montufar-Helu) 表示，拜登政府似乎已经采取的做法更符合欧盟呼吁消除对华关系风险，而不是推动完全脱钩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们听说拜登政府正在寻求采取更加慎重和有选择性的做法”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，他们不再谈论更多的商业技术，例如生物技术和清洁技术，我认为这符合耶伦部长的要求4月在约翰·霍普金斯大学高级国际研究学院发表演讲。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海咨询公司Tidal Wave Solution合伙人卡梅伦·约翰逊表示，拜登政府的目标是推动美中关系发展圣诞节前稳定下来并“达到更高水平”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着 2024 年选举季的到来，关系恶化的可能性很高，特别是在美国总统选举候选人攻击拜登政府的情况下，”他解释道。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“通过让关系更加稳固，希望任何恶化都不会低于 2023 年春季。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马罗持谨慎乐观态度，解释说美国公司应该预料到压力在可预见的未来，出口管制、制裁、投资限制和其他贸易限制措施等政策将持续存在并加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的出口将走向何方？越来越少地针对美国——至少是直接的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这些措施与美中关系的整体外交和地缘政治前景息息相关，尽管布林肯到访，但这种前景仍然相当暗淡，”他补充道。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这些措施与美中关系的整体外交和地缘政治前景相关。” p>;&lt;p>;中国社科院美中关系专家卢翔表示，贸易等实际问题仍然是两国可以找到中间立场和共同利益的领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“中美之间的冲突本质上是结构性的，而贸易可能有助于双边关系从谷底反弹，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但这可能不是一个重大突破，鉴于美国在管理[进口]关税清单方面不太透明，我们也不知道贸易可以在多大程度上帮助重建关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们普遍预计拜登政府将继续保持这种关系。特朗普时代对中国商品加征的 3000 亿美元关税，以及其对华策略的技术遏制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济学人智库的马罗表示，“美国对中国的关税将无限期维持”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;他补充道：“拜登政府在国内没有足够的政治空间来考虑取消这些关税，因此取消关税的结果不太可能实现。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但马罗表示，“只是有一些问题”。世界最大的两个经济体之间“存在太多联系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国认识到，它无法推动与中国的经济全面‘脱钩’，即使在某种程度上，这种情况已经发生在全球技术和数字生态系统的一部分。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京智库中国与全球化中心高级研究员何伟文表示，美国“有必要”放松对中国的科技遏制，因为现代科技的进步需要世界市场的支持。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why India is wary of China’s BRICS expansion push as Indonesia, Saudi Arabia, Egypt – and others – seek to join]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3226537/why-india-wary-chinas-brics-expansion-push-indonesia-saudi-arabia-egypt-and-others-seek-join?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/832d67f7-fcd2-4e2d-983e-502d2a03ebc5_c6264d30.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;并非主要新兴经济体金砖国家集团的所有成员都支持推动分析人士表示，印度对该计划尤其“谨慎”，因为人们对该组织能否成为现有区域联盟的制衡力量存有疑虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当金砖国家成员——巴西、俄罗斯、印度、中国和南非 - 下个月将在约翰内斯堡举行领导人峰会，加入该集团的领跑者将包括阿根廷、埃及、印度尼西亚、阿拉伯联合酋长国、沙特阿拉伯、阿尔及利亚、孟加拉国和伊朗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二开始了由高级官员参加的为期三天的会议，扩大提案预计将列入议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金砖国家曾被视为不同新兴经济体的松散联盟，旨在促进和平、安全、发展与合作 – 占世界人口的 43%、土地面积的 26% 和全球经济的约 30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国去年表示，希望欧盟开始努力接纳但印度外交部长苏杰生 (Subrahmanyam Jaishankar) 上个月表示，这一进程仍在“进行中”，并表示需要审议扩大后的组织的标准、准则和程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;巴西一所大学 Fundacao Getulio Vargas 的国际关系副教授奥利弗·斯图恩克尔 (Oliver Stuenkel) 表示，印度国内对“扩张在多大程度上符合新德里的利益”存在一些担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我斯图恩克尔表示：“我们认为我们必须等待，看看是否会朝这个方向发生任何重大行动。”他指出，中国是迄今为止金砖国家扩大后最强烈的支持者，其次是俄罗斯。与此同时，印度和巴西“都对失去在一个大集团中的影响力感到有点警惕”，他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;观点：金砖国家集团已经取得了长足的进步，但它还不是一个世界强国&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;“新成员的加入很大程度上是为了更加接近中国，而不是为了接近巴西或印度，”斯图恩克尔说道，并补充说，该集团已经成为西方的制衡力量，也是强大集团的替代模式。英国、加拿大、法国、德国、意大利、日本和美国等七国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论是否扩大，金砖五国[已经]在各自地区具有重要影响力”斯图恩克尔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈佛大学文理学院研究员阿努·安瓦尔表示，印度最近向西方倾斜表明它是金砖国家中的“异常值”，这意味着它“有道理” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，德里加强了与美国、日本、澳大利亚和欧盟的经济、国防和技术合作，并在四方安全组织，特别是在大流行期间为印太地区生产疫苗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四方安全组织（还包括澳大利亚、日本和美国）近年来为应对中国日益增长的全球影响力而复活&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔表示，金砖国家不太可能成为七国集团的替代品，因为第一世界集团中几乎所有国家都是北约成员国或与美国结成其他形式的军事联盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔表示：“金砖国家之间没有一个军事联盟，而且在不久的将来也不太可能形成军事联盟。”他补充说，这样的联盟是建立新世界秩序的关键。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“虽然将成员扩大到少数中等强国和区域参与者确实可以使全球力量平衡发生重大转变，但不太可能有助于形成替代性国际秩序。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;金砖国家会见“朋友”，在推动集团扩大的过程中寻求更密切的联系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德国国际与安全事务研究所副所长Günther Maihold表示，建立新的世界秩序显然符合中国和俄罗斯的利益.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们正在共同促进金砖国家的扩大，以使这一愿望合法化，”迈霍尔德说，并指出巴西、印度和南非对维持现状更感兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;梅霍尔德表示，中国对扩大该组织和“扩大影响力”的兴趣可能会“适得其反”，因为这可能会引起其他金砖国家成员的抵制，而且这个相当非正式的组织在扩大后可能会更加难以管理。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“[这也可能]产生更多的内部竞争，”迈霍尔德说，他不仅指中印两国因边境冲突而关系不佳，还指争夺更大的地区和国际影响力的竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雪莉哈佛大学肯尼迪学院阿什中心高级研究员泽宇表示，扩大金砖国家将反映该集团的实力和北京日益增长的影响力，因为仅中国就占金砖国家国内生产总值的三分之二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;于说：“随着越来越多的成员加入共同的多边框架，中国将成为规则制定者。”他指出，任何扮演这一角色的国家都将在未来几十年产生巨大的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;于，伦敦经济学院中非项目主任补充说，与西方集团不同，金砖国家并不是基于共同的意识形态结盟，而是基于改革现有国际体系以反映非洲发展需求的共同愿望。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新开发银行（NDB）由金砖国家于2015年成立，旨在为新兴经济体的基础设施发展提供资金，类似于中国主导的亚洲基础设施建设投资银行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据其网站称，新开发银行自成立以来，已向五个创始成员国的超过96个项目发放了价值330亿美元的贷款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国副主席-国务院总理丁薛祥在五月份的新开发银行年会上表示，北京方面仍然决心将新开发银行发展成为一家开放的多边银行，并补充说，新开发银行旨在通过为更多基础设施和可持续项目提供融资，更好地服务新兴经济体。&lt;/p>;&lt;近年来，新开发银行已接纳孟加拉国、阿联酋和埃及为新成员。乌拉圭正在准备加入，而沙特阿拉伯也在就加入进行谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;观点：金砖国家带头推动摆脱西方金融体系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Stuenkel 表示，鉴于该银行的由于新开发银行有能力对抗世界银行和国际货币基金组织等西方主导的多边银行的影响力，因此新的国家可能很快就会加入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它已经这样做了”，斯图恩克尔表示，他指出，发展中国家强烈要求建立一个更强大、更有影响力的新开发银行。 “新开发银行扩张的潜力可能最大，金砖国家集团的影响也最明显。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，安瓦尔表示，新开发银行的资产和业务领域意味着它只发挥了补充作用。目前还无法取代世界银行和国际货币基金组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新成员肯定会带来更多资本并扩大这些基础设施领域的运作范围”，但这些不会“消除[世界银行和国际货币基金组织]作为全球金融市场监管者和稳定者的传统角色”。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange “ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘US$2 to buy one happy afternoon’: viral video of father in China secretly scattering clams on beach for daughters to find delights social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3226370/us2-buy-one-happy-afternoon-viral-video-father-china-secretly-scattering-clams-beach-daughters-find?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/03/a0939c61-8071-42e5-85a8-517a0688c2ef_2b6d6f5f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国东部的一位父亲买了一袋 15 元（2 美元）的蛤蜊&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据山东卫视报道，父亲把一袋藏在背包里的蛤蜊藏在沙滩上，并把它们埋在海滩上，让女儿们挖出来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 6月27日，中国东部山东省。网上发布的视频捕捉到了这一场景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的两个小女儿在附近的海滩上拿着网和铲子玩耍，很快就发现了埋藏的蛤蜊。 ，然后兴奋地向他展示了他们的“奖杯”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这段10秒的视频片段在中国疯传，微博上的浏览量达到了900万，抖音上的浏览量达到了700万。很多人都称赞这位父亲为女儿们创造了一个好玩的游戏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“父亲的用意真好，也很用心。女儿们为有这样的父亲而感到高兴！” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一人说：“父亲花了15元给两个女儿买了一个快乐的下午。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三位网上观察者说：“当女孩长大后，他们会记得小时候和父亲一起去海边，沙滩上全是蛤蜊。合格的父母才能给孩子带来最幸福的童年回忆。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位匿名妈妈在抖音上评论：“年前，我们家里养了几只鹌鹑，儿子希望它们下蛋。于是我从市场上买了一些鹌鹑蛋，偷偷地放在窝里。我还记得当我儿子在鸟巢里发现鸡蛋时，他非常兴奋。他真的以为是鹌鹑生的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;父母和孩子的感人故事经常在大陆社交媒体上引起关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，一名五岁女孩在大陆的社交媒体上引起了关注。中国东部江苏省的一名医生，用父亲制作的工具为自己的宠物狗和家人进行“体检”，在社交媒体上疯传。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有，南方的一位母亲三月份，中国将旧纸箱变成了玩具，包括一个巨型剧场、一座城堡和一辆变形金刚汽车，为她的三个女儿赢得了网上的掌声。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China puts advanced WS-15 engines through J-20 stealth fighter paces]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3226562/china-puts-advanced-ws-15-engines-through-j-20-stealth-fighter-paces?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/7ddd130b-22e8-4982-895d-676905cd8663_6fe9bed9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After two decades of development, China&#39;s most powerful engine has had its maiden flight in one of the country&#39;s most advanced stealth fighters, an upgrade that defence analysts say narrows the technology gap with the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a video circulating online since June 28, a J-20 prototype jet fighter fitted with two WS-15 engines took off from a test airfield in Chengdu, southwest Sichuan province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city is the base of the J-20&#39;s developer, Chengdu Aerospace Corporation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is unclear when the flight took place and there was no official announcement from the People&#39;s Liberation Army.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But photos and footage of the test have been circulating freely on social media platforms at home and overseas, a sign of official endorsement in China&#39;s heavily censored information environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Military enthusiasts also posted clips of the J-20&#39;s maiden flight with Russian AL-31 engines in 2011 and Chinese WS-10Cs in 2021, comparing them with the most recent test.&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“The lack of censorship of social media posts about the latest maiden flight represents quasi-official confirmation of the successful development of the WS-15 turbofan engine,” said Zhou Chenming, a researcher of the Beijing-based Yuan Wang military science and technology think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With the new WS-15, we can see the J-20 is much more manoeuvrable and faster in climbs, showing it is almost on a par with the American F119 engine designed for its F-22 and F-35 stealth fighters.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou said the WS-15 would be fitted to the J-20B variant of the fighter, overcoming a major “heart problem” with the aircraft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After 12 years since the J-20&#39;s maiden flight in 2011, the Chinese air force finally got the engine it had long been waiting for,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ The accomplishment of the sophisticated WS-15 engine means the PLA Air Force will no longer [be at risk of a] &#39;heart attack&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But former PLA instructor Song Zhongping said the WS-15 did not yet have the endurance of the American engines, which can exceed 500,000 flight hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is still a gap between WS-15 and the F119 engines,” Song said. “It&#39;s an experimental success for the WS-15, but it&#39;s too early for it to enter mass production. It still needs tests and improvements.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is keen to have a stealth aircraft capable of competing with the best in the world as tensions rise in the Asia-Pacific and the United States ramps up deployment of its fifth generation F-22 and F-35 fighters in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PLA introduced its most advanced J-20 in March 2017, an aircraft with Russian AL-31 engines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has produced at least 200 J-20 fighters, most of them powered with AL-31 engines, with the thrust-vectoring WS-10C engine as stopgaps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the US plans to deploy up to 300 of its stealth fighters to the region by 2025, according to earlier reports by the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong universities can ‘double intake of non-local students’ under proposal to attract more talent to city]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3226569/hong-kong-universities-can-double-intake-non-local-students-under-proposal-attract-more-talent-city?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/e0a00106-d8ee-4e01-830f-403ea04ffab8_4faa0106.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s publicly funded universities will be allowed to double the number of non-local undergraduates newly admitted in the 2024-25 academic year to around 6,000 under a proposal to attract more talent to the city, the Post has learned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The proposal, which has been submitted to education authorities, would not affect the number of subsidised places for Hongkongers as non-local students would pay tuition fees in full, a source from the university sector said on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source said that under the scheme, proposed by the University Grants Committee (UGC), the quota for non-local admissions to undergraduate programmes would be lifted from the equivalent of 20 per cent of the number of approved subsidised places to 40 per cent. The UGC allocates government money to higher education institutions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;6 out of 7 Hong Kong universities in global survey drop in rankings&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Based on 15,000 publicly funded first-year degree places, the intake of non-local students would jump from around 3,000 to 6,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The initiative is against the backdrop of the [government] blueprint of turning Hong Kong into a regional education hub and the policy of attracting talent globally,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The eight publicly funded universities charge non-local undergraduates between HK$140,000 and HK$182,000 annually, while tuition fees for local students are HK$42,100 a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Similar arrangements have been suggested for non-local postgraduate admission places, although demand is far lower than for undergraduate programmes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 100 non-local students attended such courses during this academic year, compared with 2,507 Hongkongers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UGC chairman Tim Lui Tim-leung confirmed to the Post that the subject of increasing non-local student places was on the committee&#39;s agenda, as it fitted with the policy to attract talent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This topic is being seriously considered by the university sector,” said Lui, who declined to elaborate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source said some universities had already used up the 20 per cent quota for non-local students and some had even slightly over-enrolled with permission.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the latest government statistics, the percentage of non-local undergraduates at the University of Hong Kong (HKU) and University of Science and Technology (HKUST) reached 23.7 per cent and 22.4 per cent respectively in 2021-22, while the average among the eight institutions was 18 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source said the universities had been consulted about the plan, which might be announced in Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu&#39;s policy address in October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An Education Bureau spokeswoman said it was government policy to develop Hong Kong into a regional education hub through measures such as the enrolment of non-local students to postsecondary institutions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We review the relevant data from time to time and consider appropriate measures to further our policy objectives as necessary,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;4 universities in Hong Kong rise in ranking of Asia&#39;s top schools&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The cap on the number of non-local students was last raised from 10 per cent to 20 per cent in 2008, when then chief executive Donald Tsang Yam-kuen announced the move in his policy address in 2007.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Students from mainland China account for the largest share among the non-local population at the publicly funded universities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to UGC statistics, 68 per cent, or 9,693 students, studying programmes were from the mainland in the current academic year, and the rest from other parts of the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The growing number of mainland students at Hong Kong universities was noted in the Times Higher Education Rankings 2023, a global league table. It said Hong Kong had witnessed a surge in mainland students at its institutions, without going into any impact brought on by such an increase.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong recorded a 9 per cent increase year on year in students from the mainland in 2021-22,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the government regarding a shortage of hostel spaces as a major hindrance for institutions to admit more non-local students over the years, a paper submitted to the Legislative Council earlier revealed that an extra 8,500 dorm places at four public universities would be completed in 2024 or after.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Professor Lau Chi-pang, a lawmaker and associate vice-president of Lingnan University, said institutions in Hong Kong had sufficient capacity to admit more non-local students. He said he did not see it being an issue if mainland students took up most of the additional places.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Mainland Chinese academics outnumber locals at Hong Kong universities for first time&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“You can take a look at universities in the United States and Europe, their non-local students are also dominated by mainland students. It is a global trend,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aside from HKU, HKUST and Lingnan, the other publicly funded universities are Baptist University, City University, Chinese University, Polytechnic University and the Education University of Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook faces legal setback in EU court decision on data privacy and ads]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226576/facebook-faces-legal-setback-eu-court-decision-data-privacy-and-ads?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 07:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/a10d96ff-e803-4c4a-9818-e4960cc5f12b_18cbaaa9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Facebook lost a legal challenge on Tuesday at the European Union&#39;s top court over a groundbreaking German antitrust decision that limited the way the company uses data for advertising.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The European Court of Justice said competition watchdogs can consider whether companies such as Facebook comply with the continent&#39;s strict privacy rules, which are normally enforced by national data privacy regulators.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Luxembourg-based court ruled that antitrust authorities can take into account any violations of data privacy rules as they investigate whether tech giants are abusing their dominance in the market by boxing out competitors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are evaluating the court&#39;s decision and will have more to say in due course,” Facebook parent Meta said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court sided with a 2019 German antitrust ruling that threatened to upend Meta&#39;s business model of selling ads targeted to users based on data gleaned from how they spend time on its services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta, which also owns Instagram and WhatsApp, appealed that finding, which led German authorities to seek an opinion from the Court of Justice, the 27-nation bloc&#39;s top tribunal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tuesday&#39;s decision could pave the way for stricter scrutiny of tech companies. Europe has taken a pioneering role in reining in the power of big digital platforms with sweeping new standards taking effect next month and rules in the works on artificial intelligence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The German Federal Cartel Office, or Bundeskartellamt, was not contesting the company&#39;s use of customer data to target ads to users on Facebook.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it said for the company to combine data from all the services it runs to target ads more precisely, Facebook should have to first get permission separately from the other apps and websites to do so.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Instagram launch of Twitter rival &#39;Threads&#39; expected on Thursday&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;At issue is the way Facebook gains consent from users to process their data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A press release summarising the court&#39;s decision said the company “cannot justify” claiming “legitimate interest” as a reason for using personal data to serve ads to users. Under European Union privacy rules, users need to freely give consent for their data to be used.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EU court&#39;s decision will have “far-reaching effects on the business models of the data economy,” said Andreas Mundt, president of the German Federal Cartel Office.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[CK Asset dismisses concerns about rising interest rates and oversupply, will launch The Coast Line residential development in Yau Tong]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226551/ck-asset-dismisses-concerns-about-rising-interest-rates-and-oversupply-will-launch-coast-line?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/04/4dcc1da4-6833-4de8-a1d0-ff21e5a896c8_956ff145.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;CK Asset Holdings – the flagship property developer of billionaire Li Ka-shing and his family and one of Hong Kong&#39;s largest builders – will soon launch its The Coast Line residential project in Yau Tong, becoming the latest company to offer a new development in the city&#39;s weakening housing market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The project at 8 Tung Yuen Street is being developed in two phases and will have 886 flats altogether. A second phase with 658 units has also obtained presale approvals and will be launched within the month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CK Asset did not disclose prices for The Coast Line, but the developer will reference other Kowloon East waterfront projects, including residential developments around Kai Tak station, as well as the city&#39;s actual economic environment, said Executive Director Justin Chiu Kwok-hung.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company will focus on “affordability”, Chiu said. “We want to help homebuyers buy houses,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Coast Line&#39;s launch comes amid a decline in Hong Kong&#39;s lived-in home prices. Prices of such properties fell in May for the first time this year, as looming interest rate increases cast a long shadow over a market facing a glut of newly built flats. Lived-in homes saw sales plummet 13 per cent to 2,411 in June, which was the weakest month of 2023. Non-residential properties saw a 5 per cent decline in sales to 735 in June from a month ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CK Asset is expected to give a discount of around 5 per cent, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;CK Asset gets shareholder approval for takeover of UK&#39;s Civitas Social Housing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We will not see a big price reduction,” said Raymond Cheng, managing director of CGS-CIMB Securities in Hong Kong. “But the developer is likely to adjust [prices to reflect] the decline in the Hong Kong property market over the past year, and it will give some discounts on the newly launched phase to attract homebuyers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong home prices and volumes saw a strong rebound in the first quarter, but started to slow down in the second three-month period, Ken Yeung, a property analyst with Citi, said in a research note on Tuesday. The bank is more bearish than developers about the second-half home price outlook, as it has seen a quick decline in transaction volumes since April with abundant new supply, on the back of a higher-for-longer interest rate environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We expect home prices to see a 6 per cent correction in the second half of 2023,” Yeung said in the note.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Li Ka-shing&#39;s energy flagship has US$2.3 billion cash for shopping&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;CK Asset&#39;s Chiu is, however, confident about the property market&#39;s outlook. “The economy will continue to improve in the second half of the year, [and] property prices will follow the economy towards a stable development,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An expected increase in interest rates in the second half of the year “is not a big problem”, Chiu said, adding that more project launches increased the supply of residential property and choices for buyers, which is a sign of a healthy market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The market has been moving in the right direction, Chiu said, adding that he is looking forward to the long-term healthy development of the property market.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China mounts cultural offensive to win ‘war of narratives’ against US. Will other countries be swayed?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3226039/china-mounts-cultural-offensive-win-war-narratives-against-us-will-other-countries-be-swayed?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/76e1576a-08bb-42fe-90e5-76f0b2ec998f_3016a0a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Warner Bros Discovery executive Vikram Channa was there – as was Oscar-winning British documentary director Malcolm Clarke.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two were among four foreign film industry players invited by China&#39;s State Council Information Office to give an online lecture late last month on how to tell China&#39;s stories to the West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 10,000 attendees from Chinese government departments, Communist Party bodies, universities, media, embassies and consulates took part in the virtual workshop in a quest to understand “advanced” international methods to “explain the charm of China, Chinese culture and Chinese civilisation”, according to the information office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China has been the subject of a lot of negative publicity in the West during the last 10 years,” Clarke said in a video for the workshop. “Part of what I&#39;m trying to do is to counter that kind of negative publicity, not by necessarily telling happy, good stories about China, but just simply by telling the truth about what&#39;s happening here.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The workshop was the latest in China&#39;s efforts to build soft power through a cultural counteroffensive as Beijing and Washington engage in an intense war of narratives. However, analysts said that while Beijing could succeed at boosting cultural pride within China, it might struggle to convince the rest of the world of its alternative to the Western-dominated global order.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier in June at a cultural symposium in Beijing, Chinese President Xi Jinping said China&#39;s unique development path was rooted in the historical continuity of its culture. Since then, Xi&#39;s vocal support for traditional Chinese culture – as shown by his recent visits to the National Archives of Publications and Culture and the Chinese Academy of History – has been echoed by state media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While at home the party aims to boost confidence in China&#39;s history and culture, to the outside world, it is promoting the Global Civilisation Initiative (GCI).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The initiative calls for respecting the “diversity of civilisations” and opposes “stoking ideological confrontation” or imposing the values of one country onto another.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi unveiled the initiative in a keynote speech to the Communist Party High-Level Dialogue with World Political Parties in March, an event attended by leaders of about 500 political organisations from more than 150 countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the dialogue, Xi called for respecting the diversity of civilisations, advocating common values, valuing the history and innovations of different cultures and strengthening people-to-people exchanges and cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The practice of stoking division and confrontation in the name of democracy is in itself a violation of the spirit of democracy,” he told the audience. “It will not receive any support.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi&#39;s speech came just two weeks before US President Joe Biden co-hosted his second Summit for Democracy. A total of 85 world leaders took part in the meeting – and China was not invited.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;George Magnus, a research associate at Oxford University&#39;s China Centre said it was “probably no accident” that the two meetings took place back to back.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The important question is whether Xi&#39;s framing of the GCI is fundamentally any different from Biden&#39;s framing of the struggle of democracies and autocracies,” Magnus said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think that what we have is a clash of ideologies, not cultures, which ultimately comes down to differences in the ways we perceive rights, beliefs, standards and values.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Xi&#39;s China and liberal leaning democracies may speak to a common agenda of peace, development, equity, justice, democracy and freedom, but he uses Marxism and ancient Chinese culture to define a very different version of what these mean from the alternative based on rights, and the rule of law.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Magnus, the stark contrast in the narratives is designed to cement bonds with a disparate group of nations with differing political systems and goals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that while Xi probably had little chance of swaying developed market economies to his side, there were hopes that many countries in the Global South – encompassing most of the world outside North America, Europe and a few rich Asia-Pacific nations – could be persuaded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A mainland-based political analyst, who requested anonymity due to the sensitivity of the matter, said the Communist Party launched the GCI to counter the “cultural hegemony” of the West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The party thinks that the China model of development and modernisation is downplayed and even criticised in the Western-dominated narrative. What Beijing wants to do is to make its voice heard, make the Chinese wisdom a public product for the world and fight back against Western cultural hegemony,” the analyst said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The rhetoric of appreciating perceptions of values by different civilisations has some appeal to developing countries, which are desperate for funds, technology and know-how from China or share China&#39;s disdain for Western values.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why China&#39;s C-pop has yet to score as a soft power music machine&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Liu Zhenmin, a Chinese diplomat who was undersecretary-general for the United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs from 2017 to 2022, said the GCI, together with China&#39;s Global Development Initiative and Global Security Initiative, reflected Xi&#39;s world view of a “shared destiny for mankind”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[This world view] is to break the values-based Western diplomacy, stop suppression by Western countries under the name of democracy and unite countries around the world,” Liu told a GCI symposium in March hosted by the Study Times, the newspaper of the Central Party School in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the development initiative, a complement to the Belt and Road Initiative announced in 2021, China says it will deliver public goods beyond infrastructure, prioritising poverty reduction and capacity-building in low-income countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the security initiative, unveiled last year, China says it wants to show the world that it seeks peace and development. As part of the framework, Beijing has come up with a proposal to end the war in Ukraine and brokered a truce between Iran and Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s efforts in general do seem to be gaining it some favour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a report released in October, University of Cambridge researchers found that 62 per cent of citizens in developing countries viewed China favourably, which rose to 70 per cent among those who did not live in liberal democracies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And for the first time since the data was first collected in 2011, slightly more people in developing countries (62 per cent) were favourable towards China than towards the United States (61 per cent).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the study, which combined data from 30 surveys covering 137 countries, developing nations with high levels of trade and investment with Beijing – especially members of the Belt and Road Initiative – had the most favourable view of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Early last year China formed a group in the United Nations called the “Friends of the Global Development Initiative”, with 53 member states. Now it has nearly 70, as China&#39;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs revealed last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While China is making some progress in its bid to build a multipolar world, especially in the Global South, few countries will go all in on Beijing, as it remains in their best interests to hedge between the rival superpowers and avoid picking sides, according to analysts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Quite a few countries tilt towards China only for short-term interests, as Western cultures and values have a bigger sway after a long period of colonisation or because Western countries have economic or market supremacy,” the anonymous analyst said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s Xi hails cultural continuity for powering nation&#39;s rise&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sourabh Gupta, a senior fellow at the Institute for China-America Studies in Washington, said China intended to “soften the ground” for its rise – and acceptance of that rise – within the international system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The aim seemingly here is to suggest that China&#39;s rise will not follow the beaten path of the Western powers, and that Beijing cherishes and advocates for the diversity of world civilisations. It is not so much an anti-Western message as it is a non-Western message to those interested in lending an ear,” Gupta said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The GCI narrative will not sway countries markedly one way or the other. The civilisational dialogue theme is a tried-and-tested one and runs up against a certain [low] ceiling in terms of its resonance.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gupta said that when it came to stoking cultural pride among Chinese people, Xi was preaching to the choir, but “for the great mass of the non-converted beyond China&#39;s borders, they will stay that way”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Noting Beijing should do more to explain the GCI to those outside China, he said: “Westerners have neither the curiosity nor the inclination to parse these highly conceptual utterances, especially beyond economic policy measures, and I doubt they will provide a platform for engagement and contestation in a &#39;narrative war&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pang Zhongying, a professor of international affairs at Sichuan University, said the initiative needed to be well defined.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What does &#39;global civilisation&#39; mean? If it refers to a new civilisation that unites countries regardless of ethnicity and nationality to address global crises and challenges such as climate change, it would be a good initiative,” Pang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So far, the initiative is still ambiguous with empty slogans.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>