<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Michelle Yeoh’s marriage, China’s take on Barbie: 6 weekend reads you may have missed]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3229416/michelle-yeohs-marriage-chinas-take-barbie-6-weekend-reads-you-may-have-missed?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/edbb4aa6-ade3-4d8b-9e3e-04c93e8f880a_4eaef7de.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;我们从上周末报道的香港、中国大陆、香港、更广泛的亚洲地区及其他地区与我们的读者产生共鸣，并阐明了热门问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果您想查看我们的更多报道，请考虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;第一位获得 2023 年奥斯卡最佳女主角奖的亚洲女性杨紫琼 (Michelle Yeoh) 宣布与瑞士多年的未婚夫让·托德 (Jean Todt) 结婚，并在社交媒体上发布了他们温馨婚礼的照片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;请在此处阅读全文。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;越来越多的印尼年轻人在慷慨的奖学金和诱人的就业前景的吸引下，放弃公民身份，成为新加坡人。印度尼西亚移民机构总干事 Silmy Karim 表示，新加坡有一项针对该地区年轻人才的政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此处阅读全文。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;喜欢与其他暹粒面条小贩不同，钦米斯在午夜过后还在为饥饿的游客忙碌，但很少有顾客知道他是一位著名的诗人。他以前的学生和作家同事认为他应该担任大学职务。相反，这位 43 岁诗人的生活取决于他每盘热气腾腾的盘子所赚取的 2.5 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此处阅读完整的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国本土种植的榴莲将在几天内上市。消费者将很难买到这种水果，而且价格看起来比从东南亚进口的榴莲高出约三倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此处阅读全文。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在中国女性在统治精英中代表人数最少的时代，好莱坞电影《芭比娃娃》出人意料地成为了女英雄。中国热门电影评级网站豆瓣上的一条评论说：“你知道，中国女性在电影院里看到纯粹女性视角的电影的机会并不多。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阅读全文&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;索尼娅是澳大利亚一家游戏公司的技术主管，今年早些时候，她拒绝了一份工作邀请，因为她的未来雇主告诉她必须在办公室每天。 “这不仅仅是通勤的费用，我知道我要吃午餐，两到三杯咖啡……在家工作，我的私人生活感觉更快乐，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这里阅读完整的故事。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese battery companies spy a South Korean loophole to skirt US subsidy rules]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3229448/chinese-battery-companies-spy-south-korean-loophole-skirt-us-subsidy-rules?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 11:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/17bbc061-ed74-4168-bf3f-82c216290365_c8a18aa6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国企业排队投资韩国电池行业，因为他们想利用它将其作为进入美国市场的门户，破坏了华盛顿限制中国参与电动汽车供应链的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去四个月，中国企业及其韩国合作伙伴宣布了约 5.1 万亿韩元（投资40亿美元在韩国新建五家电池工厂。新万金开发投资局的官员表示，至少有一个地方政府正在就更多项目进行谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和韩国企业正在寻求利用韩国与韩国签订的自由贸易协定美国，考虑到在东亚国家制造并安装在美国制造的电动汽车上的电池可能有资格根据乔·拜登总统的通货膨胀削减法案享受税收减免。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宁波容百新能源科技有限公司上周宣布，已获准在韩国设立一家工厂，最终将每年生产约 73,000 吨三元前驱体，这是一种形成阴极的成分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该产品公司韩国基地生产的产品符合IRA法案中合格关键矿产的相关要求，出口欧美市场时可享受关税政策优惠。”容百新能源表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尤桑- Ronbay韩国分公司负责人yul在接受采访时单独表示，“韩国在电池方面拥有大量的人才和知识。由于 IRA，选择韩国是我们全球战略的一部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国企业在全球电池和电池材料供应链中占据主导地位，为韩国三大电动汽车电池制造商生产阴极、阳极和前驱体 – LG Energy Solution Ltd.、三星 SDI Co. 和 SK On Co.。这三家公司随后向通用汽车公司 (General Motors Co.)、特斯拉公司 (Tesla Inc.) 和大众汽车公司 (Volkswagen AG) 等电动汽车制造商供货。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登政府希望减少美国的其供应链对中国公司的依赖，但中国公司的根深蒂固将使供应链变得困难，汽车制造商正在游说美国政府宽松，允许包括一些中国生产的零部件。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;电动汽车让中国走上了正轨超越日本成为第一大汽车出口国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府目前正在起草规则，规定允许任何“外国关注实体”发布多少内容。这是政府对中国和俄罗斯等美国地缘政治敌人拥有或控制的企业或团体的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将继续评估和应对与国际和国内供应链相关的任何国家安全问题。”美国财政部发言人阿什利·沙皮特尔 (Ashley Schapitl) 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国和韩国，我们彼此需要，”首尔韩国电池工业协会 (Korea Battery Industry Association) 官员李明奎 (Lee Myung-kyu) 表示。 “韩国电池制造商认为，由于 IRA，从中国进口阴极和前驱体等电池材料存在风险。如果这些原材料全部在韩国制造，这意味着韩国将在国内拥有更稳定的供应链。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了容百新能源之外，SK On还宣布与一家中国公司成立合资企业3月份，浙江华友钴业有限公司同意与LG集团的化学子公司和浦项制铁未来M有限公司成立合资企业。浦项制铁控股公司 (Posco Holdings Inc.) 6 月宣布与中国 CNGR Advanced Material Co. 达成协议，建设一家镍精炼厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SK On 和 LG 签署的协议尚处于早期阶段，合同条款尚未最终确定公司发言人表示，等待最终的 IRA 细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师 James Lee 表示，与中国公司建立合作伙伴关系对韩国公司来说可能存在风险，因为美国可能随时阻止合资企业享受任何 IRA 税收优惠&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了缓解此类担忧，LG 在 4 月份的财报电话会议上表示，如果发生这种情况，它将准备从华友钴业手中收购合资企业的股份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;然而，韩国的分析人士认为，该国将能够维持与中国的伙伴关系，至少在一段时间内。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么韩国在与美国在芯片领域合作的同时还需要中国，以及更多&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“美国不能将中国企业排除在电动汽车供应链之外，”首尔电池研究公司 SNE Research 副总裁 James Oh 表示。 “如果他们禁止韩中合作，美国将永远无法生产电动汽车。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，韩国公司甚至可能从中国合作伙伴那里学习如何生产电动汽车的相关知识。中国在电池领域占据主导地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“电池不像半导体那样是高科技产业，”新万金开发投资局官员 Moon Bong-sub 表示，Ronbay 和 LG Chem 计划在新万金开发投资局建立自己的电池工厂。植物。 “这是一个很好的情况，因为韩国可以学习中国的电池技术。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s Xi Jinping sharpens focus on food and mineral supply chains]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3229422/chinas-xi-jinping-sharpens-focus-food-and-mineral-supply-chains?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/30/07f82806-b6a7-47ce-ab75-00a932b151ec_d78fe390.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国国家主席习近平呼吁加强食品和关键矿产的供应链，因为世界第二大经济体正在努力应对与美国日益激烈的经济和高科技竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平上周在访问资源丰富的西南省份四川时发出这一呼吁，告诉干部们， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“构建新能源体系需要科学规划，促进水电、风电、氢能、天然气等能源互补发展”。国家通讯社新华社援引习近平的讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“加强粮食和战略矿产资源生产供应，打造保障国家重要初级产品供应的战略基地。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;他还要求学术机构利用科技创新“攻克一批关键核心技术，着力打造西部地区‘创新高地’”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就在几天前，北京对两种矿物（镓和锗）以及三打以上相关金属和其他材料的出口限制将于周二（8 月 1 日）生效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;矿物是关键四川拥有丰富的资源，包括石油、天然气和煤炭，以及全国最大的锂储量，钒和钛——对关键清洁能源技术至关重要的矿物，是中美竞争的前沿之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该省的粮食产量也是全国最高的，去年产量为 3500 万吨，去年，这一数字在中国排名第九。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一呼吁突显了北京正在努力消除地缘政治焦虑，部分原因是美国及其盟国的孤立尝试，以及可能加剧全球粮食和能源危机的长期乌克兰战争。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济复苏缓慢、极端天气和化肥价格飙升加剧了中国的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近几周，随着黑海协议的破裂，这些担忧进一步恶化。乌克兰粮食出口的安全通道。世界最大的大米出口国印度也已采取行动限制非巴斯马蒂大米的出口，据称是为了压低国内大米价格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周一举行的粮食峰会上发表讲话时，联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯警告说，“全球粮食系统已经崩溃，数十亿人正在为此付出代价”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What is the bill calling for changes to Chinese University’s governing council and why is it so controversial?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3229435/what-bill-calling-changes-chinese-universitys-governing-council-and-why-it-so-controversial?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/82cab94c-61fe-45d5-ace7-c7bd59eacc0c_5cbf0c43.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港中文大学校董会预计将于周二召开会议，讨论一项私人三名议员提出的法案将允许外部任命者主导该组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一份要求立法会否决该提案的请愿书获得了近 1,600 个签名，前领导人梁振英支持该法案，周日呼吁对校长段崇智教授的领导进行特别调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《2023年香港中文大学（修订）条例草案》于六月在立法会获得首读，并已通过尽管批评者认为该政策可能会损害学术自由，但仍将其提交法案委员会进行审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这里，《华盛顿邮报》详细分析了该法案的范围、提出该法案的原因以及该法案为何引起如此大的争议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该法案由立法会议员张宇人、邓家骠及刘国勋共同提出，他们均以外部委任身份出任大学校董会成员。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们建议将理事会成员数量从55名削减到34名，并将外部任命与内部任命的比例调整为2:1。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还寻求提高投票门槛决定大学副校长的人数从目前的简单多数增加到四分之三，在极端情况下只允许七名成员投赞成票。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;管理机构起草了在呼吁改革后，我们于 2009 年和 2016 年提出了自己的提案。然而，改革失去了动力，最终没有进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;建制派人士也呼吁对段的治理进行更严格的审查，因为有人指责段在校园成为警察和反政府武装之间的战场时同情抗议者。 - 2019 年的政府示威者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tuan 去年 4 月的连任引发了他们的进一步抗议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该大学后来辩称，如果理事会在全球范围内寻找合适的替代者，需要时间成员们未能就他的三年延期达成一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一般来说，该市的大学需要 12 至 18 个月的时间来寻找新的领导者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当该大学揭晓后，该大学陷入了进一步的争议十月，在该机构今年成立 60 周年之际，设计了简化版的彩色中国凤凰徽章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会议员和立法会成员张、邓和刘指责该机构的管理层绕过了管理机构机构并要求对重新设计过程进行独立调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还将该事件描述为“黑匣子”事件，未能很好地反映大学的治理。一周后，该徽章被丢弃，并使用了之前的徽章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梁周日点名批评段，指责他没有出席上周五的法案委员会会议。他还指责校董会秘书兼大学副校长吴树培放弃中立，与反对者一起请愿反对改革法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在上周致法案委员会的一封信中，查尔斯该大学校董会成员兼新亚书院董事局主席梁英伟也对管理机构的运作方式表示不满，并呼吁尽早通过该法律。他称校董会是橡皮图章机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;校董会成员杨宇明，也是大学毕业典礼的主席，这是一个由所有毕业生组成的法定机构– 是游说反对该法案的关键人物。他与志同道合的议员一起发起了网上请愿活动，自 7 月 22 日起，截至周日上午 11 时 30 分，已收集了近 1,600 个支持签名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;签名者中包括许汉忠。 、前香港机场管理局行政总裁吴志华、香港故宫文化博物馆馆长及政府疫情顾问许树昌教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前香港天文台助理台长梁永武签署者包括前商务及经济发展局副局长梁振国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官政策组副组长关家明也签署了该文件，但后来因公众关注此事而撤回签署。可能存在角色冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港立法会议员猛烈抨击“组织混乱”的中文大学理事会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;杨坚称反对者并不反对改革，但指责该法案背后的三名议员绕过了立法会理事会，未经咨询成员或获得其正式批准。杨还表示，三人无视该委员会2016年检讨报告中达成的共识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨强调，教育自治和学术自由受到香港小宪法《基本法》的保障。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;立法会议员拒绝了这些说法，称他们的法案纳入了2016年审查中的大部分建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中文大学理事会成员敦促香港立法会议员推迟改革法案&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;杨提出了另一项建议，建议将立法会议员人数削减至两名，并为立法会成员保留两个席位。他还希望决定校长人选的投票门槛定为三分之二。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;立法会阻止香港就中文大学校董会变动举行公开听证会&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;反对者表示，法案委员会应该等到大学理事会讨论改革法案之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“立法机关没有必要仓促行事，因为立法院正在暑假休会。” ”法案委员会拒绝了这一呼吁，其中委员邓国强表示担心公开听证会很容易沦为“对个别议员的人身攻击”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法案委员会最终选择了书面陈述。感兴趣的各方提交意见的截止日期是周一下午5点。截至上周四中午，委员会已收到40份意见书，其中25份赞成该法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在上周五的会议上，委员会主席梁美芬也强调，不存在任何问题。必须等到大学理事会批准该法案后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“立法会不是大学的橡皮图章，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Arab states sour on Israel in blow to US aim of Saudi peace pact]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3229446/arab-states-sour-israel-blow-us-aim-saudi-peace-pact?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 11:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/2eb5217f-e3c8-41f7-9b65-630628185460_1a5fa0bb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;历史性和平协议三年后，海湾国家与以色列之间的紧张局势正在加剧，并有所放缓预期的投资，并挫败了美国通过将主要大国沙特阿拉伯纳入该地区而进一步一体化的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿拉伯联合酋长国对与以色列的高层接触对 2020 年《亚伯拉罕协议》的结果表示失望据知情人士透露，这主要是由于对以色列与巴勒斯坦关系恶化的担忧 — — 以最近的致命袭击为代表。杰宁市难民营的问题以及一些极右翼以色列内阁成员的煽动性言论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些压力可能会使美国深化以色列与中东国家关系这一本已充满挑战的目标变得更加复杂，特别是沙特阿拉伯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫一直鼓励沙特王储穆罕默德·本·萨勒曼与以色列就一项协议进行接触。这位事实上的统治者迄今为止一直推迟与以色列的宿敌伊朗的外交关系，并于三月份通过中国斡旋的安排恢复了外交关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这不是《亚伯拉罕协议》中一些人的愿景的一部分 -以色列希望将其作为反伊朗轴心，”研究沙特对以色列政策的利雅得分析师阿齐兹·阿尔加什安 (Aziz Alghashian) 表示。 “该地区现在正朝着不同的方向发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国在中东崛起的作用能否为以色列-巴勒斯坦和平建立动力？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;沙特阿拉伯公开表示，一个独立的巴勒斯坦国是一个独立的国家。承认以色列为盟友的先决条件。私下里，它要求美国提供坚定的国防保证、获得美国顶尖武器，并为其包括国内铀浓缩在内的核计划开绿灯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡引发了大规模的抗议活动。抗议活动和司法改革计划让投资者感到不安，他正在主持该国最虔诚的联盟。它支持在被占领的约旦河西岸建立更多的犹太人定居点，其中包括财政部长贝扎莱尔·斯莫特里奇（Bezalel Smotrich）等人物，他在三月份表示“不存在巴勒斯坦人民这样的东西”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这暴露了阿联酋和巴林最近在约旦河西岸的攻势加剧了阿拉伯公众舆论的强烈反对，以色列称这次攻势是针对武装分子并旨在销毁他们的武器。阿联酋谴责了导致 12 名巴勒斯坦人和一名以色列士兵死亡的行动以及斯莫特里奇的言论。巴林政府没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;摩洛哥是另一个与阿联酋和巴林同时与以色列建立关系的国家，上个月推迟了阿拉伯-以色列会议以表示抗议反对以色列扩大定居点的计划。这个北非王国后来表示，以色列现在支持其控制有争议领土西撒哈拉的愿望，这可能会改善情况。此后，内塔尼亚胡的办公室表示，他已被邀请访问摩洛哥。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在内塔尼亚胡的双边访问上拖延了几个月后，阿联酋仅邀请这位以色列领导人参加一项国际活动——今年晚些时候举行的 COP28 气候会议年在迪拜。内塔尼亚胡的举动也令美国感到沮丧，自去年年底重新掌权以来，他一直难以获得华盛顿的邀请，尽管总统乔·拜登已表示这将在某个阶段发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海湾计划的一些投资以色列的公司已经陷入停滞。其中包括阿布扎比国家石油公司和英国石油公司以 20 亿美元收购以色列天然气生产商 NewMed Energy 的一半股份。该交易于三月份临时宣布，但尚未最终确定。据一位熟悉英国石油公司和阿布扎比国家石油公司谈判情况的人士透露，由于以色列监管机构需要时间来批准，该计划被推迟，但预计仍会在今年年底前完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由财富领导的阿布扎比​​公司组成的财团ADQ 基金取消了收购以色列保险公司和资产管理公司 Phoenix Holdings Ltd. 控股权的计划。根据他们发给凤凰城的一封信，这是因为规则可能会限制该财团的一些成员在以色列进行额外投资，该消息公布后，凤凰城的股价应声下跌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，双方之间的经济联系仍然存在。以色列和阿联酋正在扩张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双边商业流量在 2020 年之前为几千万美元，到 2022 年将达到 26 亿美元，届时阿联酋将成为以色列第 16 大贸易伙伴。据以色列估计，这一数字今年预计将增至 30 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自两国建立关系以来，已有超过 100 万以色列人访问了阿联酋，但很少有阿联酋人前往其他地方。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;以色列部长说巴勒斯坦人民“不存在”，这引起了愤怒&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“签署这些协议的阿拉伯国家有明确的经济利益来继续签署，”以色列分析师迈拉夫·宗泽因 (Mairav Zonszein) 表示致力于防止冲突的国际危机组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿布扎比的一座犹太教堂于二月开放，是一座天主教堂和一座清真寺综合体的一部分，展示了这一转变。据该国第一位常驻拉比 Levi Duchman 称，自 2014 年以来，阿联酋的犹太人数量增加了 10 倍，达到 7,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这仅仅是开始，”他说。 “人们想搬到这里，因为这里有一个绝佳的机会生活在一个安全、生活质量高的国家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;犹太教堂的开放“给社区带来了很大的信心，让他们相信他们在这里受到欢迎”在阿联酋，”以色列驻阿联酋大使阿米尔·哈耶克说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位特使承认阿联酋和以色列之间的关系并不总是直截了当。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在推动方向是正确的。”他在接受采访时说道。 “有时我们需要走弯路，但我们的方向是正确的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列表示希望与阿联酋的经济和商业关系鼓励其他阿拉伯国家承认该国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据一位了解阿布扎比想法的人士称，阿联酋认为，尽管遭遇挫折，《亚伯拉罕协议》仍然取得了成功，与以色列建立外交关系有助于解决其担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民意调查由华盛顿研究所委托进行的调查显示，海湾地区对《亚伯拉罕协议》的支持率大幅下降。根据最新调查，在阿联酋和巴林，分别只有 27% 和 20% 的受访者认为这些举措对该地区有利。相比之下，2020 年这一比例为 47% 和 45%。在沙特阿拉伯，这一比例大致减半至 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;持续的痛处是，阿联酋暂停了有关购买先进 F 飞机的谈判。在华盛顿坚持取消与中国华为的 5G 移动技术合同后，美国将于 2021 年底从美国派遣 -35 架战机。当阿联酋同意与以色列建立关系时，就得到了向其提供武器的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙特分析师阿尔加什安表示，沙特阿拉伯一直在密切关注阿联酋在《亚伯拉罕协议》方面的经历。 “它意识到与以色列合作的局限性，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= “color:orange” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[From Singapore to India, Nepal and Myanmar, Asia must ‘adapt’ to heatwaves]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/health-environment/article/3229283/singapore-india-nepal-and-myanmar-asia-must-adapt-heatwaves?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/4caf673b-3ec4-4cee-8617-bc03a7948554_8175647e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新加坡居民在未来几周和几个月内每次醒来时，他们可能会在上班或上学之前，检查高温警报是他们早上例行公事的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种情况在不到十年前可能是不可想象的，但这是亚洲金融中心的人们将会遇到的事情新加坡当局也没有过于谨慎，因为气候科学家本周证实 7 月将是最热的——有史以来每个月都有记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国和欧盟监测人员表示，最近的高温可能是数千年来前所未有的，并警告说这只是未来气候的预兆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样根据莱比锡大学气候科学家 Karsten Haustein 博士的分析，温暖的气候仅在 12 万年前出现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着气候变化，包括新加坡在内的世界上许多国家的气温都在上升。因此，公众适应这一点很重要。”新加坡可持续发展部和国家环境局在最近的一份联合声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡的努力很可能很快就会以不同的形式在世界各地复制亚洲，该地区极易受到气候变化的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，印度北部发生致命洪水，而中国新疆省部分地区的气温高达 52.2 摄氏度，打破了此前创下的 50.6 摄氏度的纪录。 2017年。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着极端天气事件的增加，热浪每5年袭击中国一次：研究&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;极端天气灾难部分归因于厄尔尼诺现象，这种天气现象通常会扰乱每年的降雨模式几年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在厄尔尼诺现象期间，亚洲的气温往往会升高，通常会导致空气变得更加潮湿和温暖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，由于我们对地球的无情燃烧，这种天气现在将变得司空见惯。科学家表示，化石燃料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只要我们继续燃烧化石燃料，我们就会看到越来越多的极端现象，”格兰瑟姆气候研究所气候科学高级讲师弗里德里克·奥托说伦敦政治经济学院的变化与环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[但是]即使我们现在停止燃烧化石燃料，气温也不会下降，”她说。 “因此，我们现在看到的热浪，我们肯定必须忍受。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高温已经对那些生活在难以获得公共卫生服务的边缘化社区的人们的健康造成了严重损害， “柳叶刀”气候变化与健康倒计时执行主任玛丽娜·罗曼内洛 (Marina Romanello) 表示，自 2000 年代初以来，全球与高温相关的死亡率增加了约 70%，追踪两者之间的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;影响是巨大的，炎热的天气严重降低了农民等人每天在田地里工作长达 12 个小时的能力，就像他们几代人所做的那样.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗曼内洛表示，仅 2021 年，气温飙升就导致全球损失约 4700 亿个工作时间，造成约 7000 亿美元的经济损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约有 4.5 亿人亚太地区的小农。科学家表示，最贫穷的国家（如孟加拉国、尼泊尔、巴基斯坦和缅甸）往往首当其冲地受到气候变化的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;原因包括重建受自然灾害影响的低收入社区需要时间。 、缺乏社会福利安全网以及地理因素（例如位于脆弱的沿海地区）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高温还会造成其他危害，包括毁灭性的森林火灾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周，印度尼西亚当局表示，由于天气干燥，7 月 17 日至 23 日期间，容易发生野火的地区数量增加了一倍，这让人想起 2015 年那场毁灭性的大火，这场大火让东南亚笼罩在雾霾中达五个月之久。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; “我们将面临水危机”：马来西亚通过播种云来降雨&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国的一项研究后来将当年的雾霾与印度尼西亚、马来西亚和新加坡超过 10 万人过早死亡联系起来。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“虽然并非所有热点都会变成火灾点，但我们仍然必须保持警惕，因为我们看到火势显着增加，”印度尼西亚 BNPB 减灾机构发言人表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚气象局本月表示，预计该国下半年将出现 2019 年以来最严重的旱季，部分原因是厄尔尼诺现象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;炎热潮湿的气候也带来了更多蚊媒传播的担忧致力于减轻气候压力的非营利性亚洲创投慈善网络主题合作总监阿拉文丹·斯里尼瓦桑 (Aravindan Srinivasan) 表示，这些疾病已经在东南亚、南美洲和非洲流行。撒哈拉以南非洲地区，但现在已开始在欧洲等未知地区爆发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，人口稠密的亚洲仍然面临最大的风险。斯里尼瓦桑指出，世界上最容易受到气候变化影响的五个国家——印度、中国、孟加拉国、巴基斯坦和印度尼西亚——位于该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Srinivasan 总部位于新加坡的网络, which counts philanthropists and large companies among its 600 members, is keen to fund mitigation and renewable generation programmes in Asia. It has been working in India for the past six months and plans to soon launch operations in China, as well in Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His non-profit network cooperates with grass-roots enterprises and works with different organisations who collaborate with governments to identify problem-solving programmes for local communities, such as painting rooftops to lessen heat, but these initiatives are often strapped for cash, Srinivasan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have to look at both sides of the coin – mitigation and adaptation,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mitigation and adaptation are becoming evermore important as extreme weather prompts a surge in electricity demand to power air conditioning and fans, threatening yet more emissions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Power consumption records in several Chinese cities have been broken recently, with Shanghai reportedly burning hundreds of tons of coal per hour to keep the city cool, while people in other nations, like Vietnam, have had to cope with rolling blackouts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Climate activists are now eyeing a year-end UN climate meeting in Dubai, hoping there will be agreements to phase out fossil fuels and ramp up renewable energy. But they say nations need to prioritise the environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Striking a balance between energy needs and reducing emissions is key to preventing more frequent and intense heatwaves, said Julie Arrighi, director from the Red Cross Red Crescent Climate Centre at The Hague in the Netherlands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asian countries are often tempted to turn to coal-based power as the fuel is readily available in the region, but this strategy is fraught with risks amid a changing climate, experts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thermal power facilities – those which operate using energy produced by a steam boiler, often fuelled by coal or gas – do not operate as efficiently in very hot weather, said Grant Hauber, strategic energy finance adviser at the Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He noted that such facilities often suffer capacity reductions when it is very hot. According to energy think tank Ember, around 62 per cent of the world&#39;s electricity came from fossil fuels in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Is Asia finally turning away from filthy fossil fuels to embrace green energy?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The International Energy Agency said on Thursday that global coal consumption rose to a new all-time high in 2022 and will stay near that record level this year, as strong growth for power generation and industrial applications in Asia outpaces declines in the United States and Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coal usage last year rose by 3.3 per cent to 8.3 billion tonnes, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asian demand has remained strong over the last couple of weeks as China has been ramping up coal fired-power generation, ANZ bank said recently.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But renewable energy&#39;s declining prices mean that over the longer term, demand in Asia is likely to shift more towards green sources, experts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Increasingly, it may actually be renewables that step in to fill the gap,” said Hauber, noting that solar power saved the day during heat-related outages at gas-fired plants in the US state of Texas last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Agence France-Presse&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Post-China’s rise, India emerges as global investors’ new destination of choice: ‘India’s time has come’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3229434/post-chinas-rise-india-emerges-global-investors-new-destination-choice-indias-time-has-come?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/df7fd5af-3992-47ed-8984-0a9e80d64ba3_1ee250dc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After China&#39;s rise as an economic powerhouse over the past few decades, some of the biggest names in business and investing are now pointing to another Asian nation as the next big investment destination: India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Billionaire investor Ray Dalio has said the country is ready for rapid growth, while Elon Musk has highlighted the prospect of Tesla building a factory there. Apple CEO Tim Cook has also voiced his optimism towards India, while Goldman Sachs predicts the South Asian economy to surpass the United States in size by 2075.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Factors seen favouring India&#39;s economy in the coming years include a large and relatively youthful population, a vibrant stock market, and the nation&#39;s strong tech industry, according to experts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India recently surpassed China as the world&#39;s most populous country. The nation&#39;s benchmark stock indexes Sensex and Nifty 50 hit record highs this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From billionaire entrepreneurs to Wall Street banks, all eyes are on India. Here&#39;s a closer look at their comments, projections and plans:&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Musk has been eyeing India for over two years now. Back in 2021, the Tesla CEO said he was “quite likely” to build an electric-vehicle factory in the country, but only if government officials lowered import fees for completed vehicles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If Tesla is able to succeed with imported vehicles, then a factory in India is quite likely,” Musk had said on Twitter at the time. He added: “We want to do so, but import duties are the highest in the world by far of any large country!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fast forward to 2023, and Musk is starting to see those visions move closer to reality. After meeting Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi last month, the billionaire entrepreneur said the EV maker would establish its presence in the country “as soon as humanly possible”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tesla is eyeing the South Asian nation to build a factory producing a debut US$24,000 car, Reuters reported last week. Sources told the outlet that Musk is set to meet Indian government representatives to discuss a new Tesla plant this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to the billionaire investor, India is primed to be the next big global investing opportunity, especially as tensions between Washington and Beijing worsen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am pleased to be able to help PM Modi as he is a man whose time has come when India&#39;s time has also come,” Dalio said in a tweet. “He and India are in an analogous position to Deng Xiaoping and China in the early 1980s – ie, at the brink of the fastest growth rates and biggest transformations in the world,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The challenges both between and within China and the US are putting PM Modi in a unique position to influence the complexion of the world order via influencing the non-aligned world&#39;s dealings with these two leading world powers,” the Bridgewater Associates founder continued.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Legendary emerging-markets investor Mark Mobius recently hailed India as the “real future”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mobius cited India&#39;s high growth rate – gross domestic product is expected to have grown by 7.2 per cent for the financial year that ended on March 31 – for his bullishness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A rule of thumb is that if the country has a 7 per cent growth rate, then a reasonably good company should be able to double that,” he told Bloomberg.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wall Street bank Goldman Sachs attracted much attention recently when it forecast India&#39;s economy to surpass the US by 2075, to become the world&#39;s second-largest after China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goldman Sachs expects the South Asian nation&#39;s GDP to surge to US$52.5 trillion by then, from US$3.4 trillion at the end of 2022. That compares with forecasts of US$57 trillion and $51.5 trillion for China and the US, respectively. That&#39;s thanks to a booming tech scene, rising capital investments and a growing population.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s economic potential has also lured interest from Big Tech.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple CEO Tim Cook has previously voiced confidence in the country, once telling investors he&#39;s “very, very bullish and very, very optimistic about India”, back in 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His sanguineness towards India has seen Apple open its first two stores in the country earlier this year. He&#39;s also noted that India&#39;s youthful demographic and growing middle class translates into a higher appetite for advanced and expensive technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This article was first published by &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s manufacturing activity contracts for fourth straight month in July despite uptick]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3229436/chinas-manufacturing-activity-contracts-fourth-straight-month-july-despite-uptick?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/2302d7c0-8b15-44cf-9f69-08b0de5e2376_e9706451.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s factory activity picked up in July, but remained in contraction for a fourth straight month amid an overall slowing economic recovery, while expansion in the non-manufacturing sectors slowed this month, data released on Monday showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official manufacturing purchasing managers&#39; index (PMI) rose to 49.3 in July, up from 49 in June, according to the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS), but remained in contraction for a fourth straight month. The 50-mark separates growth from contraction on a monthly basis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official non-manufacturing PMI, which measures business sentiment in the services and construction sectors, fell to 51.5 in July from 53.2 in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Within the official manufacturing PMI, the new orders subindex rose to 49.5 in July from 48.6 in June, while the new export orders subindex fell to 46.3 from 47.2.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official composite PMI, which includes both manufacturing and services activity, fell to 51.1 in July, down from 52.3 in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Within the non-manufacturing gauge, the services subindex fell to 51.5 in July from 52.8 in June, while the construction subindex fell to 51.2 from 55.7.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Ji Siqi&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More to follow …&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Given a second life’: home-alone toddler in China tumbles from third floor flat, caught by man among dozen of passers-by who rushed to rescue]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3229106/given-second-life-home-alone-toddler-china-tumbles-3rd-floor-flat-caught-man-among-dozen-passers-who?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/30/25a43e21-77e3-4384-bd80-c8d6a7bb742b_f3e409c5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;People on mainland social media have flocked to view a viral video which captures the moment a group of passers-by performed an instinctive and dramatic rescue of a toddler falling from the third-floor balcony of a building.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Surveillance footage from July 24 shows a group of passers-by reacting in unison by running towards the building in China&#39;s northwestern Shaanxi province with open arms and trying to catch the child who was tumbling down from the third floor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amazingly, the toddler, 19-month-old Chenchen, landed in the arms of one of them and only suffered minor grazes to his legs, according to the news outlet Huashang News.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man who caught him, Wang Jing, is a bus driver and a father of two children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said he was riding an electric bike on his way to work when he suddenly spotted Chenchen walking on the balcony outside the third floor flat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said he immediately put the bike aside and rushed towards the building as the youngster looked like he was about to fall over the edge of the balcony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said he did not realise he was not the only one who had reacted on seeing the boy&#39;s predicament until he saw the surveillance video.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The only thing he remembered was kneeling in front of the toddler after he caught him, eager to check if he was fine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The footage also revealed that Wang had tripped over some steps during the act of catching Chenchen, which cushioned the impact of the boy landing in his arms and without which both he and the youngster might have suffered worse injuries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said he only suffered minor strain to his arm, adding that he acted out of “the instincts of a father”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I thought since I am fat, I could even catch the kid by letting him fall on my body,” added Wang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The day after the rescue, Chenchen&#39;s parents took the toddler to the bus station to thank Wang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The father embraced Wang tightly and cried: “I hate to think what would have happened to my kid without you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said Chenchen&#39;s grandmother had left him alone sleeping while she went out to buy medicine and had not expected him to wake up so soon. A gate between the bay window and balcony had also been left unlocked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thanks to these passers-by who came to the rescue, not only has this toddler been given a second life, a family has been saved,” said one online observer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is hard to imagine what would have happened to the bus driver without the cushioning effect of the steps. Parents really should be more careful,” said another person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Everyone looked above without noticing the steps below. What a group of selfless people,” said a third.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, mainland social media was moved by a dozen neighbours who used an outstretched quilt to catch a 40-day-old baby dropped from the fourth-floor window of a blazing flat by its mother in eastern China&#39;s Zhejiang province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mother was later rescued by the firefighters.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why the hunt for Hong Kong schools is ‘miserable’ for some mainland Chinese arriving through talent pass scheme with children]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3229199/why-hunt-hong-kong-schools-miserable-some-mainland-chinese-arriving-through-talent-pass-scheme?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/1fd082ae-35ba-49cd-b865-4b4df7ce093f_97538e93.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Mainland Chinese talent drawn to Hong Kong under a new scheme have begun settling in, with some complaining that it is hard to get their children into schools in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parents who spoke to the Post said school admission tests were hard and their children&#39;s lack of proficiency in English and Cantonese proved a problem. Some said they were sending their children for lessons in both languages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One principal said he had to turn away applicants who could not speak Cantonese, the school&#39;s medium of instruction for Chinese classes.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Easier than a library card? Mainlanders seek pastures new with Hong Kong visa&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Top Talent Pass Scheme introduced last December offered successful applicants a two-year visa. Candidates must have earned no less than HK$2.5 million (US$320,500) over the past 12 months or be graduates of one of the world&#39;s top 100 universities who have worked for three of the past five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Graduates from the world&#39;s top 100 universities in the past five years with less than three years of experience may also apply, but the number is capped at 10,000 annually.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who are not graduates of these universities are also eligible if they earned an annual salary of HK$2.5 million or more in the year before they apply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Successful applicants are allowed to bring their spouses and children to settle in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Immigration Department, there were 25,961 successful main applicants as of June, and 22,751 dependent visas were issued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 95 per cent of the approved applications so far have been for mainlanders, the Post reported earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Information and technology sector professional Jessica Liu, 32, said she would be moving to Hong Kong with her husband and their two daughters, aged eight and 1½ years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finding a school for her elder girl proved a challenge. She said she applied to nearly 20 primary schools, but not many offered places.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The schools&#39; entrance assessments were a hurdle. “Hong Kong schools have higher requirements for English than mainland ones,” she said. “For interviews, some schools emphasise proficiency in Cantonese.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said her family did not speak any Cantonese.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong approves 1,400 applications for new talent scheme in 7 days&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Education Bureau said it did not have figures for the number of students who came to Hong Kong via the Top Talent Pass Scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Davis Chan Wai-lun, principal of Wah Yan College, Hong Kong, an elite school, said there was a sharp rise in applications this year from the mainland and some were top-notch students.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There was a boy who has been the first in class and never dropped to second place out of about 300 students in his grade on the mainland,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He did not accept that boy because there were no more school places, adding he had to turn down others due to a lack of fluency in Cantonese.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Because we teach Chinese in Cantonese, we will not accept applicants who do not understand Cantonese. Teaching the subject in Mandarin, for now, is not on our agenda,” Chan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the long run, we may need to consider opening options for students to choose to study Chinese in Mandarin.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said some students from across the border who previously studied in Hong Kong and went back to the mainland during the Covid-19 pandemic had returned to the city too.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Tightened rules for Hong Kong talent visa schemes after Chinese biophysicist saga&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Cindy Xu, who is from Guangzhou, obtained a Top Talent Visa to work in the financial sector but said it was a “miserable” experience finding a secondary school for her 12-year-old son.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Disappointed with the school he was allocated in July, the boy began approaching ones he preferred directly, a practice referred to in Hong Kong as “door-knocking”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Out of eight secondary schools he approached, only one invited him to an interview, only to reject him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu said her son was a top student in Guangzhou and active in extracurricular activities, but the Hong Kong schools did not recognise his mainland results.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He ended up at a school in Kowloon Tong that Xu described as being “friendly to mainlanders”, but he will have to travel 40 minutes to get there from their home in Sai Ying Pun.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As new arrivals, Xu said the family had little knowledge of the city&#39;s education system, and were at a loss because there was no comprehensive information available to them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“All we could do was search on the internet or ask other new arrivals,” she said. “I suggest the government set up a hotline or provide an email to handle inquiries from new arrivals.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Mainland Chinese told not to misuse Hong Kong talent visas to have babies in city&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mainland couple Cecilia Wang Wenxi and Ray Jiang Lei, both 35, had a happier account of settling in with their two sons, aged 7½ and 1½.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The couple, both Chinese University graduates, said they appreciated the education system in Hong Kong which would give their two sons time for activities other than schoolwork.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The older boy, William, had adapted well in his class after three months at a Hong Kong primary school in Kowloon Tong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said he had a warm welcome when he started school in March, even though he did not speak any Cantonese.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The teacher asked a student who speaks good Mandarin to take care of him, and after class, many students came to greet him and showed him around the campus,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang, a stock investor, applied for the talent scheme a day after it was announced and it was approved within days on January 2.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said language, especially English, was the biggest challenge her son faced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When William first came to Hong Kong, he could not even spell a word. And we were desperate when he did his first dictation assignment,” Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We had to spend more time outside school on his English, and we eventually saw improvement. William got full marks in his third dictation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The whole family attended Cantonese classes on weekends. Wang was pleased that William learned quickly and could even answer his teachers&#39; questions in Cantonese.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The couple&#39;s younger son, Ethan, is living with his grandparents in Shenzhen. The family planned to bring him to Hong Kong to start kindergarten.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong to cast &#39;far wider net than that of Singapore&#39; in talent push&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Alyssa Wang, an accountant from Shenzhen, said it was a smooth process getting her five-year-old daughter into a kindergarten in Tuen Mun.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She succeeded with only one application and the teachers were nice, speaking good Mandarin to them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For now, the family is still living in Shenzhen and the girl is crossing the border daily to attend kindergarten. Wang said the family would move to Hong Kong if the girl continued to primary school in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She also said she was not worried about her daughter experiencing culture shock in kindergarten.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Immersed in a Cantonese-speaking environment, a little girl like her can pick up Cantonese very quickly,” Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“English might be a challenge, and to prepare her for the new semester in September, I signed her up for tutoring classes by foreign teachers,” Wang added.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What the Niger coup means for China’s presence in the Sahel region]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229399/what-niger-coup-means-chinas-presence-sahel-region?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.31 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/30/92cbc04a-1247-4b08-8450-a093252f0654_80e1a216.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Last week&#39;s military coup in Niger is adding to the growing pains for China&#39;s investments in the Sahel region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, a group of soldiers from the presidential guard detained Nigerien President Mohamed Bazoum, citing a worsening security and economic situation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past three years there have also been coups in Burkina Faso, Guinea, Mali, Chad and Sudan, all countries where China has extensive economic interests especially in the mining and petroleum industries and is looking to extend its multibillion-dollar trade and investment scheme, the Belt and Road Initiative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bazoum was elected in March 2021 in the country&#39;s first peaceful, democratic transition since independence from France in 1960.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s foreign ministry said Beijing was closely monitoring the situation in Niger and called on relevant parties to act in the interest of the country and its people and solve differences peacefully through dialogue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rahmane Idrissa, a senior researcher at the African Studies Centre at Leiden University in Netherlands, said the military was taking advantage of what looked like an international climate more tolerant of coups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Idrissa said the coup was a disaster for the Franco-Nigerien relationship and more broadly, for Niger&#39;s relations with the West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the Wagner Group – a Russian mercenary company with extensive interests in Africa – “isn&#39;t a factor but the Kremlin is certainly happy about it, not because it helps the Nigeriens, but because it might help their progress into West Africa, which has been favoured by the juntas of Mali and Burkina Faso”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Vital US support under threat as EU cuts off aid to Niger amid coup&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said China was present in Niger as an economic partner in the exploitation of oil in the eastern part of the country. “The deal will not be affected by the coup,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bazoum is a close ally of France, and other Western nations but Beijing has been making inroads into Niger as it has with other countries in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s state-owned China National Petroleum Corporation and China National Nuclear Corporation invested US$4.6 billion and US$480 million in the country&#39;s petroleum and uranium industries respectively, according to China&#39;s Ministry of Commerce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country&#39;s uranium industry supplies around 5 per cent of the world&#39;s highest-grade uranium ore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 27, Bazoum met a delegation from China National Uranium Corporation (CNUC) to discuss the conditions for the takeover of the Société des mines d&#39;Azelik (Somina), where CNUC and the Nigerien state are the majority shareholders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNUC has recently been carrying out studies on restarting production in Niger&#39;s northern region. The project, abandoned nine years ago due to global market conditions, is now being reconsidered due to favourable uranium prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Besides uranium, which Niger mostly exports to France, Canada and South Korea, the country also exports gold and oily seeds, according to data from the Observatory of Economic Complexity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Early this month, China&#39;s ambassador to Niger Jiang Feng met Bazoum and said China would build an industrial park in the capital Niamey with a significant impact on sectors such as agro-food, manufacturing, mining and real estate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the meeting, Jiang also briefed the president of his visit to Agadem, where the Niger-Benin export pipeline developed by the China National Petroleum Corporation starts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pipeline spans nearly 2,000km (1,200 miles) and is expected to bolster Niger&#39;s crude oil production and facilitate international trade through a terminal on Benin&#39;s coast.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Gunmen kidnap 4 Chinese workers from Nigeria mine&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mohammed Soliman, director at the Middle East Institute in Washington, said the coup in Niger had heightened destabilisation in the Sahel region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Niger&#39;s possession of significant uranium mines and other valuable resources, such as gold, raises concerns about the potentially far-reaching implications for the global economy,” Soliman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Soliman said that should the situation in the Sahel region escalate further, it could have considerable consequences for China&#39;s economic interests and investments in Niger and neighbouring countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The instability may disrupt infrastructure projects, extractive industries, and other ventures China has invested in, posing risks to its economic stake in the area,” Soliman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What could Niger coup and new military leader mean for West Africa stability?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Moreover, Soliman said prolonged instability and conflicts in the Sahel could impact China&#39;s broader strategic objectives and influence in Africa, prompting a re-evaluation of its engagement and presence on the continent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;John Calabrese, a professor at American University in Washington, said it would be worth watching whether the new leadership of Niger followed through with the discussions Beijing held with Bazoum&#39;s administration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gyude Moore, a senior policy fellow at the Washington-based Centre for Global Development, and a former public works minister in Liberia, said Niger was one of the last bastions of French support in francophone Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moore said China has no preference regarding regime type, so if Western governments withdrew, China&#39;s influence would grow, by default.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moore said China&#39;s contribution to Sahel security stabilisation, which includes troops joining a UN peacekeeping mission in Mali, had been tied to China&#39;s own growing economic interests in the region. “Those interests mean that China will be focused on stability, regardless of regime type,” Moore said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>