<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Scientists in favour of Hong Kong having its own drug approval system, with enough manpower to ensure efficiency, high standards]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3226228/scientists-favour-hong-kong-having-its-own-drug-approval-system-enough-manpower-ensure-efficiency?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 17:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/2b2bfe2f-fae0-46be-85de-397d11483d94_2122bfcd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港顶尖科学家欢迎香港拥有自己的药物的建议监管审批系统，称这可能意味着更快地获得新产品并促进生物医学发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他们也表示，该市必须确保拥有有效、高效和国际化地完成这项工作所需的专家人力标准，建立生产线对于促进生物医学增长至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们是在回应卫生部长罗仲茂的评论，罗仲茂在周三接受《华盛顿邮报》采访时表示，政府正在调查建立类似美国食品和药物管理局的机构来评估新的药品并吸引更多的研究和开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学顶级传染病专家洪繁毅教授香港大学（香港大学）表示，香港拥有自己的监管制度将是一件好事，因为它可以让更多地方更容易获得药品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个过程也可以更快，”他说。 “例如，如果一种中国大陆药物尚未获得海外监管机构的批准，我们自己的审批机构如果发现它有效且安全，就可以允许其使用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袁国勇教授香港大学顶尖微生物学家表示，引入这样的系统可以帮助香港在生物医学进步方面处于领先地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要在生物医学研发方面具有国际竞争力，香港必须建立一个有效的机制药物临床前开发、临床试验、批准使用。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们应该有自己的机制，而不仅仅是跟随者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;药品审批制度政府正在考虑的称为“初步评估”，指评估来自临床研究的原始数据和信息以及其他相关制造细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港目前运行“二次评估”系统，地方当局依赖内地及海外36个监管机构的注册批准，并自行评估。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;制药公司只要获得两个或两个以上监管机构的批准，即可申请在香港注册药品。 36个机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中文大学临床肿瘤学系系主任莫树锦教授表示，香港必须确保有足够的人手来执行其自身药物审批机制的复杂运作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;香港可以通过“拥有自己的药品监管体系”来吸引制药巨头&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们有我们的人才，但问题是我们是否有足够的人才，”他说，并指出建立药品监管机制需要大量的人力和时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果进来的药品种类很多，是否有足够的人力来满足所有这些要求？”及时吗？”他问。 “你需要在几个月内浏览从开发开始的所有数据，评估安全性并做出判断。没那么简单。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;身为香港科学院名誉秘书的莫克担心，如果香港的药品审批流程过于复杂，制药公司就会被推迟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“如果流程复杂、漫长，是否会为了700万的市场投入大量的金钱和时间？”他问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港制药业协会高级执行董事陈素娟表示，初级评估系统可以为寻求产品注册的制造商提供灵活性和更多选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这可能类似于新加坡发生的情况，新加坡的药物可以通过三种途径注册：接受全面评估；如果已经获得一个参考国家的批准，则进行简短的评估；如果在两个或两个以上参比药品监管机构注册，则需要验证过程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论是初级审评还是二级审评，最重要的是系统的效率、可预测性和专业性。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，要维持香港的地位，制度必须符合国际标准，并且应该承诺评估需要多长时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港香港应该“带头让内地医疗保健达到城市标准”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她说，政府正在考虑的该系统的更多细节对于确定香港是否可以充分受益非常重要。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她说，吸引更多的临床试验在该市进行需要的不仅仅是监管体系。其他因素包括试验能否快速便捷地进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾参与开发针对 Covid-19 的鼻喷雾疫苗的香港大学教授 Hung 表示，建立本地疫苗和药物生产线将有助于对于鼓励在城市进行更多临床试验至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们需要进行临床试验，最好拥有自己的生产线，而不必依赖内地……我们可以做得更多&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;从 7 月起，香港夫妇可以分享老年医疗券&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;洪的团队与一家中国大陆制药公司合作开展疫苗项目。他表示，跨境合作花了很多时间等待审批。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过在本地设立生产线，内地企业可以授权香港生产用于临床试验的疫苗，这可以吸引投资洪说：“在这种情况下，从开发、制造到临床试验，整个机制是完整的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪说，落马洲河套地区被政府指定发展创新科技，是一个有潜力设立本地疫苗制造厂的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China warns against ‘confrontation and division’ as US regains Unesco seat]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3226229/china-warns-against-confrontation-and-division-us-regains-unesco-seat?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 17:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/c3e1b655-0824-4db3-a1fd-7ce028506e98_35d65626.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国警告美国不要在联合国教科文组织制造“对抗和分裂”据官方媒体报道，本月恢复正式会员资格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国重新加入这个由 193 个国家组成的联合国遗产、教育和科学机构的提案于周五以绝大多数票通过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;根据联合国教科文组织的新闻稿，中国是投票反对该动议的 10 个成员国之一，而 132 个成员国中的“绝大多数”投了赞成票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该动议的通过将取决于美国本月全面重返联合国教科文组织，距联合国教科文组织在时任总统唐纳德·特朗普领导下退出约五年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国常驻联合国教科文组织代表杨进对重返联合国教科文组织表示担忧，称美国已经跳过了联合国教科文组织的回归由于自身立法等“可控因素”，多年来会员费被收取。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“成员国加入联合国教科文组织的目的是为了加强合作，为和平作出贡献，而不是为了对抗或抵制其影响。”中国国家电视台中央电视台援引杨的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指的是美国寻求重新加入联合国教科文组织的主要原因，即在技术竞争中获得优势与中国的合作，特别是人工智能的全球规则制定。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国计划重新加入联合国教科文组织，以反击中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;3月份，拜登政府提交了2024年财政预算年，主管管理事务的副国务卿约翰·巴斯 (John Bass) 表示，重新加入联合国教科文组织将“帮助我们解决我们的缺席在与中国的全球竞争中造成的关键机会成本”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[如果美国]真的巴斯说：“严肃对待与中国的数字时代竞争……我们不能再缺席了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在回应周五投票结果时，杨说：“[美国]应该推动据官方通讯社新华社报道，他还呼吁华盛顿履行拖欠联合国教科文组织费用的责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还呼吁华盛顿履行偿还拖欠联合国教科文组织费用的责任。 &lt;p>;联合国教科文组织在周五的新闻稿中表示，美国将向该机构提供 22% 的常规预算资金，并逐步偿还约 6.19 亿美元的欠款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;未付款自 2011 年以来，会费不断增加，自成员国投票决定将巴勒斯坦纳入其成员国以来，美国与主要盟友以色列停止向联合国教科文组织提供资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国还停止支付为联合国教科文组织提供资金的会员费。项目包括支持非洲受教育机会、纪念大屠杀和保护记者的项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017 年，特朗普政府宣布将于次年 12 月 31 日退出该组织，理由是积累了拖欠和“反以色列偏见”是主要原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列官员表示，以其世界遗产计划而闻名的联合国教科文组织忽视了犹太教与圣地等有争议的历史遗址的联系，关系进一步恶化。谢里夫或圣殿山建筑群以及希伯伦或哈利勒老城区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;星期五的联合国教科文组织投票是在拜登政府正式申请重新加入该机构几周后进行的。其 6 月 8 日致联合国教科文组织总干事奥黛丽·阿祖莱 (Audrey Azoulay) 的信中提到了该机构最近的改革和人工智能标准制定等新举措以及伊拉克摩苏尔老城的重建等，这些都是希望重返联合国教科文组织的原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿祖莱称其为“联合国教科文组织和多边主义的伟大一天”，并称该组织“随着美国的回归再次走向普遍主义”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这并不是美国第一次回归联合国教科文组织。它在 1984 年冷战时期退出，理由是腐败和亲苏反美偏见，然后于 2002 年重新加入。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong teachers and students have duty to defend national security under patriotic education bill, says education minister]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3226227/hong-kong-teachers-and-students-have-duty-defend-national-security-under-patriotic-education-bill?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 17:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/f2475432-f09b-488f-9ebd-bdf2b2fd5d2f_82a4b9ed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;师生应认识到爱国主义精神下捍卫国家安全的责任教育部长表示，香港当局寻求加强教育法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教育局局长蔡玉莲周六还表示，香港将在未来派遣更多教师访问内地培育“爱国爱港”的主流价值观，也符合“一国两制”的施政原则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是蔡英文首次参与国家提案上周，中国最高立法机构全国人民代表大会常务委员会审议了爱国主义教育法案。目前正在接受公众咨询。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法案第22条规定，国家将采取措施，加强香港、澳门、台湾地区民众对国家历史文化的认识，维护国家统一。第十四条还指出，各级各类学校应当将爱国主义教育纳入课程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而香港最高机构唯一代表李慧琼则表示，香港不会行政长官李家超在法律上有义务执行新国家法律，他期望香港能够轻松满足法案的要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“爱国价值观体现在维护国家安全的自觉意识上”，周六，崔在庆祝香港回归中国统治26周年的活动上用普通话向学生、教师和教育界其他人士发表讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只有树立对香港回归中国的使命感， ”她补充道，“了解一个公民应有的权利、义务和责任，才能关心国家的发展并自觉维护国家的安全。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港没有义务适用新的国家政策爱国主义教育法：李慧琼&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;崔表示政府将与国家合作实施爱国主义教育。她补充说，将组织更多以教师为中心的大陆旅行，以帮助教育工作者培养学生的国家认同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据周五向学校发出的通知，参加为期三至四天的学习旅行前往内地将是下一学年从9月起晋升教师的培训要求之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅行包括研讨会以及参观学校、企业和文化场所，为教师提供“直接的亲身体验”声明称，“为了更深入地了解”国家的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港教师要求北京给予更多自由来实施爱国主义教育&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京 37,000 名教师的主席黄锦良友好的香港教育工作者联会告诉《邮报》，他经营的香港第一家爱国主义教育中心将举办以中国传统文化和价值观为主题的活动，以及有关国家安全、发展和身份的活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黄说，该中心于周六庆祝成立一周年，将在来年进行升级，以展示国家的航空航天模型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括香港大学和香港大学在内的多所高等教育机构理工大学周六举行升旗仪式庆祝回归周年。理大的活动共有约 600 名教职员、学生及校友参加。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 17:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s semiconductor ambitions dealt fresh blow by new Dutch export rules on ASML chip-making machines]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3226225/chinas-semiconductor-ambitions-dealt-fresh-blow-new-dutch-export-rules-asml-chip-making-machines?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/4088659f-62eb-42c1-8cb3-2e1a2d7b0078_6a2e1c65.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;荷兰政府进一步限制出货量，给中国半导体行业带来新的打击ASML 的芯片制造设备运往中国，但这可能不是最后的决定，因为据报道美国正在寻求进一步收紧对中国芯片野心的遏制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ASML 在周五的一份声明中表示，自 9 月 1 日起，该公司将需要向海牙申请许可证才能运输其最先进的浸没式深紫外 (DUV) 光刻系统，包括 TWINSCAN NXT: 2000i 和更复杂的型号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在对此，中国政府谴责美国“胁迫”其他国家对中国实施技术封锁，“破坏市场规则和国际贸易”以及全球供应链的稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国将中国外交部发言人毛宁在周五的新闻发布会上表示：“我们将密切关注相关事态发展，坚决维护自身合法权益。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新出口管制措施的影响可能初步显现由于 NXT: 2000i 和更高端的工具用于更先进的 7 纳米和 5 纳米工艺节点，鉴于美国更广泛的出口管制，中国芯片制造商已经很难应对这些问题。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;在中国芯片大会上，行业资深人士最关心的是美国制裁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;ASML的低端NXT1980i可用于10纳米节点芯片，但仍允许向中国销售。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;ASML 的极紫外 (EUV) 光刻机已被禁止向中国出口，台积电、三星电子和英特尔等顶级芯片制造商使用其生产用于智能手机和人工智能应用的尖端芯片。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新的禁令并不完全令人意外，因为该公司早在 3 月份就曾警告称，其可能会受到更广泛的先进芯片制造设备出口限制，但这表明北京方面的外交努力荷兰外贸部长 Liesje Schreinemacher 在 3 月份致该国议会的一封信中表示，政府已决定“需要在 2020 年扩大现有的出口管制”。国家和国际安全利益”，但没有点名任何目标国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后，中国官员发出了一系列从警告到训诫的信息，试图与荷兰对话&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;科技战愈演愈烈，美国一家芯片设计公司看到中国机遇&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;外交部发言人毛泽东在早些时候的新闻发布会上表示3月，中国希望荷兰“尊重契约精神，不滥用出口管制制度……努力维护……荷中两国以及两国企业的共同利益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国驻荷兰大使谭健3月下旬警告称，此举将损害两国政府之间的关系，如果荷兰切断与全球最大市场的联系，荷兰将面临失去芯片制造技术领先地位的风险。据谭在接受当地媒体Financieele Dagblad采访时透露。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管荷兰最新的出口管制似乎为中国企业使用ASML的低端设备留下了空间，但在美国进一步施压的情况下，这种情况可能会发生变化.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据路透社援引匿名消息人士的报道，预计华盛顿将实施一项新规定，甚至可能使 ASML 的 NXT: 1980Di 机器脱离中国人的手中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着美国限制的收紧周四在上海举行的中国半导体大会上，一些芯片制造专家宣称“全球化已死”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;清华大学微电子研究所所长、中国半导体行业协会官员魏少军”，表示中国是半导体行业“逆全球化”的最大受害者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当全球化被破坏时，[行业]模式存在很大缺陷，因为中国无法实现资源的全球配置，”他&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，一些人希望中国能够找到一条不同的前进道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最大的晶圆代工厂中芯国际高级副总裁韩迪表示“传统的产业合作模式面临新的挑战和机遇。”韩说。他建议中国重点发展芯片材料和零部件，发展先进芯片制造能力。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese-led team reports first evidence of puberty in dinosaur-era reptile, offering new insight into sexual development]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3225886/chinese-led-team-reports-first-evidence-puberty-dinosaur-era-reptile-offering-new-insight-sexual?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/330eed40-5d3c-4a55-8f82-7d0a818bab40_1236352e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一些爬行动物会经历青春期，一个国际研究小组报告观察到了青春期的证据首次在灭绝的化石物种中发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;做出这一开创性发现的来自中国、日本和德国的团队上周在同行评审期刊《当代生物学》上发表了他们的发现，为性行为提供了新的见解史前脊椎动物物种的发育。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这篇文章的主题是一种已灭绝的 2.4 亿年前三叠纪时期海洋爬行动物 Keichousaurus 的样本，这种爬行动物生活在现在的中国西南部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过检查其骨骼部分，研究小组发现，雄性凯丘龙发展出了与雌性不同的特征，并通过青春期过程达到性成熟，这使它们能够发展出有利于战斗和交配的特征，例如体型更大、体型更大、体型更大等。前肢肌肉更加发达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该物种的幼体具有圆形前肢骨骼轮廓，但成年后，雄性具有三角形轮廓，而雌性则保留圆形形状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在检查了 18 个不同个体的骨骼切片后在该物种中，研究人员发现了骨骼轮廓发生变化的独特生命阶段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;利用生长曲线，他们确定该阶段发生在 Keichousaurus 一岁之后，并且这是性行为的时期合肥工业大学博士生李强表示，根据共同第一作者合肥工业大学博士生李强的说法，基于“肱骨中轴交叉部的形状变化”，研究小组可以得出结论，青春期是这些变化的原因。 -节”，这明显反映了雄性前肢骨骼更强的特征。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国化石发现表明步速的变化如何帮助恐龙生存&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;研究小组假设，青春期的过程在Keichousaurus 是由性激素的内部调节以及外部刺激或压力（例如战斗活动和觅食行为增加）引起的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;激素发育和外部压力的结合导致骨骼的发育物种发育过程中的分化和身体变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在研究古代物种的性发育时，“通常骨骼不会保存很多信息”，李周三表示。但由于Keichousaurus的骨骼结构在性别之间差异很大，他们能够仅从骨骼上观察到差异。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究小组在骨组织学研究方面经验丰富，自2016年以来一直在收集Keichousaurus化石。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们最初打算补充骨骼组织学方面的现有文献，但在注意到该物种的外部性别差异很明显后，他们试图在化石中寻找证据。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国海洋生物化石迫使人们重新思考“大灭绝”的反弹&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;灭绝物种的研究人员必须经常做出假设，特别是在考虑内部和外部刺激对性发育的影响时，因为它并不总是在遗骸中看到。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，这项研究为化石研究提供了一个方向，使这个主题更加清晰。该团队正在寻求研究更多化石，作为进一步研究灭绝物种性发育的一部分。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Anxiety over ‘censorship’ mounts as Malaysian government faces state poll test]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3226178/anxiety-over-censorship-mounts-malaysian-government-faces-state-poll-test?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/df905dba-595b-41b8-b579-60b02801b38f_99329d0b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;马来西亚媒体自由倡导者警告说，在反对派之后，政府的“审查制度”正在悄然蔓延-有报道称，一位部长威胁警方对在 TikTok 直播活动中嘲笑他的批评者采取行动，链接的新闻门户网站遭受了不明原因的中断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些事件发生在总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣 (Anwar Ibrahim) 的联合政府面临首次真正的挑战之前几周。一系列州民意调查的测试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔政府于 11 月上台，承诺扫除腐败不堪的时期并压制媒体自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，就任总理几天后，在一场分裂的 11 月选举后，政府宣布全力取缔涉及 3R（种族、宗教和皇室）的挑衅性帖子。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;对其虚构作品的批评：马来西亚电影在文化上面临保守派的愤怒战争&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;州民意调查被视为政府支持率的晴雨表——尤其是来自占选民约三分之二的多数马来人的支持——安瓦尔政府一直在被指控关闭批评空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MalaysiaNow 的编辑兼首席执行官阿卜杜尔·拉赫曼·科亚 (Abdar Rahman Koya) 表示，从周二下午开始，部分当地读者无法访问该网站，尽管工作人员没有检测到其服务器上有任何异常活动或外部网络攻击.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到周四晚上，访问已完全恢复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然我们对马来西亚人再次可以访问该网站感到欣慰，但在找到这起巧合背后的罪魁祸首之前，我们不会休息。 ”Abdar Rahman 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在数字世界中，一切都可以追踪，我们很快就会知道。”一份报告称，通信部长法赫米·法齐尔 (Fahmi Fadzil) 据称威胁观众，如果他们在周一主持的 TikTok 直播活动中不停止在评论部分批评他，警方将采取行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所有参加我的活动的人现场会议并发表这样的声明……您正在受到当局的监视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果您家外面有电话或无线电车[警车]，请不要生我的气。我们正在监控，请注意行为，”法赫米在在线会议上说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据广播公司 Astro Awani 报道，法赫米周三表示，他没有向其部门发出任何屏蔽任何新闻门户的指示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;部长早些时候也否认在他的 TikTok 直播视频中威胁观众，称他只是提醒他们不要发表有关种族、宗教和皇室的挑衅性言论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前执政党巫统领导的历届政府 –现在是安瓦尔政府的重要盟友，因对批评媒体的严厉对待而臭名昭著。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;巫统不断呼吁释放纳吉布如何冒着颠覆安瓦尔联合政府的风险&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;媒体权利组织中心独立新闻协会表示“对政府最近涉嫌的行为感到非常震惊”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这表明我们可能有一个新政府，但同样的策略被用来审查和限制我们的言论自由该组织表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016 年，在现已名誉扫地的前总理纳吉布·拉扎克 (Najib Razak) 任职期间，政府封锁了新闻门户网站《马来西亚局内人》(The Malaysia Insider) 的访问权限，因为该网站刊登了一系列关于对他提出腐败指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该禁令最终导致该新闻门户网站关闭，其所有者 The Edge Media Group 表示，这是出于商业考虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳吉布政府还暂停了印刷2013 年，现已不复存在的周报《The Heat》发表了一篇有关其妻子罗斯玛·曼索尔 (Rosmah Mansor) 奢侈消费习惯的文章，该报获得了许可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳吉布于 2020 年被判犯有与丑闻缠身的前单位有关的腐败罪。国家基金 1MDB 正在服刑 12 年，而罗斯玛正在对自己的腐败定罪提出上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;独立媒体权利组织民政党媒体默迪卡 (Gerakan Media Merdeka) 就 MalaysiaNow 遭受的短暂中断表示，这是不可接受的政府将任何形式的在线新闻或合法观点与色情、赌博和暴力极端主义等“不良”内容置于同一水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“任何此类举措 - 如果被证明属实 - 将是间接的该组织在周三的一份声明中表示，这是政府对新闻媒体的审查形式，也是对新闻自由的公然侵犯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对派对神秘的 MalaysiaNow 停电事件进行了猛烈抨击，指责安瓦尔总理政府强制执行机构“让那些揭露他们无能的人保持沉默”——尽管与政府的联系尚未得到证实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国内外的观察家现在应该知道安瓦尔和他的政府还远远没有接近议会通信和数字影子投资组合主席 Wan Saiful Wan Jan 在一份声明中表示：“他们假装是改革派。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，马来西亚互联网监管机构表示将对 Meta 采取法律行动，社交媒体巨头 Facebook 的母公司未能删除不良内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚通信和多媒体委员会 (MCMC) 在《亚洲周刊》的一份声明中表示，Meta 未能“删除此类内容” ”，并将根据《通信和多媒体法》面临诉讼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TikTok 和消息应用 Telegram 此前也曾因类似投诉与马来西亚监管机构发生过冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A名为“Article 19”的言论自由倡导组织警告说，政府针对 Meta 的举措将对言论自由产生“严重的寒蝉效应”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这也给作为中介的 Facebook 带来了不适当的压力，马来西亚《Article 19》高级项目官员 Nalini Elumalai 上周在一份声明中表示：“突然对第三方内容承担法律责任。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这将是互联网自由度的令人担忧的下降。因此，如果当局试图在法律的掩护下隐藏其任意性。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysian minister breaks silence after being accused of barging into airport to ‘free’ Chinese woman]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3226223/malaysian-minister-breaks-silence-after-being-accused-barging-airport-free-chinese-woman?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 14:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/01/6916014b-f826-4d18-a6ba-612460ad083a_567e32d1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;马来西亚旅游、艺术及文化部长张景星声称他必须亲自介入周四，一名中国媒体公司的员工从深圳抵达吉隆坡国际机场 (KLIA)，移民官员将她拦住后，为她提供帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该女子声称，尽管她的旅行证件在根据命令，她被移民官员拒绝入境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她声称，如果她想获准入境，就被要求支付数千林吉特。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该女子抵达马来西亚时带着&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据悉，虽然她的上级已获得移民局批准入境，但该女子是该高级官员的私人助理，被拒绝入境，并据称被告知她的旅行证件存在不符之处。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚的腐败评级停滞不前，许多被指控的领导人仍在掌权&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tiong 说，车站官员给马来西亚总领事馆打电话。马来西亚人在广州，看到她的同事遇险后寻求帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我接到总领事馆工作人员的电话，讲述了据称发生的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我联系了马来西亚人反贪污委员会（MACC）及其官员于下午3点前往吉隆坡国际机场进行调查。 I met and spoke to both the visitors and immigration officers on duty,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tiong said the immigration officers told him there was a language barrier, and the matter was a misunderstanding between them and the Chinese women.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the women, believed to be in their 40s, also had their mobile phones seized by immigration officers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What powers do they have to seize their phones? It was their first trip to Malaysia. The two women told me they had never encountered such problems in other countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They are appalled by the incident, which has caused them great embarrassment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They have recorded all the conversations that transpired with airport officials and intended to expose their unpleasant experience when they returned to China,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the personal assistant was later allowed to enter the country after he had intervened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tiong said he learnt that the TV station official had come to Malaysia to pursue her PhD at a local university in Shah Alam, and her personal assistant had accompanied her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tiong said it was not the first time he had shown up at KLIA to resolve such issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thursday&#39;s incident was the fifth time I had gone to intervene on such matters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Also, claims that I did not have a pass to enter the arrival zone is untrue as I do have one, which is valid until next year,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tiong said if there was a language barrier with Chinese travellers, the Immigration Department should engage translators employed by Malaysia Airports Holdings Bhd.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said he was puzzled why the Immigration Department did not engage the translators, although they had previously been advised to do so.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Could Malaysia&#39;s latest graft crackdown backfire on Anwar&#39;s administration?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;It was reported by a news portal on Thursday night that a minister had “barged” into the arrival hall at KLIA and created a commotion in an attempt to “free” a Chinese national who had been barred entry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The news site also alleged that the minister had entered the restricted zone at the airport without a permit or pass.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Immigration Department director general Ruslin Jusoh said an investigation had been opened over a news report alleging that a minister caused a commotion at KLIA.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A thorough investigation covering all aspects connected to the incident will be carried out,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This story was originally published on &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[France riots: tourism sector faces cancellations as protests over police killing of teenager Nahel persist]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226218/france-riots-tourism-sector-faces-cancellations-protests-over-police-killing-teenager-nahel-persist?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 14:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/01/fe8bd110-a1e8-46dc-87e3-d073e4410455_dde4446a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Days of violent protests across France after the fatal police shooting of a teenager have started to impact the country&#39;s tourism sector, with hotels and restaurants facing cancellations while some have also suffered damage in the unrest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the death of 17-year-old Nahel during a traffic stop in a Paris suburb on Tuesday, “our hotel members have suffered a wave of cancellations of reservations in all the territories affected by the damage and clashes,” said chef Thierry Marx, president of the main association for hotel and catering industry employers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marx said on Friday he was receiving daily alerts from industry professionals who have suffered “attacks, looting and destruction of their businesses, including some restaurants and cafes”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our establishments are intrinsically hospitality venues, and sometimes even refuges and places of help in crisis situations. They must not suffer the consequences of anger that they have not aroused and we condemn these actions,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;France riots: how teen&#39;s killing is focusing anger on police tactics&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Marx wants the authorities to do “everything” to guarantee the safety of people in the hotel and catering industry in the world&#39;s most popular tourist destination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The French retail federation (FCD) also called for reinforced police security around stores, said managing director Jacques Creyssel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The riots “gave rise to real scenes of looting”, he said, with “more than a hundred medium and large food or non-food stores vandalised, looted or even burned”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These incidents “are extremely serious and have an extremely heavy cost”, according to Creyssel, who said he had asked the economy, interior and trade ministers to act.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Paris Ile-de-France Chamber of Commerce said it was ensuring its teams were mobilised to “provide the necessary support and technical assistance, particularly in terms of continuing operations, insurance compensation, etc …” for traders and managers of affected companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The GHR organisation for independent hotels and restaurants in France deplored that “foreign [TV networks] are starting to show images of Paris on fire and blood, which does not correspond to reality”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Will the violence and riots continue and cause a real wave of cancellations? That&#39;s the risk,” managing director Franck Trouet said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Asian tourists, in particular, who are very concerned about security, may not hesitate to postpone or cancel their trip,” he warned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Didier Arino, managing director of the Protourisme firm said: “Tourists who know us well, like the Belgians or the British, who also have problems themselves in their suburbs, will be able to make sense of things”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in the end, he said “it&#39;s as if we were doing a negative publicity campaign worth several tens of millions of euros for destination France”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The confederation of tobacconists was also indignant at the “looting and ransacking of shops, including 91 tobacconists during these last days of clashes”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If it continues like this, it can significantly complicate the organisation of the Olympic Games, especially since a good part of the events will take place in Seine-Saint-Denis,” a disadvantaged area in the north of Paris, said Jean-Francois Rial, president of the Paris Tourist Office.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 14:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Warring couple in China send each other to mental hospitals, shocking public and raising fears over lax rules for psychiatric admission]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/social-welfare/article/3225713/warring-couple-china-send-each-other-mental-hospitals-shocking-public-and-raising-fears-over-lax?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/b4e754f2-cb13-461f-9420-88d6651b659e_e6b39c42.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A feuding couple in China who had each other committed to psychiatric hospitals after trading accusations of false imprisonment have shocked mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The wife, identified in media reports as Qu Yan, and her husband as Yuan Qiang, are both from Shanxi province in northern China and separately spent short periods in care facilities last year and this year but have since been released, Dingduan News reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“She kept me locked up in a mental health hospital for 80 days,” Yuan told Dingduan News.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuan, who co-owned a company with Qu, claimed that having him committed was part of a deliberate plan by his wife. He said that after they began fighting regularly in 2021, Qu frequently told him he was emotionally unstable and needed psychiatric treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite their disagreements, Yuan said he trusted Qu and went to a number of local hospitals and obtained multiple medical certificates showing he had been diagnosed with clinical depression.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuan said things escalated dramatically on the afternoon of October 10, 2022, when five men grabbed him as he was leaving his office, dragged him into a car and took him to the Xian Mental Health Center, where he was forced into a hospital gown and committed against his will.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“An hour later, I saw my wife in the ward, and I suddenly understood that this was her plan,” Yuan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the following 80 days, Yuan was forced to undergo treatment and was not allowed to see anyone apart from Qu and her friends. At the start of this year, Yuan was released with a medical certificate statinghe was not mentally ill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February, Qu was committed to a psychiatric hospital in a manner similar to Yuan&#39;s experience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuan had convinced the hospital that his wife was mentally ill by showing them videos of his wife smashing things which resulted in her being diagnosed with schizophrenia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three days after Qu was committed, her family tracked her down and subsequently secured her release.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After leaving the hospital, she tried to report the matter to the police, claiming Yuan had her wrongly committed in an act of revenge, but the police said there was insufficient evidence for an investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the local health commission investigated the cases, they discovered that the two mental health hospitals had not breached any legal requirements for diagnosing and committing psychiatric patients.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The news report did not mention if there had been any further legal action since by either Yuan or Qu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story has prompted a discussion about mental health and relationships on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “Oh my God, this is such a scary story.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another asked: “If I was sent to a mental health hospital, how would I prove I don&#39;t have a mental illness?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stories about warring couples regularly trend on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April this year, a man in Shanghai caused outrage in China after criticising his wife for complaining to a restaurant about the poor quality of a noodle dish and filming her during a fight afterwards, which he claimed showed her having an emotional breakdown.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea’s war on ‘killer’ exams leaves students in distress: ‘like I was struck by lightning’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3226160/south-koreas-war-killer-exams-leaves-students-distress-i-was-struck-lightning?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/53985b7b-0460-466f-ae6d-06b5bf641a75_439a4f4e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As South Korea&#39;s leader declares war on “killer” exam questions and after-school cram centres, activists say any education reforms will only be effective if the government manages to alleviate the intense competition teenagers face to get into choice universities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials have in recent weeks cracked down on after-school study sites, or hagwon, and conducted tax raids at major centres where students can stay until almost midnight to review for the all-important university entrance exams.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The moves come after President Yoon Suk-yeol earlier this month lambasted the inclusion of “killer questions” in the notoriously difficult SATs, known as Suneung, telling Education Minister Lee Joo-ho it was “extremely unfair and unjust” that students were tested on challenging topics which were not even covered in the official curriculum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Seeing this, people could believe education authorities and the private tutoring industry are in cahoots,” Yoon said, accusing education authorities and the private education sector of effectively working like “cartels”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why South Koreans are trapped in a lifetime of study&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Following this, the education ministry last week launched an online platform to report irregularities related to private tutoring, including exaggerated commercials made by cram schools, inflated tutoring fees and their allegedly covert association with educators who set SAT questions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a 2021 report by the Seoul Metropolitan Bureau of Education, more than 100 Seoul schools were caught posting false or misleading advertisements and subsequently received official warnings or fines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tax authorities also raided the country&#39;s top three cram schools, including the largest Megastudy, for an unannounced tax investigation as the presidential office warned of legal penalties against any hagwon suspected of tax evasions and other irregularities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Megastudy saw its annual sales jump 19 per cent to 836 billion won (US$635 million) last year, with its operating profits surging 36 per cent to 134 billion won. In 2022, there were some 85,000 hagwons across South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its head Son Ju-eun on Tuesday dismissed allegations that South Korea&#39;s private tutoring industry, public education authorities and SAT-making authorities were “in collusion” to profit from killer questions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Killer questions began appearing in tests in 2008.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That is also when the private tutoring industry flourished only “as a response to changes in the SATs” to include killer questions, Son said on a KBS news talk show.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Son said the country&#39;s private tutoring market – which was worth 22 trillion won (US$16.7 billion) last year, about 1 per cent of the country&#39;s total GDP – would be on a downward spiral soon due to South Korea having the world&#39;s lowest birth rate, falling from around 400,000 in 2016 to 290,000 last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yoon&#39;s attacks against killer questions have unsettled many students and parents because they come just months before November&#39;s crucial annual tests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I felt like I was struck by lightning only five moths before Suneung,” an 18-year-old girl at Hangaram High School in Seoul, who has to sit for the exam in November, told online news outlet MoneyS.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It took me by surprise as I&#39;ve spent thousands of dollars for private tutoring for my kid to prepare him for so-called killer questions,” said a 62-year-old father named Park, whose son is preparing for this year&#39;s test in hopes of making it to medical school.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A private maths tutor, who identified himself as Chang, said that removing killer questions would be a blow to the top 1 per cent of students who were good at solving challenging problems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now, just one mistake in Suneung could push you down from the top level to the third level, and change the entire course of your life, as there would be a lot of students who will receive almost perfect scores,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another father of a student who is sitting for the exam a second time said demand for private tutoring would persist as long as South Korea&#39;s current intensive student evaluations to enter colleges remained the same.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Under these circumstances, it&#39;s ridiculous to believe that tutoring will disappear by removing killer questions,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pro-reform activists said while Yoon&#39;s order was an opportunity for South Korea to make the SAT a fairer test and ease demand for private tutoring, more needed to be done.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Korean woman, 29, &#39;enrolled in US high school because she was lonely&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“In the long term … the country&#39;s education system which comprises highly stratified schools must be corrected as private tutoring feeds on the excessive competition to enter best schools,” said Shin So-young, a policy director at Noworry, a civic movement campaigning for education reform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shin So-young, an activist at civic group The World Without Worry About Private Education, said the planned changes may not be enough to contain the competition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The government needs to come up with a broader plan that addresses the question of how to alleviate this excessive competition to get into a few of the best universities,” Shin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gang Hye-seung, a leader at Chamhakbumo education reform movement, said authorities should focus on “levelling the playing field in educational opportunities rather than scratching the surface” with moves like removing killer questions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no evidence that egalitarian education hampers national development,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly eight in 10 students use private education products such as cram schools, according to a joint report by the education ministry and the government statistics bureau showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This heavy reliance on private education has led to South Korea having the world&#39;s highest cost of raising a child, according to a report last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Government data from 2022 showed households with an average monthly income of 8 million won (US$6,100) or more spent an average of 648,000 won per month for secondary school students to receive an average of 9.4 hours of lessons per week at a hagwon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since a total ban on private tutoring in 1980 under then-military dictator Chun Doo-hwan, South Korea has repeatedly cracked down on private tutoring.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, efforts failed as parents kept finding ways to circumvent laws and regulations, because in this highly competitive society the best schools often means the best chance of a good job and the best prospects of marriage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong technology chief says Google told officials it would only remove protest song under court order, sparking injunction bid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3226219/hong-kong-technology-chief-says-google-told-officials-it-would-only-remove-protest-song-under-court?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.01 14:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/01/d9be7059-18a9-4d5f-9d97-3a240ae988b9_4cb6ca2e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s technology chief has revealed for the first time that a government bid to ban a popular protest song through an injunction was sparked by internet search giant Google&#39;s unwillingness to remove related content without a court order.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Innovation, Technology and Industry Sun Dong on Saturday accused the US-based company of trying to compete with the government to sway opinion on the issue “internationally”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;City authorities are seeking to ban all forms of “Glory to Hong Kong”, regarded as the unofficial anthem of the 2019 anti-government protests. Critics have raised concerns over freedom of expression and if the move would result in Google exiting the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Glory to Hong Kong&#39; protest song to be banned? Government files court injunction&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The proposed ban came after organisers of several overseas sports events had wrongly played the protest tune instead of Chinese national anthem “March of the Volunteers”. Most of the errors stemmed from top search results on Google for “Hong Kong national anthem”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The local government has asked Google to ban the song from appearing in its searches but to no avail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun recalled negotiations with the tech giant, during which officials repeatedly requested for “wrong information” to be removed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without taking our suggestions, Google said: &#39;You must prove that it violates local laws and present a court order,&#39;” Sun told NowTV on Saturday. “Well, since you raised a legal issue, we used legal means to solve the problem. That&#39;s why we applied for an injunction order.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Google&#39;s policies state it will block or take down search results or material related to child sexual abuse, highly personal information and spam, as well as content under valid legal requests for removal from website owners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Saturday, a Post search on Google for “Hong Kong national anthem” found that a Wikipedia page about the protest song ranked third, while the top result was the government&#39;s upgraded webpage which allows internet users to download the right tune.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government&#39;s unprecedented injunction bid against the song would be heard by the High Court on July 21. A window was given to allow anyone who wanted to contest the ban to prepare for litigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the writ, authorities are seeking to prohibit anyone with criminal intent from promoting the song through “broadcasting, performing, printing, publishing, selling, offering for sale, distributing, disseminating, displaying or reproducing in any way”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the proposed ban raised concerns on whether Western tech giants would reduce their presence or even pull out completely from Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong court postpones hearing on government&#39;s bid to ban protest song&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sun, in the interview, also suggested that Google&#39;s refusal to remove the song had reflected its readiness to sway public opinion internationally on the matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We had hoped Google would pin the correct information about the national anthem at the top of search results. We got a strong backlash from Google, who is prepared to compete with us to influence public opinion in the international arena on this issue,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post has reached out to Google for response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kathy Lee, Google Cloud&#39;s managing director for Greater China, previously told the Post that the tech giant&#39;s government relations team worked closely with Hong Kong authorities, and that its cloud computing unit was committed to serving the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun, a scholar in biomedical engineering, is Hong Kong&#39;s first minister to be born and bred in mainland China. He was elected to the Legislative Council in 2021 under Beijing&#39;s “patriots-only” political overhaul before assuming office as bureau chief last July.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 01 Jul 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>