<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping pledges more help to Africa in both industrial and agriculture sectors]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3232237/xi-jinping-pledges-more-help-africa-both-industrial-and-agriculture-sectors?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/858a829d-d545-44f4-8497-4a7f6ac2aff7_c702130c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国将为非洲工业化和农业生产分配更多资源，并培训数千人中国国家主席习近平周四向非洲领导人承诺，将提高非洲学生的职业技能水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在约翰内斯堡金砖国家领导人峰会结束后，习近平会见非洲领导人并出席中非领导人圆桌对话会，他表示，中国将发起一项支持非洲工业化的倡议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国将利用自身资源……支持非洲发展制造业，实现工业化和经济多元化，”习近平表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时习近平没有透露具体资金数额，但表示中国将向工业化项目提供更多援助和投融资资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，习近平表示，中国将帮助非洲国家扩大粮食种植园，鼓励中国企业&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平承诺提供支持之际，乌克兰持续战争加剧了许多非洲国家面临的粮食危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11 月，中国将在中国海南岛举办第二届中非农业合作论坛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为应对部分非洲国家特别是非洲之角国家的粮食危机，中国将增加粮食紧急援助.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平表示，“中国有信心非洲通过自己的努力实现粮食自给自足。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这番言论反映了与过去十年的转变，当时中国投入了数十亿美元通过“一带一路”倡议（BRI）将美元投入港口、铁路、高速公路和水坝等大型项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但批评者也指责中国进口更多原矿，这造成了不健康的贸易对中国有利的不平衡——这解释了为什么津巴布韦、纳米比亚和刚果民主共和国等拥有大量锂矿藏的国家禁止出口电池原材料原材料，而是希望在当地加工这些矿物。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;新金砖国家成员夸耀石油、雄厚的财力和战略位置：分析师&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;不过，农业最近已成为中国与非洲接触的新焦点，北京已承诺从非洲进口更多食品非洲大陆，包括鳄梨、腰果、芝麻和辣椒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，5月份，中国通过国有贸易商中粮集团从南非进口玉米，以实现全球粮食来源多元化。中国90%以上的玉米进口严重依赖美国和乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿史汀生中心中国项目主任孙云早些时候告诉《南华早报》今年，非洲农产品引起了中国的关注，部分原因是“过去对硬基础设施的关注不再可行”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也是北京落实习近平增加非资源进口承诺的更广泛战略的一部分来自非洲。 2021年塞内加尔中非合作论坛期间，习近平承诺为非洲农产品开辟“绿色通道”，加快检验检疫速度，免除更多关税，力争到2025年进口额达到3000亿美元。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;除了允许从非洲进口某些农产品外，北京还对十几个非洲国家的产品降低了98%的关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国还表示支持非洲联盟成为非洲联盟的一部分。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明表示，非洲欢迎中国对非洲工业化、人才发展和农业现代化的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非洲欢迎中国对非洲工业化、人才发展和农业现代化的支持。 p>;&lt;p>;此外，中非合作应注重加强现有全球体制机制，确保发展中国家的参与，从而实现包容性和全球信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“长期合作”联合声明指出，应解决多边金融机构和联合国安理会改革的突出问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周四的会议上，习主席还承诺培养非洲人才，特别是在职业培训方面。中方计划每年为非洲培训500名职业院校校长和教师，为非洲培训1万名兼具汉语和职业技能的技术人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平和莫迪同意优先解决喜马拉雅边境地区局势&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;习近平表示，中方将邀请2万名非洲国家政府官员和技术人员参加研修班和研讨会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共同主持会议的南非总统拉马福萨表示，中国的“一带一路”倡议导致非洲大陆出现新的公路、铁路、港口和能源投资。他表示，基础设施投资促进了创新和生产力，降低了交易成本，并将改善非洲的一体化和互联互通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉马福萨称非洲大陆自由贸易区 (AfCFTA) 是非洲大陆增长的核心；中方承诺为其秘书处的运作提供资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在支持非洲大陆自贸区有效实施的过程中，中非合作应促进投资，促进价值链发展，增强相互生产和消费能力。”拉马福萨说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，对工业化的支持应包括加强对微型、中小型企业和非正规经济的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt; div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Burning questions after Putin calls Wagner’s Prigozhin a ‘man of complicated fate’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3232249/burning-questions-after-putin-calls-wagners-prigozhin-man-complicated-fate?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/8410a0b3-3a72-4f4f-96f4-a4dc2df5d5ea_8df4c720.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;雇佣军军阀叶夫根尼·普里戈津 (Yevgeny Prigozhin) 在飞机失事中被推测死亡是一种激烈的报复俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果是的话，是否会让普京变得更强大 — — 或者加剧两个月前普里戈任流产叛变所暴露的根本弱点？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些问题不仅引起了反响在俄罗斯境内，但在乌克兰这个主权邻国，普京在18个月前发动了全面入侵，在乌克兰努力收复被入侵者夺取的领土时，西方国家纷纷向乌克兰提供援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;周三晚上，莫斯科西北部的俄罗斯村庄库曾希诺附近的居民听到天空中爆炸声，然后看到巴西航空工业公司的喷气式飞机撞上俄罗斯乡村并起火。俄罗斯航空部不久后表示，普里戈任是机上 10 人之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坠机事件发生整整 24 小时后，普京打破了对这一事件的沉默，据官方媒体报道，他向遇难者家属表示哀悼.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在国家塔斯社报道的言论中，他称 62 岁的普里戈任（瓦格纳集团私人军队的负责人）是一个“命运复杂的人”，他“认真对待”普里戈任曾是一名热狗小贩，后来却以残酷的雇佣军领袖而闻名&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在乌克兰入侵期间，普里戈任一直占据着这个角色他经常痛斥俄罗斯军事领导层——但从来没有批评普京本人——因为他说他在发动战争方面无能。这激怒了军方高层，但他的带有脏话的视频长篇大论仍然起到了作用。俄罗斯强硬派因攻势不稳而感到沮丧，这是一种释放阀门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;导致坠机的原因仍然是个谜。周四在华盛顿，五角大楼新闻秘书表示，有关地对空导弹击落普里戈任飞机的报道被认为是不准确的，但他没有详细说明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的初步评估是，普里戈任很可能是美国空军准将帕特·莱德在新闻发布会上说。其他未获授权发表评论且不愿透露姓名的美国官员表示，未经证实的可能性是飞机上装有炸弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任被推定死亡的时间——距他发射飞机的两个月后。企图起义，夺取南部军事总部，并派遣装甲纵队向莫斯科进军，这引起了人们对普京精心策划的阴谋的怀疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些分析人士认为，也许这标志着一个令人讨厌的人物的灭亡，他的用处– 作为一项不可否认的军事资产、国际调解者和亲克里姆林宫的媒体黑魔法大师 – 已经走到了尽头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果普京确实下令杀死普里戈任，那么这一行为的纯粹厚颜无耻可能会阻止那些——新美国安全中心的俄罗斯情报专家安德里亚·肯德尔-泰勒表示，至少在短期内，他们将成为对手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这件事的惊人之处在于，他们不需要使用任何事故掩护或留下任何不确定性，”她说。 “这向其他可能考虑挑战普京的人清楚地表明，等待着他们的命运是什么。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在一个独裁国家，暗杀政治敌人等策略——如果发生了这种情况——一些分析人士表示，这是领导人权力和影响力衰退的长期迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有人知道普京领导下的俄罗斯接下来会发生什么，”伦敦大学学院全球政治副教授布莱恩·克拉斯 (Brian Klaas) ，在他的子堆栈上写道。 “但如果有人认为杀死对手以重新夺回控制权是展示力量而不是示弱，那就是妄想。强大的领导者不需要杀死他们的对手，因为他们反而会激发忠诚。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;瓦格纳老板普里戈津加入了遭受神秘命运的普京敌人名单&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;其他人看到了普京的举动克里姆林宫巩固普京的权威。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在过去两个月里，我们看到克里姆林宫机器开始重新巩固控制权。在我看来，它并没有过多说明弱点或优势。相反，它表明克里姆林宫机器可以重新巩固和重组自己，”欧洲政策分析中心主任阿丽娜·波利亚科娃说。 “最重要的是，他们已经消除了威胁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在乌克兰，总统弗拉基米尔·泽连斯基(Volodymyr Zelensky)对普京进行了几乎不加掩饰的攻击，但没有指责俄罗斯总统是坠机事件的幕后黑手，尽管他否认乌克兰有任何参与。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们没有卷入这种情况，这是肯定的，”泽连斯基与来访的葡萄牙总统一起在基辅举行的新闻发布会上表示。 “我想每个人都知道谁参与其中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;整个普里戈任事件将如何影响瓦格纳这支利润丰厚的私人军队，成为普里戈任商业帝国的核心，还有待观察。但只要看一眼那些据信也在这架致命航班上的人的名字，就可以看出，他们的计划不仅是要斩首瓦格纳集团，还要将其彻底瓦解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乘坐这架飞机的还有德米特里·乌特金 (Dmitry Utkin)，他是俄罗斯军事情报部门前特种部队军官，曾获勋章，是该雇佣军组织的创始人和精神之父。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他对纳粹传说的喜爱促使他选择了呼号“瓦格纳”，这是对理查德·瓦格纳的引用，希特勒最喜欢的作曲家，这个名字最终被整个团体采用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一名乘客是瓦列里·切卡洛夫（Valery Chekalov），据报道他在普里戈任的控股公司 Concord 中担任高级职位，并代表普里戈任拥有一家空壳公司&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登开玩笑普里戈任中毒，称普京“已经输掉”乌克兰战争&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“乌特金负责所有作战训练和作战规划，拥有极高的权威，而契卡洛夫则在除了安全服务外，负责瓦格纳从叙利亚到委内瑞拉的所有后勤和补给路线，”中东研究所和俄罗斯国际事务委员会的非常驻学者安东·马尔达索夫说，他专注于瓦格纳在叙利亚的工作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马尔达索夫补充说，这些人物的死亡使瓦格纳失去了真正的领导者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有他们，瓦格纳的指挥官委员会就不会有效，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有他们，瓦格纳的指挥官委员会就不会有效。” >;&lt;p>;政变未遂后，瓦格纳在乌克兰的存在几乎被取消，但部队仍然继续在非洲活动，甚至加倍加强在非洲大陆的存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任的最后一次出现的视频大概是在本周拍摄的，视频中他似乎身处非洲某个地方，身穿军装，手持突击步枪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在超过 122 度的温度下工作这里;这正是我们喜欢的方式。”他补充道，瓦格纳正在让“俄罗斯在各大洲变得更加强大”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，在俄罗斯支持战争的军事博主群中，普里戈任的明显流失是最令人震惊的。与瓦格纳关系密切的军事博主罗曼·萨蓬科夫（Roman Saponkov）称其为“暗杀”，并表示死亡将带来“灾难性后果”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Telegram 消息应用程序萨蓬科夫宣称，那些“下达命令的人根本不了解军队的情绪和士气”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In South Korea, Japan’s Fukushima water release inflames political tensions, public anger]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3232210/south-korea-japans-fukushima-water-release-inflames-political-tensions-public-anger?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/24/edfcc3d8-3ddd-4c14-b608-d09a436a6e60_27278fbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本周四释放被毁的福岛第一核电站处理过的水，这已成为韩国的最新的国内政治足球，因为对该计划的抵制威胁到邻国之间关系的解冻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统尹锡烈的政府表示，虽然不一定支持东京的计划，但它在科学和技术方面没有问题水释放方面。然而，这一立场只会加剧公众的不安和政治分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国总理韩德洙周四表示，只要受污染的地区“没有必要过度担心”该计划。正如日本所承诺的那样，水按照科学标准和国际程序进行处理和排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国总统的评论是在自由反对党朝鲜民主党 (DPK) 领导人李在明 (Lee Jae-myung) 发表此番言论的第二天进行的。 ，抨击放水是“恐怖行为”，并将其比作第二次太平洋战争的爆发，这将为韩国和太平洋沿岸国家带来“不可逆转的灾难”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩还批评了他称这是一场“政治驱动”的活动，利用“假新闻”煽动恐惧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和韩国的社交媒体帖子包含有关释放的虚假信息，包括篡改畸形鱼的图像，声称它们是与福岛有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，韩似乎与政府的立场相矛盾，他呼吁日本确保放水计划的透明度，并誓言坚持现有的福岛及周边县海鲜禁令。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府敦促日本政府在未来30年持续的排放过程中透明、负责任地披露相关信息，”韩说。 “现在重要的是日本是否会像向国际社会承诺的那样严格遵守科学标准并提供透明的信息。”执政党人民力量党（PPP）代表金基贤也指责道。反对派散布有关放射性水对健康风险的“假新闻”，并煽动公众对日本和尹的不满。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“朝鲜民主主义人民共和国必须立即停止其破坏渔民和人民的反国家活动。”他说：“通过虚假宣传来改善平民生活，以……赢得[明年四月的议会选举]。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比人民党拥有立法多数的朝鲜民主主义人民党周四指责日本“破坏环境”罪行”，并表示正在计划制定新的立法，类似于中国对所有日本海鲜产品实行全面禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国周四将进口禁令扩大到覆盖整个日本，而首相岸田文雄表示东京要求北京“立即取消”禁令，并呼吁“基于科学的讨论”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管政府做出了保证，但周四韩国各地的愤怒情绪仍持续高涨，16 名大学生在试图打破禁令时被捕。进入日本驻首尔大使馆，抗议放水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据当地媒体报道，大约 40 名同学随后在大楼前举行新闻发布会，挥舞横幅并高呼口号，反对放水。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国各地渔民代表周四在首尔召开紧急会议，呼吁当局加强辐射监测，并采取措施帮助促进海鲜消费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“消费由于政治辩论的蔓延和不确定的信息，甚至在受污染的水排放之前，海鲜的产量就已经大幅下降，”他们在一份声明中哀叹道。 “这场危机正在威胁渔业的生存。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继前一天在国民议会外举行烛光抗议吸引了 1,000 多人之后，朝鲜民主主义人民共和国周四在市中心举行了街头游行。参与者。它还呼吁周六举行大规模集会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本表示放水是安全的。国际原子能机构于 7 月批准了该计划，称其符合国际标准，对人类和环境的影响“可以忽略不计”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;批评者指责尹批准福岛放水尽管日本对朝鲜半岛的殖民统治留下了后遗症，而且美国试图拉拢两国对抗中国、俄罗斯和朝鲜，但为了改善双边关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Park Won-gon，首尔梨花大学的一位政治学教授表示，韩国对此次免职事件日益强烈的愤怒正在转化为反对派在明年议会选举前夕的政治资本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这种高度紧张的氛围中，科学没有发挥作用的空间。由于绝大多数韩国人反对释放，反对党不会放过这个在选举前争取支持的机会，”朴告诉《亚洲本周》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，尹政府不太可能屈服于压力并呼吁日本停止排放受污染的水，这会损害其改善与日本关系的努力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社、法新社的补充报道&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan’s semiconductor sector faces offshore production dilemma as island struggles for water, power, people]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3232156/taiwans-semiconductor-sector-faces-offshore-production-dilemma-island-struggles-water-power-people?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/24/c8afb0d1-2ca4-4e38-906f-10998245722d_66a8f9ee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾旗舰店将于 2025 年在美国运营价值 400 亿美元的建筑群半导体制造商可能会帮助其东道主赢得与中国大陆的芯片优势竞赛，但有可能破坏依赖技术的岛国经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;离岸芯片生产可能会削弱台湾在半导体世界的主导地位，除非该行业解决了一个问题分析师称，这将导致国内出现一系列难题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球最大的代工芯片制造商台湾积体电路制造公司 (TSMC) 将在亚利桑那州运营该工厂，同时还计划扩展到日本和德国。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台积电上一财年的营收为 750 亿美元，并拥有自己的不太知名的台湾供应商网络，但如果他们离开，台湾的部分经济可能会受到影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“这个问题的核心是台积电是否有能力继续保持世界半导体制造工艺无可争议的领导者地位，”美台商业委员会倡导小组主席鲁珀特·哈蒙德-钱伯斯(Rupert Hammond-Chambers)表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果尽管如此，台湾的芯片生态系统仍然是世界商业需求的核心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然而，存在一些与公共政策更多相关的挑战。影响新投资的水和土地问题是真实存在的，需要以优先考虑经济需求的方式进行管理。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;芯片行业在 20 世纪 80 年代腾飞后，台湾吸引了包括以下客户在内的客户：苹果和高通供应了全球约 60% 的半导体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但美国总统乔·拜登的目标是通过去年签署成为法律的《芯片与科学法案》来扩大美国半导体产业。该法律针对制造和供应链，重点是研发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月，德国提出了一项 220 亿美元的计划，以改善其半导体制造以及高科技产业的其他要素.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国贸易、工业和能源部也在 7 月表示，已确定半导体“专业综合体”，并考虑放松管制和税收优惠。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不断升级的贸易中美之间的紧张局势以及其他地缘政治问题促使世界各国政府认识到拥有自己的半导体制造设施的重要性，”台北市场研究公司 TrendForce 分析师 Joanne Chiao 表示。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;分析师称，即使台积电及其供应商迁往海外，台湾仍能领先于美国、德国、韩国和中国大陆，但前提是它为国内价值 1500 亿美元的产业提供适当的激励措施。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;过去三年，美国及其盟国（包括日本）对销往中国大陆的芯片制造设备实施限制，加速了北京的科技自给自足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为此，中国企业加大了零部件和设备的开发力度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但台湾芯片制造商几乎没有土地可供扩张，而一系列干旱促使他们寻找新的水源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进口化石燃料的成本，加上潜在的温室效应，进一步困扰该行业，出生率下降可能会削弱劳动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们无法为芯片制造商提供台北专业服务公司普华永道法律部董事总经理 Kent Chong 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2021 年的干旱期间，政府在台积电一家工厂附近实行配水，但没有让该公司和其他公司受到影响。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据台湾新闻媒体 Commonwealth 估计，台积电规模的新台湾工厂将使每日用水量增加 118,000 公吨。据称，这一数字相当于高雄市用水量的 7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于缺乏芯片，中国面临着成为第一大经济体的“前所未有”的压力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;不过，芯片制造商无法做到这一点。增加可再生能源，因为尽管投资了海上风电，但台湾电力供应商主要依赖化石燃料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3月份，出于公共安全考虑，台湾关闭了三座核电站之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;去年，可再生能源占其能源供应的 8.6%，其中 9.1% 来自核电。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈蒙德-钱伯斯补充道，电力获取“仍然受到投资不足的困扰”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“正确的方向”：台湾为关键部门寻求 40 万外国人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2020 年开始的人口下降也有可能限制工程师的数量，任何解决方案都需要“对台湾的技术进行重大改革” Hammond-Chambers 表示，“移民法”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾试图到 2025 年从可再生能源中获取五分之一的能源，为了确保电力供应，台积电在 4 月份表示，已签署了 20,000 吉瓦时的联合采购协议与台北 ARK Solar Energy 的子公司签订合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司表示，预计将有十几家台积电供应商参与。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，台湾水利署表示该机构表示，南部城市高雄的一个工业园区将依靠再生水来“确保稳定供应”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构补充说，台积电高雄工厂在“生产调整”后将需要更多的水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;官营的台湾电力公司去年批准发行 188 亿新台币（5.92 亿美元）的公司债券，通过升级三座发电厂来稳定电力供应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了解决人才短缺问题，台湾官员去年宣布，他们将从海外招募 40 万名人才，其中包括 4 万名专业人士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为台湾政府非常支持整个（集成电路）行业，”台湾微电子创始人刘强东表示。 Kneron 是一家总部位于加利福尼亚州的人工智能芯片设计公司，在台湾拥有 180 名员工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘相信台北可能会提供支持，包括可能的税收优惠。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他国家可能需要一段时间才能实现这一点。乔补充道，与原材料、设备供应商、芯片工厂和最终客户建立半导体“集群”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台湾深耕半导体制造数十年，半导体集群的形成并没有她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乔承认“对人才和劳动力的需求”是最“关键”的问题之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在中国和美国之间，台湾芯片行业可能会陷入困境呆在家里&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;台湾经济部工业发展局拒绝发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，允许台湾芯片行业向海外扩张可能仍然更有意义分析人士表示，考虑到台湾的限制以及地缘政治压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普华永道法律公司的 Chong 表示，如果中国大陆对台湾采取军事行动，芯片技术很容易转移到拥有台湾工厂的其他地区。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大陆将自治的台湾视为一个分裂的领土，必须统一，必要时可以使用武力。过去七年来，两国关系不断恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2 月份以来，美国官员已要求韩国和日本申请削减华盛顿根据《芯片与科学法案》预留的 500 亿美元资金，以支持韩国和日本的发展。振兴其芯片行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了帮助台积电及其在美国的台湾供应商，华盛顿还在讨论一项避免与台北双重征税的协议，此举可能会鼓励投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台积电发言人 8 月中旬表示，“[我们]欢迎就双重征税问题进行积极对话”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台积电去年占据全球非存储芯片市场 30% 的份额，高于去年的 26%胡说：“[税收协议]意味着台湾和美国的经济联系将更加紧密，使资本、投资、生产和人员在两个经济体之间更加自由地流动。”台北国立阳明交通大学商业与管理研究所教授金丽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这当然是在经济上将台湾拉向美国一边的引力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australian political assassin or innocent migrant  community leader? The tale of Phuong Canh Ngo]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3232124/australian-political-assassin-or-innocent-migrant-community-leader-tale-phuong-canh-ngo?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/24/6e740173-1907-4b49-884b-14af3e2de8e2_111fcd7d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;作为一个诞生于流放地的国家，澳大利亚有着悠久的历史人们憎恨罪犯，但最受辱骂的莫过于前越南难民 Phuong Canh Ngo，他拥有该国第一个也是唯一一个被定罪的政治刺客这一令人羡慕的称号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2001 年 6 月，最高法院陪审团发现，恩戈策划了新南威尔士州议员约翰·纽曼的谋杀案。 1994 年 9 月 5 日晚，纽曼在卡布拉马塔 (Cabramatta) 夫妇的家外，在未婚妻露西·王 (Lucy Wang) 面前被枪杀。卡布拉马塔是纽曼选区的郊区，位于悉尼西部费尔菲尔德当地政府区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;卡布拉马塔 (Cabramatta) 是该州最大的移民宿舍的所在地，该宿舍于 1990 年代初被拆除，长期以来一直是各行各业移民的栖息地。但越南战争结束后，船民抵达澳大利亚，再加上 1990 年东南亚国家放宽出境限制后移民人数大幅增加，卡布拉马塔变成了一个繁荣的亚洲社区，绰号“小西贡”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;根据澳大利亚统计局的数据，到 1995 年，该郊区有三分之一的人口是越南人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，约翰街的主干道就像历史悠久的唐人街，有一个巨大的深红色-庆祝自由和民主的彩色中国大门、象征力量的青铜狮子雕像和代表繁荣的小猪雕塑。亚洲杂货店出售来自印度尼西亚的冷冻榴莲和火龙果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这里有黄金商人、旧货店、众多小百货店，以及提供湄公河三角洲以南最好的河粉和越南三明治的越南餐馆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;h3>;为什么前往美国的中国移民冒着途经南美的致命旅程&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但卡布拉马塔的情况并不总是那么美好。摆脱了严格的等级制度（通常会限制他们在国内的叛逆倾向），许多越南出生的青少年发现自己站在了澳大利亚法律的错误一边。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到了 20 世纪 90 年代，卡布拉马塔已成为禁区对于守法的澳大利亚人来说：海洛因被公开出售，吸毒者在街头吸毒过量，臭名昭著的 5T 等亚洲帮派占据统治地位。毒品问题如此严重，以至于警方将悉尼市和卡布拉马塔之间的火车称为“瘾君子快车”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;议员约翰·纽曼（John Newman）毫不犹豫地追究谁的责任。 “涉案的亚洲帮派并不害怕我们的法律，但他们确实担心一件事：可能被驱逐回越南丛林，因为坦率地说，那是他们所属的地方，”他当时告诉澳大利亚广播公司。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Newman held particular disdain for Ngo, who he believed ran illegal gambling, heroin and money-laundering operations at Cabramatta&#39;s Mekong Club, of which Ngo was honorary president and which was often patronised by members of 5T.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nick Kaldas, then-head of the New South Wales homicide squad, who led the investigation into Newman&#39;s murder, concurred.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the morning, Ngo would sit on the board of the Area Health Service , go to council meetings and present a respectable veneer,” he told The Daily Telegraph in 2014, referring to Ngo&#39;s role in local government. “At night, he sat in his headquarters, the Mekong Club, and controlled the 5T gang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When Ngo was arrested and charged, hundreds of people from Cabramatta signed a petition pleading with the judge not to grant him bail, which is an example of the fear he instilled in many. By ridding the Vietnamese community and Cabramatta of Ngo, the area became the colourful piece of multicultural Sydney it is today.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Ngo had never been charged with a crime until after Newman&#39;s death; rather, he was a poster boy for multiculturalism and immigration in Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After arriving penniless in Cabramatta in 1982, he got to work building a business and community power base that earned him de facto leadership of Sydney&#39;s Vietnamese community. He also founded Dan Viet, a popular Vietnamese-language newspaper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1987, Ngo was elected as a municipal councillor representing the people of Cabramatta on the Fairfield City Council. In 1990, he was elected deputy mayor of Fairfield – a remarkable accomplishment for an immigrant who could barely speak English eight years earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet it wasn&#39;t enough for Ngo. He wanted to join the political big league and dreamed of becoming the first Vietnamese-Australian elected to parliament. But one man – Newman – kept standing in his way, defeating him soundly at state elections in 1991 and denouncing him as a crime boss at every given opportunity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police would later allege that Ngo decided to kill his political rival after his loss at the polls and made four botched attempts on Newman&#39;s life until he finally succeeded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t know much about enemies, but I do know that Newman didn&#39;t have many friends,” Ngo told police when they first interviewed him nine days after the murder, adding: “We had differences. I must stress I never liked the man.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With Newman&#39;s distraught fiancée unable to recall the face of the shooter or any details about the getaway car, Ngo was allowed to go about his business. Within six months of Newman&#39;s death, he had assumed the presidency of the Cabramatta State Electoral Council of the Australian Labor Party – Newman&#39;s political party – and was No 1 on the ticket and chief fundraiser for the party in the Fairfield council elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And so it appeared Ngo had got away with orchestrating an assassination – until initially reluctant witnesses began to cooperate with police, giving them the evidence they needed to charge him with first-degree murder in 1998.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After three years on remand and three trials – the first was aborted and the second ended with a hung jury – Ngo was found guilty of orchestrating Newman&#39;s murder.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a result of New South Wales&#39; Byzantine mandatory sentencing regime and the gravity of his crime – described by presiding judge John Dunford as an “attack on democracy” motivated by “naked political ambition” – Ngo was sentenced to life behind bars without the possibility of parole.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Case closed?不完全的。 Ngo has always maintained his innocence, and to this day the shooter and driver remain at large.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;David Dinh, a Vietnamese man who worked at the Mekong Club and who police accused of pulling the trigger, and Quang Dao, the alleged driver of the getaway car, were both acquitted during the third and final trial and remain adamant that Ngo could not have been involved in the crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I know for sure that Phuong is not involved in that murder,” Dao said, claiming he used the alleged getaway car – a white Toyota Camry – to pick up his children at the time of the shooting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a 2008 documentary feature by the Australian Broadcasting Corporation&#39;s Four Corners news programme that raised serious doubts about the validity of Ngo&#39;s conviction, Dao described how police offered to drop the charges laid against him and grant him clemency if he changed his story and gave evidence against Ngo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They said if I cooperate they would put me in [the] witness protection programme, not only me but my whole extended family, and I refused that,” said Dao.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cooperate. What did they want you to do?” Four Corners asked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cooperate means like saying what they want to say, which is saying Tony and Phuong were guilty of the charge that they made up about them,” said Dao, referring to a third co-accused who worked at the Mekong Club and later turned state witness against Ngo, and whose real name was suppressed by a court order.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I told them we have no deal. I don&#39;t agree to do that.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The story of how Tony changed his evidence and had his murder charge dropped is extraordinary,” Four Corners reported, saying he only changed his mind after his teary-eyed mother visited him in prison.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Dear Quang,” Tony said in a tape recording played to Dao and later obtained by Four Corners in which he tried to explain why he became a police snitch, “I suppose you will be surprised when you hear my voice in this tape. Perhaps you will be very angry but please listen to what I have to say to you.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Let me explain. Mum was crying, and she said, &#39;Tony, if you still love your mother, you have to listen to the advice&#39;. I told my mother, &#39;Mum, I cannot do it, because if I did, I will jeopardise other peoples&#39; lives, especially Quang and his family. My conscience doesn&#39;t allow me to do that.&#39;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My mother said, &#39;If you don&#39;t listen to me, I will take my life&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dao says Tony was forced “to choose between his mum, the person who raised him, and two others, who were just acquaintances. And knowing the pressure his mum was under after he heard [her] threatening to kill herself if he didn&#39;t do what the Crime Commission wants, I feel more sorrow for him than anger”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Dinh, who spent two years in prison before he was acquitted, was less forgiving. “How can someone sit there, and you work with and see day in and day out, make up all these bullc**p stories,” he told Four Corners, fighting back tears.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the Four Corners investigation was aired on national television, the New South Wales government commissioned a multimillion-dollar inquiry into Ngo&#39;s conviction, headed by retired judge David Patten. But it didn&#39;t go Ngo&#39;s way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Crown in a criminal trial has very few opportunities to &#39;choose&#39; its witnesses. So it was in this case that it became obliged to call witnesses who had themselves engaged in criminal activity,” Patten wrote in his 210-page report, adding: “It was likely that the honesty and reliability of such witnesses would be severely tested in cross-examination and indeed it was.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Patte n also highlighted the fact that Ngo chose not to testify at his third and final trial after his lawyers advised him on “the risk of exposing himself to cross-examination”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Patten discounted questions raised by Four Corners that suggested police may have planted the murder weapon: a rare .32 Beretta police divers uncovered in the nearby Georges River four years after Newman&#39;s death – and only 20 minutes after the search began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Beretta was so corroded that ballistics experts were unable to conclude that it was the actual murder weapon and prosecutors had to rely on an expert in Germany to testify against Ngo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police had alleged that Ngo dumped the murder weapon in the Georges River half an hour after Newman&#39;s murder – a conclusion they reached after triangulating Ngo&#39;s mobile phone record, the first time this investigative technique was used in Australia. But Four Corners obtained new research that showed “grey areas” near mobile phone towers that cast doubt about Ngo&#39;s whereabouts after the murder.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China needs to step up its fight to contain growing mpox outbreak&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ngo&#39;s lawyer later argued in court that “the idea that Mr Ngo would arrange contract killers to kill Mr Newman and then take an active role in the disposal of the murder weapon is such an unlikely proposition that I can scarcely believe the prosecution had the audacity to run it”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pat t en also shot down this argument, saying that irrespective of the phone records and use of triangulation technology, “Mr Ngo&#39;s supporters had sought to create a major issue out of what seems to be a relatively minor feature of the case” given that Ngo had admitted to being in the vicinity of the Georges River after Newman was killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Patten concluded he found nothing that “casts doubt upon or raises a sense of unease in respect to the conviction of Mr Ngo” or suggested the police investigation into Newman&#39;s murder was not conducted “thoroughly or competently by police officers dedicated to the task”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Homicide squad chief Kaldas commended the inquiry for its findings. “Police are of the firm view that this was one of the most compelling briefs of evidence to go before a jury and they have no doubt whatsoever that the jury reached a correct verdict of guilt against Phuong Canh Ngo,” he said, describing the case as “one of the most scrutinised investigations in the state&#39;s history”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Leslie Smith, a retired applied scientist mentioned in Patten&#39;s report as one of Ngo&#39;s most steadfast supporters, believes the retired judge&#39;s findings were incomplete since he failed to take into account key discrepancies in the trials. And there is good reason to listen to him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1982, a woman named Lindy Chamberlain was found guilty of murder after her nine-week-old baby, Azaria, disappeared during a camping trip in the Australian outback.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chamberlain claimed Azaria had been taken by a dingo (an Australian wild dog) while sleeping in a tent but a jury found her mother guilty of murder after a stain found on the dashboard of her car was identified by a forensic pathologist as blood containing haemoglobin that is present only in infants less than six months of age.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then Smith stepped in, drawing on his decades of experience to establish that the stain was, in fact, a “sound deadener” accidentally sprayed on the inside of the car during the manufacturing process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coupled with the discovery of Azaria&#39;s jacket near a dingo den, Smith&#39;s observation gave Chamberlain&#39;s lawyers the evidence they needed to reopen the case and prove their client&#39;s innocence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A decade after Chamberlain was exonerated, Smith was asked by a friend to look into Ngo&#39;s case, and what began as a passing interest turned into an obsession that consumed thousands of hours of the scientist&#39;s time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have combed through all the court transcripts, the committal hearings, inquests and inquiries and I sat through the third trial,” he says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I also visited Phuong in prison twice. It gave me an understanding of the case I think few other people have. I became particularly concerned about some discrepancies in the evidence used by the prosecution, especially sudden switches in context.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One element Smith finds particularly troubling is the evidence of two witnesses whose identities have been suppressed by a court order and who we will name Witness 1 and Witness 2.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the committal hearing before the first trial – a court date where prosecutors present evidence to the magistrate – a police running sheet presented by the prosecution claimed Ngo gave Witness 1 a photograph of Newman, and asked Witness 1 to find someone to do “nasty stuff” to the politician.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some time later, Witness 1, who it was claimed worked at a Vung Tau fish shop behind the Mekong Club at the time, offered the job to Witness 2 as he was delivering detergent to the shop. Witness 2 subsequently turned down the offer but Ngo&#39;s intent was clear, the Crown alleged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The problem,” Smith says, “is that the Vung Tau fish shop didn&#39;t open until nine months after Newman was shot, and police knew that. We have two witnesses who gave evidence about a conspiracy to commit to murder at a place that didn&#39;t exist, so it appears the conversation was fabricated.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;They called it &#39;Humiliation Day&#39;: the Canadian law that split Chinese families&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“What was the source of this coincidental evidence? I have come to the view that police acted as a conduit while these witnesses fabricated this evidence and the reason they did that was that police leaned on them because both these witnesses were dealing drugs and were offered a deal to testify against Ngo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If there was a pattern of misconduct that runs through all three trials, where police placed witnesses under surveillance, identified weaknesses and made offers of clemency in exchange for accounts of the Crown&#39;s hypothesis of how and why Newman was murdered, then the entire process was fraudulent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Smith says he attempted to present this information to the inquiry into Ngo&#39;s conviction but found there was no interest in anything he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you read the findings of the inquiry,” he says, “you will see Judge Patten did not call these two witnesses who would have been most able to assist him. He declined to hear them and it is very clear to me why: the authorities would prefer if Ngo stays in prison and this case goes away.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A retired journalist who covered the crime beat for the Fairfield Champion and other local newspapers in western Sydney for nearly a decade, Carlotta McIntosh attended all three of Ngo&#39;s trials. And she clearly remembers the moment when the conversation between Witness 1 and Witness 2 was first presented during a pre-trial hearing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The police said they had an incriminating conversation from April 1994, about five months before the murder, where [Witness 1 and Witness 2] discussed killing Newman and allegedly [Witness 1] was asked to do so by Ngo,” she says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Phuong was in the prison box and whispered to his lawyer that the fish shop did not open until the following year. His lawyer subsequently raised the point. The prosecutor still used that evidence at the first trial but by then the conversation no longer took place at the fish shop but at a different address.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McIntosh, who is currently writing a book about Ngo&#39;s conviction and how she “came to believe there was something wrong” with the trials, says that “the narrative about Newman being a crime fighter and upstanding member of the community and which painted Phuong as an evil crime boss was very simplistic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I met Phuong many times before the shooting. He was charming, very smart, a fast learner, very good at languages, a political animal. He didn&#39;t need to kill to get what he wanted. He negotiated, bargained and struck deals across party lines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Claims that he was some kind of drug lord or head of the 5T gang in Cabramatta were absolute nonsense. I covered the courts for years and there was never a scintilla of evidence that he was involved in crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Newman,” McIntosh continues, “was a different kind of person. He was tyrannical, a bully, both verbally and physically, an intimidating man and he terrorised his staff. The only thing that really seemed to bother him was the growing number of Vietnamese living in his area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Bob Carr, who was then leader of the Labor Party in New South Wales, was very worried about the bad publicity Newman was causing and wanted to replace him at the next election.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The accepted narrative, she says, led to Ngo&#39;s alleged motive and the harshness of his sentence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When Phuong was sentenced the judge talked about an assault on democracy, and that was what put him in the worst category of criminals. But it is simply not true because everyone close to Phuong knew he had given up on becoming a member of the lower house [of parliament where Newman held a seat] and wanted a seat in the upper house instead.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A police running sheet detailing a conversation between Ngo and the then New South Wales Labor Party general secretary, John Della Bosca, at a restaurant in Sydney&#39;s Chinatown on the day of Newman&#39;s murder appears to substantiate McIntosh&#39;s opinion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Newman was mentioned during lunch,” the running sheet reads. “Della Bosca suggested that Ngo run against Newman in the next election. Ngo said words to the effect of &#39;No, I&#39;ve given my word to Newman that I won&#39;t run for the legislative assembly as member for Cabramatta, [he] would not oppose Newman in pre-selection&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McIntosh says the meeting and numerous other pieces of evidence that are on the public record “completely destroy” Ngo&#39;s apparent motive for the crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If I was on the jury, I would not have found him guilty beyond a reasonable doubt,” she says. “Sure, there was loads of evidence against him but that doesn&#39;t mean the evidence was correct. Most of it came from the Crime Commission, which journalists can&#39;t report on. It&#39;s all shrouded in secrecy, like an inquisition.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Questions about Ngo&#39;s apparent motive are central to a campaign by a small but determined number of supporters urging the attorney general of New South Wales to launch an inquiry into Ngo&#39;s sentencing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;She faced racism, sexism on her rise to CEO. Now she gives others a leg-up&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“As Australians, we claim the moral high ground about our record on human rights. Yet when it comes to sentencing laws, New South Wales is now seriously out of step with the international community and its human rights initiatives,” wrote John Anderson, Felicity Wardhaugh and Daniel Matas, lecturers in law at the University of Newcastle Legal Centre, in an opinion piece published by The Sydney Morning Herald in 2013.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When the New South Wales Supreme Court sentences an offender to life without parole or the possibility of review, then arguably there has been a breach of Article 7 of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights,” the trio wrote. “No penal system is to be purely retributory in nature.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The view that it&#39;s time for New South Wales to abolish mandatory sentences, trust in the wisdom and experience of its judges and honour Australia&#39;s commitments to progressive human rights is shared by many of the state&#39;s most eminent legal minds, including retired High Court judge Michael Kirby and Nicholas Cowdery, a former director of public prosecutions for New South Wales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his 2019 biography, Frank and Fearless, Cowdery wrote that, “Mandatory sentencing laws stop judges and magistrates from doing an important part of their job – making the punishment fit the crime and the criminal and achieving justice”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even Dunford, Ngo&#39;s sentencing judge, who died in 2003, believed Ngo&#39;s case deserved future review: “This is not a case where I believe he necessarily needs to be kept in custody for the whole of that time, and if I had the power to do so, I would fix a non-parole period,” Dunford wrote in his sentencing remarks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that during Ngo&#39;s three years on remand, when the trials were taking place, Ngo had been a “model prisoner” who had “assisted young prisoners” and set up the Fairfield Drug Intervention Centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year marks the 25th anniversary of Ngo&#39;s incarceration, meaning he has already served a life sentence, including a 13-year stint at the Goulburn “supermax” Correctional Centre, the toughest prison in the country, after prison officials linked him to a gang called W2K, or Willing to Kill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has not had any opportunity to make his case for release since 2014, when he lost a final bid to appeal his life sentence in the High Court. Ngo is now 64.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The public still believes the myth that Phuong was a crime boss so it doesn&#39;t look good for him,” says McIntosh. “He has exhausted all avenues for appeal so unless Leslie [Smith] comes across a convincing piece of evidence like he did with Lindy Chamberlain, by the time Phuong dies he will have spent two life sentences in jail. Even if he is guilty, does he deserve that?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The office of the Attorney General of New South Wales Michael Daley did not respond to inquiries about the campaign to review Ngo&#39;s life sentence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Corrective Services New South Wales refused to facilitate an interview with Ngo “for a range of reasons, including limiting opportunities to re-traumatise victims and their families”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Newman&#39;s family would likely agree. “Phuong Ngo wanted the upper house,” Newman&#39;s half-brother, Peter Naumenko, told a media pack after the verdict was announced in 2001, “Now he&#39;s got the upper bunk. I hope he enjoys it.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia joins Singapore, China, Japan in tackling woes of an ageing population]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3232200/australia-joins-singapore-china-japan-tackling-woes-ageing-population?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/f3aead6c-c371-4fa9-bf49-0b0d2dc2e3b4_29e1c81f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;About one in four Australians will be older than 65 years old within the next four decades, up from one in six as of 2022-23, as Canberra joins the many governments in the Asia-Pacific facing an ageing problem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A new “intergenerational report” that forecasts outcomes in Australian society released on Thursday shows that not only is the number of older Australians rising, the country&#39;s population growth will slow to 1.1 per cent annually in the next 40 years, from 1.4 per cent in the last 40 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The double whammy of an ageing and slowing population is endemic of many countries in the region such as Singapore, Japan and China, where fertility rates have fallen and people are living longer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ageing population will place pressure on Australia&#39;s financial resources, with the report forecasting that around 40 per cent of the projected increase in government spending in the next four decades will be driven by Australians getting older.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Changes to the age structure and the old-age dependency ratio have economic and fiscal implications for Australia. For example, there was higher demand for education when the baby boomer generation was young, while demand for health and aged care services increases as more people age past 65,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The intergenerational report says Australia must plan for an older population, including reducing barriers to labour force participation for older people and for “women and historically under-represented groups” who may wish to work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Employers can make themselves more attractive to older workers by being more flexible about when and where they work, and by training older workers, the report adds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Separately, the report indicates Australia&#39;s labour productivity – output per unit of labour – has continued to fall and is now at 1.2 per cent versus 1.5 per cent in the last intergenerational report in 2021. If productivity was higher at 1.5 per cent, real GDP would also have been about 9.5 per cent higher in 2062-63.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A strategic migration plan can offset an ageing population, but it does not resolve ageing, as migrants also age, the report cautions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In releasing the report, Australian Treasurer Jim Chalmers ruled out another round of baby bonus, saying the “policy levers” were different now and there were policies that encourage women to have children such as parental leave and cheaper childhood education. In the early 2000s, Australia offered a baby bonus of up to A$5,000 (US$3,200) for every baby born.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Social egg freezing: can it help boost Singapore&#39;s flagging birth rate?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;These problems are shared by many countries in the region, which are “ageing rapidly”, according to a report by the United Nations Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP) late last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ESCAP said the number of people aged 60 years or older would rise to 1.3 billion by 2050, or one in four people, as compared with one in seven in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Due to a large population of the world living in the region, the Asia-Pacific is ageing more than the rest of the world, ESCAP said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The share of older people in populations in Hong Kong, mainland China, South Korea and Singapore would exceed 40 per cent by 2050, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the weekend, Singapore Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong addressed the city state&#39;s rapidly ageing issue during a key annual policy speech.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One in four Singaporeans would be older than age 65 by 2030, according to Lee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today, we are an aged society. Soon, we will be a &#39;super-aged&#39; society. This has massive social and economic implications. We have much to do to help our seniors age well,” he said on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Active ageing” will become more important, said Lee, pointing to new Active Ageing Centres where seniors could join activities and meet friends.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore&#39;s single women &#39;not supported&#39; even as egg-freezing rules are eased&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Hong Kong, the ageing problem is becoming chronic as it faces a shortage of elderly homes by 2032.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong will become the world&#39;s oldest society by 2050, with its population also ageing rapidly. By 2050, 40.6 per cent of its population will be aged 65 and older, according to the United Nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, whose economic engine is fuelled by its 1.4 billion population, is also suffering an ageing crisis where the number of citizens aged over 60 will grow by an average of 10 million per year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, China&#39;s population declined for the first time in six decades, with the national birth rate for 2022 falling to a record low.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Zombie takedown’: China taekwondo team banned for ‘blasphemous’ ghoul dance in Qing dynasty costumes at world contest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3231905/zombie-takedown-china-taekwondo-team-banned-blasphemous-ghoul-dance-qing-dynasty-costumes-world?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/bb46fd29-b97d-4446-84df-5f848f84a269_17264055.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A taekwondo martial arts team from China has been punished and the licence of its coach has been revoked after it performed a “Zombie dance” wearing Qing dynasty costumes at an international competition in South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The offending dance was performed by members of a taekwondo studio from southern China&#39;s Guangdong province at the 2023 Seongnam World Taekwondo Hanmadang in South Korea on July 24.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Online footage shows seven members of the studio performing taekwondo techniques wearing Qing dynasty (1636-1912) officials&#39; uniforms while performing actions typical of zombies in classic Hong Kong horror films.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On August 21, the Chinese Taekwondo Association issued a formal denunciation of the performance saying that it “smeared the image of the nation and blasphemed Chinese culture”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The association cancelled the studio&#39;s membership and banned it from participating in national taekwondo contests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also revoked the licence of the team&#39;s coach, Liu Hao, who choreographed the dance, prohibiting him from participating in training and competitions held by the association.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, opinion was divided on mainland social media about the punishment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think the performance respected neither taekwondo nor China,” one person said on Douyin, the mainland&#39;s version of TikTok.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Has the association overreacted here? It was just a non-governmental group having some fun. Why be so sensitive,” said another online observer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think it is creative. I also enjoyed watching Hong Kong zombie films when I was little. There is no need to make a fuss as long as we are confident in our culture,” commented a third person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another online observer supported the punishment and said the performance fuelled stereotypes pushed by Western countries that depict Chinese people as “old fogeys in robes with long braids”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While a number of videos of the full performance were removed online, several media outlets quoted coach Liu as saying the performance ended with the seven “zombies” “taking off their robes and receiving the world&#39;s recognition of their brand-new image”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The classic Qing Dynasty zombie image first appeared in the 1985 Hong Kong horror film Mr Vampire, directed by Ricky Lau Kwan-wai, which starred Lam Ching-ying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deviating from zombies in Western films, who usually move in a freestyle fashion, in Mr Vampire they used stiff body movements that lay the foundation for 1980s and 1990s Hong Kong zombie productions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is believed that Mr Vampire&#39;s zombie image was derived from the Qing dynasty shamanistic practice of ganshi, or driving corpses, which prevailed in the Western region of today&#39;s Hunan province in southern China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Performers of the practice travelled thousands of miles with the bodies of people who died unwillingly, such as from the death penalty, to their hometown to be buried.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to transport more than one body, ganshi practitioners attached the bodies&#39; arms to bamboo poles, so it looked like the corpses were hopping with their arms stretched out.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Quantum mechanics: the yin and yang of photon entanglement]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3232205/quantum-mechanics-yin-and-yang-photon-entanglement?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/8b0c95e9-80ea-4803-b09c-408e6fd37aed_bab08217.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A new real-time way of visualising entangled photons – the basic particles of light – has revealed a yin-yang-like image.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The technique, known as biphoton digital holography, visualised the “wave function” of the photons and was detailed in a paper published in the journal Nature Photonics last week by a team of researchers from the University of Ottawa and Sapienza University in Rome.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The work comes four years after the capture of the first photo of quantum entanglement by physicists at the University of Glasgow in Scotland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In that image the entanglement looked like a broken doughnut.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The yin-yang symbol represents opposite but connected forces and is known in China as “taijitu”, a concept that dates back to the Song dynasty (960–1279).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s not the first image of quantum entanglement but this is eye-attracting research,” said Yin Zhangqi, a professor at the Beijing Institute of Technology&#39;s school of physics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the taijitu pattern in this paper could not be “taken for granted”, saying the resulting image could have something to do with the light beam used by the researchers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yin said that taijitu had appeared in the quantum world before. In a paper published in a top physical academic journal in May, a group of Chinese scientists generated a figure that was quite similar to the yin-yang shape, using a different method, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Quantum entanglement underpins the strange science of quantum mechanics and has huge practical implications for areas such as computing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Researchers have harnessed its power for quantum cryptography, technology that uses the laws of physics to prevent eavesdropping. It also has the potential to advance other quantum technologies such as quantum imaging.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Quantum entanglement occurs when two particles become inextricably linked, and whatever happens to one immediately affects the other, regardless of how far apart they are.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has been likened to a pair of shoes – the moment one shoe is identified, the nature of the other, whether it is the left or right shoe, is immediately known.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In quantum mechanics, knowing a particle&#39;s wave function opens the door to understanding the particle&#39;s quantum state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just like the shoe&#39;s “wave function” carries information like size, colour, left or right; similarly, in quantum physics, the wave function enables scientists to predict the probable outcomes of various properties of a quantum entity, such as position and velocity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But pinning down the function of a quantum system, a process called quantum tomography, is challenging and only increases in difficulty as the system becomes more complex.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese scientists use quantum computing to simulate black hole&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Previous experiments conducted with the standard approach measuring the “high-dimensional” quantum state of two entangled photons could take hours or even days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this latest study, the researchers developed a quantum tomography technique called biphoton digital holography. They superimposed the entangled photons with a known quantum state, and then analysed the spatial distribution of the positions where two photons arrive simultaneously to capture a “coincidence image”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This study made a great contribution to quantum state tomography,” said Wang Jindong, a professor at South China Normal University in Guangdong province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said that knowing the characteristics of the wave function was essential to apply quantum physics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mainstream method, however, was time-consuming and not very scalable, but this team was delivering a new approach that might go some way to overcoming these limitations, he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Unsung heroes are showcasing Hong Kong’s compassion and culture on world stage]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3232111/unsung-heroes-are-showcasing-hong-kongs-compassion-and-culture-world-stage?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/8a893cdf-e91d-4135-a1d2-80f976250a1a_6283548e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong has many unsung heroes who make a significant social impact at home and abroad.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some play a critical role in supporting those most in need, ranging from poverty alleviation to humanitarian relief for victims of natural disasters or conflict, fulfilling a crucial role within the global community. Others use the soft power of the arts, culture and sports to engage with audiences, forge friendships and break down unconscious bias or anti-Asian sentiment, which is reportedly escalating in many Western countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These people often unofficially carry the mantle of goodwill ambassador and, through their work, promote and showcase some of the most positive qualities and achievements of Hong Kong, reflecting our caring society and rich cultural heritage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many of these organisations or individuals rely on support from the government and the generosity of donors or benefactors to underpin their operational expenses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thankfully Hongkongers are famously generous, with a compassionate inclination and a genuine desire to support those in need or make a positive social contribution, an enduring legacy handed down from generation to generation. In the World Giving Index 2022, produced by the Charities Aid Foundation, Hong Kong was ranked in 32nd place out of 119 countries for donations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong Jockey Club has supported community programmes for over a century. In 2021-22, the Hong Kong Jockey Club Charities Trust approved HK$6.6 billion and supported 292 charity and community projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How Gen Z is redefining the possibilities of generosity&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Next month it is launching the Philanthropy For Better Cities Forum, which it describes as “a platform for philanthropists, thought leaders, social entrepreneurs, policymakers, academia and NGOs from around the world to exchange views”. The concept is simple – countries and their people need to work together to solve global problems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the equine world, the CEO of The Hong Kong Jockey Club, Winfried Engelbrecht-Bresges, is also chairman of the International Federation of Horseracing Authorities, the premier thoroughbred racing authority in the world, as well of the Asian Racing Federation, comprising 28 national racing authorities and organisations covering Asia, Africa, the Middle East and Oceania.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hardship can often create heroes, and one example that many of us are familiar with is the Crossroads Foundation, which was started over 25 years ago. Sixty per cent of its donations support people in need in Hong Kong, and the remaining is distributed across 90 countries worldwide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To establish greater donor engagement and define new levels of understanding of the plight of many people affected by a disaster, Crossroads developed and curated simulated experiences on war, HIV/Aids, blindness, water shortage, hunger, poverty and more.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So significant was the impact that the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland, invited the group to share its experience programmes, engaging with some of the world&#39;s most high-profile business and government leaders. The foundation also assisted the United Nations in developing a bespoke service to match companies that want to help charities. This a powerful example of a local not-for-profit organisation making an impact on the global stage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Suhanya Raffel, museum director of M+, has been appointed president of the International Committee for Museums and Collections of Modern Art, a global network of modern and contemporary art museum experts from 86 countries. Once again, this is a valuable global platform from which to promote the culture and heritage of Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oxfam Hong Kong is another international success. It has collaborated with millions of economically disadvantaged people across more than 70 countries worldwide to combat poverty. The Oxfam Trailwalker is its signature fundraiser event, a 100km hike that has expanded from its beginnings in Hong Kong to cities around the world, raising awareness about poverty and injustice. By 2019, the Oxfam Trailwalker had expanded from its beginnings in Hong Kong to 13 events across eight other countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s Asian Youth Orchestra is beautiful example of collaboration and engagement, with an ensemble of over 100 musicians selected each year from across Asia. Among the finest youth orchestras in the world, it has just completed an intensive European and Asian tour covering five countries, 11 cities and 14 concerts. For almost 35 years, they have inspired young musicians and enthralled audiences everywhere they tour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In these uncertain economic times, public and private sector players must continue to provide their full support to the charities, NGOs or people selflessly supporting those in need, raising the profile and promoting our culture on the international stage as a caring, compassionate society.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan opposition KMT’s presidential candidate Hou Yu-ih slated for US visit in September]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3232231/taiwan-opposition-kmts-presidential-candidate-hou-yu-ih-slated-us-visit-september?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 07:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/25/a2fa9055-dcf0-4f0f-b28e-64bf84afd64c_423a96c9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The presidential candidate for Taiwan&#39;s main opposition party will visit Washington next month and meet members of Congress, think tank experts and the head of the de facto US embassy in Taipei, his campaign office said on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The eight-day trip by Hou Yu-ih, candidate for the Kuomintang, begins on September 14 and takes him to New York and San Francisco in addition to the US capital in advance of the island&#39;s politically sensitive election in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hou&#39;s visit aimed to lay the groundwork for “deeper relations” and promote ongoing “substantive exchanges” between Taiwan and the US, his campaign office said, according to Taiwanese news service CNA.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment on the visit. But in the past it has condemned trips by Taiwanese officials and semi-official representatives as dangerous separatism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is customary for Taiwanese candidates to meet US officials and members of Congress before a presidential election. Such outreach is meant to help Americans understand their policies and can burnish candidates&#39; overseas credentials with voters back home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, Taiwanese Vice-President William Lai Ching-te, the ruling Democratic Progressive Party&#39;s candidate, made two US stopovers to and from Paraguay.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the visit, Beijing slammed Lai as a “troublemaker”, accused Washington of using the island to contain China and launched military drills around Taiwan in a &#39;severe warning to separatist forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A poll released this week by the DPP-leaning Taiwan Public Opinion Foundation showed Lai held a 43.4 per cent favourable rating, compared with 13.6 per cent for Hou and 26.6 per cent for Ko Wen-je, who heads the smaller Taiwan People&#39;s Party. Other polls have shown smaller gaps between the candidates, with Lai continuing to lead.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan arms boosted as US approves US$500 million in F-16 sensors&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Industrialist Terry Gou, who is himself reportedly considering a presidential bid, recently suggested that the two opposition candidates Hou and Ko might need to join forces if they wanted to defeat the DPP.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ko visited the US in April, before announcing his candidacy, and said in July he was considering a second visit as a presidential candidate before the election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing favours the mainland-leaning KMT over independence-minded DPP. Hou, the mayor of New Taipei, was officially nominated by the KMT in July after spending some three decades in the police force, rising from a patrolman to become head of the National Police Agency in 2006.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hou&#39;s campaign did not immediately furnish the names of those he planned to meet in the US, other than Laura Rosenberger, chairwoman of the American Institute in Taiwan, a non-governmental organisation that effectively functions as the US embassy in Taipei. Nor did it state whether he would meet US government officials, saying the details of the visit were still being worked out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a 2015 visit to the US, leading KMT candidate Eric Chu and then DPP candidate and now president Tsai Ing-wen met Antony Blinken, then deputy secretary of state, ahead of Taiwan&#39;s 2016 election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“US officials and experts will be keen to hear Hou You-yi&#39;s approach to relations with the US and China if he is elected president, as well as his plan for strengthening Taiwan&#39;s defence and security,” said Bonnie Glaser of the German Marshall Fund of the United States, a public policy think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hou, who is generally regarded as less well-known in the US than Lai, is expected to assert his commitment to Taiwan&#39;s democracy and its values, his campaign office said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The election will be closely watched as tensions hover at record-high levels in the Taiwan Strait. Beijing last August launched military exercises around the island that were unprecedented in scale in response to then-House speaker Nancy Pelosi&#39;s visit.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why Taiwan&#39;s KMT will back Hou You-ih for president against all odds&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing sees the island as a breakaway province to be reunited with the mainland, by force if necessary. Washington does not have official diplomatic relations with the island and opposes any unilateral changes to the status quo by either side.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Washington&#39;s policy is to support Taiwan&#39;s military defence capability as well as its expanded presence in global health, crime prevention and aviation – objectives Beijing opposes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai&#39;s recent US stopovers in New York and San Francisco were intentionally low-key, involving no publicly disclosed meetings with senior US officials or members of Congress, analysts said, as he sought to counter his reputation for being provocative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It remained unclear how much support Hou would find in Washington for his cross-strait policy espousing closer ties with Beijing at a time when US-China relations have plumbed new lows. Lai told Bloomberg earlier this month that there was no need for him to declare Taiwan independent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July, Hou said he endorsed the 1992 consensus, a tacit agreement that there is only “one China”, but the two sides may disagree on what that refers to.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Former US president Donald Trump surrenders at Georgia jail in criminal case, posts US$200,000 bond]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3232232/former-us-president-donald-trump-surrenders-georgia-jail-criminal-case-posts-us200000-bond?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 07:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/25/737c08a0-30a9-47ec-a0cb-4107aacc3ebd_6e14f92e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Former US president and 2024 White House contender Donald Trump surrendered at a Georgia jail on Thursday, his every public move recorded by scores of cameras, adding to his record of unprecedented firsts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His long-awaited surrender on criminal charges at Atlanta&#39;s Fulton County Jail at 7:30 pm, apparently timed for prime-time TV ratings, was unparalleled for an American president, as was the US$200,000 bond he posted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump faces 13 counts stemming from his alleged effort to overturn Georgia&#39;s 2020 election results. The ex-president, who now faces a total of 91 charges across four criminal cases, has denied any wrongdoing and claimed repeatedly that he is the victim of a biased political crusade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The president should never have been indicted,” said Steven Sadow, his lead attorney, speaking before Trump&#39;s appearance. “He is innocent of all the charges.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this latest case, the most wide-ranging and ambitious of the four, Fulton County District Attorney Fani Willis charged Trump, 77, and 18 other defendants with racketeering, a charge often associated with organised crime prosecutions, along with various other counts. Several of his fellow defendants surrendered on Wednesday ahead of the Friday noon deadline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump was expected to have his mugshot taken, another presidential first. Unlike the other cases, he will not be formally arraigned – an initial hearing when charges are read out and the defendant pleads guilty or not guilty – until next month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But his bail terms stipulate that he cannot intimidate witnesses or other defendants or “obstruct the administration of justice,” a trenchant warning given his past conduct verbally attacking judges and prosecutors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Soon after the Georgia investigation was announced, Trump took to social media accusing Willis, an elected official, of “continuing to campaign, and raise money on, this WITCH HUNT” and the prosecution of interfering in the 2024 election.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Witch hunt!&#39; says Trump, on indictment of trying to overturn election result&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, Republican lawmakers in the US House of Representatives announced an investigation into Willis, spearheaded by House Judiciary Committee chairman Jim Jordan, who is among Trump&#39;s staunchest Congressional allies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a letter to Willis, the Ohio Republican pointedly asked whether she coordinated the Georgia investigation with the US Justice Department or used federal tax money to carry out her probe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The federal government has a substantial interest in the welfare of former presidents,” Jordan said in his five-page letter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump is polling well ahead of his rivals for the Republican presidential nomination, allowing him to spend less time on the campaign trail as he juggles his legal cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, he opted to skip the first Republican debate in favour of a pre-recorded interview, concluding, analysts said, that a poor performance could hurt him politically.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump has so far faced relatively easy booking arrangements in his other criminal cases allowing him to breeze through formalities. Delay is a key part of his strategy, experts have said, amid hopes he is re-elected president, able to pardon himself and stay out of prison.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three others involve a Manhattan “hush money” probe, a special counsel Mar-a-Lago classified documents case and a special counsel January 6 election interference investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the Georgia case is potentially more problematic since presidents do not have the authority to grant clemency in state cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least two other defendants, including former White House chief of staff Mark Meadows, have tried to have their Georgia cases transferred to federal court. Meadows was booked at the Georgia jail and released on US$100,000 bail earlier on Thursday after his transfer request was denied.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What is Rico, the Georgia anti-mafia law used to charge Trump?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While others booked at the Georgia jail spend months awaiting indictment or trial, Trump is not expected to spend time at the jail -- noted for its crumbling infrastructure and overcrowding -- after he&#39;s booked. In the hours leading up to his arrival, demonstrators for and against Trump milled, held up signs and yelled slogans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dramatic evidence in the case is expected, including a recording of Trump telling Georgia Secretary of State Brad Raffensperger: “I just want to find 11,780 votes” – the margin he was trailing now-US President Joe Biden in the crucial swing state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Trump received special accommodation on Thursday, partly because he has an armed Secret Service detail as an ex-president, Georgia has indicated it would largely follow normal procedures in the case. This could include televised proceedings, a medical screening and fingerprinting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several of his co-defendants had their mugshots taken, including his lawyers Rudy Giuliani, Sidney Powell and Jenna Ellis. Giuliana, a former New York City mayor, was released on US$150,000 bail, while Powell and Ellis, posted bail of US$100,000 each.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump is the first American president to be impeached twice, face criminal charges and refuse to concede an electoral defeat; the first in 28 years not to win a second term of office; the first in 45 years not to release his income tax returns; and the first in 89 years to lose the White House, House of Representatives and Senate in a single term.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the criminal cases have piled up, Trump has defied political convention by turning his legal troubles into political gold, at least so far. He has often been quick to announce his indictments to his defiant base of supporters, prompting the viral spread of mock mugshots and political donations to soar.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Donald Trump indicted on 4 counts over efforts to overturn 2020 election&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But so have his legal costs. Election records show that Trump took in more than US$53 million in donations from January 1 to August 1, but burned through at least US$42 million, much of it on lawyer fees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An analysis by the Associated Press found that his political committees have spent at least US$59 million for over 100 lawyers and law firms since January 2021, when his supporters stormed the US Capitol.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Signs of stress in his legal ranks have surfaced too. In the Florida documents probe, his then-lead lawyer exited the case weeks before the indictment, and two other lawyers resigned the morning after charges were announced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And on Tuesday, Trump reportedly replaced his lead lawyer with Georgia criminal defence lawyer Sadow.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>