<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong to hit pre-Covid passenger numbers by end of next year, global airline body predicts just weeks after putting date at 2027]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3226566/hong-kong-hit-pre-covid-passenger-numbers-end-next-year-global-airline-body-predicts-just-weeks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 22:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/305fb7b1-b9cd-4b84-aa10-2e91ed8e1ba5_2bd3623d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;全球航空公司进一步修订了对香港航空业复苏的预测，预测预计该市将在明年年底前达到大流行前的客运水平，而就在该协会将日期定为 2027 年几周后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际航空运输协会 (IATA) 的这一举措先于总干事威利 (Willie) 采取的行动沃尔什计划下个月访问香港，参加他的组织与机场管理局举办的为期两天的活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我期待八月在香港与各合作伙伴会面，并参与富有成果的活动沃尔什在周二的一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港将在 2027 年突破新冠疫情爆发前的航空客运量，但枢纽地位受到损害：国际航空运输协会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据香港航空管理局发言人称该协会代表约 300 家航空公司，在观察到香港政府“缓解香港航空业劳动力短缺”的努力后，该机构上调了预测。他表示，这一变化反映了行业预测，即亚太地区的复苏速度将快于此前的预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;IATA 负责人还指出，当局计划引进 6,300 名工人，以填补清洁工和其他一线岗位的空缺。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府上个月宣布将引进20,000名工人，以帮助缓解目标行业的劳动力紧缺问题，其中12,000名工人将进入建筑行业，1,700名工人将进入客车和小型巴士行业。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沃尔什表示，中国大陆 2 月份的重新开放促进了香港的复苏步伐，预计机场交通量将在 2024 年底恢复到“危机前”的水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港机场管理局表示欢迎最新的预测，首席运营官张家辉表示：“我们一直与国际航空运输协会和全球利益相关者就香港的最新发展进行密切沟通。我们很高兴在政府宣布允许输入劳动力支持航空业的新计划后，国际航空运输协会修改了预测，表达了乐观的前景。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于缺乏足够的资源，大多数中国内地人通过香港飞往海外。航班选择：国际航空运输协会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当局发言人周二表示，香港国际机场已达到疫情前水平的 60%，即每天约 12 万名乘客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月在伊斯坦布尔举行的国际航空运输协会年会上，沃尔什向《华盛顿邮报》表示，预计香港航空业要到2027年才会超过2019年之前的水平。他解释说，虽然香港曾经是交通枢纽，但航空公司已经习惯了替代航线在大流行期间该市关闭边界后被迫适应之后，他们需要“很大的说服力”才能返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这仍然是去年 12 月的升级，当时沃尔什表示，预计该市要到 2028 年才会全面反弹。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong to carry out more research on Japan’s plan to discharge radioactive waste water from Fukushima nuclear plant into sea, despite UN watchdog’s go-ahead for plan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3226567/hong-kong-carry-out-more-research-japans-plan-discharge-radioactive-waste-water-fukushima-nuclear?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 23:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/657c137e-265f-489f-b565-e73367ad33e9_14990942.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港将就日本排放处理后放射性水的计划进行更多风险评估尽管联合国监管机构批准将其泵入大海，但国际原子能机构 (IAEA) 周二表示，经过两年的考虑， ，日本处理受污染水的计划符合国际安全标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际原子能机构总干事拉斐尔·马里亚诺·格罗西在东京向日本首相岸田文雄提交的这份报告称，受到控制和控制逐步排放处理后的水“对人类和环境的放射性影响可以忽略不计。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们同意国际原子能机构将继续驻扎在该地点，并将继续审查该计划是否向前迈进……如果政府决定继续进行，国际原子能机构将在未来几十年里永久在这里审查、监测和评估这项活动。”格罗西承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工厂的水因2011年地震和海啸后，将用海水稀释至日本安全标准允许浓度的40分之一，然后通过水下隧道释放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计需要长达30年的时间才能释放。处理工厂内137万吨受污染的水，这是一个长期过程，引发了香港政府和立法者对其潜在健康和环境影响的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环境生态局表示为审查该计划而成立的工作组正在审查国际原子能机构的最终报告，将进行进一步的风险评估，并要求日本提供有关排放计划的更多信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，它已多次告诉日本当局，一旦该国开始排放污水，香港将采取预防措施，包括对该国高风险地区的海产品实施进口管制，以防止可能受污染的食品进入香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;关于日本的情况了解一下计划将福岛废水排入大海&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该局表示，政府将“在充分考虑最终结果后，按照科学和基于风险的原则制定并公布日本相关食品的进口管制措施”国际原子能机构的报告、中国内地专家的意见、风险评估和相关资料。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会环境事务委员会主席葛伊丽莎白呼吁政府立即禁止进口&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，公众告诉她，他们担心这些食品的泄漏。废水将对全球海洋生态造成不可逆转的破坏，并影响子孙后代的健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港人少买日本食品，避免国家过度废水计划：民意调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;陆兵香港核学会主席林表示，虽然处理后废水的放射性水平通常不足以损害人体健康，但他同意政府应对日本进口食品进行更严格的检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“作为一个负责任的政府，他们不应该完全依赖别国的研究。政府应该采取更加保守的方式来解决公民的担忧并进行自己的风险评估。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年，香港是日本第二大农渔业出口市场，进口量约为香港价值 123 亿美元（16 亿美元）的商品。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese cloud computing services provider UCloud flags risk of securing orders of Nvidia’s advanced chips amid high demand, tightened US curbs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3226536/chinese-cloud-computing-services-provider-ucloud-flags-risk-securing-orders-nvidias-advanced-chips?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/047cf76e-2c06-419e-a0ca-e654121224ba_7defc039.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国云计算服务提供商 UCloud Technology Co 表示，在确保先进半导体安全方面面临不确定性英伟达公司的需求量很大，因为美国对此类芯片的出口限制继续阻碍中国人工智能 (AI) 的发展努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于上海的 UCloud，提供基础设施即服务和人工智能服务面向互联网公司和传统企业的平台，周一告诉投资者，允许出口到中国的英伟达 A800 图形处理器 (GPU) 的订单已陆续抵达，对公司运营的“贡献有限”。 UCloud在回复投资者询问其A800订单时写道：“公司采购周期受多种因素影响，我们订购的剩余GPU的交货时间和数量存在不确定性。”上交所网上问答平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“公司将持续跟进供应情况。请注意投资风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最近一次与银行家的路演中，UCloud表示已订购英伟达的A800和H800 GPU，这两款GPU均为修改版本，用于出口到中国根据该公司的另一份文件，UCloud 在 6 月份宣布了这些订单，并推出了配备云基础设施的产品，但拒绝透露其采购数量。配备专门用于开发人工智能模型的高性能计算机，这是一项专为各种国内举措而设计的新产品，旨在创建类似 ChatGPT 的服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，UCloud 服务和中国企业的人工智能开发举措一直受到关注。去年 8 月，美国政府禁止向中国出口芯片供应商 Advanced Micro Devices 和 Nvidia 的某些产品，这削弱了这一禁令的影响。 Nvidia 几乎垄断了用于训练人工智能系统的 GPU。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UCloud 在确保安全方面的不确定性Nvidia GPU 的充足供应突显了中国对先进半导体的巨大需求，以推动新的人工智能开发项目，这已经为走私 GPU 创造了快速增长的本地市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国对先进芯片的强劲需求为走私的英伟达 GPU&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国的人工智能野心可能面临新的打击，据称美国政府正在考虑限制中国公司使用美国云计算服务，这将阻止亚马逊网络服务和微软公司使用据《华尔街日报》周二报道，先进人工智能芯片的力量将使其大陆客户受益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;云计算服务使企业能够购买、销售、租赁或分销一系列软件和其他数字产品。资源作为互联网上的按需服务，就像来自电网的电力一样。这些资源在数据中心内进行管理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，中国主要公司仍然渴望在市场上抢购 Nvidia GPU，因为几乎没有可行的替代品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国互联网巨头例如，腾讯控股于 4 月份推出了基于 Nvidia H800 GPU 的用于大规模 AI 模型训练的新服务器。据报道，TikTok 和抖音所有者字节跳动今年已从 Nvidia 订购了价值 10 亿美元的 GPU。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Beijing will keep up intimidation, but little chance of a full economic blockade, Taipei official says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3226556/beijing-will-keep-intimidation-little-chance-full-economic-blockade-taipei-official-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/11f98019-bfc1-47cf-bfda-bd81c0cf940b_4029829b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;尽管存在威胁，但台湾认为北京全面经济封锁的可能性很小台湾外交部副部长李罗俊 (Roy Chun Lee) 周二表示，在两岸紧张局势加剧之际，台湾爆发了战争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，似乎也没有机会修改台湾达成的两岸服务贸易协议。十年前的北京和台北。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李在接受海外记者采访时表示，北京不太可能对台北实施广泛的经济封锁，因为此举也会伤害大陆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，“我认为中国将继续谈论对台湾实施（经济）封锁的可能性”，并补充说，北京将继续暗示将采取此类行动，以加大对台北的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;李说，这将是北京建议恐吓台湾的“最便宜的方式”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从历史上看，封锁距离军事冲突只有一英里之遥，”他说，并补充说，有很多打破这种围困的“漏洞”。李没有详细说明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了封锁成本高昂之外，这样的包围还会带来不确定性，导致北京“继续口头上”而不是付诸实施，他说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为其领土，如有必要，可以通过武力将其控制回自己的控制之下，在时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西上次访问台湾后不久，北京对台湾实施了部分贸易制裁&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括美国在内的大多数国家并不认为台湾是一个主权国家，但他们反对任何单方面以武力改变现状的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;除了在台湾岛内进行一系列实弹演习外，北京还暂停了约 120 家台湾企业的 2,000 多种食品和工业品的进口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，北京开始据称，台湾对 2,455 种中国大陆产品设置贸易壁垒，包括食品、纺织品、矿物、金属、塑料、化学品和建筑材料，并威胁采取惩罚措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾分析人士表示，部分&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“到目前为止，中国大陆还没有高级官员正式呼吁对台湾实施经济封锁，因为该行为本身也会影响到台湾的经济封锁。”台北智库台湾国际战略研究会常务理事马克斯·罗表示：“习近平尚未​​决定是否在 2027 年统一台湾：米利”罗说，上个月在大陆城市厦门举行的一年一度的海峡论坛上，大陆最高政治顾问王沪宁呼吁两岸经济繁荣，并补充说福建省应该成为“台湾经济融入中国的示范区” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这意味着大陆没有计划对台湾实施经济封锁，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中华智库高级分析师许尊子台北经济研究智库表示，对台湾的部分制裁“不会影响台湾的整体出口表现，因为它们占台湾对大陆出口总额的比例不超过0.5%”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;她补充说，北京不太可能扩大对大陆急需的芯片等台湾高科技产品的制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交部副部长李在四月份接受彭博社采访时，表示台湾在过去两年里加大了储存关键货物和矿产的力度，并出台了新的立法，使该岛能够更好地抵抗可能的制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李还对台湾的复兴表示怀疑。李说，《海峡服务贸易协定》是前国民党政府于2013年达成的一项协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议导致了岛上的许多政治和经济争端。 “[它]完全不符合当前国际经济秩序的发展，”李补充道，并强调北京的政治气候与十年前签署该协议时非常不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英国前首相特拉斯支付了 10 万美元进行了 4 小时的台湾之行&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他说，当时许多国家认为与北京接触将有助于其转变为尊重国际规则秩序的经济体。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;自那时以来，北京越来越多地将其经济武器化，以通过恐吓来实现政治利益，李补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就是我说贸易协议早该达成的原因，”他说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李发表此番言论几天前，两位总统候选人——主要反对党国民党的侯裕一和亲大陆的台湾人民党的柯文哲——呼吁恢复该协议以帮助在一月份的总统选举和立法选举之前改善两岸关系并促进双边投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾立法院在送交批准该协议时搁置了该协议，因为担心该协议不符合台湾公司的利益。&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Catastrophe: French rail operator fined after train runs over beloved pet]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226565/catastrophe-french-rail-operator-fined-after-train-runs-over-beloved-pet?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 22:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/26621c3f-e9d0-400b-8dd0-115d84ba9778_5516d27e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;法国法院周二裁定法国国家铁路运营商在火车出发后犯有疏忽罪显然是故意碾压了一只躲在轨道上的猫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一月份，巴黎蒙帕纳斯车站 Neko 的死亡事件（日语中的意思是“猫”）引起了公愤，内政部长杰拉尔德·达马宁 (Gerald Darmanin) 宣称自己“特别震惊”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;动物权利机构碧姬·芭杜基金会 (Brigitte Bardot Foundation) 问铁路运营商 SNCF：“你不感到羞耻吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乘客 Georgia 和她 15 岁的女儿 Melaina说他们的宠物从旅行包中逃脱并消失在高速列车下，当时它正准备离开巴黎前往法国西南部的波尔多，车上载有 800 名乘客。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我希望它们看起来迷人” ：马来西亚主人给猫开斋节服装&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在试图说服工作人员救它20分钟后，火车开走了，杀死了猫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们看到他被切成两半” ，梅莱娜当时告诉动物权利协会3000万朋友。 “他们告诉我们这不是他们的问题，这只是一只猫，我们应该用皮带拴住它”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SNCF 向猫的主人提供了一张前往波尔多的免费机票作为补偿。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;但该协会以“严重虐待和虐待导致动物死亡”为由提出申诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项指控可处以最高 75,000 欧元（超过 80,000 美元）的罚款）和五年监禁，但巴黎法院以“疏忽”为由对 SNCF 处以 1,000 欧元罚款，裁定宠物被杀是“非自愿”造成的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该判决违背了 SNCF 的建议。检察官要求运营商洗清所有指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SNCF 旅行社分公司被责令向宠物的两名主人各支付 1,000 欧元的损害赔偿金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以下Neko 去世后，Darmanin 宣布将对全国 4,000 个警察局的警察进行培训，以应对动物贩运和虐待行为。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China can’t count on US giving any strategic ground soon: top Chinese academic Wang Jisi]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3226552/china-cant-count-us-giving-any-strategic-ground-soon-top-chinese-academic-wang-jisi?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/7df482e0-9bc0-41e8-b954-51ba313920ce_088a1b57.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国应该放弃任何美国会在两国关系紧张的关系中做出战略让步的幻想，研究两国关系的中国顶尖学者王缉思表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王缉思周一在北京清华大学世界和平论坛上发表讲话时表示，中美之间最近的和解是脆弱的，今年年初的气球事件等事件可能会导致这一计划脱轨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“就我个人而言，我认为中国实际上将美国视为其最大的外部威胁，这种威胁不仅涉及国家安全，还涉及政治， ”他在小组讨论中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国经常说它不想改变中国的[政治]制度，但我们非常担心，因为它正在做的事情以及事实上美国在政治上对中国的看法非常负面。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说，尽管努力改善沟通，但北京和华盛顿几乎没有看到任何改变的迹象。相反，两国以国家安全为由，加强了经济和外交政策立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就是为什么我认为我们应该放弃任何美国会对中国做出战略让步的幻想，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近几周，美国的外展工作势头强劲。美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯上个月访问了北京，财政部长珍妮特·耶伦将于周四抵达中国首都。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计会有更多高层接触，但尚不清楚是否会产生足够的善意中国国家主席习近平将出席 11 月在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会。如果他真的去，这将是习近平自 2017 年以来首次访问美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但王表示，两国关系不太可能很快得到改善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美中关系的性质“中美关系已经确定不会在短期内得到改善，而且双方现在都对对方抱有负面看法。”王说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“即使两国关系真的好转，也只是北京大学国际战略研究所所长王表示，人们还担心另一起类似气球事件的潜在后果。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我担心任何意外事件，例如气球事件或其他事件，都可能使双边关系再次恶化，我们希望避免这样的事件，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“双方没有更好的渠道，只能通过各自的外交使团进行沟通，但中国驻美国大使馆怎么可能知道是谁送来的气球呢？中方需要时间来找出答案，而美方很难理解为什么花了这么长时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果发生任何事件，特别是在亚太经合组织会议或亚太经合组织会议之前在新德里举行的 G20 峰会上，各方都需要“避免激烈争论或任何对抗”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为这是我们可以希望的，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;观察人士指出，明年紧张局势的另外两个主要来源是：台湾和美国总统选举。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登预计在竞选连任期间对中国采取鹰派立场。台湾竞选中任何有独立倾向的候选人当选都可能意味着两岸改善的终结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说，他担心北京和华盛顿对台湾的看法不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“美国人常说要维持台海现状，但他们也说，他们听说北京希望（与台湾）统一取得进展，不希望台湾和大陆继续分裂下去。” ”王说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他警告说，这种关于台湾地位的分歧将会持续甚至加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国必将加大对‘台独’势力的镇压力度，变本加厉地打击‘台独’势力。”其统一努力，而美国可能会继续向台湾出售武器并提供一些政治支持——这是我主要担心的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为一个分裂的省份，将重新纳入其管辖范围最终并在必要时使用武力。美国不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对改变台湾现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王还质疑美国是否会放弃对台湾的“战略模糊”政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我认为战略清晰度是不可能的，因为无论如何，美国都不太可能说它愿意在什么时候介入台湾的军事事务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“日益敌对” &#39;：美中关系是否正在走向螺旋式下降？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他预计美国将继续成为“世界上最强大的军事、经济和政治大国”，但中国有自己的优势，例如强大的治理体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国的实力一直在迅速上升……而美国的实力也在上升，但速度很慢，因此可以说美国相对于中国正在衰落，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，王说，他担心美国政治日益两极分化，这损害了华盛顿作为伟大民主国家的声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“正如观察到的人一样在美国呆了几十年，我之前没有想到美国的国内政治会发展到如此党派之争，争论的不是政策而是两党。这不利于美国的长期发展。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU climate chief urges ‘decisive’ joint action with China on climate crisis]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226563/eu-climate-chief-urges-decisive-joint-action-china-climate-crisis?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 22:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/b5cc5122-73ca-4ad8-861b-0f9522976812_04276e54.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧盟气候负责人弗兰斯·蒂默曼斯周二呼吁采取更快、更果断的联合行动正在北京参加气候谈判的蒂默曼斯在北京会见了中国国务院副总理丁薛祥。周二，中国领导人在钓鱼台国宾馆接待高级外国访客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒂默曼斯说，人类面临着“三重危机”，即全球变暖、生物多样性丧失和污染。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“危机正在加速。如果我们想遏制它们，我们需要比迄今为止采取的行动更快、更果断。”蒂默曼斯告诉丁，并补充说中国和欧盟之间的协调行动可以激发全球行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在欧洲中国总理李强坚决反对脱钩&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;丁表示，环境和气候问题一直是中欧合作的重点。他呼吁通过高层对话改善合作成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，蒂默曼斯表示，随着全球碳预算迅速缩减，中国应该更快地达到碳排放峰值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国根据欧盟的一份声明，他在北京清华大学的一次演讲中表示：“我们仍在建设更多的煤电产能，而且规模很大，我认为我们可以同意，这是最肮脏的发电方式。” p>;&lt;p>;中国已承诺减少煤炭消耗，但要到 2026 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国官员周一要求发电厂和煤炭供应商“尽一切可能”确保今年夏天的电力供应，因为更多城市在炎热的气温下变得闷热。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.最好&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 22:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: China’s move to impose controls on gallium and germanium is a mixed blessing for country’s exporters]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3226548/tech-war-chinas-move-impose-controls-gallium-and-germanium-mixed-blessing-countrys-exporters?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/04/862925cb-a276-4214-85dc-a9b7813d5f62_8aed65c7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国决定从下个月起对重要材料镓和锗实施出口管制中国专家表示，在半导体制造领域，这是一项旨在提高国家安全的有针对性的措施，但也可能带来行业混乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举被广泛视为北京对美国及其盟友强加芯片的报复为了对中国实施限制，中国商务部和海关总署宣布，从 8 月 1 日起，关键金属及相关产品的出口将受到政府批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京此举是利用其准垄断地位低品质的镓。中国占全球稀土金属产量的 90% 以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京吉亚半导体材料有限公司副总经理陈锋表示，该公司年产 60 吨镓，北京已实现“鉴于金属对国家安全的战略重要性，这是正确的举动”。与此同时，陈表示，新的出口制度可能会影响中国镓提取商和出口商的业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国在芯片制造金属方面的主导地位受到供应减少的威胁：专家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然陈补充道，中国对镓原料的提取具有准垄断地位，中国企业在将稀有金属加工成中间或最终产品时处于劣势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“镓材料需要纯化并复合成半绝缘材料，但在高纯度材料的生产和成分的稳定性方面，中国与世界领先企业还有相当大的差距。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道，德国的Freiberger Compound Materials、美国芯片晶圆制造商 AXT 和日本住友电工 (Sumitomo Electric) 是镓加工领域的强大参与者。在中国拥有制造工厂的 AXT 周一表示，将寻求继续从中国出口镓和锗基板产品的许可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一年前，美国商务部工业与安全局，华盛顿出口管制部门将氧化镓添加到其出口管制清单中，因为含有此类材料的设备可以“显着增加军事潜力”。氧化镓也被列入中国出口管制清单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据美国地质调查局的数据，目前全球金属镓储量约为27.93万吨。中国在这些储备中所占比例最大，达到 68%。到2022年，中国的初级低纯镓产量将占全球的98%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师还表示，中国的出口管制可能会推高全球镓及相关产品的价格。券商国金证券发布的一份报告指出，鉴于中国以外的替代品有限，外国供应商可能难以获得足够数量的镓材料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾以赛亚研究公司副总裁 Lucy Chen 表示，此举将“直接影响”下游半导体行业，包括住友、Freiberger和AXT等镓衬底供应商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在中国的出口管制下，镓和锗的成本可能会增加，”陈说。她补充说，这可能会对射频产品、功率放大器和通信设备等相关领域产生“连锁反应”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出口管制的消息导致中国主要金属锗生产公司的股价周二走高，其中投资者押注此举将有利于国内芯片材料行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海上市的国有企业驰宏锌锗股价飙升6.1%。该公司的锗年产能为60吨，该公司周二表示，其红外领域的锗产品出口量“非常小”，预计此次管制对其财务业绩影响不大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yunnan Germanium, which has over 40 years of experience in the mining, processing and development of germanium, said it will “actively communicate” with relevant departments regarding the latest export restrictions, and is currently unable to assess the impact. Shares of the Shenzhen-listed company surged 10 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong shaken but not stirred by recent earthquake tremors. The Post learns more about seismic activity near the city]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3226560/hong-kong-shaken-not-stirred-recent-earthquake-tremors-post-learns-more-about-seismic-activity-near?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 21:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/04/202f9015-a0c7-4af8-835f-7ef194df1252_bb8b0520.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hongkongers reported feeling the tremors of a magnitude 3.7 earthquake earlier this week, marking the third time in three months the city has experienced such seismic activity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s forecaster said the epicentre of Monday evening&#39;s quake was located in a southern part of mainland China, with some residents in Hong Kong briefly feelings its effects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post talks to seismologists and breaks down what readers need to know about the rumbles in Hong Kong&#39;s concrete jungle.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong team sent on Turkey quake mission named as first winner of top award&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;When were the recent tremor reports?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to the Observatory, the epicentre of Monday&#39;s earthquake was about 23km (14.2 miles) west-northwest of Heyuan, Guangdong province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The forecaster added that Hongkongers back home had experienced “minor shaking, the duration of which was a few seconds”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident came after the city felt the ripples of a 4.9 magnitude earthquake over the South China Sea during the early hours of May 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong was also on the periphery of another quake on April 22, which had a magnitude of 5.3. Its epicentre was about 190km west of Gaoxiong, a port city in southern Taiwan, some 450km east of Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Observatory said tremors from the quakes on Monday and in April would have felt like the “passing of light trucks”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But tremors from the earthquake in May were more intense and likely caused hanging objects to swing and rattled windows, dishes and doors, since the seismic event was about 300km closer to the city, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earthquakes are generally measured by their magnitude and intensity. The former is determined by the amount of energy released at the quake&#39;s source, while the latter charts how much the ground shakes at a certain location.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yang Hong-feng, an associate professor at Chinese University&#39;s science faculty, said Hong Kong generally experienced the tremors of nearby quakes six or seven times a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is common for Hongkongers to feel earthquakes, but we have not noticed a clear increase in earthquake activity in the area this year,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So far this year, the city has felt the vibrations from seven separate quakes, including five that occurred in Guangdong province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang also noted that earthquakes near Heyuan were not unusual since the construction of the neighbouring Xinfengjiang Reservoir in 1958.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Three years after it was built, there was a magnitude 6.2 earthquake right next to the dam of the reservoir,” he said. “Since then, Heyuan has become active in regularly producing earthquakes of magnitudes four or less.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scholar, who is conducting research in the region, said water from the reservoir could have flowed into the earth&#39;s fault lines, lubricating them and potentially triggering quakes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Located about 167km northeast of Hong Kong, Heyuan reported 74 quakes with magnitudes of two and above over the last 12 months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Quakes near the southern Chinese city also accounted for three out of the seven times Hong Kong reported experiencing tremors.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Thousands jolted awake as minor earthquake rattles Hong Kong&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Observatory said Hong Kong&#39;s location affected its chances of being struck by an earthquake of a larger magnitude.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Most earthquakes in the world occur along the boundaries of crustal plates. Hong Kong lies within the Eurasian Plate and is located far away from the nearest boundary with the Pacific Plate on the Circum-Pacific Seismic Belt that runs through Japan, Taiwan and the Philippines,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s potential for quakes was much lower than locations such as Japan, Taiwan, the Philippines and western parts of the United States, the Observatory said, explaining those areas lay close to “more seismically active zones”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese University geophysicist Tan Yen-joe echoed the forecaster&#39;s remarks, saying: “Hong Kong is rarely the epicentre for earthquakes, but we do have faults that are big enough to generate a large-scale earthquake.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that Hong Kong was more likely to be affected by tremors from nearby earthquakes occurring in areas such as Guangdong province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city has not recorded any deaths or injuries as a direct result of tremors since official records began in 1905.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The only seismic activity to cause structural damage in Hong Kong was a 7.2 magnitude earthquake that struck Shantou, about 300km away, in 1918 during Lunar New Year celebrations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The damage included several cracks in the walls of the Observatory&#39;s headquarters.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chinese University&#39;s Yang said the city&#39;s “newer buildings should be able to withstand an earthquake with an intensity of seven”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The intensity of earthquakes is measured on a 12-point scale known as the Modified Mercalli Intensity range. The system takes into account damage assessments and eyewitness accounts, with results also depending on how near someone is to a quake&#39;s epicentre and how close it was to the surface.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But questions remain about older buildings and whether they would be able to withstand an earthquake similar to the one in 1918,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tan, meanwhile, explained the city typically experienced seismic activity that ranked low on the scale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The tremors felt in Hong Kong are usually of an intensity of three or four, which is considered minor,” he said. “The biggest threat to the public would be items shaking or swinging that could hit someone if they fell.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Buildings Department had also concluded that frequent typhoon activity meant many buildings in the city were built to withstand strong winds and had a certain degree of seismic resistance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While acknowledging that such buildings were not specifically built to be quake resistant, the department noted earthquakes with an intensity of five to six were only likely to occur locally once every 72 years and those reaching seven might only hit every 475 years.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong security chief dares fugitive activist Nathan Law to stand trial at home, accuses him of exploiting protesters’ misfortunes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3226561/hong-kong-security-chief-dares-fugitive-activist-nathan-law-stand-trial-home-accuses-him-exploiting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 21:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/04/4ca7b871-b053-4ffe-bbbd-0868aa7074c0_25a18940.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s security chief has challenged wanted activist Nathan Law Kwun-chung to leave the United Kingdom and stand trial in the city, while accusing the former student leader of exploiting young protesters&#39; misfortunes for his own gains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Security Chris Tang Ping-keung on Tuesday dubbed the opposition figure a “modern-day traitor”, hours after Law disputed the collusion charges against him and called on police to share their evidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A day earlier, the force offered a bounty of HK$1 million (US$127,640) each to anyone who could offer information leading to the arrest of Law and seven other opposition activists accused of violating the national security law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fugitives were last known to be living in Australia, the United States and the UK.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s bounty for 8 security law suspects sends world &#39;strong message&#39;: Lee&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Superintendent Steve Li Kwai-wah of the force&#39;s National Security Department had conceded that arrests were only possible if the suspects set foot in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Responding to the bounty, Law said: “What I&#39;ve done has been legitimate peace advocacy work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I urge Steve Li to disclose any evidence that I have colluded with foreign forces – I have neither received any foreign funds nor been employed by any foreign government agencies,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking after a Legislative Council panel meeting, Tang dared the opposition activist to return to the city to learn more about the evidence against him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If he thinks [what he has done is] legitimate and legal, I urge him to come back to Hong Kong and we will show the evidence to all Hong Kong residents in court,” the minister said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Law was believed to have left Hong Kong for the UK before Beijing imposed the national security law in June 2020, obtaining refugee status a year later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to his personal website, the fugitive activist also published a book titled Freedom in November 2021 and has engaged in a string of speaking engagements in Britain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Referring to Law&#39;s role as a well-known activist during the 2019 anti-government unrest, Tang accused him of exploiting young protesters&#39; misfortune for his own benefit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You have been acting like a cowardly turtle hiding its head and … indulging in a lavish life in a foreign country, while young people incited by you in Hong Kong are left to bear the legal consequences,” the minister said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang reiterated that city authorities would “exhaust lifelong efforts” to bring the eight suspects to justice, warning they could become “abandoned pawns” once they were no longer useful to their foreign hosts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said investigators were also working on tracking down those funding and supporting the wanted fugitive, adding that the bounties would encourage residents to come forward with any evidence or information on the suspects&#39; movements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The minister also stressed that it was illegal to provide financial support to those accused of national security offences. Tang declined to say whether the families of the fugitives, including Elmer Yuan Gong-yi, would be interviewed as part of any investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong national security law: police offer HK$1 million rewards for arrest of 8&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yuan is the father-in-law of New People&#39;s Party legislator Eunice Yung Hoi-yan, who bought a newspaper advert last August saying she had severed ties with the staunch opposition supporter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawmaker told a radio programme on Tuesday that she had advised her husband, political analyst Derek Yuen Mi-chang, to be mindful of the legal and financial implications of maintaining ties with his father.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Yuan] has become so extreme in his views against the country. Birds of a different feather do not flock together,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong national security law: police offer HK$1 million rewards for arrest of 8&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Barrister Ronny Tong Ka-wah, a member of key decision-making body the Executive Council, told a separate radio show that a son offering financial support to his father out of filial piety was not a violation of the law since the act was not intended as a national security threat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Beijing-imposed legislation prohibits acts of secession, subversion of state power, terrorism and foreign interference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tong also conceded that the police&#39;s bid to bring the eight back to Hong Kong was a long shot, since suspects accused of political offences were generally not covered under international extradition treaties.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Dozens of Hong Kong residents on police national security ‘wanted’ list, including for crowdfunding drives, the Post has learned]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3226559/dozens-hong-kong-residents-police-national-security-wanted-list-including-crowdfunding-drives-post?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.04 21:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/04/967b1cc1-37c8-4f09-9f7b-1b180a29b6da_f9ce98fa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Dozens of Hongkongers have been placed on a police wanted list for alleged violations of the national security law, including people who were involved in crowdfunding drives, the Post has learned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The news on Tuesday came a day after police offered rewards of HK$1 million (US$127,700) a head for information leading to the arrest and prosecution of eight opposition figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A government source said city residents suspected of offences under the national security law included people who had jumped bail and fled overseas after they were arrested by National Security Department police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Those being sought by national security police] are all Hong Kong residents. Some of them hold foreign passports, but have the right of abode in the city and are considered local citizens,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added they all left the city just before or after the law came into force in 2020 and that most of them were in Australia, Europe and North America at present.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some of them have been involved in crowdfunding activities worldwide and the source said that one activist could raise hundreds of thousands of Hong Kong dollars in a month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source warned supporters could be considered to be in breach of the national security law if their donations were used to fund offences such as the promotion of secession or subversion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he admitted police could do little to stop that type of activity because the bank accounts used to collect donations were based outside Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He and another government source also admitted it was unlikely that overseas law enforcement agencies would help catch the fugitives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They explained they could be considered as political refugees who were usually not listed as wanted through Interpol&#39;s “red notice” programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;National security police have arrested 260 people aged from 15 to 90 since the law came into force on June 30, 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The force said 161 people and five companies had been charged. A total of 79 have been convicted.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong national security law: police offer HK$1 million rewards for arrest of 8&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The eight with a price on their heads are former legislators Nathan Law Kwun-chung, Dennis Kwok Wing-hang and Ted Hui Chi-fung, trade unionist Mung Siu-tat, lawyer Kevin Yam Kin-fung, and activists Finn Lau Cho-dik, Anna Kwok Fung-yee and Elmer Yuan Gong-yi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said seven of the eight had appealed for international sanctions against Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another source said the eight were singled out because they were alleged to have been involved in serious crimes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They were also said to have taken part in activities that endangered national security to a greater degree than others on the wanted list.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But critics questioned the effectiveness of the bounty offer because the countries the activists lived in – Australia, Britain and the United States – had suspended extradition treaties with Hong Kong after Beijing&#39;s imposition of the national security law on the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They added that alleged political offences were also usually exempted from extradition agreements.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Who are the 8 Hongkongers wanted over national security with HK$1 million bounties?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Post has learned that others on the wanted list include ex-legislator Sixtus Baggio Leung Chung-hang, former British consulate employee Simon Cheng Man-kit and activists Sunny Cheung Kwan-yeung and Raymond Wong Toi-yeung.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheung is the former spokesman of the Hong Kong Higher Institutions International Affairs Delegation, who lobbied for support for the Hong Kong Human Rights and Democracy Act.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three others, Hong Kong independence campaigner Wayne Chan Ka-kui, Lau Hong, a former member of the disbanded separatist group Studentlocalism, and US-based Samuel Chu of the Hong Kong Democracy Council were also put on the list.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chief Superintendent Steve Li Kwai-wah of the National Security Department on Monday appealed to the fugitives to return to Hong Kong and surrender themselves, which would guarantee less severe penalties if they were convicted of offences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he added under national security law provisions, they would also have to give a truthful account of any offences they were involved and report any crimes committed by others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The department has received more than 500,000 tip-offs about possible violations of national security legislation since a special hotline was launched in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The hotline was set up to give the public a way to relay information, photos, and audio and video clips by SMS, WeChat or email.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said the hotline was not answered, replies were not sent and personal details were not collected or disclosed to anyone else.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 04 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>