<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong police uncover HK$3.8 million in illegal drugs stashed in subdivided flat described as ‘mini narcotics supermarket’, 2 arrested]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3222408/hong-kong-police-uncover-hk38-million-illegal-drugs-stashed-subdivided-flat-described-mini-narcotics?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 13:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/e9561ac9-e697-4cbb-b45b-894d1188c3fe_540c8d35.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港警方在香港查获价值 380 万港元（485,000 美元）的非法毒品一个分隔的单位，并逮捕了两名男子，以打击向尖沙咀娱乐区供应毒品的贩运集团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名熟悉案件的消息人士周三表示，九龙市中心的房屋已被用于大约一年的时间来储存和生产快克可卡因等非法毒品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，调查发现该集团雇用持有人持有担保书——临时移民文件，供人们留在该市但不工作——负责管理毒品生产线和仓储中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二晚上在代号为“Hotclash”的行动中被捕的两名嫌疑人是一名巴基斯坦人和一名印度人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港海关4个月内在机场检获价值8亿港元的毒品&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“情报显示，检获的毒品是为重庆大厦的毒贩和供应尖沙咀娱乐场所而准备的，”消息人士称。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;西九龙总区重案组搜集证据后，于周二晚上七时过后截获该名印裔男子，该名印裔男子在旺角新填地街一个单位外当哨兵。这名巴基斯坦人大约在同一时间离开其中一间公寓时被接走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在公寓内查获的非法药物包括 2.46 公斤可卡因、1 公斤摇头丸、780 克大麻和 700 克海洛因, 根据力。警方表示，这批货物的街道价值估计为 380 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港对在酒精、毒品影响下驾驶船只的行为提出新的处罚&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;消息人士称该处所是“迷你超市”和各种非法毒品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官员还查获了毒品制造和包装设备，例如塑料封口机、秤和塑料袋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消息人士称，一台压缩机用于转动在公寓里还发现了砖块状的大麻芽。 “有可能是将成型的大麻芽藏在饭盒中，以避免在运送给买家时被发现。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;10名涉嫌贩毒及其他罪行的香港嫌疑人在香港被捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两名男子，同年三十七岁，因涉嫌贩运毒品及制造危险药物被拘留，根据《危险药物条例》最高可判处终身监禁及罚款港币五百万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至周三下午，两名嫌疑人仍被警方拘留，不排除进一步逮捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;临时数字显示，该市缉获的五种主要毒品——可卡因、大麻、甲基苯丙胺、海洛因和氯胺酮——上升今年 1 月至 3 月期间，从去年同期的 797 公斤增加了 142% 至 1,929 公斤。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Air New Zealand to weigh passengers before boarding: ‘we know stepping on the scales can be daunting’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3222390/air-new-zealand-weigh-passengers-boarding-we-know-stepping-scales-can-be-daunting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 13:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/6870d11c-3d10-4fd2-a3b6-ee120d5496e3_26f9f569.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新西兰民航局计划让其国家航空公司在起飞前开始称重乘客&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据 CNN Travel 报道，该计划将持续到 7 月 2 日，被称为乘客体重调查，并将提供新西兰航空公司国际航班的重量负荷和分布数据。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们对飞机上的所有物品进行称重——从货物到机上餐饮再到货舱中的行李，”该航空公司的负载控制改进专家 Alastair James 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“对于客户、机组人员和随身行李，我们使用平均重量，这是我们从这项调查中获得的，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司声称重量记录将保持匿名&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在飞行前办理登机手续时，乘客将被要求站在数字秤上，据报道，这些信息将被提交到数据库，但机上人员无法看到...我们想让我们的客户放心，任何地方都没有可见的展示。没有人能看到你的体重，甚至我们也看不到，”詹姆斯在声明中继续说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新西兰航空公司此前曾要求乘客在 2021 年的一项调查中站上体重秤，但这是第一次该航空公司表示，该规定将影响国际旅客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首批参与新计划的群体之一将是从奥克兰直飞纽约肯尼迪机场的旅客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个 17 小时的航班于去年秋天推出，是新西兰航空公司在大流行后改造的一个里程碑，也是世界上最长的航班之一。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese scientists develop new gene-editing tool that differs in approach to CRISPR-Cas9]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3222401/chinese-scientists-develop-new-gene-editing-tool-differs-approach-crispr-cas9?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 13:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/4d27aaf7-0a05-4c0b-9712-5092c26b5a07_50900a59.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国研究人员开发了一种新的基因编辑工具，他们说这种工具非常精确和安全.该技术有望治疗或治愈某些遗传疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与众所周知的基因编辑工具 CRISPR-Cas9 不同，CRISPR-Cas9 充当“分子剪刀”，可以剪断基因组中的两条 DNA 链并依靠细胞的自我修复机制进行修复——称为“碱基编辑器”的新工具可在不切割双螺旋的情况下修复基因组中的特定位点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一个碱基编辑器于 2016 年提出由哈佛大学的 David Liu 领导的团队，但中国团队使用不同的方法可以取得相同的结果，这可能使中国能够挑战美国在该领域的领导地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的研究发表在5 月 16 日在中国科学院主办的同行评审期刊《国家科学评论》上发表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这意味着我们已经建立了自己的系统，这对于临床和商业应用至关重要”，该研究的通讯作者、中国科学院脑科学与智能技术卓越创新中心研究员杨辉说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究对于疾病模型的开发也很重要这组作者说，他们在基础研究和基因治疗领域都处于领先地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CRISPR-Cas9 是细菌用来抵御病毒攻击的一种自然防御机制，是这一领域最重要的科学发现之一世纪。两位科学家——柏林马克斯·普朗克病原体科学研究所主任 Emmanuelle Charpentier 和加州大学伯克利分校教授 Jennifer Doudna——因开发基因编辑工具而获得 2020 年诺贝尔化学奖。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;然而，CRISPR-Cas9 也有其缺点。由于它依赖于细胞的自我修复机制来重新连接断裂的菌株，因此可能会导致脱靶效应，例如染色体重排或大量 DNA 缺失，这可能会引起安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国问题 &#39;自基因编辑婴儿丑闻以来最全面的“生物伦理学规则”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;科学家们发现了一种方法，可以使用碱基编辑技术精确纠正单个 DNA 字母或“碱基”的拼写错误。 DNA 中有四种碱基——腺嘌呤 (A)、胞嘧啶 (C)、鸟嘌呤 (G) 和胸腺嘧啶 (T)——它们应该以特定的配对配对：A 与 T，C 与 G。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;通过使用 CRISPR 剪刀但禁用切割 DNA 的能力，David Liu 的团队附加了一种可以在 DNA 碱基上进行化学反应的蛋白质，使其能够将 C 转化为 T，或将 A 转化为 G，例如。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Liu 在 4 月份告诉 The Conversation，碱基编辑可以纠正 DNA 中出现的四种最常见的拼写错误，约占所有已知致病 DNA 错误的 30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yang说：“CRISPR-Cas9就像一把剪刀，可以剪断DNA，可能导致碱基对的缺失或插入，而碱基编辑就像铅笔和橡皮擦，可以擦掉一个碱基，把它改成另一个”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在以前的研究中，脱氨作用——从分子中去除氨基——是碱基编辑的第一步，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“以前，科学家们使用脱氨基腺嘌呤或胞嘧啶的化学反应。当身体发现碱基发生突变时，它有一系列的机制来修复它们，从一个碱基转变为另一个碱基，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们的看法是脱氨基是碱基发生突变的第一步编辑，但我们通过找到另一种酶——糖基化酶——来打破固有概念，它也可以进行碱基编辑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更重要的是，杨说，以前的方法不能直接修正鸟嘌呤，但新的碱基-编辑方法使鸟嘌呤编辑成为可能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在我们有一个独立的碱基编辑知识产权体系，我们可以免费应用它进行任何碱基编辑修改，”杨说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他补充说，碱基编辑已经成为治疗遗传病的主要手段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人类基因突变中有一半以上是由单碱基突变引起的，因此碱基编辑可以精确修复这些突变，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国科学家表示，新的细胞编辑器可以加快遗传病治疗&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;碱基编辑的临床试验正在开展，以治疗一些遗传病，包括镰状细胞-细胞疾病、血液病 β-地中海贫血和心血管疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，英国的一名 T 细胞白血病患者接受了碱基编辑细胞疗法的治疗——这是世界上首次应用该技术。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着基因编辑工具的不断进步，更多的罕见病将能够进入临床试验，并被科学家和生物医药公司解决，”杨说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nato to send 700 more troops to Kosovo after violent clashes with ethnic Serbs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222395/nato-send-700-more-troops-kosovo-after-violent-clashes-ethnic-serbs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 12:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/408c3893-3307-4bcf-8987-8ab1f4d791b1_9eea2216.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北约将向科索沃北部增派 700 名士兵，以帮助平息冲突后的暴力抗议活动该联盟宣布，那里的塞族人造成 30 名国际士兵受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该地区最近的暴力事件激起了人们对 1998-99 年科索沃冲突再次爆发的恐惧，该冲突夺去了 10,000 多人的生命，留下了超过100 万人无家可归，导致北约维和行动持续了近四分之一个世纪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冲突源于上周发生的对抗，此前阿尔巴尼亚族官员在投票中当选，遭到塞族人的压倒性抵制进入市政大楼就职。当塞族人试图阻止他们时，科索沃警察发射催泪瓦斯驱散人群。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一塞族人与警察和北约维和人员发生冲突后，发生了更多暴力事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北约秘书长延斯·斯托尔滕贝格表示，如果需要更多部队，将增加一个预备营，以备不时之需。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些是谨慎的步骤，”斯托尔滕贝格说，他在与挪威首相会谈后于周二在奥斯陆宣布了这一消息.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;塞族人同意疏通科索沃的道路，但紧张局势仍在发酵&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北约领导的该地区维和行动被称为驻科部队，目前有近 3,800 名士兵。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;也是在星期二，驻科部队的多国维和人员使用金属栅栏和带刺铁丝网围栏来加强已成为热点的北部城镇的阵地。军队封锁了 Zvecan 的市政大楼，周一的骚乱导致紧张局势飙升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科索沃曾是塞尔维亚的一个省，贝尔格莱德不承认 2008 年宣布独立。阿尔巴尼亚族占人口的大部分，但科索沃在该国北部与塞尔维亚接壤的地区有少数民族的塞族人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯托尔滕贝格谴责暴力并警告说，北约部队将“采取一切必要行动维持科索沃所有公民的安全环境”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他敦促双方不要“进一步采取不负责任的行为”，并重返欧盟支持的改善关系谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国和大多数欧盟国家已承认科索沃从塞尔维亚独立，而俄罗斯和中国则站在贝尔格莱德一边。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国周二表示支持塞尔维亚“维护其主权和领土完整”的努力，莫斯科在争端中多次批评西方政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为应对上周的对抗，塞尔维亚将本国军队置于最高戒备状态，并向与科索沃接壤的边境派遣了更多军队。塞族人周一再次抗议，坚持阿尔巴尼亚族市长和科索沃警察必须离开科索沃北部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当塞族人试图进入位于首都以北 45 公里（28 英里）的 Zvecan 的市政办公室时，对抗更加恶化，普里什蒂纳。他们首先与科索沃警察发生冲突，然后与国际维和人员发生冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周二晚间发布的视频信息中，科索沃总理阿尔宾库尔蒂说，4 月 23 日当选的市长“是唯一有合法性的人在市政大楼和为公民服务”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;塞尔维亚捍卫中国 FK-3 导弹交易，对邻国“没有威胁”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;暴力的煽动者已经被查明，总理说，他点名了一些塞族商人，这些商人迫使他们的员工抗议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在科索沃，权力是通过选举赢得的，而不是通过暴力和犯罪，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;美国和欧盟最近加紧努力谈判塞尔维亚和科索沃之间的协议，担心俄罗斯在乌克兰的战争肆虐导致不稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟已向塞尔维亚和科索沃明确表示，如果他们想在加入欧盟方面取得任何进展，他们就必须实现关系正常化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天欧洲已经发生了太多的暴力事件。我们承受不起另一场冲突，”欧盟外交政策负责人何塞普·博雷尔周二在布鲁塞尔告诉记者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，作为缓和紧张局势的第一步，科索沃警方应暂停针对市政建筑的行动&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了应对最近的动乱，北约决定增加驻科部队，并在西巴尔干地区部署“后备行动部队”声明说，没有具体说明数字。另一支部队将待命，“准备好在必要时增援驻科部队”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;驻科部队周二发表声明称，有 30 名士兵（11 名意大利人和 19 名匈牙利人）受伤，包括骨折和被简易爆炸物烧伤燃烧装置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明补充说，三名匈牙利士兵“因使用枪支而受伤”，但他们的伤势没有生命危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;塞尔维亚总统发誓要加强枪支管制2 起大规模枪击事件&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;塞族官员说，有 52 人受伤，其中三人伤势严重。据科索沃警方称，四名抗议者被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;驻科部队指挥官 Angelo Michele Ristuccia 少将说：“双方都需要对所发生的事情承担全部责任，并防止事态进一步升级，而不是躲在虚假的叙述背后” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贝尔格莱德和普里什蒂纳互相指责对方导致局势升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，来自所谓的五胞胎国家——法国、德国、意大利、英国和美国的大使– 周一在普里什蒂纳会见了库尔蒂，周二在贝尔格莱德会见了塞尔维亚总统亚历山大·武契奇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;武契奇后来还会见了俄罗斯和中国驻塞尔维亚大使。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一份声明中在他的办公室，武契奇对库尔蒂助长对塞族人的暴力行为的国际“容忍”表示“极大的不满和强烈关注”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;确保科索沃塞族人安全的紧急措施是武契奇坚称，这是任何未来会谈的先决条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;库尔蒂感谢驻科部队“在暴力极端主义面前采取英勇行动维护和平”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯和中国都提出了尖锐批评西方支持科索沃独立。俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京经常引用 1999 年北约轰炸塞尔维亚的“先例”来为他非法吞并乌克兰部分地区辩护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1998 年科索沃冲突爆发，当时分离主义的阿尔巴尼亚族人反抗塞尔维亚的统治，塞尔维亚以残酷的镇压作为回应。大约 13,000 人死亡，其中大部分是阿尔巴尼亚族人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北约 1999 年的军事干预最终迫使塞尔维亚撤出该领土，并为驻科部队维和行动的建立铺平了道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;br >;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/一个>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong renovation saga: strength of modified load-bearing wall at flat can’t be ‘100 per cent’ restored even if legal mark fulfilled, buildings authority head warns in Lohas Park case]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3222394/hong-kong-renovation-saga-strength-modified-load-bearing-wall-flat-cant-be-100-cent-restored-even-if?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 12:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/d5246b75-4679-4b8b-b65b-0c82f02f9d31_9cde09cb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港单位改建承重墙的结构强度未必即使符合法律标准，也不能“100%”修复，该市建筑管理局负责人就私人住宅的装修争议发出警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;建筑署署长 Clarice Yu Po-mei 周三表示她所在部门的一个电台节目正在详细评估将军澳日出康城京华大厦案件的长期影响，同时向该街区的居民保证没有即时危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的重点是修复工作是否符合我们的标准……我们的标准是安全标准，”她说。 “要恢复某些东西，它怎么能 100% 恢复到在墙上开洞之前的状态？每个人都可以想象这是不可能的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;余补充说，屋宇署将确保对有关结构进行的修复工作符合法律标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该署长在另一个广播节目说，必须详细评估翻新的长期影响，她所在的部门已经开始进行审查。她补充说，公寓业主雇用的授权结构工程师还需要查看数据并计算修改墙体对整个街区的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但于强调，住宅小区不会立即出现&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此案以国会大厦一套 681 平方英尺（63 平方米）的公寓为中心，在线用户在一段显示该公寓内部的视频后猜测承重墙遭到非法改造该房屋在互联网上浮出水面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局随后发现该单位的翻新工程存在违规行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;修改墙壁的香港单位业主被勒令采取行动确保安全&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;于周三澄清说，并非所有对承重墙所做的修改都会被当局拒绝，尽管此类工作需要很多理由。 “他们将接受详细讨论。如果公寓位于最高楼层或单元面积较小，则有可能获得批准……这将取决于建筑物的设计和房屋的位置，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港工程师学会的薄国明分别向《早报》表示，涉事单位的墙体已被砍断，修复墙壁并非易事。他指出，房主不得不聘请一名注册工程师和承包商来解决这个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，最初的改造意味着建筑物中的其他墙壁必须承受更多的负荷，这可能会导致裂缝、进水渗漏可能导致钢筋生锈，损害结构完整性。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;有关改造香港公寓的所有信息以及如何安全地进行改造&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“如果问题早期发现，业主可以将钢筋上的锈迹去除并涂上防锈材料，然后将裂缝填平，防止进水，就可以解决。”Bok说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;于同时还透露，该部门已经收集了一些有关该项目幕后承包商的信息，但她补充说，在调查中她不能说更多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她表示，该部门正在收集证据，并会寻求法律途径关于是否起诉业主的建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;星期六，一段显示日出康城房屋翻新的视频引起互联网用户的怀疑，该翻新事件曝光后，卧室和客厅已被拆除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;屋宇署证实，客厅和卧室之间的 72 厘米乘 215 厘米（28 乘 85 英寸）结构墙的一部分被擅自拆除。据该部门称，单位业主已经在门口安装了临时支架。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;当局称屋顶上的太阳能电池板非法飞离香港建筑物&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;初步评估和-现场观察附近的单位，拆除部分占承重墙的6%，占整个楼层的1%，但对整体建筑结构没有风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部门表示将“在几天内”批准各方提出的修复建议，并补充说业主必须在 15 天内开始施工并在 30 天内完成。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Kevin McCarthy confident on US debt vote despite threat by hardline Republicans to oust him]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222388/kevin-mccarthy-confident-us-debt-vote-despite-threat-hardline-republicans-oust-him?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 11:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/6a0e5f95-d4a3-4420-b3ae-811d5831640b_d7ca77f5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国众议院议长凯文麦卡锡驳斥了共和党强硬派因债务问题将他赶下台的威胁-他与乔·拜登总统达成了限制协议，并表示相信立法者将及时通过立法以避免美国违约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案将于周三晚上（香港时间周四上午）在众议院投票，促使共和党国会议员 Dan Bishop 呼吁就罢免麦卡锡的议长进行投票，声称该协议给予民主党太多让步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位保守派议员 Chip Roy 承诺对麦卡锡进行“清算”，并且称这笔交易为“粪便三明治”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二被问及是否担心自己会失去议长职位时，麦卡锡回答“不”。他说，支持这项交易“对共和党人来说是一次轻松的投票”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管共和党人反对，但该法案在周二晚上清除了一个关键障碍，当时强大的众议院规则委员会以 7-6 票通过了该法案.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该立法将为未来两年的联邦支出设定方向，并将债务上限暂停至 2025 年 1 月 1 日——将另一场关于借贷的斗争推迟到总统大选之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;分析人士表示，尽管美国债务协议前景广阔，但中国仍面临风险&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;拜登和麦卡锡都表示该措施将获得通过，并且各自在阵亡将士纪念日假期的大部分时间里都在游说各自政党的成员。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;为了换取共和党对暂停的投票，民主党同意限制未来两年的联邦支出。白宫对上限的解释是告诉立法者，该协议将在十年内将支出减少约 1 万亿美元，而共和党则辩称，支出削减幅度是这个数字的两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无党派国会预算办公室周二估计，该法案将在 10 年内削减 1.5 万亿美元的赤字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案需要在众议院获得 218 票，共和党领导层依靠民主党的支持，因为他们准备支持多达 60 个222名成员叛逃。达不到要求会在政治上削弱议长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在整个众议院，至少有 17 张共和党人投了反对票。共和党的首席计票员、国会议员汤姆·埃默 (Tom Emmer) 通过电话防止这个数字膨胀到远远超过这个数字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数强硬的保守派都没有公开呼吁麦卡锡下台，尽管至少有其他保守派极端保守的众议院自由核心小组在国会大厦举行的新闻发布会上暗示要进行报复。该组织要求进一步削减联邦开支。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论发生什么，都会有一个清算，”德克萨斯州共和党人罗伊周二表示，并补充说共和党立法者已经“被撕裂了”根据协议拆分”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院通过后会将法案送交参议院。该措施需要在 6 月 5 日之前获得国会批准，届时财政部可能会在美国历史上首次用尽偿还债务的资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果财政部无法偿还债务，可能会引发经济危机美国和全球经济的混乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任何众议院议员都可以强制投票罢免议长，这需要众议院的简单多数。传统上，反对党成员不会投票支持议长，尽管一些温和的民主党人已经承诺在这种情况下支持麦卡锡。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;如果华盛顿不进行改革，美元的地位将崩溃&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;北卡罗来纳州共和党人毕晓普表示，保守派持不同政见者将决定对麦卡锡采取行动的最佳时机。没有其他共和党立法者在公开言论中明确要求罢免他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“麦卡锡已经失去了一些信任，”南卡罗来纳州国会议员拉尔夫诺曼说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共和党总统候选人对麦卡锡的挑战更加复杂宣布反对该交易的竞争者，包括佛罗里达州州长罗恩德桑蒂斯和前驻联合国大使妮基黑莉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前总统唐纳德特朗普，共和党领跑者，自交易达成以来未发表评论宣布，尽管他此前曾敦促共和党人利用违约威胁作为杠杆来实现他们想要的支出削减。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，众议院民主党领袖哈基姆杰弗里斯表示，现在讨论民主党是否会支持“为时过早” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议还激怒了民主党的左翼，国会进步核心小组主席普拉米拉·贾亚帕尔周二表示，她所在小组的大多数成员不支持削减开支，能源允许语言和法案中扩大了工作要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;进步的民主党人通常没有像另类右翼那样迅速谴责拜登或其他党派领导人。但 Jayapal 表示，约有 100 名民主党人的核心小组尚未决定是否采取正式立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社和法新社的补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan’s seafood catch has hit record lows – but there’s still plenty of salmon and anchovies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222384/japan-seafood-catch-hits-record-lows-theres-still-plenty-salmon-and-anchovies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 12:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/4071403a-d0fd-4739-ae66-63078e290749_26362b0b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;2022 年日本海产品捕捞量同比下降 7.5%，创历史新低根据政府数据，由于气候变化继续造成损失，减少了 385 万吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括养殖鱼类在内的总量是自 1956 年可比数据可用以来的最低数字根据农林渔业部发布的数据，连续第二年下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二发布的年度渔业白皮书称，该地区的捕捞量可能会持续下降&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;按类别划分，秋刀鱼比上年下降 5.6% 至 18,400 吨，而日本飞乌贼下降 8.3% 至 29,700 吨，章鱼下降 18.7% 至 22,200 吨吨——数据显示，均创历史新低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于宫城县和爱知县的渔获量不佳，沙丁鱼下降了 4.2% 至 613,200 吨，而鲭鱼则下降了 28.5% 至 315,900 吨，受低谷拖累数据显示，茨城县和三重县的数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了气候变化，过度捕捞也是导致渔获量下降的一个因素，日本政府正在努力加强监管。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;日本将秋刀鱼捕捞量下降归咎于中国大陆和台湾&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;为了更好地了解和管理资源，日本政府表示，其目标是将其监测的海洋物种数量从 2018 年的 50 种增加到 200 种左右截至本财政年度结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，鲑鱼增加了 55%，达到 87,900 吨，凤尾鱼增加了 13.3%，达到 135,100 吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在养殖品种中，扇贝增加了 4.6%至 172,100 吨，其中北海道产量增加，而鳗鱼则下降 7.3% 至 19,155 吨。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nun whose body shows little decay since 2019 death draws hundreds to US town]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222393/nun-whose-body-shows-little-decay-2019-death-draws-hundreds-us-town?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 12:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/31/255d7e79-bafe-49fd-be60-470b9cb76f8e_98636a9d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数百人涌向密苏里州的一个小镇这周也是最后一次看到一位修女，她的尸体自 2019 年以来几乎没有腐烂。有人说这是天主教圣洁的标志，而另一些人则说没有腐烂可能并不像人们想象的那么罕见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;修女根据密苏里州高尔的使徒女王玛丽本笃会的一份声明，威廉明娜·兰开斯特于 4 月被挖掘出来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;修女们一直在准备增建圣约瑟夫神殿，这涉及到声明说：“重新安葬我们敬爱的女创始人威廉米娜修女的遗体。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他们挖掘兰开斯特时，他们被告知只期待骨头，因为她被埋在一个简单的木棺中，没有四年前的任何防腐处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，他们发现了一具完整的尸体和“一个保存完好的宗教习惯，”声明说。 The nuns hadn&#39;t meant to publicise the discovery, but someone posted a private email publicly and “the news began to spread like wildfire”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Volunteers and local law enforcement have helped to manage the crowds in the town of roughly 1,800 people, as people have visited from all over the country to see and touch Lancaster&#39;s body.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;7 charged after mummified cult leader found in Colorado home &#39;shrine&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“It was pretty amazing,” said Samuel Dawson, who is Catholic and visited from Kansas City with his son last week. “It was very peaceful. Just very reverent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dawson said there were a few hundred people when he visited and that he saw many out-of-state cars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Visitors were allowed to touch her, Dawson said, adding that the nuns “wanted to make her accessible to the public … because in real life, she was always accessible to people”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The monastery said in a statement that Lancaster&#39;s body will be placed in a glass shrine in their church on Monday. Visitors will still be able to see her body and take dirt from her grave, but they won&#39;t be able to touch her.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Diocese of Kansas City-St Joseph also released a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The condition of the remains of Sister Wilhelmina Lancaster has understandably generated widespread interest and raised important questions,” the diocese said. “At the same time, it is important to protect the integrity of the mortal remains of Sister Wilhelmina to allow for a thorough investigation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Incorruptibility has been verified in the past, but it is very rare. There is a well-established process to pursue the cause for sainthood, but that has not been initiated in this case yet,” the diocese added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Benedictines of Mary, Queen of Apostles, also said that Lancaster has not yet reached the required minimum of five years since death for the sainthood process to begin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rebecca George, an anthropology instructor at Western Carolina University in North Carolina, said the body&#39;s lack of decomposition might not be as rare as people are expecting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;George said the “mummification” of un-embalmed bodies is common at the university&#39;s facility and the bodies could stay preserved for many years, if allowed to.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coffins and clothing also help to preserve bodies, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Typically, when we bury people, we don&#39;t exhume them. We don&#39;t get to look at them a couple years out,” George said. “With 100 years, there might be nothing left. But when you&#39;ve got just a few years out, this is not unexpected.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Will China’s reopening mark a shift towards sustainable tourism in Southeast Asia?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3222353/will-chinas-reopening-mark-shift-towards-sustainable-tourism-southeast-asia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/31/c04f9cf1-5485-4853-a1ce-04886ddbfaad_5e66fdf2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s tourism recovery is shaping up to be a big boost for sustainability as a shift in travel trends by the world&#39;s largest group of travellers promises to open up untapped market segments worldwide, experts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Outbound travel from China has been picking up since the country opened its borders earlier this year, although volumes lag behind 2019&#39;s pre-pandemic levels, when Chinese visitors accounted for 14 per cent of global tourism spending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The market went into virtual hibernation during three years of lockdowns, when people were mostly travelling to domestic destinations or not travelling at all.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While a full return to pre-pandemic travel abroad is expected only by the end of 2023 or early next year, a silver lining is the shift to increased demand for experiences that do less harm to the planet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am very optimistic that China will become the number one source market again and the recovery in travel will be sustainable and meaningful,” said Wolfgang Georg Arlt, CEO of the China Outbound Tourism Research Institute in Germany&#39;s Hamburg, which has helped worldwide destinations and firms attract Chinese tourists for 20 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Arlt, who recently retired from a tenure at a German university, gives guest lectures abroad, including at Sun Yat-sen University in Guangzhou.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese tourists would often travel in big groups which earned them a bad name of putting pressure on fragile ecosystems, he said, but now more people want to travel in smaller groups and stay in a single location rather than different places on package tours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This old idea of Chinese tourists travelling in big coaches, and eating only Chinese food is becoming less and less [common],” Arlt said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese travellers shun tour groups for free and easy trips to Southeast Asia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Instead, more visitors from China want to pursue the likes of nature photography, golf and camping in forests, he said, and experience local culture through homestays.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South and Southeast Asian countries including Thailand, Indonesia, the Maldives and Nepal, as well as European destinations, are anticipating a big rebound in tourism revenue following China&#39;s reopening, but they will need to play to the demands of environmentally-conscious Chinese travellers, Arlt said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tour operators will also need to offer authentic cultural experiences and be open to ideas like visitors going shopping for food with hotel chefs and cooking local dishes with them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many more Chinese people speak English these days or have apps on their phones which help to translate and communicate with local people, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hotels can also attract the new breed of travellers by showcasing their efforts for greening the planet such as by using renewable energy or recycling plastic rubbish, Arlt said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The tourism industry has to understand how the market has changed,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tourism destinations have been concerned by a relatively slow pickup in the number of Chinese tourists, but they do not realise that visa delays and capacity constraints such as the number of aircraft available have hobbled the recovery, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Domestic travel during a five-day “Golden Week” holiday in May surged to around pre-pandemic levels, indicating that a wider recovery in outbound travel is likely in the coming months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a May 29 report by risk assessment firm Moody&#39;s, tourism and consumer services companies have benefited the most from China&#39;s reopening, after the sudden disruption to business caused by the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We expect these sectors will continue to have revenue growth moderately higher than or equal to GDP growth,” Moody&#39;s said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese outbound travellers are more likely to travel in families and are likely to seek out new cultural experiences, concurred Honggen Xiao, a professor in the School of Hotel and Tourism Management at Hong Kong Polytechnic University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Smaller groups allow them more travel flexibility. On the other hand, it makes making travel arrangements easier,” he said. “This may open up the potential for the outbound market.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Families, especially from urban areas, are likely to be more conscious about environmentally-friendly lodging facilities, Xiao said. They are also more likely to opt for offbeat locations, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are already signs that Chinese travellers are taking part in sustainable tourism, said Kelly Shen, business director for travel and lifestyle at Gusto Collective, a leading brand technology group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, some are paying more for eco-friendly travel options such as green transport and responsible wildlife tourism. “Some Chinese travel players are investing to offer sustainable travel packages and promote sustainable tourism practices,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The recovery in outbound travel is still nascent but discernible in certain locations like Thailand, where Chinese tourist arrivals have exceeded 1 million since the start of the year, according to a Bloomberg report this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Southeast Asia is better prepared than long-haul destinations like Europe or North America “because of proximity and cultural similarities” Xiao said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the region&#39;s tourism industry must work hard to ensure it can meet the changed demands placed on it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are seeing an increasing number of hotels and tour operators pursue sustainability certifications to demonstrate their commitment to responsible tourism,” said Hannah Pearson, director of Pear Anderson, which specialises in advising on tourism strategies for Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Smarter destinations and tourism operators who watched consumer trends during the pandemic “will have realised that their long-held preconceptions about Chinese outbound travellers – that they like to travel in big groups, and only care about shopping and taking vanity photos – is long outdated”, Pearson said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Chinese travellers are taking sustainability increasingly seriously,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blessed with natural resources, Southeast Asia can position itself as the centre of sustainable tourism in Asia, she said, highlighting that on May 24 Unesco designated an additional six national parks in the region as Global Geoparks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These areas combine conservation with sustainable development while involving local communities. There are almost 200, across some 50 nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new sustainable travel trend is also creating opportunities for filling up “empty months and empty areas” – or slack periods and offbeat locations – as Chinese tourists are increasingly open to new ideas, unlike many European tourists who have fixed preferences like going to a beach in the summer, Arlt said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How Malaysia came to have a French city in the rainforest – thanks to Mahathir&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For example, the Camino de Santiago in Spain, a 100km-plus walking pilgrimage to the Cathedral of Santiago de Compostela – where the remains of apostle Saint James the Elder are said to be – can be marketed in China because it has a large Christian population, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After three years of pent-up demand, he said wealthier Chinese travellers are also likely to be willing to spend more.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others say the speed with which different segments of the tourism industry respond to shifting patterns of demand is bound to vary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gary Bowerman, director of Check-In Asia, a travel consulting and consumer research firm, said some “will lead the way, others will lag behind”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It will be fascinating to watch the speed with which Chinese tourists align themselves with responsible travel providers, because this could frame the way global tourism faces up to the challenges ahead.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China leads the world in preparing for extreme weather threats to power supplies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3222386/china-leads-world-preparing-extreme-weather-threats-power-supplies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 11:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/31/43e9a3b8-adda-48ce-aa66-f26c7ef7cb17_26fe37ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;It&#39;s not even June, and China is fielding sweltering temperatures in Shanghai, and peak power demand from Guangdong to Hainan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Extreme weather is already promising a fresh test of the electricity grid just months after heatwaves and drought throttled hydropower and triggered widespread power shortages. The good news is that China is better prepared than many other countries, according to a report from The Lantau Group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Learning lessons from China will be important for grid operators around the world as a warming planet makes once rare climate events more commonplace – and more necessary to plan for. While the Chinese government has been quick to respond to the threat, it&#39;s less clear that other countries, including the US, are rising to the challenge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last summer, the worst drought in decades dried up parts of the Yangtze River, reducing the amount of electricity that China&#39;s mighty dams could produce. At the same time, heatwaves caused power demand from air conditioners to surge. The combination forced officials to shut down factories for weeks in Sichuan province, and industrial activity has been curtailed for months in Yunnan, both hydropower-reliant areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The response has been fast, according to Lantau Group&#39;s Mike Thomas and David Fishman. At the end of last year, Sichuan announced it would build a fleet of new gas-fired power plants and more transmission lines connecting the province to neighbouring grids. In Guangdong, which relies on imported hydropower from Yunnan, officials unexpectedly approved 17 gigawatts of new coal-fired plants, part of a massive buildout across the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Will China&#39;s approach to future-proofing its grid from future disruptions to generation succeed? We think so,” Thomas and Fishman wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In other parts of the world, not so much. For many operators, having too much excess capacity sitting idle is inefficient and raises costs. The California and Texas grids have suffered shortages in recent years thanks to growing demand and extreme weather, yet neither is making big changes to the way they model future weather risks and the need for more reliable supply, said Thomas and Fishman.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the outcome is that more money must be spent on grid resiliency, even at the risk of redundancy, it&#39;s still going to be far less costly than the outages or disruptions caused by next year&#39;s unanticipated 100-year drought that knocks out half of the grid hydro,” they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That isn&#39;t to downplay the problems China faces. Hydropower is likely to be challenged again this year, according to Citigroup, citing a 90 per cent probability of an El Nino weather pattern between May and July that could bring another round of heatwaves. The bank downgraded China Yangtze Power this week because of weaker hydropower utilisation and assumptions that low rainfall will persist.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cities in eastern China may face electricity shortages during peak hours this summer, while central and southern areas could also see tight power supplies, according to a report by Shanghai Securities News on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Mum doesn’t want to let go’: Hong Kong man, 30, must tell mother his whereabouts when with friends and prove with video call]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3221800/mum-doesnt-want-let-go-hong-kong-man-30-must-tell-mother-his-whereabouts-when-friends-and-prove?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.31 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/59aea6aa-affe-4fbc-8f3e-5fed2e1f36a6_5200ffc8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The behaviour of a Hong Kong mother who keeps a tight rein on her 30-year-old son has been publicly exposed after details of their unhealthy relationship were posted online by a concerned friend of the son.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The post was made by an unidentified woman on Hong Kong&#39;s popular DiscussHK forum, describing the intensely close relationship between her long-suffering friend and his “controlling” mother. The post was first published late last year but received renewed interest after a local media outlet HK01 reported it earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman wrote that she has a male friend about to turn 30 who has his comings and goings strictly monitored by his mother, to whom he has to explain his every action and seek her permission for just about everything.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Does this mother care about her son, or does she just not trust him? My friend is a mature person. Why does he still need to be so strictly watched?” the woman asked in the post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Sometimes I don&#39;t even want to hang out with him because I don&#39;t want his mother to call me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mother&#39;s invasive behaviour and attempts to control her son did not end there; the friend described how the mother would ask her son to provide the names and phone numbers of any friends he was spending time with, justifying it by claiming she feared being unable to contact him in an emergency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once the mother received her son&#39;s friends&#39; details, she would call each of them to check if they were with her son. If his friends answered her call, she would remind them to be careful going out and not stay out too late.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then, on top of this layer of surveillance, on the days her son went out, she would make video calls so she could see if he had lied about where he was and who he was with.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On DiscussHK forum, most of the more than 80 comments on the post felt the mother was too strict and controlling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This mum doesn&#39;t want to let her son go,” said one person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person said: “Sometimes this kind of mother can drive her children crazy and make it hard for them to get along with others in the future.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some saw the humour in the story, with one person joking: “It&#39;s not strict at all. She didn&#39;t even ask to go out with her son.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few people defended the mother for caring so much, with one person commenting: “It&#39;s a blessing to still have a mother in charge at 30. Cherish it!”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 31 May 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>