<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s West Kowloon Cultural District CEO on a mission to beat money woes, says arts hub was ‘jumping on one leg’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3229188/hong-kongs-west-kowloon-cultural-district-ceo-mission-beat-money-woes-says-arts-hub-was-jumping-one?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/f85ecbd5-5871-44cb-bc76-ecf503b8a7c2_bfa7bebe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;冯程淑仪出任西方行政总裁后震惊不已九龙文化区管理局于 2021 年底管理该市最新的艺术地标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前公务员对该法定机构的财务状况感到震惊。她越检查，就越担心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我接手时，那是有史以来最糟糕、最糟糕的时期，”她回忆道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被授权获得当局的财务资助健康和运营步入正轨后，她发现该机构的现金只够维持到 2023 年底。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我开始深入了解该机构的财务状况时，这真的很可怕，”她在接受《华盛顿邮报》采访时告诉《华盛顿邮报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港艺术中心的管理机构正在寻找资金以避免金融危机&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府早就明确表示，在注入资金后不太可能注入任何新资金2008 年斥资 216 亿港元（28 亿美元）设立捐赠基金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;占地 40 公顷（99 英亩）的艺术中心是世界上最大的文化区之一，自 1990 年代以来一直在建设中，但它的第一个标志性景点——当代艺术博物馆 M+，直到 2021 年才开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几十年来，由于一系列问题，从政治角力到发展计划的变化、管理层的改组、 Covid-19大流行以及在邻近地点建造西九龙高铁总站的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个明星景点香港故宫文化博物馆的突然加入，使财务状况变得更加复杂。时任特首林郑月娥于 2016 年宣布。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港“0+3”监控期间“应允许游客进入博物馆”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;36 亿港元该项目于去年 7 月开放，展示北京故宫博物院的中国国宝，未经公众咨询就被纳入其中，其建设由香港赛马会资助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该项目的其他关键组成部分艺术中心包括中国戏曲设施、戏曲中心、当代表演场地自由空间以及适合家庭和宠物的艺术公园，其中演艺综合剧场预计将于 2025 年开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冯先生的说法并不夸张。她描述了该机构严峻的财务困境。截至去年 3 月的财政年度，其亏损从 2021 年的 8.69 亿港元翻倍至 15.6 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，到今年 3 月，其亏损已削减至 7.18 亿港元，收入则有所上升2021-22 年度增长 13.7% 至 6.3526 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我当公务员已有 35 年，但我现在非常有创业精神，”她说。 “我告诉各级同事，他们必须真正以业务为导向。他们必须非常注意自己花的钱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管有所改善，但她说当局还远没有脱离险境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fung 表示，她开始时的首要任务是首席执行官将大幅削减成本，这导致 2022-23 年赤字从预计的 10.7 亿港元减少三分之一至 7.18 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这意味着其可用资金将延长 16 个月到 2025 年将超过预期，而不是在今年年底用完。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 Fung 表示，她无法在未来一年继续削减成本。员工队伍已经很精简，设施还需要空调和保安，节目必须定期更改以吸引游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我只见骨头，不见肉”，她说。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;“设施越多，赤字就越大”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;艺术中心融资问题的核心在于其独特的融资模式中收入与支出之间的滞后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;该机构的资金本应来自该地区商业开发（包括酒店和办公楼）所产生的收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，疫情和房地产市场的变化导致了土地招标的延迟。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;第一个商业地块在 2 月份未能吸引投标者后，去年 11 月才被授予。当局将发展项目的营运期延长13年至47年后，新鸿基地产成为唯一中标的699,654平方英尺（65,000平方米）土地，估价105亿港元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开发商表示，艺术广场塔楼项目将拥有三座办公楼，设有零售、餐饮和娱乐空间，预计将于 2026 年竣工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据协议，该开发项目的所有权运营期结束后将移交给管理局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冯表示，修改后的条款意味着管理局从办公室租金中获得的收入将减少，并且必须为2025-2070年提出新的融资方式.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到2025年演艺剧场竣工时，它也将面临更大的赤字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们开放的设施越多，赤字就越大，”冯说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，收入和支出就像两条腿，一起跑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们已经用一条腿跳了很长一段时间，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;p>;她表示，基础设施的建设和运营已经耗尽了政府捐赠。由于没有大量收入，长期不匹配。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位接近当局的消息人士表示，创收项目应该先于博物馆和表演场馆建设。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消息人士称：“不幸的是，天知道是什么原因——可能是官僚作风、不明智的决定、简单的错误——他们却采取了相反的做法。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冯透露，在大流行对在房地产市场上，管理局正在改革其融资模式，该模式是政府于 2016 年批准的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她预计办公室租赁空间将出现过剩，这可能会导致去年 12% 的空置率进一步恶化。疫情还重塑了城市的工作模式，越来越多的人远程工作，进一步抑制了对办公空间的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据房地产公司戴德梁行称，今年上半年写字楼整体租金继续呈下降趋势和韦克菲尔德的办公楼空置率达到 2020 年第三季度以来的最高水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构正在研究如何改革其商业模式，例如，最大限度地利用尚未招标的土地.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;门票销售是核心收入来源&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与世界上一些最知名的博物馆不同，例如主要由国家资助的巴黎卢浮宫和古根海姆四大博物馆私人资助的博物馆，香港的 M+ 和故宫博物院属于公私合作模式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旧金山大学研究博物馆资助的教授约翰·扎罗贝尔 (John Zarobell) 表示，还有其他博物馆公私合作的模式，但据他所知，西九文化区管理局的基金是唯一一个不依赖政府支持运营，而是靠自身发展的基金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是史无前例的” ，“ 他说。 “这是基于这样一个事实，即城市发展会产生更多资源……所有这些优势不是私下获得，而是被推入公共领域，不是直接推向市政府，而是推向机构本身。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;专门研究博物馆管理、曾任艺术中心博物馆顾问小组成员的中文大学何庆基教授表示，M+被设想为“视觉文化”的空间，主要是更少漫画等昂贵的作品和廉价的街头设计。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不幸的是，它似乎正在收集绘画、雕塑、装置等主流艺术，相比之下，这些艺术品的价格更高，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;故宫博物院是一个计划外的项目，大大增加了枢纽的成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“运营一个价值极高的古董博物馆 - 维护、保险、运输 - 的成本要高得多。比当代艺术博物馆还贵，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，除非有大量资金，“这将是一场灾难”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港文化中心正在寻找竞标者第一个商业项目&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;首先，游客需要支付更多费用才能参观故宫博物院。 9月27日，普通入场费将由成人50港元上涨20%至60港元，优惠票价将从25港元上涨至30港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;M+的成人及优惠一般入场费与香港相同票价分别为120元和60港元，而特别展览则采取灵活的定价结构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如“草间弥生：1945年至今”展览的标准票价为240港元，而即将举行的“宋女士： “先锋艺术与时尚在中国”展览的标准票价为港币140元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;入场费是两间博物馆的核心收入，也吸引企业赞助其项目。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;冯先生指出，两间博物馆的成本回收率（成本回收率占机构营运成本的百分比）表现良好，因此百分比越高越好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两家博物馆的成本回收率均位居前列。她表示，M+ 博物馆的收视率为 46%，故宫博物院为 44%，为全球最高，而纽约大都会博物馆为 36%，新加坡国家博物馆为 10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与她补充说，除了香港的两家博物馆之外，世界各地的许多博物馆都获得政府的运营资助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至于香港的政府运营博物馆，例如香港科学馆和香港艺术馆，其成本回收率分别为 7% 和 2.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府目前运营着 15 个公共博物馆，涵盖视觉艺术、科学和历史等领域。它们隶属于康乐及文化事务署，2022-2023年的营运开支达11.6亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;M+过去一年的收入来源之一来自输出日本艺术家弥生的策展服务草间弥生的圆点艺术作品向西班牙毕尔巴鄂古根海姆博物馆展出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港的展览于今年 5 月结束前的六个月内吸引了 280,000 名参观者。在西班牙，它在 6 月开幕的一周内吸引了 35,000 名观众。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们首次针对成立一年的博物馆举办的特别展览可以在古根海姆举办 - 这对于西班牙的任何博物馆来说都是一件大事。 ”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从长远来看，她希望政府能够制定全面的政策来支持文化艺术产业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然她总是想着钱，冯对艺术中心的未来感到乐观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她说，如果不是缺乏资金，现在就是充分发挥这一大型项目潜力的时候了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们问我，‘为什么你总是谈论金钱？’我必须谈谈钱。如果我没有钱，我什么也做不了。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[From Singapore to Australia, hybrid work sparks a ‘fundamental shift’ in office demand]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3229309/singapore-australia-hybrid-work-sparks-fundamental-shift-office-demand?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/5f8affd7-69ef-45b9-8af7-19ef25ca4fb7_9c404513.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;索尼娅*，澳大利亚一家游戏公司的技术主管，拒绝了一份工作今年早些时候，在她未来的雇主告诉她必须每天都在办公室后，索尼娅就向她提供了工作机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;索尼娅是一位一直在抚养女儿和事业之间取得平衡的单亲家长，她表示在家工作的常态化疫情使她能够在家办公，这改善了她的工作与生活平衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于索尼娅来说，全职出勤现在是一个大问题，她过去一年半要出差往返她位于悉尼中央商务区的办公室的往返时间为数小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这不仅仅是通勤成本，我知道我要去吃午餐、两到三杯咖啡......在家工作“我的私人生活感觉更快乐，”她说，并补充说，她的日常生活让她每天都能接女儿放学，并在她睡觉前花时间陪伴她。 “过去，一切都与工作有关。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;疫情后在家办公的现象已在整个亚太地区扎根，而不仅仅是在澳大利亚，但这种新工作文化的强度因国家而异&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在家办公的广泛接受代表了办公室使用方式的范式转变，而此时，由于利率上升和大流行的结束，整个地区和世界的经济正在放缓。时代支出闪电战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然经济周期通常是办公室需求的主要驱动力，但这次一个新的非经济因素也在影响需求：员工将福祉置于工作之上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;这两种力量（工作习惯的改变和经济放缓）同时作用的结果是，整个地区的办公楼里一排排空荡荡的办公桌在闪闪发光的办公楼后面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个根本性转变。新加坡物业服务公司戴德梁行 (Cushman &amp; Wakefield) 亚洲租户代表董事总经理马克·兰帕德 (Mark Lampard) 表示，无论经济衰退如何，这都是我们在房地产领域见过的最大变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们从在入住率达到 90% 到 100% 的情况下，我们让每个人都呆在家里……因此，这两股力量绝对以比我们在[2007-08]全球金融危机期间看到的更加明显的方式推动着我们。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;旧金山市中心能在亚太经合组织峰会之前摆脱低迷吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然亚太地区的情况没有那么严重，但空置的办公室正在成为许多西方经济体的一个担忧，特别是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在旧金山，随着经济低迷，科技公司大规模裁员，据数据显示，上季度末办公室空置率达到创纪录的31.6%房地产服务公司 CBRE。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;疫情爆发之前，该市办公室空置率徘徊在 4% 左右，但现在大约有三分之一的办公桌是空的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在英国二十年后，汇丰银行决定缩小规模并搬出位于金丝雀码头的总部，理由是在家办公文化或混合工作方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港的办公室曾经几乎没有多余的空间，现在却被搬走了。看起来越来越空虚。不过，根据世邦魏理仕的说法，罪魁祸首是中国企业的办公楼需求低于预期，而不是在家办公。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;物业服务公司仲量联行表示，6 月底香港办公室的空置率为 12.6% – 是 2019 年底 5.9% 的两倍多。根据 Cushman &amp; Wakefield 的数据，如果包括未来 12 个月内将竣工的新办公室，空置率甚至更高，达到 17.3%。&lt;/ p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与房地产市场一样，商业地产（包括写字楼）等主要资产市场的崩溃是银行业危机的先兆，这可能会进一步降低信心并加深当前的全球经济危机。经济低迷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年的廉价债务和低利率导致投资者购买商业地产，特别是办公楼，因为事实证明它们比银行里的现金更有利可图。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在写字楼资产投资者正受到需求放缓、租金下降以及利率上升的打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着偿还银行贷款变得越来越困难，投资者也难以为贷款再融资，因为成本高昂。借贷降低了他们的投资价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“写字楼投资长期以来一直是一种备受青睐的资产类别，可提供可靠的风险调整回报。然而，在新的大流行后环境中，该行业面临着一系列新的挑战，这促使投资者质疑旧的正统观念，”物业服务公司第一太平戴维斯 (Savills) 的西蒙·史密斯 (Simon Smith)、南希·王 (Nancy Wong) 和亚当·埃文内特 (Adam Evennett) 在上周的一份报告中表示。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;写字楼房地产市场正在走向一个转折点——尤其是在美国，违约业主可能被迫交出钥匙，这唤起了人们对次贷危机的记忆。经济学家还担心，如果真的发生贷款违约海啸，美国银行体系可能会崩溃，从而导致全球蔓延。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但根据星展银行发布的一份报告，这种情况发生的可能性很低。银行首席投资办公室 5 月份表示，如今全球银行已经做好了更充分的准备，写字楼市场的任何崩溃只会伤害美国的地区性银行。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然不是第一太平戴维斯 (Savills) 的 Smith、Wong 和 Evennett 等专家表示，由于不受增长放缓和在家办公做法的影响，亚太地区的办公楼需求比欧洲或北美更有支撑力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;需求变化的方式也各不相同跨越新加坡和香港等国际中心（这两个城市都有国内外对办公室的需求）、雅加达等新兴亚洲市场以及悉尼和奥克兰等更成熟的市场，在这些市场，在家办公文化已变得根深蒂固。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;根据高纬环球 (Cushman &amp; Wakefield) 的数据，新加坡最高质量的“A 级”写字楼空置率仅为 4.3%，但与其他市场一样，这一数字正在上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在“我的办公室，大家都回来了。”一位不愿透露姓名的当地房东说道，并补充说在家办公在新加坡并不像其他地方那么突出。他说，员工很乐意返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有大量的空办公桌，主要是因为新加坡有很多外国利益以及本地需求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cushman 说写字楼需求受到“在东南亚强劲增长前景、中国重新开放以及财富持续流入新加坡的情况下不断迁往新加坡”的推动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管竞争对手香港的写字楼市场受到了冲击由于大量的职位空缺，新加坡似乎取得了相反的效果。例如，主要开发商国浩房地产表示，其位于新加坡中央商务区的新国浩城办公楼的 80% 已获得预先承诺的租赁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新加坡培育并推动了需求，而每个人都在努力培育和推动需求。其他人发现这样做更具挑战性，”兰帕德说。 “政府很快就建立了旅行走廊，然后开放国际旅行返回新加坡。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;良好的交通网络也让新加坡人更容易返回办公室，从而提高了入住率”，兰帕德补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，随着新加坡经济在今年第一季度出现收缩，盔甲上的一些漏洞已经开始出现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然经济挑战仍然存在第一太平戴维斯 (Savills) 在 5 月份的一份报告中表示，就在六个月前，市场还认为科技行业是办公空间需求的驱动力，而科技行业则面临着更多的融资问题，租金仍在上涨，尽管涨幅不大。 p>;&lt;h3>;为何香港人与“老派”老板就重返办公室展开拉锯战&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港人也在重返办公室——不仅因为交通高效，还因为他们的家第一太平戴维斯 (Savills) 的史密斯表示，这些城市规模较小。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;史密斯表示，但由于中国大陆对办公空间的需求低迷，再加上世界上一些最严厉的新冠疫情限制措施导致外国企业大量外流，这座城市正面临着困境。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“内地对写字楼的需求并没有真正像人们希望的那样强劲回归，我认为这背后的很大一部分原因就是中国目前的经济形势，这并没有让企业据彭博社报道，香港亿万富翁李嘉诚的长江中心 6 月份空置率约为 25%。该大楼的租户纷纷撤离，其中包括杰富瑞金融集团 (Jefferies Financial Group) 和本月初离开的联合办公企业 The Great Room。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国的缓慢复苏也影响了该公司的发展。房地产机构莱坊印度尼西亚表示，疫情影响了印度尼西亚的商业活动和对办公室的部分需求，但疫情造成的损失更大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莱坊租户策略和解决方案副总监 Rina Martianti 表示，疫情造成的损失更大。商业活动冻结了两年，即使在边境开放后，商业活动仍然受到抑制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些当地企业也选择采用混合在家办公模式，这进一步降低了对办公空间的需求，Martianti 说，并补充说，一些企业新的优质“甲级”建筑仅占 30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“明年我们将举行选举，因此 [企业] 会出现‘观望’的情况， ”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莱坊的数据显示，在印度尼西亚主要城市雅加达，办公室入住率为 73%，而疫情之前为 77%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下降房地产公司仲量联行亚太研究团队表示，到目前为止，办公空间规模一直很小，但预计入住率将随着租金继续下降，该团队在今年早些时候的预测中表示，企业将选择较小的办公室以节省成本和签署租约需要更长的时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在悉尼第二大中央商务区帕拉马塔，这里曾经是一个炙手可热的写字楼市场，尤其是对银行租户来说，租赁代理罗伯特·卡拉姆 (Robert Karam)商业机构 Khoury 本周在亚洲展示了空置一年的办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Karam 表示，自疫情爆发以来，政府机构等租户不断缩小曾经 1000 平方米或 1000 平方米的宽敞办公室的规模。更多的是面积只有 200 或 300 平方米的较小的办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他引用了一位抵押贷款经纪人的例子，这位抵押贷款经纪人搬出了该地区的一间大型办公室，然后告诉房东，它将考虑重新租赁该地区内一个较小的细分空间。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，房东现在正在分割他们的办公室，并向租户提供高达租金 50% 的经济激励措施，例如免租期或装修办公室的捐款吸引他们签署租约。过去，相当于租金30%的激励措施被认为是很高的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们对细分不满意，但如果不这样做，他们将不得不等待两年才能找到租户。”卡拉姆说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khoury 董事总经理 Anthony Khoury 表示，WFH 文化已经席卷了澳大利亚所有主要城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[电信公司] 位于布里斯班阿德莱德街的 Telstra有九层楼，大约有 10 个人在里面工作，”他说。 “如果你是业主……我会对你说，‘看，至少两到三年内会很艰难’。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khoury 表示，Parramatta 的空置率已接近最高水平。超过 20% 的办公室空置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汤姆·布罗德里克 (Tom Broderick) 表示，避免因公共交通供应不足而导致的长途通勤是澳大利亚办公室工作人员在家办公的主要动机之一世邦魏理仕澳大利亚办公室和资本市场研究主管。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科技工作者索尼娅表示，她每天利用不用通勤节省下来的三个小时来“终于做一些运动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;澳大利亚在家办公的文化如此根深蒂固，以至于在过去的一个月里，联邦银行的员工威胁说，如果他们被迫返回办公室，就会辞职，而悉尼兰德威克市议会的工作人员则对管理层结束混合工作的决定表示抗议。&lt;/ p>;&lt;h3>;在家工作：一场正在酝酿的革命&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;不同城市的粘性各不相同。布罗德里克说，珀斯和布里斯班等在大流行期间封锁较少的城市比墨尔本和悉尼更成功地鼓励员工返回办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;墨尔本是澳大利亚封锁最多的城市疫情期间，该市6月底的写字楼空置率为16.2%。仲量联行的研究显示，所有州首府的空置率也持续激增，除了堪培拉之外，目前每个州的空置率都达到了两位数。澳大利亚首都受到政府租约的支撑，空置率为 7.1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于劳动力市场紧张且员工流失可能会带来问题，公司可能会犹豫是否强迫员工重返办公室”，布罗德里克说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为没有人会幻想它会回到每周五天......但我认为期望是长期的，它将达到更加标准化的水平，人们不再是平均每周在家三天，而是平均只在家一天或两天。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，写字楼投资者不仅细分他们的办公室，还考虑改造他们的办公室他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布罗德里克和许多观察家一样，乐观地认为空置问题不会迅速恶化，而是保持“稳定状态”——除非当前的经济危机恶化。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;*应受访者要求隐去姓氏&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mango pits as pets: young people in China ‘raise’ hairy seeds like dogs and cats, grooming them, even keeping bizarre diary]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3229001/mango-pits-pets-young-people-china-raise-hairy-seeds-dogs-and-cats-grooming-them-even-keeping?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/c782b3e0-8398-4f09-a8c0-751c332daac9_b2815de6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;似乎一只简单的猫或狗已经不足以满足年轻人的渴望中国的动物爱好者们现在奇怪地把芒果核当作“宠物”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新的“动物”伴侣时尚，年轻人用芒果种子发芽的毛来塑造“宠物”，网络媒体《九派新闻》7月20日报道后，震惊了大陆社交媒体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种奇怪的做法与去年出现的大学生用纸板制作“宠物”的类似怪异趋势相似。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;业主们表示，他们毛茸茸的芒果坑宠物给他们带来了与狗或猫一样的快乐，并为他们提供了治疗上的舒适感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一个案例中，一所 19 岁的大学来自中国北方港口城市天津的刘姓学生自五月以来一直在养两只这样的宠物，甚至在中国类似 Instagram 的社交媒体平台小红书上保留了这对宠物的“芒果坑日记”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;到目前为止，她已经发布了 11 篇关于大毛和二毛的日记，或者说毛一和毛二，她都将它们指定为女性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘记录了芒果核质地的变化&#39; 的头发，并详细介绍了头发如何从干燥、多刺发展为“拍起来非常舒服”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日记还记录了芒果种子从黄色到白色的颜色变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一位芒果坑养者小萌告诉九拍新闻，饲养理想的坑宠需要主人购买合适品种的芒果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;培育“宠物”需要付出很大的努力。 ”因为种子不仅需要清洗和刷子，还需要在阳光下放置一段时间以防止发霉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以刘为例，小萌一边用吹风机刷芒果核，一边使其蓬松。 ，将芦荟凝胶涂在种子上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘形容她的两个“女儿”是“理想的宠物”，是“仓鼠的廉价替代品”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说她的室友还养了一个毛茸茸的同伴芒果，但“没有我的好看”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在刘的社交媒体帖子下，评论者甚至自愿成为芒果坑的“阿姨”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“护发素和护肤霜会让头发变得更光滑吗？”一个人问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个人补充道：“我觉得大毛看起来更安静，而二毛似乎性格活泼。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三个人支持这种时尚：“太好了，毕业后可以把这些宠物带回家，我们没有看到宠物猫和狗被遗弃。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人表示，这种奇怪的做法让他们想起了几年前出现的一种趋势，人们在阳光下晒太阳。 -将芒果核晒干并着色，制成发夹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，在Covid-19中国大学封锁期间，全国各地的许多学生用纸板制作了狗和猫，以求“精神安慰”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“纸板狗不会老，不会生病，永远在门口等我。”一名学生在微博上说道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s West Kowloon Cultural District Authority searches for money to avert financial crisis as endowment set to run out in 2025]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3229308/hong-kongs-west-kowloon-cultural-district-authority-searches-money-avert-financial-crisis-endowment?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/f00a1690-235d-4ee7-8512-bef854483e51_2517ea77.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;西九文化区管理当局已将香港艺术中心的商业模式纳入一位高级官员告诉《华盛顿邮报》，将进行审查，以最大限度地提高收入并避免金融危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西九文化区管理局首席执行官程淑仪透露，该机构正在重新考虑该机构的商业组成部分两个区域，称为 2A 和 2B，尚未招标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，当局可能不会遵循艺术中心另一个区域（标记为 3B）的建设-运营-转让和收入共享模式，去年年底招标时采用的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府在 2016 年批准的模式，称为强化财务安排，对我们构成了巨大挑战，”冯先生在周一接受采访时表示，并指出该安排下的开发项目将主要是办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她强调了近年来，由于疫情使远程工作变得司空见惯，办公室空置率很高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然，使用相同的模式并不意味着”不工作，对吧？”她说。 “我正在研究最初的开发计划中允许哪些内容，”她补充道，指的是政府在 2016 年授予的建造酒店、办公室和住宅区的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当当局批准时该公司成立于 2008 年，政府为整个片区的开发提供了 216 亿港元（30 亿美元）的一次性捐赠，冯表示，目前这笔资金足以持续到 2025 年 3 月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 3B区的商业部分面积为65,000平方米（699,660平方英尺），于去年11月以估计105亿港元的价格授予新鸿基地产，经营期为47年，包括设计和建造。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s struggling arts hub pins hopes on mainland Chinese tourists&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The operation period was extended by 13 years as a sweetener after the tender attracted no interest in February last year amid a weak market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun Hung Kai will hand over ownership of the development to the authority in 2070 under the build-operate-transfer model. Three grade-A office towers there are expected to be completed in 2026.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vincent Cheung, managing director of Vincorn Consulting and Appraisal, said the estimated rental revenue could be more than HK$13 billion annually, referencing rents of the office building directly opposite the arts hub, the International Commerce Centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Fung said the estimate would only amount to a small cash injection for the arts hub. She is searching for sustainable income before 2070 when the authority gains 100 per cent of the development&#39;s earnings. The split of the rental income between the developer and the authority has not been publicised.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong Palace Museum to raise admission prices by 20 per cent&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“But what about 2025 to 2070? That is a long time. We have to think about how to come up with financial resources to support the district,” Fung told the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said even if residential units were built, they would not be a panacea for all of the hub&#39;s financial ills because of the 20 per cent, or 172,000 square metres, cap on residential uses in the total gross floor area of the cultural district.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I hope the government will be flexible in looking at what we are going to develop here,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In reply to the Post&#39;s inquiry, the Culture, Sports, and Tourism Bureau noted that the arts precinct operated on a self-financing basis and the government would continue to support the authority&#39;s “proactive key revenue generation strategy leveraging sponsorships, venue hire and the commercial development projects”.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden publicly acknowledges 7th grandchild, Hunter’s daughter, for the first time]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229336/biden-publicly-acknowledges-7th-grandchild-hunters-daughter-first-time?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 08:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/1be1742b-22bc-4433-a876-522f3705eda5_ac79228b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden on Friday for the first time publicly acknowledged his seventh grandchild, a four-year-old girl fathered by his son Hunter with an Arkansas woman, Lunden Roberts, in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our son Hunter and Navy&#39;s mother, Lunden, are working together to foster a relationship that is in the best interests of their daughter, preserving her privacy as much as possible going forward,” Biden said in a statement. It was his first acknowledgement of the child.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is not a political issue, it&#39;s a family matter,” he said. “Jill and I only want what is best for all of our grandchildren, including Navy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hunter Biden&#39;s paternity was established by DNA testing after Roberts sued for child support, and the two parties recently resolved outstanding child support issues. The president&#39;s son wrote about his encounter with Roberts in his 2021 memoir, saying it came while he was deep in addiction to alcohol and drugs, including crack cocaine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I had no recollection of our encounter,” he wrote. “That&#39;s how little connection I had with anyone. I was a mess, but a mess I&#39;ve taken responsibility for.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A lawyer for Roberts did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The president, who has made a commitment to family central to his public persona, has faced increasing criticism from political rivals and pundits for failing to acknowledge the granddaughter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a person familiar with the matter, he was taking the cue from his son while the legal proceedings played out. The person spoke on condition of anonymity to discuss private matters.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hunter Biden pleads not guilty to tax crimes after plea deal unravels&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hunter Biden has four other children, including a son, Beau, born by his wife Melissa Cohen in 2020. He was named after the president&#39;s late son who died of cancer in 2015, leaving behind two children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden&#39;s grandchildren have played a distinctive role in his presidency, often accompanying the president or first lady on trips and making regular visits to the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The president has also credited his grandchildren with persuading him to challenge then President Donald Trump for the White House in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden&#39;s statement was first reported by People Magazine.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As culture and finance intersect, a chance to invest in music royalties and support Cantopop]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3228988/culture-and-finance-intersect-chance-invest-music-royalties-and-support-cantopop?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/98236224-876e-4144-96ae-d61b4f94370c_dd6a3a45.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;At a shopping centre or in the comfort of home, music accompanies us everywhere. But have you ever imagined being able to earn royalties on your favourite songs?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The phrase “copyright trading” has become increasingly popular, even appearing for the first time in Hong Kong Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu&#39;s policy address last year, after China&#39;s 14th five-year plan envisioned Hong Kong becoming a centre for regional intellectual property trading and international cultural exchange.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While we traditionally associate copyright trading with buying the rights to an illustration or literary work through licensing and assignment, it can take a variety of forms. A platform has recently emerged in South Korea that lets retail investors buy the rights to song royalties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musicow works by paying artists a sum upfront for rights to their song royalties, before splitting the rights into smaller shares and putting them up for auction. Based on streaming activities, investors receive royalties each month and can also trade their shares through the platform. So far, the company has accumulated more than 200 billion won (US$157 million) in investments, with transactions worth twice that.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Music as an asset class is not a new concept. As the music industry has moved from a transaction-based to a subscription-based model in recent years, music content is more accessible than ever. Musicow has jumped onto this trend by bringing investment in songs – something previously reserved for large corporations – to retail investors. As the streaming model has matured, music royalties have become more predictable, making it attractive to investors looking to diversify.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fractional investment platforms like these are particularly welcomed by young investors. The barriers to entry are low – some rights are available for less than HK$100, or US$13 – and it is a new way to engage with and own a small stake in the cultural works they enjoy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musicow features songs by well-known K-pop stars, including IU and Exo. For lesser-known creators, the platform could also theoretically provide an avenue to channel financial support. The initial lump sum payment for music rights helps artists secure short-term finance and once the rights are auctioned, they receive half the profits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Musicow&#39;s model is not unique. SongVest in the United States and ANote Music in Europe also allow investment in music royalties. A new platform, JKBX (pronounced Jukebox), is also due to open this year with over US$4 billion of music rights. On the Chinese mainland, music streaming service NetEase Cloud Music has a similar service.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These platforms not only help to capture members of the public beyond regular fan bases, but also show the financial viability of music as an asset class.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Music offers a unique investment opportunity. Revenue from recorded music is relatively immune to economic downturns, and offers recurring income, which is particularly attractive amid low interest rates and dividends. The adoption of new technologies also promises to lower the risk, for example, in the use of artificial intelligence and big data to improve valuations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Private equity giants like Blackstone have invested billions into back catalogues and Goldman Sachs expects the recorded music industry to exceed US$50 billion by 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cantopop may not be in its golden years, but Hong Kong&#39;s music scene is still thriving. The likes of Beyond and Anita Mui still have an active audience base, with hundreds of thousands of monthly listeners on Spotify. New artists have been steadily gaining popularity, such as Keung To, MC Cheung and Gareth.T, to name a few.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This way of monetising and trading copyrights illustrates how the music and finance industries can collaborate to engage audiences, encourage creators and diversify investments. It may also offer fresh ways to finance the cultural and creative industries. Hong Kong&#39;s financial sector is in a good position to mobilise support for cultural and creative endeavours, and models like Musicow are worth picking up on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course, risks cannot be eliminated. Rights to lesser-known songs might be hard to trade and streaming activity, which is ultimately based on personal preferences, can be hard to predict. Quality remains king when it comes to investing in creative works and having an environment that cultivates high-quality content is a prerequisite for any copyright trading to happen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is high time to explore ways to integrate culture with finance to create better content, support artists and encourage wider participation in creative endeavours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Remnants of curry dating back 1,800 years found on stone tools in Southeast Asia is oldest outside India]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3229230/remnants-curry-dating-back-1800-years-found-stone-tools-southeast-asia-oldest-outside-india?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/5979116b-c7d3-483c-bec5-d3cc4076a647_ec1a9c4d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;An international team has uncovered the oldest evidence of curry outside India and shown the historical significance of the journey its spice ingredients took to get there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dish – known for its earthy, spicy taste, originally from South Asia and now popular around the globe – was probably brought to the Vietnamese table more than 1,800 years ago thanks to maritime trade networks, researchers from Australia, Vietnam and China have found.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By analysing stone grinding tools unearthed at an archaeological site in southern Vietnam, they detected traces of turmeric, ginger, clove, nutmeg and cinnamon, among other spices that remain key ingredients of today&#39;s curry recipes, the team reported in Science Advances last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our study suggests that curries were most likely introduced to Southeast Asia by migrants during the period of early trade contact via the Indian Ocean,” said the study&#39;s first author, Weiwei Wang, a PhD candidate at the Australian National University (ANU) in Canberra.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Given these spices originated from various different locations, it&#39;s clear people were undertaking long-distance journeys for trade purposes,” Wang said in a statement on the university&#39;s website on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The history of curry began more than 4,000 years ago in India and Pakistan. Archaeological excavations in India have found remains of turmeric, ginger, aubergine and mango attached to human teeth and in cooking pots, according to Wang and her colleagues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, it is not clear how curry started to reach the rest of the world. Historians have long known about a maritime trade route running between Asia and Europe during the same era as the land-based Silk Road, but their knowledge relied mainly on written records rather than physical evidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Between 2017 and 2019, a series of unique stone tools were found at the archaeological complex known as Óc Eo, which is believed to have been a major port city in the Kingdom of Funan from the 1st through to the 7th centuries AD.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tools ranged from grinding slabs to pestles and mortars, and were apparently used for pounding and grinding spices into powders and for releasing their flavours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Originally, the researchers were not focused on curry but hoped to learn how those tools worked and what they might reveal about the ancient spice trade, wrote Wang and co-author Hsiao-chun Hung, also from ANU, in a separate article for the Australia-based website The Conversation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How almost every Asian country has its own versions of curry&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;After extracting hundreds of starch grains – tiny structures in plant cells that can be preserved for a long time – stuck on the surface of the tools, the researchers identified eight culinary spices: turmeric, ginger, fingerroot, sand ginger, galangal, clove, nutmeg and cinnamon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the microscopic remains were dominated by ginger plants, the researchers found some components originated from outside Vietnam. For instance, cinnamon originates in Sri Lanka and nutmeg is native to the Banda Islands in eastern Indonesia, according to the researchers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our research is the first to confirm, in a very tangible way, that spices were valuable commodities exchanged on the global trading network nearly 2,000 years ago,” Wang and Hung wrote in The Conversation article.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you&#39;ve ever prepared curry from scratch, you&#39;ll know it&#39;s not simple. It involves a range of unique spices and the use of grinding tools. It&#39;s interesting to note that nearly 2,000 years ago, individuals living outside India had a strong desire to savour the flavours of curry,” they wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Also fascinating is the fact that the curry recipe used in Vietnam today has not deviated significantly from the ancient Óc Eo period … It goes to show that a good recipe will stand the test of time.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In their paper, the researchers implied that the grinding tools were probably imported from India, too, but some scholars were sceptical.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To assume that people in Southeast Asia couldn&#39;t figure out how to basically crush their food with these stones is a huge leap,” Tom Hoogervorst, a linguist and archaeologist at the Royal Netherlands Institute of Southeast Asian and Caribbean Studies, told the Scientific American, which reported on the research.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Did pasta come from China? Absolutely not, historians say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Next up, the team planned to compare their findings with larger plant remains unearthed from the site, said the co-authors, which also included researchers from the Centre for Archaeology at the Southern Institute for Social Sciences in Ho Chi Minh City and the department of history at Sun Yat-sen University in Zhuhai, southern China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The team said it would also analyse remarkably well preserved plant seeds excavated from the site and look for other spice plants to better understand when and how each type of spice or plant started to be traded globally.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 07:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US unveils US$345 million in military aid for Taiwan to help counter China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229335/us-unveils-us345-million-military-aid-taiwan-help-counter-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 07:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/7914eb4c-8a1b-497b-a9dd-e4100862ca8f_785e22d3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The US on Friday announced US$345 million in military aid for Taiwan, in what is the Biden administration&#39;s first major package drawing on America&#39;s own stockpiles to help Taiwan counter China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The White House&#39;s announcement said the package would include defence, education and training for the Taiwanese.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington will send man-portable air defence systems, or Manpads, intelligence and surveillance capabilities, firearms and missiles, according to two US officials who spoke on the condition of anonymity to discuss sensitive matters ahead of the announcement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US lawmakers have been pressuring the Pentagon and White House to speed weapons to Taiwan. The goals are to help it counter China and to deter China from considering attacking, by providing Taipei enough weaponry that it would make the price of invasion too high.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The package is in addition to nearly US$19 billion in military sales of F-16s and other major weapons systems that the US has approved for Taiwan. Delivery of those weapons has been hampered by supply chain issues that started during the Covid-19 pandemic and have been exacerbated by the global defence industrial base pressures created by Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The difference is that this aid is part of a presidential authority approved by Congress last year to draw weapons from current US military stockpiles – so Taiwan will not have to wait for military production and sales. This gets weapons delivered faster than providing funding for new weapons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Pentagon has used a similar authority to get billions of dollars worth of munitions to Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan split from China in 1949 amid civil war. Chinese President Xi Jinping maintains China&#39;s right to take over the now self-ruled island, by force if necessary. China has accused the US of turning Taiwan into a “powder keg” through the billions of dollars in weapons sales it has pledged.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan says Beijing&#39;s military supremacy over Taiwan growing swiftly&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US maintains a “One China” policy under which it does not recognise Taiwan&#39;s formal independence and has no formal diplomatic relations with the island in deference to Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, US law requires a credible defence for Taiwan and for the US to treat all threats to the island as matters of “grave concern”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Getting stockpiles of weapons to Taiwan now, before an attack begins, is one of the lessons the US has learned from Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine, Pentagon deputy defence secretary Kathleen Hicks said earlier this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine “was more of a cold-start approach than the planned approach we have been working on for Taiwan, and we will apply those lessons,” Hicks said. Efforts to resupply Taiwan after a conflict erupted would be complicated because it is an island, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China regularly sends warships and planes across the centre line in the Taiwan Strait that provides a buffer between the sides, as well as into Taiwan&#39;s air defence identification zone, in an effort to intimidate the island&#39;s 23 million people and wear down its military capabilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Pengyu, a spokesman for China&#39;s embassy in Washington, said in a statement on Friday that Beijing was “firmly opposed” to US military ties with Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US should “stop selling arms to Taiwan” and “stop creating new factors that could lead to tensions in the Taiwan Strait”, Liu said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese coastguard ships sent on fisheries patrol mission to the northern Pacific]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229313/chinese-coastguard-ships-sent-fisheries-patrol-mission-northern-pacific?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 05:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/265a76ac-f173-46a3-85ea-11a51c625b1f_271de832.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China has sent two coastguard ships on fisheries patrols in the northern Pacific as the country extends its reach farther from its shores.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Qushan and the Haimen left Shanghai on Friday on a mission that is expected to last several weeks in waters where hundreds of Chinese fishing boats operate every year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Carrying out law enforcement patrols on the high seas is an important move to fulfil China&#39;s international obligations and to show itself as a responsible big country,” state broadcaster CCTV reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mission was authorised under the Convention on the Conservation and Management of High Seas Fisheries Resources in the North Pacific Ocean, an intergovernmental agreement signed in 2012 to manage regional fisheries and protect marine ecosystems, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report said China had in recent years organised high-sea inspections, cracked down on illegal fishing activities, and played an important role in the sustainable development of fisheries resources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Qushan and the Haimen have frequently taken part in patrols in disputed waters in the East China Sea and the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two vessels were registered with the North Pacific Fisheries Commission as inspection vessels to have the power to board and inspect civilian ships on the high seas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has four coastguard vessels registered with the commission, with the other two being the Changshan and the Shicheng.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July 2021, the Qushan and the Haimen carried out the first such patrols by the Chinese coastguard.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a 31-day journey, the vessels sailed through the straits of Tsushima, Tsugaru and Osumi, the international sea channels near Japan to and from the Pacific Ocean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They observed and recorded a total of 111 fishing vessels, and boarded three of them for inspections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Changshan and the Shicheng conducted the same mission in July and August 2022, in which they travelled 15,000 nautical miles in 45 days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 180 fishing vessels from various countries were observed and recorded – 20 were identified for questioning and five were boarded and inspected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other members of the commission include Canada, the European Union, Japan, South Korea, Russia, Chinese Taipei, the United States and Vanuatu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US has 25 inspection vessels registered to board and inspect civilian ships in the region, followed by Russia&#39;s eight and five from Taiwan, registered as Chinese Taipei. Canada, Japan and China each have four ships registered.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 06:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[White House remains ambiguous about inviting Hong Kong leader John Lee to Apec meeting]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229334/white-house-remains-ambiguous-about-inviting-hong-kong-leader-john-lee-apec-meeting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 06:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/d7aa492f-3c12-48ef-bde6-6e7e159e6156_7b2cf99c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The White House remained elusive on Friday about whether it would invite Hong Kong Chief Executive John Lee to a high-level gathering of Pacific Rim economies in November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Responding to questions after The Washington Post reported that US President Joe Biden would not invite Lee, administration officials have avoided language suggesting that all top Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation leaders would be invited to the meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, Lee – then Hong Kong&#39;s security secretary – was one of several officials sanctioned by the US for the crackdown on Hongkongers&#39; political rights. He became chief executive in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the sanctions, Lee was “designated for being involved in coercing, arresting, detaining, or imprisoning individuals under the authority of the National Security Law”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked whether Lee would be barred from attending, John Kirby, the National Security Council spokesman, said on Friday that the US would “make sure that attendance is in keeping with the US laws and regulations.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And we continue to work with all our partners who are coming together for Apec to make sure that everybody is appropriately represented,” Kirby told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked again later, Kirby declined to elaborate: “I&#39;m not going to update my language or how I worded.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, The Post quoted three unnamed US officials who said the White House had decided to bar Lee from the gathering, to be held in November in San Francisco.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s Lee asks US to let him go to US Apec summit after ban report&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong has been a member of Apec since 1991. According to The Post, citing the unnamed US officials, the sanctions on Lee do not prevent Hong Kong&#39;s participation in Apec, allowing for another senior representative to attend instead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier on Friday, Beijing demanded that Washington lift the sanction against Lee and invite him to the summit, with a Foreign Ministry spokeswoman saying that the US had “flagrantly violated the Apec rules and seriously broken the US commitment to hold the meeting”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Visiting Malaysia on Friday, Lee said he expected the US to act in accordance with Apec “rules, guidelines and conventions” and invite all member economies, including Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing says Hong Kong leader John Lee should be invited to Apec meeting in US&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A decision to bar Lee would complicate the prospects for a face-to face meeting between Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping during the summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pair last met in person on the sidelines of the G20 summit in Bali, Indonesia, in November 2022. But relations were further strained in February when the US shot down a Chinese balloon after it transited across North America.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, Chinese Defence Minister Li Shangfu, who is also under US sanction, refused to meet with US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin during a security summit in Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese military snubbed invite to defence conference, says US admiral&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A US State Department spokesperson said on Friday that Biden anticipated hosting senior representatives in San Francisco in November, using “officials” rather than “leaders”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“During our host year we have already welcomed senior officials from all 21 Apec economies to meetings in Honolulu, Palm Springs and Detroit,” the spokesperson said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We look forward to welcoming officials from all 21 Apec economies to our next series of meetings in Seattle in August and expect the same for Apec economic leaders&#39; week in San Francisco,” the spokesperson added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Mark Magnier&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 06:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden jokes that Republicans may impeach him because inflation is starting to cool down]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229333/joe-biden-jokes-republicans-may-impeach-him-because-inflation-starting-cool-down?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.29 05:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/29/2ecc1486-2427-463b-ab90-e706bb3aeb76_dc9e937e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden – buoyed by new signs the economy is continuing on the upswing – took a swipe on Friday at House Republicans&#39; flirtations with an impeachment inquiry, quipping that the rival party&#39;s lawmakers may decide to impeach him because inflation is cooling down.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Standing in a textile manufacturing facility in Auburn Biden pointed to inflation statistics that showed the US has the lowest rate of price increases among the world&#39;s biggest economies. Though he was careful to say he was not taking a victory lap on the economy, Biden suggested that his Republican opponents in Congress may need to find a fresh line of attack against him because of improving economic circumstances.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Maybe they&#39;ll decide to impeach me because it&#39;s coming down,” Biden said. “I don&#39;t know. I&#39;d love that one.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this week, House Speaker Kevin McCarthy made his most direct remarks yet that Republican lawmakers could launch an impeachment inquiry into Biden over unproven claims of financial misconduct related to Hunter Biden, the president&#39;s son.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the California Republican has acknowledged privately that it is too soon to know whether the president was aware of – much less involved in – his son&#39;s financial dealings in a way that would rise to the level of impeachable conduct.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While McCarthy publicly floated the inquiry this week, the White House has engaged little with those efforts, instead focused on promoting “Bidenomics” and the president&#39;s domestic agenda. Aides have repeatedly played down any inquiry as a hypothetical and pointed out the hesitation among McCarthy&#39;s own ranks about pursuing impeachment against the president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re not going to get into what House Republicans want to do, may not do, hypotheticals, that&#39;s on them,” White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre told reporters on Air Force One en route to Maine earlier on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What I can speak to is exactly what we&#39;re doing today, right? We&#39;re going to Maine. We&#39;re going to be able to talk about an issue that matters to Americans: investing in America, manufacturing, bringing good union-paying jobs back to America.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hunter Biden pleads not guilty to tax crimes after plea deal unravels&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Indeed, that was the focus of the White House on Friday, as Biden used the trip to Maine to sign an executive order that would encourage companies to manufacture new inventions in the United States. It was Biden&#39;s first trip to the state as president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m not here to declare victory on the economy. We have more work to do,” Biden said. But “we have a plan for turning things around. &#39;Bidenomics&#39; is just another way of saying restoring the American dream.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Democrat won three out of the state&#39;s four electoral votes in 2020 and is seeking to shore up his support in the state. Maine allocates its electoral votes by congressional district, and Biden lost the vote in the state&#39;s 2nd District, which provided the only electoral vote in New England for then-President Donald Trump, a Republican.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By going to that district on Friday, Biden sought to show its blue-collar voters that he is committed to them, as a single electoral vote could be critical in a narrow 2024 presidential election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Democrats can compete in Maine&#39;s 2nd District as Jared Golden has been its congressman since 2019. But Golden has also been one of the Democratic lawmakers who has openly criticised Biden over his handling of debt limit talks this year and the administration&#39;s forgiveness of student debt that has since been overturned by the Supreme Court.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite distancing himself from the White House on some policies, Golden travelled with Biden on Air Force One on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And soon before Biden spoke at Auburn Manufacturing Inc., Golden noted to the audience that “it&#39;s no secret” he doesn&#39;t always agree with the president&#39;s agenda but that he “proudly” supports Bidenomics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Republicans have said that Biden&#39;s policies have led to higher inflation. Consumer prices climbed to a four-decade high last summer, but inflation has eased over the past 12 months to a rate of 3 per cent annually.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;CEO says Intel may build &#39;less factories&#39; if US expands China chip curbs&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Bidenomics is hurting working people in my district,” said Maine state congressman Joshua Morris, a Republican. “The cost of groceries, heating oil, gas, healthcare and electricity have gone up as a result of Joe Biden&#39;s policies. He should be apologising to us while he&#39;s here, not bragging.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The National Republican Congressional Committee went on the attack against Golden, calling him “Joe Biden&#39;s loyal foot soldier” who had backed inflation-boosting policies earlier in his presidency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The White House outlined the executive order being signed by Biden, which would improve the transparency of federal research and development programmes to meet the administration&#39;s goals for domestic manufacturing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The order asks agencies to weigh US national security and economic interests when determining if domestic manufacturing requirements should be broadened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The order also urges federal agencies to consider domestic production when investing in research and development and to use their own legal authorities to encourage manufacturing new technologies in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But when goods cannot be made in the US, the order instructs the Commerce Department to create a clearer and timelier process for receiving a waiver.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Auburn Manufacturing Inc., where Biden spoke Friday, is a maker of heat- and fire-resistant fabrics for industries that include shipbuilding, oil refining and electricity generation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company challenged China for its unfair trade practices regarding amorphous silica fabric, or ASF, which is a heat-resistant material.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 29 Jul 2023 05:50:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>