<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[TSMC’s US plant the result of industrial policy meant to counter China, giving states like Arizona more economic heft]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224273/tsmcs-us-plant-result-industrial-policy-meant-counter-china-giving-states-arizona-more-economic-heft?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/5890bffb-45e2-4cbd-ab06-a540bf3515c0_d51dcae6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013 年亚利桑那代表团访问台北时，国家希望从台湾吸引一些重大投资，但自治岛屿的芯片制造巨头台积电 (TSMC) 并不是主要目标。这一荣誉归于 Apple 供应商富士康科技，正式名称为鸿海精密工业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年后，在时任总统唐纳德·特朗普政府要求在美国开设工厂的压力下，富士康最终同意在威斯康星州建立一个新的显示面板工厂。富士康为该州制定的计划包括一块 315 英亩的土地，该土地本应容纳一个可以创造数千个新工作岗位的设施，但它从未实现。微软最近同意以 5000 万美元购买这块土地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事后看来，亚利桑那州可能躲过一劫。但台积电对这个在沙漠中拥有强大半导体产业的国家来说总是更有意义。因此，亚利桑那州已成为美国复兴的以地方为基础的产业政策的最大受益者之一，该政策寻求利用某些地方的特定产业优势，因为该国寻求对抗中国的技术崛起，而产业政策长期以来一直是中央政府规划的主要内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果任其自生自灭，这些公司将被吸引到已经有大量业务的地方。这是亚利桑那州的优势，”布鲁金斯学会研究地方产业政策的高级研究员马克穆罗说。 “作为一个新的阳光地带，它是半导体领域最成熟的地方之一。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国总统乔拜登于 2022 年 8 月签署芯片和科学法案成为法律近一年后，亚利桑那州为自己赢得了一个美国员工在 Glassdoor 等网站上抱怨加班和高要求的工作，尽管不断有关于紧张局势的报道，但它仍是全球芯片制造领域的关键一环。与此同时，台积电将雇用数千名工人，附近的皮奥里亚市正在考虑建设货运机场以利用台积电项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最终，亚利桑那州无法与台积电达成先进的交易晶圆制造厂，或晶圆厂，没有隐含的保证联邦资金即将到来，《芯片法案》中 530 亿美元的资金中的大部分用于激励国内半导体制造。在 2021 年 1 月至 2023 年 1 月国会通过的 770 亿美元基于地方的产业政策支出中，这笔支出占了大部分，布鲁金斯学会的研究人员（包括 Muro）确定了这一支出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这代表了从过去的转变Muro 将过去几十年华盛顿的“不拘一格，有时非常不同的创新战略”称为更强有力的产业政策，该政策正在寻找内陆新的增长区域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它可能不会在沿海地区进行大量投资Muro 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chris Camacho，公司总裁兼首席执行官大凤凰城经济委员会 (GPEC) 承认，联邦支出对于获得台积电新制造厂至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“上届（美国）政府和现任政府都在这一过程中发挥了作用，因为它是一项多年的努力，”卡马乔在一月份告诉南华早报。 “让他们来美国进行的部分讨论是确保《芯片法案》能够向前推进。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《芯片法案》明确支持“区域经济发展”，重点是有条件的地方“解决新兴技术交叉问题”的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月中旬，拜登政府宣布了一项新举措，以支持五个“劳动力中心”，凤凰城就是其中之一。其他城市是俄亥俄州的哥伦布；马里兰州巴尔的摩；佐治亚州奥古斯塔；和宾夕法尼亚州匹兹堡。根据政府的说法，目标是创建“与全国各地的合作伙伴一起复制”的模型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凤凰城和哥伦布因其在半导体领域的优势而被特别命名，但亚利桑那州迄今为止仍然是一个更尽管某些环境限制因素（例如持续的水资源短缺最近迫使该州限制新的开发），但对此类投资具有吸引力的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在拜登担任总统期间，在 41 项涉及半导体的私人投资交易中，有 10 项已进入亚利桑那州，根据白宫发布的数据——比其他任何州都多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚利桑那州在半导体领域的优势来自数十年来为英特尔服务的经验教训，英特尔自 1979 年以来一直在该州，并且其他几家大型芯片公司。因此，该州已经制定了可以复制以满足台积电需求的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英特尔目前正在亚利桑那州建造另一座晶圆厂，并在俄亥俄州建造一座新晶圆厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“[有]哥伦布周围的一个相当先进的地区，但它不像那里有另一个大型晶圆厂，”Muro 说。 “这不像英特尔可以像在亚利桑那州那样重复这个过程。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了达成与台积电的交易，亚利桑那州调整了教育和培训渠道，以说服该公司拥有所需的员工，并且这家芯片制造商将使用英特尔多年来一直采用的水循环技术——这是任何制造设施的关键组成部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲尼克斯市政府在道路、水和基础设施方面的投资高达 2.05 亿美元1,100 英亩土地周围的污水和污水，这将很快成为台积电在台湾以外最先进的晶圆厂的所在地。台积电目前在华盛顿州经营着一家较小的 8 英寸晶圆厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们满足了他们的每一项要求或需求，我认为我们与台积电及其管理团队建立了真正的信任，”卡马乔说。 “在这个多年的过程中，我们一直在为他们努力，以确保他们取得成功，而且我们仍在这样做。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;劳工长期以来一直被强调为芯片制造的主要障碍回到美国。高昂的劳动力成本和技术人员短缺的结合使亚洲的生产更加经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了解决这个问题，亚利桑那州一直在努力增加教育渠道，为这家芯片巨头提供从入门级到级技术员到半导体工程师。它与亚利桑那州立大学合作，亚利桑那州立大学拥有该国最大的工程学院，去年秋天招收了 30,000 名学生。 《美国新闻与世界报道》将其工程专业排在全国第 40 位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该州还一直在建设社区大学级别的管道，英特尔已经从中吸取了教训。马里科帕社区学院的一项新计划旨在通过向人们传授入门所需的基本技能，然后在工作中学习其余的技能，让入门级员工快速进入台积电。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须深入研究并真正获得必要的能力，使这个人能够敲门，满足工作角色，并通过非常短期的周转和干预获得一份高薪工作，”Leah Palmer，执行董事帮助设计该计划的亚利桑那先进制造研究所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划包括虚拟现实和增强现实培训，以帮助人们了解在晶圆制造厂工作的意义，然后再继续前进。 “大多数人对晶圆厂中发生的事情一无所知，”Palmer 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为入口的一部分，该计划有一个登陆页面，申请人可以在其中进行测验以评估他们现有的能力了解他们的知识水平，看看他们必须学习哪些东西才能在台积电这样的公司工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 Palmer 的说法，在六个月内，有 2,600 人访问了该网站，其中 2,300 人通过了测试。从 2022 年 6 月到 2023 年 5 月，在参加这些课程的 684 名学生中，有 578 名学生获得了半导体相关认证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目标是拥有一个庞大的综合人才库，台积电可以从中吸取新的人才工厂，预计最终将雇用约 4,500 名员工。其中一些将来自台湾，例如去年飞往凤凰城的最初 300 名特遣队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台积电现在拥有和需要的许多工作角色都是他们试图在台湾培训的角色.我们有一些这样的人，但我们肯定没有大规模的，”帕默说。 “因此，我们现在正在做的是努力建立一个有针对性的半导体轨道，以便它有目的地针对这种增长所关注的目标。不仅仅是入门级别，而是更高级别。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚利桑那州努力的回报是美国最大的外国直接投资交易，到建设结束时估计达到 400 亿美元。该工厂预计明年开始生产 7 纳米芯片，到 2026 年开始生产 3 纳米芯片。相比之下，华盛顿对向中国出口半导体相关产品的限制针对的是能够生产 14 纳米或更先进芯片的技术。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;自2021年1月拜登上台以来，台积电承诺在美国进行第四大私营部门投资，其在亚利桑那州的扩大投资占全国总投资4628亿美元中的280亿美元，根据白宫公布的数据。台积电120亿美元的初始投资是在特朗普总统任期内宣布的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台积电的亚利桑那工厂是最大的单一项目，但英特尔、德州仪器和美光在过去两年中各自承诺投入更多资金，通过多个项目，其中德州仪器 (TI) 计划在其家乡投资 300 亿美元的设施是该时间段内最大的投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国消费电子产品和芯片制造商三星电子也在建造一个 17 美元的工厂德克萨斯州数十亿美元的晶圆厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从亚利桑那州与台积电开始讨论以来，围绕台湾及其在半导体供应链中的关键地位的问题只会变得更加政治化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是在一些人之前当今主流的关于中台美问题的国家或国际头条新闻，”卡马乔说。 “这确实是一项经济发展战略。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 8 月，美国前众议院议长南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 访问台北，围绕台湾的问题变得更加激烈。当月晚些时候，时任亚利桑那州州长的道格·杜西 (Doug Ducey) 在他上任的最后几个月也访问了台湾首都。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚利桑那州在历史上一直是台湾的大力支持者，这可能有助于为具有里程碑意义的台积电交易。不过，如果没有华盛顿的参与，很难想象这样的交易会发生，因为“很少有州有足够的资金随着时间的推移持续进行此类投资”，Muro 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“毫无疑问，背景背景是美国联邦层面支持更多半导体制造本地化的新举措，要实现这一目标，要实现国家目标，州和地方的执行绝对至关重要，”他说。 “这就是台积电需要或不交付的许多特定东西的地方。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US man charged with murder after shooting South Korean pregnant restaurant owner to death]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224417/us-man-charged-murder-after-shooting-south-korean-pregnant-restaurant-owner-death?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 09:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/275c1c96-3daa-4a3a-8c03-583b97148527_386fb082.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;警方称一名男子在开枪后表现出精神健康危机的迹象，本周在西雅图市中心杀死了一名怀孕的餐馆老板，她周五被指控犯有一级谋杀罪。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，30 岁的 Cordell M. Goosby 被捕，此前有目击者称他跑向了 34 岁的 Eina Kwon 和她 37 岁的丈夫 Sung Kwon 所乘坐的汽车，后者是一家寿司店的老板在该市著名的派克市场附近，并在没有挑衅的情况下开始用偷来的枪向车辆开火。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;怀孕 8 个月的 Eina Kwon 被杀。 Sung Kwon 身受多处枪伤，胎儿在紧急分娩后很快死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金县检察官办公室周五表示，如果受害人“活产”，州法律允许提起谋杀指控；它正在审查医疗记录，以确定是否有理由对婴儿的死亡提出谋杀指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我们不能坐在那里”：大规模枪击事件促使更多亚裔美国人购买枪支&lt;/h3>; p>;检察官办公室要求以 1000 万美元的保释金保释古斯比。目前尚不清楚古斯比是否有可以代表他发言的律师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古斯比还被指控在对成权的袭击中谋杀未遂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“被告的行为留下了一个家庭和社区破碎了，”高级副检察官 Aubony G. Burns 在指控文件中写道。 “当被告杀害 E. Kwon 时，受害者 S. Kwon 和他的家人不仅失去了妻子、母亲和女儿，还失去了一个无辜的女婴。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇在一个当局说，在他们去餐厅 Aburiya Bento House 上班的路上，古斯比跑到他们面前开始射击。他将 9 毫米手枪的子弹倒进车内，将枪放下，然后起飞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当警察在附近发现他时，他举起双手说：“我做到了，我做到了，”警察&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据警方报道，在被捕后的一次采访中，古斯比告诉侦探他有过精神保健史，而且他一直受到陌生人的骚扰，这些陌生人散布关于他性取向的谣言，并说他有对他的办案员做了什么。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在侦探看来，他确实处于某种形式的危机中，无论​​是真实的还是故意表现出来的，”警方在一份可能的原因声明中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西雅图市长Bruce Harrell 周四表示，他已经与 Sung Kwon 进行了交谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Eina 是我们社区的领导者和企业主，与她的家人一起经营 Aburiya Bento House，”Harrell 说。 “本来应该是 Kwon 一家的欢乐时光，却变成了一场由毫无意义的枪支暴力造成的难以想象的噩梦。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;犹太教堂枪手在美国最致命的犹太人袭击中杀死了 11 人&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;枪击事件让 Kwon 一家悲痛欲绝，他们也有一个蹒跚学步的孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为支持这个家庭并将来自韩国的亲属带到葬礼上的众筹活动筹集到的资金超过美国160,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哀悼者在他们现已关闭的餐厅，包括大韩民国驻西雅图总领事馆 Eunji Seo 献上了鲜花和其他纪念品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kwons 开设了 Aburiya，于 2018 年供应传统寿司和融合寿司。这家餐厅深受游客和寻求午餐优惠的市中心工人的欢迎。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea’s ‘overwhelming pro-US’ Pacific tilt triggers alarm in China: ‘this could become a nightmare’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3224373/south-koreas-overwhelming-pro-us-pacific-tilt-triggers-alarm-china-could-become-nightmare?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/bed6ec15-d658-4e07-aeae-5818d9c7f632_3bb562a7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国最近与太平洋岛国举行的峰会反映了其成为“全球经济体”的更广泛战略关键国家”，在东亚以外发挥更广泛的作用，尽管分析人士警告说，它明显倾向于美国可能会与中国发生冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在首尔举行的为期两天的首届韩国-太平洋岛屿峰会上个月就扩大经济发展、安全和应对气候变化方面的合作达成了协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国总统尹锡烈承诺加强对每个太平洋岛国的“量身定制”支持，同时明确表示首尔总统发言人李道云表示，韩国尊重所有国家的独立和主权以及基于规则的国际秩序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国还表示，将把对太平洋地区的发展援助规模扩大一倍，以据韩联社报道，到 2027 年将达到 3990 万美元。 Yoon会见了库克群岛、马绍尔群岛共和国、所罗门群岛、纽埃岛和帕劳群岛的领导人，并与其他五个太平洋岛国的首脑举行了峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Peter Lee，研究人员悉尼大学美国研究中心研究员表示，首尔与太平洋地区日益密切的接触反映了它希望发挥更大的作用并实现其成为“全球关键国家”的愿望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“南韩国认识到它可以与美国和澳大利亚等传统伙伴一起为太平洋岛屿做出微不足道但仍然重要的贡献，”李说，并指出尹的前任并没有关注太平洋。 “因此，在这个地区，尹政府可以通过新的想法和合作让自己脱颖而出。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首尔与太平洋岛屿的接触也可以为经济发展、能源等区域问题提供“独特的韩国方式” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yoon 去年 2 月在外交事务网站上的一篇文章中首次提出了“全球关键国家”的想法，当时他还是总统候选人，呼吁韩国采取“明确和大胆”的新外交政策，并指责他的前任文在寅政府“胆小”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么韩国要成为“全球大国”还有很长的路要走关键国家”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yoon 宣布他希望将国家转变为一个将自由、价值观和国际规则的支持置于其外交核心的国家，他说这一新方法将涉及加强与美国和日本，并对中国采取更加挑剔的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于加利福尼亚州的兰德公司韩国政策主席兼高级政治学家埃里克莫布兰德表示，直到最近，韩国对该地区的外交兴趣不大&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在，首尔向太平洋岛屿做出了这一提议，这是韩国传统上与该地区没有紧密联系的地区，”莫布兰德说，并补充说可能会有发展援助的机会， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些将发挥韩国的优势，同时也为太平洋岛国面临的与气候变化相关的威胁提供应对措施，”莫布兰德说，并指出如果这些项目做得好，可以&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于首尔在海外基础设施建设方面的实力，韩国国土交通部宣布计划将该国打造为世界四大海外建设国家之一，有能力到 2027 年每年赢得 500 亿美元的海外交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于气候变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于檀香山的太平洋论坛的非常驻 James A. Kelly Korea 研究员 Alexander M. Hynd 表示，首尔正在寻求扩展到新市场并创建新的区域论坛，以证明它可以展示中等大国在发展和气候危机方面发挥领导作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“太平洋岛屿地区满足这两个标准，”Hynd 说，并补充说鉴于地区大国在太平洋地区争夺影响力，它使得首尔确保这些国家考虑其核心安全利益是明智的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国“不受限制”地进入巴新基地以削弱中国的影响力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;近年来，中国已通过扩大经济联系加强与该地区的接触。它还于 2022 年与所罗门群岛签署了一项安全协议。美国的回应是增加对该地区的援助，在瓦努阿图开设大使馆，并于去年主办了第一届美国-太平洋岛屿峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Andrew Yeo布鲁金斯学会韩国研究高级研究员兼 SK-韩国基金会主席表示，首尔最近对太平洋岛屿的兴趣可能受到华盛顿对中国在该地区日益增长的影响力的担忧的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[韩国的] 参与较少是关于 [太平洋岛屿] 对韩国“重要”，更多的是 [首尔] 在印太地区提供公共产品，它可以在解决气候变化和气候变化等问题方面发挥早期和重要作用发展援助，”Yeo 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;上周三，Yoon 政府发布了第一份国家安全战略，强调韩国成为“自由、和平与全球关键国家”的愿景。在瞬息万变的国际环境和日益加剧的地区安全威胁的背景下实现繁荣”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五年来首次发布的政策文件概述了应对当前和未来安全挑战的必要性，同时捍卫自由民主并促进全球繁荣与团结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该战略，韩国的目标是保护其主权，在朝鲜半岛建立和平并为东亚的繁荣奠定基础，同时扩大该国的全球作用，Principal 表示国家安全副顾问 Kim Tae-hyo。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是在去年 12 月发布的印太战略之后发布的，首尔称该战略致力于增强该国“在解决该地区各种问题中的作用”并建立积极的地区秩序”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;太平洋国家喜欢美国和中国争夺朋友和影响力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“认识到韩国从半导体和电池到核能的经济、社会和文化实力权力和 K-pop 文化，国际社会现在期望韩国的角色和贡献与其提升的地位相匹配，”政府文件“自由、和平和繁荣的印度洋-太平洋地区战略”说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;这些最近的战略似乎建立并取代了首尔早先于 2017 年 11 月宣布的新南方政策 (NSP)，旨在将其与东南亚和印度的战略伙伴关系深化到类似于首尔与美国、中国、日本和俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了访问所有东南亚国家联盟成员国外，前总统文在寅还与印度举行了两次首脑会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布鲁金斯学会的 Yeo 表示，尹政府希望公布一项更雄心勃勃的印太战略，该战略将超越 NSP 并与 Yoon 的“全球关键国家”概念相联系。 Yoon 在 2022 年发起了韩国-东盟团结倡议，旨在促进与东南亚的经济和战略合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安全战略，”Yeo 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国最近对太平洋岛屿的兴趣符合其印太战略，并表明首尔“作为能够与较弱国家共享资源的二线区域参与者的地位”太平洋论坛的 Hynd 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印太战略建立在 NSP 的基础上，在贸易、投资和民间外交中使用了许多相同的方法。改变的是愿景的范围，它已经扩展到真正的区域层面，并且明确使用了一些新的战略语言，例如韩国之前犹豫不决的“印度-太平洋”，”Hynd 补充说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在上届政府的领导下，首尔实行了“战略模糊”，旨在在其军事盟友美国和战略经济伙伴中国之间取得平衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>; p>;韩国明显向美国战略轨道倾斜的做法逐渐激怒了中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在首尔去年 12 月公布其印太战略后，中国外交部发言人王文斌表示，北京主张所有国家团结合作， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4月，在尹宣布台湾是堪比朝鲜的“全球性问题”后，中国外交部副部长孙卫东向韩国驻华大使郑郑月娥提出严正交涉Jae-ho 对 Yoon 的“错误言论”进行了报道，报道了中国民族主义小报《环球时报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共产党控制的日报还警告说，Yoon 的“势不可挡的亲美政策可能成为韩国的噩梦”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，首尔将与华盛顿的联盟升级为“核联盟”的决定遭到了中国的蔑视，中国认为在朝鲜半岛部署美国核武器是一种危险和挑衅的行为对中国、俄罗斯和朝鲜采取行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“华盛顿和首尔将面临战略层面的报复，这可能在该地区引发另一场核危机，”《环球时报》称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与美国的关系上周，中国驻韩国大使邢海明警告首尔不要在中美竞争中“下错赌注”，并补充说“赌中国输的人一定会后悔”，这让中国沸腾了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yoon 除了召集 Xing 提出抗议并对首尔称之为“挑衅”的言论表示“强烈遗憾”之外，还质疑 Xing 作为外交官的做法。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国转向“强硬” -line&#39; on China as Yoon 质疑特使的评论&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“从邢大使的态度来看，他是否具有作为外交官相互尊重或促进友谊的态度值得怀疑，”韩联社报道尹说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;伦敦国王学院国际关系教授拉蒙·帕切科·帕尔多表示，自从 2017 年的“THAAD 骚乱”和三年后 Covid-19 大流行爆发以来，首尔变得更加愿意挺身而出&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布鲁金斯学会的 Yeo 也有同样的看法，称现任政府在推动基于价值观的外交和基于规则的国际秩序方面显得更加坚定和自信。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自韩国于 2017 年安装末端高空区域防御系统以来，安全分歧有可能破坏双边改善关系的努力。首尔表示该系统的目的是直接威慑朝鲜，但北京将其视为安全威胁，称其雷达可用于监视中国的军事设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2017 年部署“萨德”系统后，中国停止了与韩国的贸易和文化交流，并实施限制，实际上禁止其公民访问该国。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;中国采取报复措施后，根据现代研究院的数据，韩国汽车制造商现代汽车 2017 年第二季度在中国的销售额同比下降 64%，而乐天超市在中国的销售额同比下降 95%同期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;禁止中国游客前往韩国的禁令导致 2017 年估计收入损失 156 亿美元，促使时任总统文在寅同意所谓的“三不”北京取消经济制裁的回报。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国着眼于新的北约战略以应对中国的影响力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“三个不”是指首尔同意不会进一步反击- 韩国的弹道导弹系统，没有加入美国的区域导弹防御系统，也没有涉及韩、美、日的军事联盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;太平洋论坛的海德说，虽然一些韩国人担心此次中国可能再次动用经济制裁和胁迫手段，北京更关心首尔在台湾问题上的态度，尤其是其作为美军基地的角色。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李勇军，a韩国外交部前官员上个月警告说，韩国将不可避免地被卷入台海的潜在战争，因此必须采取措施做好准备，防止冲突爆发。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘No point going home’: husband sits in car after work, says wife ‘nags’ him at home in viral video, causing outrage in China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224031/no-point-going-home-husband-sits-car-after-work-says-wife-nags-him-home-viral-video-causing-outrage?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/7e7fcfa4-a297-4446-9ac3-53e3309ce928_b7d97e7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个中国男人下班不想回家被拍到睡觉&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频在网上疯传后，这位来自中国中部湖北省的无名男子成为众怒的对象，许多人指责他离家出走责任，曼景视频报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频显示，当他的妻子从前排乘客座位上与他交谈时，该男子向后靠在驾驶座上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你为什么不想要回家？”妻子问他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我不来找你，你会睡在车里吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丈夫看着前方，打了个哈欠，然后回答：“我为什么要回家？躺在车里比回家好多了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我在家的时候，你对我各方面都不满意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“回家也没意思。当我试着花一点时间玩电子游戏或智能手机时，你就不停地唠叨我。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;听到抱怨后，他的妻子伸出手轻轻地抚摸他，但他推”她的手拿开，提高了嗓门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我一整天都在努力工作。我不能在车里享受一会儿吗？”他问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频结束时，他的妻子一直保持沉默，听他讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该视频在内地社交媒体上引发了对丈夫的广泛批评。尽管一些评论者赞同他的观点，但大多数人认为他是自私和不公平的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个人说：“他说得好像他的妻子一整天都不工作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有人说：“看样子，他老婆比他累多了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他把责任都推给了老婆。多么懒惰和不负责任的丈夫，”第三个人评论道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Whistle-blower Edward Snowden chose Hong Kong to expose US in 2013, but would perceived lack of press freedom under national security law stop him today?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3224268/whistle-blower-edward-snowden-chose-hong-kong-expose-us-2013-would-perceived-lack-press-freedom?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/b8f73ac6-96ed-47a6-9814-3f7e2c02fc87_2f1883b0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;举报人爱德华斯诺登利用香港发动了十年来世界上最大的情报泄密ago, but others would not be able to do that today because of the government&#39;s tightened grip on media in the city, according to his former lawyer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking on the 10th anniversary of the explosive leaks which revealed the United States&#39; global spying activities, Canadian lawyer Robert Tibbo said the national security law introduced in 2020 had made the city “a place where whistle-blowing is almost impossible”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is a real possibility that if Snowden were to happen again, reporters and anyone who helps him in Hong Kong would be arrested and charged under national security law,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They could be accused of collusion with foreign forces, one of the offences under the law which also prohibits acts of secession, subversion and terrorism. “The law is far too broad and ambiguous,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;June 12, 2013: US spy net targets Hong Kong, Edward Snowden reveals to SCMP&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Rejecting such fears, former security chief Regina Ip Lau Suk-yee argued that laws in the city were far less stringent than in other parts of the world and that freedom of expression was not under threat locally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think any whistle-blower will be in jeopardy in the future, unless they are involved in an offensive against China,” she said. “If Snowden comes again, he&#39;ll be free to spill the beans about the US or any other country.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Snowden, 39, is a former US National Security Agency employee who leaked thousands of highly classified documents which exposed how the US spied on its own citizens, world leaders and countries around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He came to Hong Kong in May 2013, and from the Mira Hotel in Tsim Sha Tsui, began leaking documents to media outlets, including the Post. He said he chose Hong Kong because of its press freedom.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Four Hong Kong &#39;Snowden refugees&#39; arrive in Canada for new life as residents&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He checked out of the hotel on June 10 and Tibbo, fearing that Snowden would be sent back to the US, helped him hide in the homes of three families of asylum seekers who were also his clients.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US revoked Snowden&#39;s passport and issued charges against him under espionage laws, but he slipped out of Hong Kong and made his way to Russia, which granted him citizenship last year. He is now living in Moscow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like Tibbo, former Central Intelligence Agency analyst John Kiriakou, who was jailed in a separate case for exposing the US government&#39;s use of torture as an interrogation technique, said Hong Kong&#39;s national security law could deter whistle-blowing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now an author and journalist living in Washington DC, from which he hosts the Political Misfits podcast, he said free journalism played a critical role in whistle-blowing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Firstly, journalists are often sceptical about whistle-blowers and therefore require lots of evidence,” he said. “Secondly, without the media, the revelations may as well not even be made.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kiriakou, who was sentenced to 30 months&#39; jail in early 2013 for giving classified information to a reporter, said Hong Kong&#39;s national security laws meant that anyone involved in the whistle-blowing process could be prosecuted under the law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think the consequences would be dire,” he said. “There is no guarantee that you are going to be able to tell the people why you did what you did in open court.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong will forge ahead with plans to pass Article 23: justice secretary&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Between the time Beijing imposed the national security law on Hong Kong in June 2020 and February last year, 20 journalists and press freedom advocates had been arrested under it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But former security chief Ip, now convenor of the Executive Council, the city&#39;s top decision-making body, said Hong Kong&#39;s laws were far less stringent than in other parts of the world and freedom of expression was not under threat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no attack on freedom of expression,” she argued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She also said many countries were acting to regulate internet freedom too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think we are doing anything particularly out of line compared with what other jurisdictions are doing,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Misplaced priorities&#39;: Hong Kong accused of ignoring asylum seeker&#39;s basic needs&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Looking back at the events 10 years ago, Tibbo said he and the asylum seekers who helped Snowden came under pressure afterwards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From 2013 to 2016, few were aware of the asylum seekers who helped Snowden. But that changed with the release of the film Snowden, directed by Oliver Stone, in 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vanessa Rodel, an asylum seeker who housed Snowden in a subdivided flat in Kowloon, recalled: “When the film came out, things got scary, journalists found where we lived and were knocking on our doors.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rodel, originally from the Philippines, came to Hong Kong as an asylum seeker in 2003. She and her stateless daughter were granted refugee status by Canada in 2019 and have resettled in Montreal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said International Social Services-Hong Kong (ISS), which is contracted by the Social Welfare Department to help asylum seekers, kept asking her where Snowden was and eventually cut off her benefits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I did not have anywhere to live or money for food,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite that, Rodel said she would not hesitate to help Snowden again. “I would not think twice about it. It was the right thing to do,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tibbo said that in 2017, all his pending cases in court were suddenly pushed through and it felt like his workload was deliberately being increased to force him to leave Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I had 50 or 60 clients and I suddenly started getting court dates for all of them,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the Immigration Department asked for him to stop representing the asylum seekers involved in the Snowden case, and accused him of breaching his professional code of conduct and having conflicting interests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tibbo returned to Canada in November 2017, but remains a member of the Hong Kong Bar Association and can represent clients in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An ISS spokesman said it would not comment on individual cases due to privacy concerns. But it cautioned that it “may not be able to render assistance to service users at particular periods of time if they do not show up at service renewal, provide incomplete documentation to support the assessment and/or refuse the services rendered”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An Immigration Department spokesman said: “ISS is commissioned by the Social Welfare Department to provide humanitarian assistance to eligible non-refoulement claimants. [The welfare department] may approach the Immigration Department for verification of the status of non-refoulement claims as necessary.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why the US must look beyond its rivalry with China and engage Southeast Asia on its own merits]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/opinion/article/3224310/why-us-must-look-beyond-its-rivalry-china-and-engage-southeast-asia-its-own-merits?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/c09bbe6b-4198-4a58-98ec-c8918fe7d64a_f55e7f26.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;In November 2011, US president Barack Obama announced that United States foreign policy would make a “pivot” to Asia. But then in January 2017, a key part of that pivot – greater economic interaction – was reversed, as just-inaugurated president Donald Trump launched his “America First” agenda by yanking the US out of what he labelled the “job-killing” Trans-Pacific Partnership.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Damage from the abandonment of the TPP was hefty. The prospects for the US to seriously boost trade with Asia were dented, trust in the US took a hit and the way was left open for non-TPP member China to expand its already-substantial trade and economic links with the 10 members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump did not much care about Asean, even though the member states have more than 675 million people and together form a major part of the global economy. As US president he generally disdained multilateral groups and skipped most Asean summits and other big Asian regional meetings, which the leaders of China, Japan and South Korea never missed. He also left some key ambassadorships open for years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The no-shows definitely upset Asean leaders, as personal relationships can really matter in Southeast Asia, where “being there” is important. In a 1979 movie satirical film with that title, Peter Sellers plays a simple gardener whose comments on plants and growing somehow lead to him being considered a good candidate for the US presidency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Joe Biden&#39;s administration recognises the importance of being there. And it is trying to grow economic engagement through the 14-member Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity; but because it does not give widened market access, the grouping – including seven of Asean&#39;s 10 members – is unlikely to generate much enthusiasm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A big problem is that protectionist and anti-China sentiments are much stronger and deeper in the US than when Obama launched his pivot. Biden will not push trade liberalisation measures, and even if he could, they might be wiped out in 2024, should the US election be won by Trump.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US clout in Asean grows even as China still viewed as most influential: survey&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Deteriorating relations between the US and China have generated more attention than usual in Southeast Asia, where each country has its own view of Beijing and Washington. In recent years, there has been a crop of good books focusing on China&#39;s sometimes-fraught relations with Southeast Asia, and now there is one specifically on US ties with the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is titled Imperfect Partners – The United States and Southeast Asia, by highly experienced diplomat Scot Marciel who is now retired from the US State Department. He has a clear view of what Washington should and should not do; a primary thing not to do is to try the “non-starter” of turning Asean into an anti-China group. Instead, the US needs to engage the region as growing and pivotal on its own merits, rather than as important turf for big-power competition with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US approach “cannot be simply a corollary of its China strategy”, Marciel asserts, adding that Washington should not think that Southeast Asia&#39;s resistance against China, like over territorial claims in the South China Sea, means it feels the same as the US does about Beijing as a “largely malign influence”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, he argues, is going to have significant influence in Southeast Asia, no matter what Washington does. China, for obvious reasons, will keep dominating talk in the US about Asia, as Southeast Asia is a “sideshow”. The Stanford University think tank where Marciel is currently attached has 12 analysts working on China, only two on Southeast Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The former diplomat says the US needs to keep showing up and boost relations in Southeast Asia. In an area “long sceptical of US staying power in the region, showing up consistently at the highest levels is essential”, he writes, adding that Washington needs to be a “consistent, reliable and good partner”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marciel is extremely qualified to write about the US and Southeast Asia. Over 35 years, he held senior Asia posts in Washington, and was ambassador to Asean, to Indonesia and to Myanmar – before the calamitous February 2021 coup.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His book is part-memoir and part-primer, with a background that would be helpful to potential investors or people new to Southeast Asia. The meaty text is imperfect in a few places. The chapter on Vietnam mentions the 1964 Gulf of Tonkin incident without any context, making it tough for younger readers on understanding what it was. There are a couple of slightly wrong dates in the Indonesia chapter, and the full name of Apec – the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum – is incorrectly given as Asia-Pacific Economic Coordination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, there is a lot of very solid material. Among the strongest chapters are two on Myanmar, which shed a lot of light on what was going on in the long-closed country before the coup. Marciel spent substantial time with Aung San Suu Kyi, and he writes about her asking him and the US government not to use the word “Rohingya”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Guests in our own land&#39;: Rohingya in refugee camps won&#39;t return to Myanmar&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Some personal experiences of a diplomatic life help keep the text highly readable. Marciel relates how, in 1993, he was sent to Vietnam – on which the US still had a trade embargo – to be a “presence” in Hanoi, where Washington then did not have anyone resident. For the assignment, he carried in nearly US$50,000 in cash to pay for his hotel and other expenses. The officer in the US embassy in Bangkok who handed over the cash bundle “warned me that I would be personally responsible for it if I were robbed or lost the money”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marciel writes well, and has a sense of humour, which not every foreign-service officer does. On the theme of showing up, he writes that attending Asean meetings “is like going to your spouse&#39;s family reunion. It might not be the most memorable thing you ever do, but joining the event will bring rewards, and not showing up definitely will cost you”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Richard Borsuk has worked as a reporter and news editor in Southeast Asia for more than 40 years, including 11 years in Jakarta (1987-1998) as The Wall Street Journal&#39;s Indonesia correspondent. He co-authored a book on Indonesian history, “Liem Sioe Liong&#39;s Salim Group: The Business Pillar of Suharto&#39;s Indonesia”, published in 2014. Borsuk currently is an adjunct senior fellow at the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Grammy rules say only human creators can win, amid rise of AI music]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224416/new-grammy-rules-say-only-human-creators-can-win-amid-rise-ai-music?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 07:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/a1ebd100-0c09-4da7-b838-48f47941f36e_67819246.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“Only human creators are eligible” for the Grammy Awards, the Recording Academy declared on Friday, as the body that grants the world&#39;s most recognised music awards seeks to curb the use of artificial intelligence (AI) in the industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AI-only work is banned, but some music created with AI help may qualify in certain categories, the academy&#39;s updated rule book reads.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A work that contains no human authorship is not eligible in any categories.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Music creators must now contribute to at least 20 per cent of an album to earn a nomination. In the past, any producer, songwriter, engineer or featured artist on an album could earn a nomination for album of the year, even if the person had a small input.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first Grammy Awards ceremony took place in 1959, to reward music creators from 1958.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November 2022 OpenAI launched ChatGPT, a free chatbot backed by Microsoft Corp that can generate humanlike dialogue based on simple inputs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AI apps have mushroomed, allowing users to animate still photos, create avatars in films and write songs, essays and articles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People in many professions are growing fearful that AI could displace humans. For example, the Writers Guild of America (WGA) and the Screen Actors Guild (SAG-AFTRA) are wrestling with the use of AI in the creative fields of screenwriting and acting.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hollywood writers to strike as studio talks fail&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The WGA wants to curb the of AI in screenwriting while SAG actors want to ensure its members can control use of their digital personas and receive proper compensation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;WGA writers went on strike in early May and have yet to agree with studios on the use of AI, among other issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Actors could go on strike as well if SAG-AFTRA cannot reach a deal over similar concerns.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s booming one-man bookstore on WeChat shows how Tencent is taking on ByteDance in live-streaming e-commerce]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224369/chinas-booming-one-man-bookstore-wechat-shows-how-tencent-taking-bytedance-live-streaming-e-commerce?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/dfa759c5-7d72-490b-a461-888ecbec6c5d_9596acee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Zhao Jian used to run a massive bookstore in Nanjing that covered 9,000 square metres; now he runs a one-man shop online in front of a camera.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The shift to e-commerce has turned into a windfall for the 30-year-old merchant. With the right timing and support from WeChat Channels, Zhao found he could sell as many books in a day as he used to sell in a week at his bricks-and-mortar location that had more floor space than 20 basketball courts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tencent Holdings has been promoting Zhao&#39;s story for Channels, the short-video platform on the company&#39;s widely used WeChat messaging app. During this year&#39;s June 18 shopping festival, which started in late May, Zhao has been selling an average of 1 million to 1.5 million yuan (US$140,000 to US$200,000) worth of books each day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shenzhen-based tech giant is now boosting support for merchants on its platform as it seeks a greater slice of China&#39;s online retail market. For the duration of the shopping festival this month, Tencent has cut the “technology support fee” for merchants to 1 per cent. Normal rates range from 1 to 5 per cent, depending on the product category.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Live streaming has emerged as a new way of shopping in China, particularly for young consumers who are accustomed to ordering goods they see in videos recommended by merchants and influencers. Douyin, the Chinese version of TikTok that is also owned by ByteDance, has moved aggressively to monetise user attention through sales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Group Holding, owner of the South China Morning Post, is also betting on live streaming to woo consumers. In one recent case, Alibaba invited football star Lionel Messi to join a Taobao merchant&#39;s stream.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like many Chinese online retailers these days, Zhao said he live-streams every day, typically from 7.30pm to 11.30pm, introducing a new book every 30 minutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some books I&#39;ll discuss [with readers] several times,” Zhao said in an interview arranged by Tencent. “For example, I talk about [the classic text of ancient Chinese historiography] Zizhi Tongjian two or three times every week. I guide readers in the live-streaming room to read it chapter by chapter following the table of contents.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao now has more than 1.8 million followers on WeChat Channels, which he grew initially through the app&#39;s Moments feature, similar to Facebook&#39;s Feed, he said. This eventually attracted people who were not in his social circle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 30 per cent of his followers are based in Beijing, and more than 20 per cent are from Shanghai, Zhejiang, Jiangsu, and Guangdong provinces, Zhao said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Shenzhen wants to become a global live-streaming e-commerce hub&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Drawing on WeChat&#39;s vast base of 1.3 billion monthly active users, Channels has been growing rapidly with an estimated 813 million monthly active users as of June last year, according to data analytics firm QuestMobile. That put it ahead of the 680 million users on Douyin and the 390 million on Kuaishou that same month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although founder Pony Ma Huateng referred to Channels as the “new hope” of the company in an internal meeting at the end of 2022, Tencent has been measured in its approach to monetising the feature.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In terms of e-commerce in relation to live-streaming in Video Accounts, there&#39;s actually a very big opportunity, and part of it is already proven in the other short-video companies,” Tencent president Martin Lau said in a conference call with analysts in May. “But we want to do it on a gradual basis so that we can build the infrastructure right.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since its beta launch in January 2020, WeChat Channels has launched a series of e-commerce tools and incentive schemes to help merchants sell more through live-streaming, from which Tencent extracts commission. Gross merchandise value, a measure of the total value of goods sold on the platform, grew 800 per cent last year, according to the company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As part of Tencent&#39;s bid to attract more influencers to join its platform, WeChat announced in March that it will allow content creators to set up paid subscriptions on their channels. It will also add new advertisement space in comment sections while giving channel owners a cut of the revenue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tencent&#39;s cautious approach was the right move to ensure the quality of user experience and content, according to Zhang Yi, CEO of Guangzhou-based market research firm iiMedia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For Tencent, the most important prerequisite is to keep WeChat users, and not to lose them due to commercialisation,” Zhang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Tencent is still a long way from turning Channels into a cash cow. In contrast, Douyin has been a mature revenue generator for some time, with 1.41 trillion yuan in gross merchant value last year, according to a report by The Information.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Short video apps are also drawing advertisers away from other social media platforms. It was the only internet category with growth in ad revenue last year, according to a report by Interactive Marketing Lab Zhongguancun and PwC in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While Douyin is still the most outstanding in the live-streaming e-commerce market, it&#39;s not impossible for Channels to catch up in the future with its wide user base and a strong social network,” Zhang said. “But for Tencent, they are also looking at the problems exposed by Douyin&#39;s live streams [to learn from them].”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 07:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Antony Blinken’s visit to China could be a success even without breakthrough agreements: analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224415/antony-blinkens-visit-china-could-be-success-even-without-breakthrough-agreements-analysts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 06:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/84ea9ce4-d5a9-4d43-b145-e93c1eb2adf6_e1124442.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The measure of success for US Secretary of State Antony Blinken&#39;s highly anticipated visit to China is not whether it produces breakthrough agreements but whether it re-establishes some predictability to the relationship, according to analysts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After months of bilateral acrimony following incidents like a suspected Chinese surveillance balloon detected over American territory – a high-profile setback for relations that derailed Blinken&#39;s planned February visit to Beijing – analysts argue that the coming trip by Washington&#39;s top envoy is more important for testing the future of the relationship than for any substantive discussions that will take place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The trip is the first step in an exploratory process to determine if there is sufficient mutual intent to try to moderate the trajectory of the relationship,” said Ryan Haas, senior fellow at the Brookings Institution, a Washington-based think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken&#39;s visit affords him an opportunity to reaffirm core American principles amid China&#39;s ascent and “maybe even to do a little better job” at making diplomatic inroads than the administration as a whole has done, said Michael O&#39;Hanlon, also of Brookings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The trip, in either direct or maybe implicit ways, can help signal that kind of a return to normalcy where our goals are about sort of guiding China back towards a path of peaceful rise and not viewing it as our next enemy,” O&#39;Hanlon added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken is slated to hold meetings with senior Chinese officials on Sunday and Monday. He will be the first US cabinet-level official to visit China since 2019, the first secretary of state since 2018, and the highest-ranking US government official since President Joe Biden took office in January 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts anticipate that Blinken will be granted, per custom, a visit with Chinese President Xi Jinping, though no official announcement has yet been made. Blinken was also expected to meet Xi in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Part of the reason for Xi&#39;s taking a meeting with Blinken is because Chinese leaders would want the same access granted to them when they visit the US, Haas said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ahead of Blinken visit, China urges US to avoid &#39;illusion&#39; of strength&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;And if the two were not to meet, that would send a message that something had gone wrong, according to Patricia Kim, another Brookings fellow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Xi Jinping actually just made time for Bill Gates and so it would be striking if he didn&#39;t make time for the secretary,” she said, referring to the Chinese leader&#39;s meeting with the Microsoft co-founder and billionaire philanthropist in Beijing on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken&#39;s trip this week is also primed to serve as the opening gambit for major global meetings like the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation leaders&#39; summit in San Francisco in November and the Group of 20 leaders&#39; summit in September.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And it is expected to set the stage for trips to China by other top US officials, including Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo and Secretary of Treasury Janet Yellen, both of whom have voiced interest in making the journey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken&#39;s visit would transpire after multiple meetings held between senior American officials, including his February meeting with Wang Yi, China&#39;s top diplomat, in Munich, and National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan&#39;s May meeting with Yi in Vienna. Raimondo and US Trade Representative Katherine Tai met last month with Chinese Commerce Minister Wang Wentao in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, William Burns, director of the US Central Intelligence Agency, and Daniel Kritenbrink, assistant US secretary of state for East Asian and Pacific Affairs, both recently returned from visits to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, experts say the possibilities for diplomatic advance have attenuated since the early months of this year, right after Biden and Xi&#39;s November meeting at the G20 in Bali. Earlier this month, Chinese defence minister Li Shangfu declined a meeting with US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin Lloyd Austin at the Shangri-La Dialogue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kurt Campbell, Biden&#39;s special adviser for Indo-Pacific affairs, on Wednesday said Blinken had three goals for the trip: establish communication channels to discuss “important challenges, address misperceptions, and prevent miscalculation”; speak out on US concerns on a range of issues; and explore potential cooperation on transnational challenges, including how to increase people-to-people exchange.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the Biden administration has made clear it is not entering the meeting intending to make any breakthroughs. It has also stressed that competition drives the relationship and that China is the US&#39;s greatest geopolitical challenge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response, Beijing on Friday said Washington should not contain and suppress China under the guise of competition and that viewing China as its biggest challenge was a “serious misjudgment”. Days earlier, Chinese Foreign Minister Qin Gang urged Blinken to “show respect” and stop undermining China&#39;s interests.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Are US-China ties headed for a thaw or just an era of managing differences?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The tone coming from both sides in the post-meeting readouts would be important to watch, observers said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Beijing officials, Blinken&#39;s visit is a facet of their “charm offensive” and would help them “even if there&#39;s no specific progress”, according to David Dollar, another Brookings senior fellow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Noting the slowing Chinese economy and falling confidence in it from the foreign and domestic private sector, Dollar said the trip could show Europe and China&#39;s allies in the US that Beijing is willing to cooperate in “stopping the downward spiral” with Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a result, Blinken&#39;s visit could reinforce “European reluctance to go full in with the United States on technology competition with China and containing China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese Foreign Minister Qin Gang and US envoy break diplomatic ice&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Haas said the visit would present a “test of discipline” for Blinken and his team to “tune out the noise” and focus on what the Chinese were conveying behind closed doors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it is unlikely that Biden would be able to claim progress in establishing “guardrails” to “responsibly manage” bilateral competition, experts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the US has largely framed the relationship in terms of zero-sum competition, China would be sceptical of any such guardrails, according to Michael Swaine of the Quincy Institute, another Washington-based think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before any serious progress is made, Swaine said, “there needs to be a recognition by both sides that each side is contributing to this negative dynamic”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s culture police spark fears of overkill as Communist Party steps up ideological drive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3224401/chinas-culture-police-spark-fears-overkill-communist-party-steps-ideological-drive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/7bee7ef0-c13f-4cbd-b307-5c6ed41fca68_86bad3b0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Cultural law enforcement in China – central to its recent crackdown on the stand-up comedy scene – is in full swing as the ruling Communist Party pushes ahead with its ideological campaign led by the doctrine of President Xi Jinping.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But observers are warning of a possible excessive use of power as official control of culture – launched decades ago – advances to another level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The enforcement drive gained nationwide attention last month after stand-up comic Li Haoshi was investigated in Beijing over jokes deemed to be “humiliating” to the People&#39;s Liberation Army. The investigation, sparked by tip-offs on Li&#39;s act, also saw a penalty of more than 14 million yuan (US$2 million) slapped on the comedy troupe representing him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cultural law enforcement force has focused on stand-up comedy, live shows, game rooms and movie studios lately as part of its pledge to uphold mainstream socialist values.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the drive has raised concerns about the already limited space for artistic impression, faced with the party&#39;s aims to bring China&#39;s online, celebrity and media into line with government policy and “Xi Jinping Thought”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lynette Ong, a professor of political science at the University of Toronto, said the cultural law enforcement appeared to be aimed at “cleaning up people&#39;s minds”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s like ideological domination directing people, telling them what they can or cannot believe or practise or utter in public,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li&#39;s case grabbed media attention again last Monday, when a notice said the Beijing theatre he performed in was also fined 100,000 yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A company under Shanghai Xiaoguo Culture Media, the troupe Li worked for, had also been fined 70,000 yuan for “engaging in unauthorised commercial performance business”, a separate notice the same day said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest penalty was also related to the Li case, Shanghai Xiaoguo said on Tuesday, while pledging that “we will never resume any performance without receiving official permission”. All Shanghai Xiaoguo performances nationwide had earlier been suspended as penalty for the Li incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This comes as the party&#39;s central leadership pushes for ideological “unity of thought” under Xi&#39;s political doctrine – Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era – which was enshrined in the constitution in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi himself has also been promoting the mix of Marxism and Chinese traditional culture, and elevated culture work to the level of national security a decade ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;From Mao to Xi: how Communist Party leaders have shaped its ideology&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Cultural law enforcers in cities other than Beijing also appear to be taking a more active role in supervising entertainment venues and comedy clubs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officers in southwestern mega city Chongqing inspected entertainment venues last week, including businesses running popular “escape room” and role-playing murder mystery games, state-owned Chongqing Daily reported. They identified content deemed “bloody and violent” or as “distorting history”, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It did not specify any punishments, saying only that those guilty of “minor offences” – and had rectified them – were not penalised.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Enforcers in the eastern city of Ningbo and Dingxi in the northwest had also conducted citywide inspections of stand-up comedy clubs in recent months, media reports said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Organisers of offline events in China are already required to obtain approval from their corresponding local cultural regulators, and events like stand-up comedy shows need to submit scripts to be reviewed in advance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cultural law force was included in a 2018 reform plan for party and state institutions, aimed at consolidating administrative law enforcement with dedicated teams also for market supervision, ecological and environmental protection, transport and agriculture.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s new rural law force accused of strong-arm tactics against farmers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Under the guidance of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, the force is responsible for supervising issues and events related to culture, historical artefacts, publishing, radio and television, films and tourism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sida Liu, a professor of law and sociology at the University of Hong Kong, noted that the force was not newly created in 2018. The ministry had issued a regulation on it as early as 2011, and it went into effect in 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Therefore, for over a decade, the cultural law enforcement forces have had a solid legal foundation from this ministry regulation,” Liu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“However, the challenge lies in their enforcement. The recent crackdown on stand-up comedy exemplifies the &#39;campaign-style law enforcement&#39; approach often taken by Chinese administrative agencies in response to high-profile cases or incidents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The issue is not the legality of these forces, but rather how to prevent excessive use of power during such campaigns.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Late last month, the cultural law team in northeastern China&#39;s Heilongjiang province held a uniform-wearing event in the city of Jiamusi, exhorting all teams to “resolutely guard the baseline of ideology and cultural safety”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Their peers in Shaanxi and Zhejiang provinces put up similar events earlier this year, while those in Beijing, Shanghai, and the provinces of Fujian and Yunnan held them last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cao Pengcheng, party chief for Beijing&#39;s cultural law enforcement force, urged officers to use the event “as an opportunity to forge an all-round hardened cultural &#39;iron army&#39;”. Calling on officers to be “loyal defenders” of Xi, he said they must stand ready to “safeguard the political, ideological and cultural security of the capital&#39;s cultural market”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ong at the University of Toronto said the crackdown on comedy clubs was an extension of cultural activities the government was trying to take control over, a process that started years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But sending a dedicated force to control these activities is taking it to the extreme. It almost reminds me of the Cultural Revolution,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In post-reform China, the government has been trying to impose control but a lot of this is actually by regulation: better regulating society by passing certain laws that encourage society to regulate itself. [But now] to direct society on what they can or cannot do, I think is taking it to another level.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ong added that the control was not only about top-down directives, but could take on another dimension in the hands of overcautious local officials keen to avoid any wrongdoing and to anticipate the central government&#39;s lines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Given the general political environment and the tightening of space [of free expression] by the central government, people at the local level have become extra risk-averse. So they may take extra precautions in stopping certain activities, even though they have not received any signal.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Brazil and China officials resume bilateral defence talks but also discuss fishing complaints]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224414/brazil-and-china-officials-resume-bilateral-defence-talks-also-discuss-fishing-complaints?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.17 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/17/25cac9f7-028e-4036-9784-8acfa0711d8a_54956b4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Brazil used the visit of a Chinese naval delegation on Friday to complain about alleged illegal fishing by Chinese vessels between the Brazilian and African Atlantic coasts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The military entourage arrived on Thursday, with the visit expected to last two days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Led by the Secretary of the PLA Navy Yuan Huazhi, the group also includes the Navy Deputy Chief of Staff Admiral Li Pengcheng; China&#39;s defence attaché in Brazil, Zhang Linhong; and five other officers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The commander of the Brazilian Navy, Admiral Marcos Sampaio Olsen, and the chief of staff of the navy, Admiral José Augusto Vieira da Cunha de Menezes, hosted their guests in Brasilia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting points to the resumption of bilateral defence talks, postponed since 2020 due to the pandemic. Sources familiar with the matter confirmed that the visit was brokered by Brazilian President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva and arranged just days in advance – the reason no military agreement is likely to be signed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Brazilian military complained about Chinese fishing vessels leaving the African coast, sailing through Atlantic waters without being tracked, and engaging in illegal fishing, the Brazilian newspaper Folha de S. Paulo reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So-called illegal, unreported and unregulated (IUU) fishing occurs when foreign vessels fish illegally in the exclusive economic zone of other countries, defined in the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea as the area up to 200 nautical miles off a state&#39;s coast.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Global Fishing Watch, a non-governmental organisation that promotes transparency in the fishing industry and helps government agencies fight illegal fishing, told The Post that up to one in five fish caught at sea are the result of IUU fishing, a market estimated to be up to US$23.5 billion a year&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Brazil&#39;s Lula heads to China with plans to promote BYD takeover for Brazil Ford factory&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to a report published by Investigative Journalism Reportika in February, Chinese vessels account for 60 per cent of all IUU fishing cases reported in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, American University in Washington reported in October that the crime had led to the decline of fish stocks and the extinction of protected marine species in South America.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Besides economic losses and the consequences for the environment, Brazil is also concerned about regional security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Filipe Porto, a fellow at the Brazilian Naval War School&#39;s Conjuncture Assessment Centre, said that the strengthening of Chinese military ties with African coastal nations, as well as alleged Chinese interest in building a naval base in Argentina to consolidate its presence in the South Atlantic, raised concerns by Brazilian military officers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The military doctrine adopted by Brazil, Porto said, provides for the protection of the region in partnership with the countries that share the Atlantic coast. Despite the unease, however, the Lula administration has pushed for greater engagement with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The armed forces have the tactical and operational autonomy to patrol the area and detect crimes such as illegal and unregulated fishing, but the power to do something about it rests with the presidency,” Porto said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Brazilian military has a long tradition of alignment with the West, many officers have studied at American schools and may even take a more hawkish attitude towards China, but the Navy is the most pragmatic of the armed forces … The IUU fishing [issue] will certainly be addressed diplomatically and militarily.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese embassy in Brazil sent a statement to The Post that China conducts fishing in distant waters following international laws and regulations and “adopting a zero-tolerance attitude towards illegal fishing”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The embassy also noted that Beijing had instituted voluntary moratoriums in certain parts of the high seas and that China is committed to “science-based conservation and sustainable use of international fisheries”.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 17 Jun 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>