<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Little hope of progress on US-China military talks when two sides remain so far apart]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3229429/little-hope-progress-us-china-military-talks-when-two-sides-remain-so-far-apart?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/2ea27e26-99ca-41c1-a1bd-b3ac986a602f_20f485cf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯近期访华的主要目的是他表示，这有助于减少“误解和沟通不畅”，防止双方发生事件。不过，他未能成功重启军事对话，而且似乎仅仅同意对话就已经变得政治化，而沟通过程却被用来为一方或另一方谋取利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中美军事沟通水平正处于最低点，两国军队之间的事件发生频率和强度不断增加。随着这些事件的激增，越来越多的政策制定者和分析师呼吁在事态失控之前加强沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;紧张局势依然严峻。 6月3日，台湾海峡发生险些相撞事件，一艘中国军舰突然横穿美国军舰船头。在此事件发生之前，5月31日发生了一起事件，当时一架中国战斗机迫使美国在国际空域的一个侦察地点飞过其尾流湍流。美国国防官员将这些事件描述为中国更具侵略性行为模式的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国希望重新建立通信以帮助降低冲突的可能性，但中国不合作。正如史汀生中心东亚项目联席主任、高级研究员、中国项目主任孙云所指出的，其重启军事对话的立场可能是包含沟通过程的战略的一部分。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;至少，似乎已经捕捉到了它们之间的根本差异。由于美国对俄罗斯入侵乌克兰和全球其他热点地区非常感兴趣，北京可能会认为华盛顿比实际情况更厌恶冲突。这意味着中国认为自己有更多的外交空间可以回旋，也可能认为同意沟通会破坏其边缘政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，中国可能想让美国猜测其意图和红线，其越境可能引发军事冲突。在最极端的情况下，中国甚至可能认为危机将提供一个机会，迫使美国做出让步，并通过谈判建立和平共处的制度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国也可能认为军事沟通过程对美国有利，因为它可以表明这是其善意的努力，并在谈判继续进行时拥有更多的行动自由。鉴于此，中国可能希望放慢军事交流的进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现实政治正在影响谈判的努力。中方希望美方用实际行动展现诚意，而不仅仅是口头上。似乎每一次有意义的谈判机会之前、之后甚至伴随着双方的侵略性或消极行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近距离情报收集和航行自由行动继续有增无减。美国表示，在向台湾派遣武器和高级政客的同时，也遵循“一个中国”政策。北京希望美国停止近距离情报收集以及在中国海洋主张附近进行的海军行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么美国可能有“紧迫感”来改善与中国的军事关系&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;最重要的是，北京希望美国停止对台湾的政治和军事支持。它指责华盛顿破坏构成两国关系基础的外交协议。在中国的条件得到满足之前，很难想象会出现任何富有成效的对话。否则，相互猜疑就会占上风。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使两国军队之间的沟通有所改善，中美之间的信任差距也不太可能改善，危险事件仍然可能发生。因为它们并非源于误解和沟通不畅，而是源于对国际秩序和战略利益的更深层次分歧。因此，谈判的最佳结果是在这些事件发生时进行管理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方都阐明了两国关系的基本政策。习近平主席提出“三不”：中国“不寻求改变现有国际秩序，不干涉美国内政，无意挑战或取代美国”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 与此同时，美国总统乔·拜登提出了中国报道所说的“五不”。这些认为，美国不谋求新冷战，不谋求改变中国制度，重振同盟不是针对中国，不寻求与中国发生冲突，更不支持台独。但到目前为止，美国的行动似乎与这些话不符。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平提出了“新型大国关系”，这意味着在国际事务中平等和共同责任。但到目前为止，美国似乎拒绝了这一想法，并且期望很快改变是不现实的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一通信难题是军事事务相互透明概念的必然结果。虽然军事事务的透明度听起来中立且合理，但它有利于更强大的国家。一个国家可以通过暴露自己的能力来恐吓对方，而军事实力较差的国家则可以展示自己的弱点，而这些弱点可以被更强大的一方利用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，透明度的概念是模糊的。美国称其透明，但试图就其核潜艇的地位和作用或其在南海的具体情报收集能力提出质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到双方都“不”事实证明，有意义的军事交流不会取得什么进展，南海的紧张局势仍将高度紧张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Standard Chartered to open 3 centres for wealthy customers in Hong Kong, tapping growing opportunities from Greater Bay Area, Southeast Asia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3229534/standard-chartered-open-three-centres-wealthy-customers-hong-kong-tapping-growing-opportunities?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/c748abb4-5f0d-418e-a9df-c2bc66eb07f7_cc8561f4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;渣打银行计划在香港开设另外三个专门针对富裕客户的网点该行驻香港的最高负责人表示，今年将在香港招聘更多员工，以抓住大湾区和东南亚市场不断增长的机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家总部位于伦敦的银行，其大部分利润来自新兴市场香港首席执行官禤惠仪周一接受采访时表示，未来几个月将在太古广场、旺角和大围等旅游热点地区开设专门针对高端客户的金融管理中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;禤表示，该行上半年已招聘约 300 名新员工，并预计为其新的零售银行网点招聘更多员工，这些网点专为来自湾区和香港的高净值客户量身定制。 ”边境重新开放后，我们看到大湾区居民来港开设新账户、购买保险和其他投资产品的强劲需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此外，我们也看到强劲的需求东盟国家的客户希望通过香港投资大湾区，而内地客户也希望利用香港作为在东盟国家拓展业务的门户。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东盟指的是东南亚11个国家，包括新加坡、印度尼西亚和马来西亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huen表示，今年上半年，该银行与湾区相关的零售业务增长了80％，而与湾区相关的零售业务增长了26％与东盟相关的交易增加了 50%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这帮助该银行在前六个月在香港创造了创纪录的高利润和收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，该银行报告了 3.3 美元截至 6 月底的六个月内，渣打银行实现税前利润 10 亿美元，比去年同期增长 25%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在其最大的单一市场香港，渣打银行实现了创纪录的税前利润上半年销售额达10.2亿美元，同比增长166%。营业收入也创下历史新高，达到 20.9 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;收入比去年高出 31%，比 Covid-19 来袭之前的 2019 年上半年高出 22%，禤女士表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“上半年旅客回国人数达1300万人次，使经济活动恢复正常，预计将提振贷款和其他理财业务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说。 p>;&lt;p>;香港政府于 9 月放松了社交距离措施，并于 1 月全面重新开放与内地和其他海外市场的边境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;禤先生表示，利率上升也将有助于增加贷款收入。渣打银行周一将最优惠利率上调 12.5 个基点至 6.125%，为 2008 年 2 月全球金融危机期间以来的最高水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也可能使借款人在申请贷款时更加谨慎。渣打银行报告称，上半年贷款增长了 1%，存款增长了 7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多企业家正在采取观望态度，因为他们不知道利息何时会增加。”利率将达到顶峰，”她说。 “总体而言，我认为下半年贷款增长和其他业务的前景仍将保持谨慎乐观，但可能不会有大幅增长。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s consumer spending puzzle is missing a key piece: disposable income]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3229480/chinas-consumer-spending-puzzle-missing-key-piece-disposable-income?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/6ec050eb-e817-42eb-b1b1-32cc871097c8_ab39a44b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京一再呼吁消费者增加消费，在中国社交媒体上引发了一个流行的梗：为什么我的政府仍然相信我很富有？我应该怎么做才能让政府知道我实际上破产了？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些话包含了有关消费者支出性质的某些事实。归根结底，人们的消费水平是由他们的可支配收入和对未来收入的预期决定的。当他们贫穷、负债累累或对未来高度不确定时，很难要求他们增加支出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然中国政府在要求人们放松钱包方面似乎很坚决，甚至绝望，但国务院周一公布的最新一揽子政策表明，明显省略了如何增加人民收入的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;概述的措施涵盖从新能源汽车到旅游景点等广泛领域这些措施的基础是中国消费者有能力消费，而供应方的调整——例如延长餐馆的营业时间——可以释放隐藏的消费者力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些措施可能会产生一定的效果。要点：例如，到 2022 年，中国的家庭储蓄将增加 17.8 万亿元人民币（2.49 万亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该政策文件读起来就像是向中国人民进行大规模推销，但尽管采取了全面而详细的措施” ，这对国家有利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在举办盛大的派对和建造令人惊叹的建筑方面，世界上很少有国家能与中国相媲美，但2022年全国人均可支配收入仍然相对较低，为36,883元。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;中国过去三年的疫情控制对零工经济工人、小企业主和私营部门雇员的收入造成了沉重打击。相信那些入不敷出的人会因为政府的要求而增加支出，这纯粹是一厢情愿的想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，虽然传统观点认为中国人倾向于过度储蓄，但事实并非如此。现在不再是这样了。借贷在中国已经变得无处不在，尤其是在年轻一代中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国央行数据显示，截至6月底，家庭抵押贷款余额为38.6万亿元，这对许多人来说已经是一个难题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，推动消费者支出的真正秘诀是关注收入和预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，世界各国政府发放现金的情况很常见，或者以香港为例，在疫情期间和之后发放准现金消费券。但尽管中国公众经历了巨大的经济混乱，中国却没有向消费者提供任何有意义的直接补贴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个问题是不愿改变导致中国消费支出低迷的结构性问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，中国最高税率为45%的累进个人税制，以及巨额强制性社会福利缴款，显然不利于消费者支出，但情况似乎没有什么改变的希望。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;消费支出是经济增长的原因还是结果也很有趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;面对经济下滑，中国政府显然将消费支出视为推动经济增长的引擎。增长，从长远来看，实现“内循环”。但时机再糟糕不过了，因为现在公众的趋势是降低消费，为经济困难做好准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，中国的最新指令看起来与其他信息有点矛盾。一方面，中国人被告知要克制个人欲望，为国家应对未来的各种风险和挑战做好准备。另一方面，他们还被告知要尽可能多地花钱来帮助国民经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;显然，人们不能两者兼得。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong driver is first person awarded cash for tip-off about terrorist plot]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3229519/hong-kong-driver-first-person-awarded-cash-tip-about-terrorist-plot?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/88e685d9-4a71-417f-b269-686d6357f29f_d8196973.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;专业司机成为全港首位获得现金奖励的人士警方在周二发起一项要求出租车司机帮助保护国家安全的运动之前向警方通报了一起恐怖阴谋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“出租车司机每天穿越城市，遇到不同的人和事件，”跨部门反恐小组组长高级警司梁伟基表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们在载客或开车上路时，可能会接触到与罪案有关的信息。相信如果及时向我们报告这些信息，很多犯罪行为就可以避免。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名司机在三月份获得了奖励，他听到两名乘客正在讨论炸弹袭击的细节，于是报告了此事。梁在周五有关该活动的媒体吹风会上表示，他们在将他们送走后向警方透露了计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，警方随后逮捕了两名当地男子，他们后来被判犯有炸弹恶作剧罪，以及负责的警官案件的负责人指定司机获得现金奖励。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方以保密问题为由，没有详细说明案件的细节，包括该男子驾驶的车辆类型或奖励的金额。梁说，对其他线人的悬赏超过三项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“任何提供严重暴力或恐怖主义案件关键和真实线索的人，在犯罪嫌疑人被法庭定罪后，都可能获得现金悬赏。” ”梁说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反恐奖励和举报疑似恐怖主义非紧急线索热线于2022年6月推出，旨在鼓励居民举报可疑人员、物品或事件。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;香港硬件、化学品供应商被要求报告可疑客户&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;居民可以通过拨打热线电话6366 6999、通过短信或即时通讯应用程序微信提供信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至7月中旬，该热线已收到2万多条信息，涉及约5000起疑似案件，但并非所有案件都与暴力或恐怖主义有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部门没有提供相关逮捕或定罪的数字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我们收到了各种各样的举报，包括诈骗、危险毒品甚至国家安全案件。梁振英表示，如有需要，我们会将这些举报转介有关部门跟进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他赞扬公众对暴力或疑似恐怖活动提供“详细”举报，并留下联系方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“这不仅仅是我们是否逮捕嫌疑人的问题。设立热线电话的目的是为了提高居民的反恐意识。在这方面，我们认为热线的结果是理想和令人鼓舞的。”梁补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港反恐部门将推出举报热线&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该部门将推出举报热线&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周二与出租车行业开展反恐活动，官员将为出租车司机举办研讨会，以识别可疑人员、物品和事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部门还将为司机提供显示反恐热线的保险杠贴纸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;的士司机陈金明因举报他在路上发现的嫌疑人而获得警方颁发的2021年好公民奖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我晚上开车驶出狮子山隧道，遇到了警察的路障。前车司机行为怪异，多次开关车门。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国安法热线六个月内收到10万条举报：警方&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;“当我向前走到那辆车之前停的地方时，我看到[地上]有一把刀。一名警察靠近我的车，我告诉他，‘前面的车有问题’，”陈补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方后来在可疑车内发现了武器，司机被发现处于危险之中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只需​​简单一句话就可以举报，这是我们应该做的。如果案发后才采取行动，那就太晚了。”陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据跨部门反恐小组称，该市的恐怖威胁级别为“中等”，即存在攻击的可能性，但没有具体情报表明香港可能成为目标。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Doomsday cult mum sentenced to life for murdering children and romantic rival]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229557/doomsday-cult-mum-sentenced-life-murdering-children-and-romantic-rival?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 07:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/bff3e485-b298-416a-aace-e9d45b19739a_58335128.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位拥有“世界末日”宗教信仰的美国母亲周一被判处终身监禁，没有被判终身监禁因谋杀她的两个孩子和密谋杀害丈夫的前妻而获得假释。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lori Vallow 因杀害她 16 岁的女儿 Tylee Ryan 并收养了 7 岁的孩子而于 5 月被判有罪。 -老儿子约书亚“JJ”瓦洛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你被判处州惩戒委员会羁押，服刑最高允许刑期……终身监禁，不得假释，”法官史蒂文·W·博伊斯 (Steven W Boyce) 说道，在美国西北部爱达荷州的一家法院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦洛声称自己是一位女神，负责为耶稣基督的第二次降临做好准备，并说她相信自己可以与天使沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;检察官指控她利用宗教信仰为谋杀辩护，这成为去年上映的 Netflix 真实犯罪纪录片系列《我们母亲的罪孽》的主题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还声称存在经济损失。犯罪动机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的第五任丈夫查德·戴贝尔（Chad Daybell）是多部世界末日小说的自行出版作家，正在等待审判，罪名包括谋杀他的第一任妻子塔米（Tammy）。他对所有指控均表示无罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在瓦洛的孩子失踪后，该案于 2019 年底首次成为全国头条新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国末日邪教的妈妈因谋杀她的两个孩子而被定罪瓦洛和戴贝尔从未报告过孩子们失踪的消息，他们的尸体于 2020 年 6 月在爱达荷州戴贝尔拥有的房产上被发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有消息称，有几个人与瓦洛和戴贝尔有联系的人近年来去世了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括戴贝尔的妻子塔米，她于 2019 年 10 月表面上死于自然原因，就在这对夫妇搬到夏威夷的几周前。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦洛是摩门教徒，随着时间的推移，她的宗教信仰变得越来越激进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年，她在 2018 年的一次宗教会议上遇到了戴贝尔（Daybell），戴贝尔是一个为末日做准备的激进摩门教派的领导人。犹他州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于瓦洛罪行的严重性，博伊斯法官周一连续判处三项无期徒刑，而不是同时判处无期徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在爱达荷州，无期徒刑就是——不得假释的无期徒刑，”他说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，“由于在三个不同的时间发生了三起不同的谋杀案，涉及三名不同的受害者，因此同时进行计数不符合正义的利益，”他说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你需要对三起谋杀案分别承担责任。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UK sanctions Russian judges as Putin critic jailed for 25 years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3229555/uk-sanctions-russian-judges-putin-critic-jailed-25-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 06:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/aedafa63-e068-46f8-9577-2d042d0c47f7_d5648251.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英国周一制裁俄罗斯法官和检察官，因为他们在所谓的“俄罗斯反对派政客弗拉基米尔·卡拉-穆尔扎 (Vladimir Kara-Murza) 因政治动机被定罪，呼吁释放这位英国双重国籍人士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有俄罗斯和英国公民身份的卡拉-穆尔扎 (Kara-Murza) 对 25 年监禁的上诉败诉。据俄新社周一报道。这位 41 岁的男子于 4 月份因叛国罪和其他罪行被判入狱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是绝望且毫无根据的，”总理里希·苏纳克 (Rishi Sunak) 在 X（以前称为 Twitter）社交媒体平台上表示。 “拒绝@vkaramurza 的上诉是没有道理的。他应该立即被释放。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国表示已对莫斯科市法院法官维塔利·别利茨基和叶卡捷琳娜·米哈伊洛夫娜·多罗希娜实施资产冻结和旅行禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡拉-穆尔扎是其中之一。 2022 年 2 月莫斯科向乌克兰派遣数万军队后，少数反对派知名人士留在俄罗斯并继续公开反对俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国政府，此前曾制裁其他一些人与卡拉-穆尔扎案有关的委员会表示，还对巴斯曼地区法院法官纳塔利娅·尼古拉耶芙娜·杜达尔进行了制裁，称后者进一步延长了卡拉-穆尔扎的审前拘留时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“卡拉-穆尔扎拥有英国双重国籍，英国外交、联邦和发展办公室在一份声明中表示，“他因反战立场而受到俄罗斯政权的迫害”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他制裁目标包括两名检察官和一名“专家证人”。英国称其为拘留卡拉-穆尔扎提供了虚假理由。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;普京批评者因叛国罪被判入狱 25 年，这是多年来最严厉的判决&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;卡拉-穆尔扎在战后两个月被捕乌克兰开始，被指控传播有关武装部队的虚假信息，并宣布其为“外国代理人”。他被拘留的几个小时前，美国有线电视新闻网 (CNN) 播出了对他的采访，他在采访中称俄罗斯是由“杀人犯政权”统治的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡拉-穆尔扎后来因发表有关战争的演讲而被指控犯有叛国罪，其中包括 2022 年 3 月向亚利桑那州众议院提交的一份报告，其中称普京正在轰炸乌克兰的房屋、医院和学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科表示，其无意针对平民，但乌克兰已造成数千人死亡。&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Argentina strikes deal with People’s Bank of China to secure US$1.7 billion in yuan for IMF debt]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3229556/argentina-strikes-deal-peoples-bank-china-secure-us17-billion-yuan-imf-debt?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 06:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/e9cbfcb6-0380-491b-8bf4-0ba1b6601c38_58e23418.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿根廷政府已与中国人民银行达成协议，获得1.7美元中国经济部长周一表示，中国将通过货币互换向国际货币基金组织支付 27 亿美元的债务，以履行其对国际货币基金组织的 27 亿美元付款义务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;剩余的付款余额将由国际货币基金组织贷款的 10 亿美元来支付。拉丁美洲开发银行，也称为 CAF，总部位于委内瑞拉加拉加斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该安排，阿根廷将比索存入中国人民银行，中国人民银行则给予人民币作为回报。随后，布宜诺斯艾利斯无需动用美元储备即可向国际货币基金组织付款，目前阿根廷中央银行估计其价值为负 80 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿根廷经济部长塞尔吉奥·马萨 (Sergio Massa)感谢中国人民银行和中国政府“做出授权支付的决定”，并表示会的。 “确保阿根廷能够继续出口，同时履行其对国际货币基金组织的付款义务”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议将允许阿根廷“不使用一美元储备”履行其国际货币基金组织义务，马萨补充道。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;继六月决定允许商业银行以人民币开设客户账户后，这项交易标志着这个南美国家在更广泛地使用人民币方面又迈出了一步。同样是在今年，阿根廷证券监管机构批准在当地市场发行人民币计价证券。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位熟悉此事的政府消息人士告诉《华盛顿邮报》，此次掉期预计将是一项短期债务偿还在国际货币基金组织承诺的资金到位之前，中国的参与可能充当“临时桥梁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贷款期限和阿根廷为新债务支付的利率都没有确定。由 CAF 或经济部披露。布宜诺斯艾利斯表示，与中国人民银行的互换条款是机密协议的一部分，不能公开。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;参议员们感叹美国在拉美政策上输给了中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国际货币基金组织的债务问题可以追溯到 2018 年，当时的主席毛里西奥·马克里获得了一笔 440 亿美元的贷款，这是当时国际货币基金组织历史上最大的一笔贷款。阿根廷现任领导人阿尔贝托·费尔南德斯 (Alberto Fernández) 政府后来对债务进行了重新谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布宜诺斯艾利斯承诺国际货币基金组织调整其公共支出水平、增加储备并维持有竞争力的利率，以换取新的支出偿还五年前的债务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与中国政府的协议避免了“戏剧性的局面”，因为布宜诺斯艾利斯将缺乏偿还债务所需的美元，阿里尔·冈萨雷斯·莱瓦吉 (Ariel Gonzalez Levaggi) 表示阿根廷天主教大学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莱瓦吉相信此举将扩大中国在阿根廷经济中的影响力，因为该国一半以上的国际储备已经是人民币。他表示担心该战略可能被证明“不可持续”，因为“重新谈判的国际货币基金组织债务条款无法为阿根廷提供可行的出路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“阿根廷正在努力争取时间，并且毫无疑问，中国正在为这一努力提供帮助。然而，现在的问题是北京会要求什么让步作为回报。”莱瓦吉说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国一直在向阿根廷政府施压，要求其购买中国JF-17飞机和中国北方工业集团制造的8x8装甲战车他补充说，中国北方工业公司（Norinco）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，北京正在等待国有的中国核工业集团公司批准在该国开始建设一座耗资 83 亿美元的新核电站。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;莱瓦吉解释说，由于费尔南德斯无法与华盛顿就可能的国际货币基金组织债务减免达成协议，阿根廷总统向北京寻求帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;报告称，中国可以提升人民币的国际地位&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;最终布宜诺斯艾利斯将“被迫选择一方，这将非常非常复杂，”他说。 “美中关系正面临动荡时刻。这场双重游戏可能迟早会结束”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议可能不会给北京带来直接的经济优势，但它“肯定有助于扩大人民币作为国际货币的使用，国际政治学协会的亚历山大·科埃略表示，“尽管人民币自 2016 年以来已成为国际货币基金组织货币篮子的一部分，但其用于债务结算的用途并不广泛”。常见的。阿根廷选择的道路开创了先例，未来可能会被其他类似情况的新兴国家效仿。”曾担任中国银行法律顾问的科埃略表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “这项协议或许也表明美国在国际货币基金组织中的影响力已经下降了多少，华盛顿过去曾多次利用国际货币基金组织来指导拉美政策，”他补充道。 “中国在前进，而美国人却在袖手旁观。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU’s von der Leyen warns against China’s aggression in Asia during speech in the Philippines]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/article/3229538/eus-von-der-leyen-warns-against-chinas-aggression-asia-during-speech-philippines?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/31/277a86e9-dd5a-4d3c-9604-c170c31236d5_093fcc7d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧盟执行委员会领导人援引俄罗斯入侵乌克兰对大陆发出警告中国在有争议的印度太平洋水域和针对台湾的行动日益强硬，并于周一表示，欧盟不会容忍在这两个地区的侵略行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟委员会主席乌尔苏拉·冯德莱恩在与菲律宾举行的联合新闻发布会上发表讲话小费迪南德·马科斯总统在马尼拉举行旨在加强贸易、经济和安全关系的会谈后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领导人宣布，由 27 国组成的集团将恢复与菲律宾就自由贸易协定进行的谈判。 2017 年，马科斯的前任罗德里戈·杜特尔特 (Rodrigo Duterte) 领导下。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;欧盟领导人同意“降低”欧盟与中国的贸易往来风险&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;冯德莱恩 (Von der Leyen) 还强调了安全合作的必要性，称俄罗斯全面入侵乌克兰表明独裁领导人“愿意对他们的威胁采取行动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“俄罗斯对乌克兰的侵略战争动摇了国际秩序的基础。 It is in violation of the UN charter and the fundamental principles of international law, such as territorial integrity and sovereignty,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is why Europe supports Ukraine&#39;s brave fight against the aggressor, because the illegal use of force cannot be tolerated, not in Ukraine, not in the Indo-Pacific,” von der Leyen said. “Security in Europe and security in the Indo-Pacific is indivisible. Challenges to the rules-based order in our interconnected world affect all of us.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is why we are concerned about the rising tensions in the Indo-Pacific,” she said, adding that the EU backs a free and open Indo-Pacific “because an Indo-Pacific free of the threats of coercion is key to all our stability to our peace, and to the prosperity of our people.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Without naming China, von der Leyen reaffirmed the EU&#39;s recognition of a decision by a UN-backed tribunal that invalidated China&#39;s territorial claims in virtually the entire South China Sea on historical grounds. China has rejected the arbitration decision as a sham and continues to defy it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Von der Leyen&#39;s visit to the Philippines is a sign of improving ties after a stormy period between the EU and Duterte over human rights. It&#39;s the first such top-level visit in nearly six decades of Europe-Philippines relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EU leader later spoke more bluntly against China at a business forum in Manila, where she warned that Beijing&#39;s increasingly aggressive actions in Asia “could also have global repercussions.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She criticised China&#39;s stance on the war in Ukraine, its increasingly aggressive actions in disputed Asian waters and its provocative moves against Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s show of military force in the South and East China seas and in the Taiwan Strait directly affects Philippines and other partners in the region,” the EU leader said. “But it could also have global repercussions because any weakening of regional stability in Asia … affects global security, the free flow of trade and our own interests in the region.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has turned seven disputed reefs into missile-protected island bases in the last decade, further alarming Western governments and rival claimants, including the Philippines, Vietnam, Malaysia, Brunei and Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s fleet of coastguard ships and swarms of militia boats have warned vessels from rival claimant states and the US military and its allies not to stray into its claimed territories in the disputed waters, which straddle one of the world&#39;s busiest sea lanes and are believed to be sitting atop undersea deposits of oil and gas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Von der Leyen urged Asian nations never to rely on a single supplier for energy and raw materials, citing how “Russia tried to blackmail us” by considerably cutting its natural gas supply to European countries after the EU imposed sanctions against Moscow over the invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We could not choose our neighbours, but we can choose who to do business with and on what terms,” she said. “We made a mistake with Russia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippines, she said, exports 90 per cent of its nickel ore to China “instead of processing it inside the country to create more jobs and added value,” she said. “But this can change.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was no immediate reaction from China to von der Leyen&#39;s remarks. China has warned the United States and its allies from meddling in what it says is a purely Asian dispute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Philippines came under intense EU criticism during Duterte&#39;s six-year term, mainly because of the bloody anti-drugs crackdown he oversaw that left more than 6,000 mostly petty suspects dead. Marcos succeeded Duterte in June 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The killings sparked an International Criminal Court investigation as a possible crime against humanity. Duterte withdrew the Philippines from the ICC in 2018, but its prosecutor has proceeded to investigate the widespread deaths that occurred in the years when the country was still part of The Hague-based court.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Marcos can learn from Duterte&#39;s China approach, as his Beijing visit shows&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Duterte often lashed at EU criticism of the brutal anti-drugs crackdown with profanity-laced outbursts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marcos and von der Leyen said relations between the EU and the Philippines were entering a new era.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We “are like-minded partners through our shared values of democracy, sustainable and inclusive prosperity, the rule of law, peace and stability, and human rights,” Marcos said, comments that reflected a stark departure from Duterte&#39;s hostile rhetoric against the EU.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine’s Zelensky likely to visit New York for UN General Assembly]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229552/ukraines-zelensky-likely-visit-new-york-un-general-assembly?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 05:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/01/cc8e8f83-addd-435a-bd7d-639c1c43baf9_fe137b1e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky is likely to head to New York in September for the United Nations General Assembly, where he is expected to make the case for his “peace formula” plan, according to people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky&#39;s 10-point blueprint for ending the conflict with Russia calls for Russian troops to withdraw completely from Ukraine, release all prisoners of war and deportees, and ensure food and energy security. It also includes security guarantees for Ukraine once the fighting ends and aims to restore safety around the occupied nuclear power plant in Zaporizhzhia, which he says is at risk from Russian sabotage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plan will be discussed this weekend at a gathering hosted by Saudi Arabia with more than two dozen nations invited. In New York, Zelensky is expected to take part in other sessions and meetings during the week of the general assembly, said the people, who asked not to be identified discussing confidential information.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky&#39;s office did not immediately respond to a request for comment.白宫国家安全委员会发言人拒绝置评。 The travel plans have not been locked down and could change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government in Kyiv has been pushing for a summit on the peace formula during the UN gathering. But some of Ukraine&#39;s allies are reluctant due to the complex logistics that would be involved, and prefer to hold events within the week&#39;s planned framework, the people said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some allies would also like to first see more countries from the so-called global south on board with the concept, one of the people said.他们补充说，另一种选择可能是安理会讨论乌克兰和平问题。俄罗斯可能会参加这样的会议。 Another person said nothing had been finalised yet about such meetings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russian President Vladimir Putin is not expected to travel to New York for the UN assembly, the people said. The Russian leader&#39;s movements have been severely limited due to an arrest warrant issued by the International Criminal Court for alleged war crimes related to the abduction of children from Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine to start talks with US on security guarantees: senior official&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Separately, the US could hold a Security Council meeting next month on child protection issues to coincide with Ukraine&#39;s independence day on August 24, the people said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Secretary of State Antony Blinken will lead a session on Thursday in the Security Council on “Famine and Conflict-Induced Global Food Insecurity” that is expected to focus on the war&#39;s impact after Russia&#39;s withdrawal from a plan that allowed shipments of grain from Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US is taking advantage of its turn in a monthly rotation to lead the Security Council and shape the topics it will discuss.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 05:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Is China in danger of Japanification? What can Beijing’s policymakers do to avoid lost decades?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3229517/china-danger-japanification-what-can-beijings-policymakers-do-avoid-lost-decades?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 04:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/000b1d49-a293-4a62-88e3-d3fc1c9bed1b_e2106b9d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;With China entering an era of slower growth, along with an ageing and shrinking workforce, weak consumer demand and a property market downturn, analysts are drawing strong parallels with Japan and raising the daunting prospect that the world&#39;s second-largest economy could be heading for a similar so-called lost decades of stagnation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan&#39;s growth slowed significantly after its asset price bubble burst at the end of 1989, with companies and households burdened by debt preferring to pay off their liabilities rather than spend money on goods and services. Its working-aged population was also declining, but debt continued to balloon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And in its “Fiscal Monitor” report in April, the International Monetary Fund estimated that Japan&#39;s public debt to gross domestic product ratio would continue to rise and would hit 258.2 per cent in 2023 - the highest in all advanced economies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China and Japan have pursued the same economic model – one that relies on high savings and high investment, with the governments also pushing for supply side measures that are designed to bolster exports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the key differences, however, is that China&#39;s credit boom was largely extended to state-owned or controlled companies, including local governments, meaning they only stop borrowing if instructed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deteriorating finances, particularly in its poorest provinces, have raised the spectre of a looming local government debt crisis in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The comparison with Japan] offers an interesting but not necessarily complete template of what might happen to China during the next five to 10 years,” said George Magnus, a research associate at Oxford University&#39;s China Centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The key lesson for China, analysts said, is not to repeat the same mistakes that Japanese policymakers made in the 90s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Bank of Japan was slow to make interest rate cuts, while the government guided its stimulus towards investment, rather than consumption, and both stock and property bubbles bursting turned into decades of stagnation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Richard Koo, chief economist at the Nomura Research Institute, said that there are already signs that Chinese companies and householders are reluctant to borrow even afte China&#39;s central bank cut interest rates in June in an attempt to spur consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And that&#39;s a very bad sign macroeconomically. Individually they might be doing the right things, but collectively, they may be killing the economy,” Koo told Bloomberg earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;French investment bank Natixis analysed 3,000 listed Chinese companies between 2021 and March 2023 and found that capital expenditure growth has not recovered since collapsing in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While China is nowhere near Japan&#39;s lost decade in the 1990s, it is true that corporates and households are now less sensitive to interest rates,” the bank said earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Despite the lower borrowing costs, most Chinese corporates are deleveraging, keeping more cash and making less investments due to poorer return on capital and confidence.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese real estate developers have seen a sharp decline in leverage revenue and capital expenditure, and as real estate forms 32 per cent of privately-owned companies in China by assets, they cannot be easily replaced by other sectors in the short term, Natixis said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Zhang Monan, deputy director of Institute of American and European Studies at the China Centre for International Economic Exchanges, said unlike Japan, there has not been a huge shock to Chinese asset prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Recovery is going from bad to worse&#39;: 6 takeaways from China&#39;s economic data&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;However, the credit demand in the property sector and for households has taken a hit over the past few years, said Zhang, who has previously worked for China&#39;s economic planner, the National Development and Reform Commission.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s economy is in transition – the traditional industries are taking a back seat, although the new industries are growing rapidly, the growth rate has yet to match the old engines,” Zhang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And China is still a developing country, there&#39;s room for growth when it comes to consumption.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang added that various pension reforms, as well to China&#39;s hukou household registration system, will boost consumption within rural migrant workers as access to public services is currently based on the birthplace of the holder rather than their place of work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Proposals, such as the establishment of a unified domestic market to break down market barriers within different regions, would also make a significant difference to long term growth, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If there are no reforms … we are not sure what faces China&#39;s economy in the future,” Zhang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But I think the new administration are pushing for various reforms … a lot of people are asking, why hasn&#39;t there been any large-scale stimulus? The focus [for policymakers] is on the medium to long term.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People&#39;s Bank of China adviser Liu Shijin said there is a sense of “confusion” in China over the new ways of generating growth as the tried and tested investment-led model is running out of steam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once again, the country is a crossroads that requires experimentation, or “crossing a river by feeling the stones” – a phrase coined by China&#39;s reformist leader Deng Xiaoping – according to Liu&#39;s speech last month, published by the China Development Research Foundation under the State Council last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some people may ask, we have been doing this for more than 40 years, is this still necessary? The answer is yes, because different problems have to be solved in different periods,” Liu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Issues such as achieving high-quality and sustainable economic and social development will still face a large amount of unknowns and uncertainties, and the answers cannot be found in sitting in an office in Beijing.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In perhaps its strongest message to China&#39;s private firms, Beijing offered solid political backing in a new 31-point action plan this month that aims to shore up the ailing sector that underpins economic growth, jobs and technological innovation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will new action plan give backbone of China&#39;s economy the wings to fly higher?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Magnus at Oxford University&#39;s China Centre said without a shift of policymaking focus towards consumers and the services industry, it would be difficult to get economic growth back on track.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The potential for growth as China gets richer is declining, when that happens you have to adapt your political institutions in order to change in which you can get smarter and more productive growth. That&#39;s basically the lesson richer countries have had to learn over the last 50 to 6o years,” Mangus added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What really defines the economic problems for China now, and for the foreseeable future, is whether politically it has the capacity to accommodate the changes or reforms which have to be undertaken in order to shift economic performance.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts said that President Xi Jinping&#39;s focus on making the state sector bigger and stronger may not be conducive to China&#39;s long-term growth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And as it seems inevitable that China&#39;s growth will be much slower at the end of the decade than previously anticipated, policymakers can still push back against the slowdown by channelling more credit into the economy, said Mark Williams, chief Asia economist at Capital Economics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But that would just be repeating the mistakes made in Japan and wouldn&#39;t ultimately work – it would just create more debt to add on top of the problems of slower growth a few years down the line,” Williams said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The only way to avoid a slowdown in the long run is to embrace significant structural change, allowing market forces to play a greater role across the economy and for the state to step back. That&#39;s not going to happen while Xi is leader.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 04:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Climate change: it’s past time to count the environmental costs of economic growth]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3229463/climate-change-its-past-time-count-environmental-costs-economic-growth?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.01 03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/f119f6b4-8fbf-44fc-abfe-617962c67fc6_907ad6ab.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Homepage editors at major news outlets had a difficult challenge last week. What should get top billing: US economic growth blowing past expectations or the fact that July was set to be the Earth&#39;s hottest month on record?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two items shifted position as the stories were updated last Thursday, when the sets of data were released, and remained well above the fold for much of the day, along with stories about searing heat in Phoenix and wildfires on Greek islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This juxtaposition is becoming increasingly difficult to stomach, particularly in the way that the surprising growth of the US economy is treated as something completely disparate from the others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It&#39;s difficult to know exactly how much of our economic activity is responsible for the extreme weather driving people from their homes in Europe and Canada because of wildfires, or into their homes in many other parts of the northern hemisphere to escape the unprecedented heat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We know that activities like smelting aluminium, raising livestock and transporting untold millions of needful things to our front doors send massive amounts of carbon into the atmosphere, trapping heat and, subsequently, causing increasingly disruptive climate events.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But too many of us have a persistent and Pavlovian response to news of economic growth: “strong growth good;增长疲弱不好”。 And the deeper analyses that follow the headline numbers tend to focus on the political implications for those in power and/or the likelihood of further interest rate rises.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before July&#39;s heat and countless other meteorological data points showed us that warnings of climate scientists were accurate, negative viewpoints about economic growth mostly centred on how the wealthiest tend to reap the most and the neediest are left to fight for scraps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These political arguments still resonate, as they should.但是，随着成为头条新闻的天气事件每年都更加令人信服地强调我们几十年来听到并忽视的警告，我们有更令人信服的理由质疑经济增长作为公共利益的效用。 It&#39;s killing us in increasingly apparent ways.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The cost of living in a world getting rapidly hotter? It&#39;s a killer&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;So what can we expect from the world&#39;s two largest economies and carbon emitters?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Joe Biden&#39;s White House regularly touts America&#39;s Inflation Reduction Act, which allocates billions in subsidies and other support for green energy, as the answer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This mobilisation of capital does more than any previous government initiative to hasten our transition to a lower-carbon economy, but you&#39;d be hard pressed to find any climate scientist willing to say that this alone will halt the climate crisis. It&#39;s going to take a broader effort.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There&#39;s no one step we can expect everyone to take.然而，我们应该期望每个人都做一些减少碳足迹的事情。 Anything.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This expectation will run up against resistance, of course. As we know from the way America&#39;s right-wing assailed any measure designed to fight the spread of Covid-19 and demonised public health officials trying to grapple with a poorly understood new contagion, no weather-related crisis will be dire enough to make a large chunk of the country change their habits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In China, meanwhile, a different dynamic is playing out. Beijing has declared that the country&#39;s carbon emissions will continue to climb until 2030, and we can assume that no pressure from within or abroad will convince the government to change course.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So what&#39;s to be done?环保主义者警告说，我们的经济正在将我们推入一场规模巨大的环境灾难，最终将导致经济崩溃。他们坚持认为，我们需要以不同的方式衡量我们的经济，以反映我们的产出可能造成的损害。这并不是一个新的论点。 Nor will such an approach to economic data be easy.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Capitalism with a conscience? Social stock exchanges could be the answer&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;How do we measure the carbon footprint of the solar panel industry?就其安装过程中开采工业金属、硅精炼和运输所产生的温室气体而言，太阳能电池板的环保程度如何？ The same questions apply for electric vehicles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is not an argument to halt the deployment of these vital technologies. It&#39;s a call for a clearer accounting of the real environmental impact of our economies and an inclusion of this analysis in every GDP report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The American right will call this a “woke” conspiracy.让他们。 Their message will be lost in the smoke of our burning forests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As thermometers reveal the accuracy of the climate warnings more clearly than ever, we will be forced to analyse the economic factors driving the crisis, and growth will no longer be treated as bullish news.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 01 Aug 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>