<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[A timeline of China’s 32-month Big Tech crackdown that killed the world’s largest IPO and wiped out trillions in value]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3227753/timeline-chinas-32-month-big-tech-crackdown-killed-worlds-largest-ipo-and-wiped-out-trillions-value?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.15 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/35154761-794b-426c-b654-7c1e4357f695_eb92b8a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国当局于 2020 年底发起了针对该国大型科技公司的监管风暴。人们担心该国的主要互联网平台变得过于庞大和强大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京对科技行业的监管使中国科技公司损失了数万亿美元的市值，削弱了世界上最具活力的行业之一第二大经济体，加速中美脱钩。结果，曾经在规模上与美国同行相媲美的中国大型科技公司现在规模要小得多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以下是 32 个月前开始的中国打击大型科技公司的主要里程碑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以下是中国打击大型科技公司的主要里程碑。 >;&lt;h3>;在监管罚款和股票回购之后，蚂蚁集团的 IPO 计划备受关注&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蚂蚁集团的首次公开募股，这将是有记录以来全球最大规模的首次公开募股，在上海和香港的最后一刻被取消，震惊了全球投资界。阿里巴巴集团联合创始人马云上个月发表有争议的演讲后，首次公开募股被取消。蚂蚁金服是《南华早报》所有者阿里巴巴的金融科技子公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国金融监管机构急忙将蚂蚁金服的业务纳入传统金融监管范围，迫使这家科技巨头进行内部重组。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月晚些时候，中国当局传唤了 27 家主要互联网公司，包括腾讯控股、外卖巨头美团以及 TikTok 母公司字节跳动和阿里巴巴，责令他们纠正涉嫌垄断行为、不正当竞争和假冒行为。中国的反垄断监管机构国家市场监督管理总局（SAMR）紧急出台了反垄断指南，以遏制互联网垄断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最高领导人在年度中央经济工作会议上强调会议指出，国家必须防止“资本无序扩张”，这一目标旨在遏制大型科技公司的影响力和规模。向投资者和企业家传达的信息是，中国互联网行业的“野蛮”增长已经结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平安夜，国家市场监督管理总局宣布正式对阿里巴巴启动反垄断调查。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国市场监管机构对阿里巴巴处以创纪录的 182 亿元人民币（28 亿美元）罚款，相当于其 2019 年收入的 4%，理由是滥用“自 2019 年以来其在中国在线零售平台服务市场的主导地位”。 2015年”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反垄断机构随后约谈阿里巴巴、腾讯、美团等34家科技公司，要求他们“充分重视阿里巴巴案的警示”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国市场监管机构自 2000 年代初起就开始调查并购案件，并对大型科技公司因未能报告某些交易进行反垄断审查而处以罚款。它对阿里巴巴、腾讯和网约车巨头滴滴出行开出了至少 22 处 50 万元人民币的罚款，这是中国反垄断法允许的最高处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;暴跌，企业开始剥离之前的投资以缩减资产负债表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国强大的互联网监管机构国家互联网信息办公室 (CAC) 也对滴滴出行发起了史无前例的调查，涉嫌违反数据和国家安全行为两天后，该公司在纽约证券交易所进行了 44 亿美元的首次公开募股。此举开辟了打击大型科技公司的新战线，导致中国在美国的首次公开募股陷入停顿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;滴滴被勒令停止在其主要应用程序上注册新用户。两个月后，中国的《数据安全法》正式生效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国对美团点评罚款 34 亿元人民币，原因是美团点评滥用其市场支配地位，采取“二选一”的方式。 ”这种做法迫使商家进行独家交易。此次罚款相当于美团 2020 年国内总收入 1147 亿元的 3% 左右。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当当局发布促进“健康饮食”的指导意见时，中国的监管风暴开始消退。平台经济的可持续发展”。文件重申了北京打击垄断、不公平竞争和滥用数据的承诺，但该文件还通过承认大型科技公司在经济中的作用并鼓励其发展，采取了更加积极的基调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;副总理刘鹤向几位科技高管表示，政府将支持该行业的发展和公开上市，这给科技股注入了一针强心剂，并让人们燃起了北京监管审查最糟糕时期已经过去的希望.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家网信办对滴滴全球数据违规行为处以人民币80亿元的罚款，结束了为期一年的调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;国家主席习近平在北京召开的中央经济工作会议上发表讲话。会议得出的结论是，将支持互联网平台在提振经济、创造就业和国际竞争方面“充分发挥能力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;滴滴全球表示已恢复新用户注册其网约车应用程序获得网信委批准后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同月，蚂蚁集团及其他 13 家平台公司表示，在金融监管机构的指导和监管下，他们“已基本完成业务整顿”。 2020 年底，蚂蚁金服被责令解决各种合规问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在政府阻止蚂蚁集团 IPO 两年半后，金融监管机构对这家金融科技巨头处以总计因违反“公司治理和金融消费者保护”相关规定被罚款71亿元。此举被行业专家视为中国对科技行业打压的结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国总理李强随后在一次研讨会上表示对大型科技公司的支持，而中国强大的经济规划机构则赞扬了阿里巴巴、腾讯和感谢美团为国家发展和技术进步做出的贡献。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 15 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nepali, Indonesian farm workers in UK trapped by ‘systemic’ recruitment debt bondage]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/article/3227786/nepali-indonesian-farm-workers-uk-trapped-systemic-recruitment-debt-bondage?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.15 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/d5ca5e7d-717e-4f24-b773-30018cee58aa_fbc5123a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;去年，当拉吉听说英国农民正在从尼泊尔雇用季节性工人时，他跳了起来有机会为他的家人赚取他认为可观的收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位两个孩子的父亲已经在马来西亚和沙特阿拉伯工作过，他认为他可以在 6 个月的农场工作中赚到足够的钱。英国，这样就不必再次在国外找到工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毕竟，他在社交媒体上读到，他每月可以赚取高达 3,000 英镑（3,870 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“尼泊尔国内没有足够的工作机会，所以这份工作对我来说是照顾家人的最大机会，”拉吉说。由于英国签证逾期，他使用了化名。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰国工人要求针对芬兰采摘浆果的困难采取行动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这名 36 岁的男子表示，他为签证和机票借了 26 万尼泊尔卢比（1,980 美元）的贷款，认为自己可以轻松支付&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，四个月内，拉吉和他的同事被告知他们工作的苹果农场不再有工作。招聘他们的机构表示，他们应该立即回国，因为没有其他工作机会，但向他们承诺今年会优先工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但英国农场在一月份停止雇用尼泊尔和印度尼西亚工人，因为有报道称，许多尼泊尔和印度尼西亚工人支付了过高的招聘费用，导致他们陷入债务束缚，许多人在签证到期后还没有回国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，一些已经在英国的人发现自己仍然背负着债务。慈善机构和移民专家表示，由于他们无法再以季节性工人的身份返回英国，更多人逾期居留并找到非正规工作来赚取所需的钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;反奴隶制慈善机构关注劳动力剥削 (Flex) 表示，移民工人经常被欺骗，向其祖国的当地经纪人支付非法招聘费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果你带着这个来到这个国家债务水平......那么你就不能简单地返回你的祖国。 Flex 首席执行官 Lucila Granada 表示：“我们可以合理地预期，处于这种情况的人将不得不到其他地方寻找工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;40 岁的巴哈杜尔（也使用化名）表示，他从亲戚那里借了 80 万尼泊尔卢比，以维持生计。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名孩子的父亲在 Covid-19 疫情严重影响旅游业之前曾担任登山向导，他说，一名经纪人告诉他，他在英国农场每月可以节省 40 万尼泊尔卢比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;相反，巴哈杜尔花光了所有工资还清了债务，在果园度过了令人筋疲力尽的六个月，却没有任何表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我没有向经纪人支付那么多钱，工作合同结束后我就可以回到自己的国家，并在下个赛季回到这里。”他说。 “但我必须把所有的钱都退回来还清贷款。现在我需要工作来存钱并养家糊口。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然许多尼泊尔和印度尼西亚工人返回家园，但像拉杰和巴哈杜尔这样的其他人却在非法工作，迫切需要偿还贷款并赚取足够的收入来维持生计。社区支持组织东南亚和东亚中心 (SEEAC) 认为，这次旅行值得。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SEEAC 项目经理 Nova-Fransisca Silitonga 表示，一名印度尼西亚工人将自己的家庭住宅作为抵押，银行贷款，而其他人则向邻居借钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果你无力偿还，你会在村子里感到羞耻，高利贷者可能会向你的家人借钱，”她说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Silitonga 表示，一些骗子以 2,500 英镑左右的价格向负债累累、希望留在英国的印尼人出售假英国居留卡和驾驶执照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bahadur 表示，他在季节性申请庇护时申请了庇护。工人签证已过期，在内政部评估他的申请期间可以合法留在该国。但他并不希望自己的申请能够获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我担心自己不能在这里呆太久。在内政部做出决定后，我要么去葡萄牙，要么非法留在这里。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴哈杜尔和拉吉都表示，一些尼泊尔工人利用走私者前往葡萄牙等欧洲国家，他们认为这样更容易在那里获得签证和工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Raj 表示，工人们必须付出如此大的努力来偿还债务，这是不公平的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“任何人都不应该在贷款后留下来因在国外工作而负债累累。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英国向中国、印度工人支付的工资高于其他少数民族，未能解决种族多样性问题&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;官方数据显示，乌克兰人曾经是英国最大的季节性农业工人群体，但当俄罗斯于 2022 年 2 月入侵乌克兰时，数量急剧下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;少数获得许可的招聘人员 - 被称为“计划”运营商转向亚洲来解决劳动力短缺问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方数据称，截至 3 月份的 12 个月内，英国发放了超过 35,000 份季节性工人签证，比上一年增加了 10%。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;随着政府今明两年将季节性工人签证配额增加至 45,000 个，这个数字将会上升——比 2019 年试点时的 2,500 个大幅跃升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但没有由于对海外招聘的监管，慈善机构担心更多的移民工人可能会面临债务奴役。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“实际情况几乎没有透明度。劳工权利组织 FairSquare 的研究员玛丽莲·克罗瑟 (Marilyn Croser) 表示：“政府采取了非常不干涉的方式来对其进行监管。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年与尼泊尔和印度尼西亚工人签订的合同被取消后，英国计划运营商开始招募员工来自其他亚洲国家，例如孟加拉国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“问题不是在系统层面上解决，而是从一个国家转移到另一个国家，”法律慈善机构反人口贩运和人口贩运组织的约翰娜·怀特 (Johanna White) 说道。劳工剥削部门。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;内政部表示，季节性工人计划是“英国农村经济的一个组成部分”，并允许海外工人每个季节重新申请，前提是他们在工作时间离开时签证到期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在单独的电子邮件评论中，内政部和代表超过 46,000 个英国农场的全国农民联盟拒绝就非法招聘费用发表评论，但两者都表示他们认真对待工人的福利.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;人口普查显示，自英国脱欧以来，英国对海外工人的依赖有所增加&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一些运营商表示，他们正在努力改善招聘流程。新获得许可的 Regency Recruitment 雇用了孟加拉国工人，该公司表示正在与一家反奴隶制慈善机构合作，以降低招聘阶段的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;董事总经理 Naseem Talukdar 表示，他的团队进行了深入的采访和参考检查，拒绝第三方的简历，一开始只雇用了大约 50 名员工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些人真的滥用了系统并利用了人们，这真是太遗憾了，”Talukdar 说。 “但这不应阻止像我们这样的公司开始改变现状。我们希望使这种情况可持续发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼泊尔工人 Raj 说，他希望通过打零工赚到足够的钱来养家糊口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我没有什么宏伟的计划永远留在英国或获得护照或成为公民。我只想为家乡的家人赚更多的钱。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 15 Jul 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China eyes Asean trade ties, but members fear ‘geopolitical trap’ as US also seeks regional influence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3227769/china-eyes-asean-trade-ties-members-fear-geopolitical-trap-us-also-seeks-regional-influence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.15 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/90d1c3bf-9962-4cca-b8e8-cebe924e2a53_d543d31d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这是关于中国多年来如何发展的两部分系列中的第一个故事加强贸易基础设施和加强联系的努力正在增强与东南亚的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两年前，当越南附近的中国港口城市的一家工厂破土动工时，一项雄心勃勃的计划启动了新能源材料供应商CNGR将在未来几年加强该公司的贸易联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该基地位于毗邻越南的港口城市钦州，一期投资100亿元人民币（美元）耗资 14 亿美元）建设了一家工厂，该工厂将作为 CNGR 的基地，从其印度尼西亚基地或合作伙伴接收镍和其他矿物的货物，并将生产锂电池的关键元素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;涵盖数百个工厂该厂址位于广西省钦州市，占地 20 英亩，选择该厂址是为了最好地服务于公司不同地质的客户。一期投产才一年多，目前还剩两期，总耗资330亿元，年数不详。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“可以作为互联互通的桥头堡”海外资源和物流。”5月，中核基地总经理胡培红对媒体代表团表示。 “我们在如此短的时间内建设和运营了工业基地（一期），因此我们可以与海外合作伙伴合作，并将其快速复制到中国之外。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;外国投资者连续第六次抛售中国债务月&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;其中一个好处是，从中国港口城市钦州到越南工业门户海防的航运现在只需半天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年 8 月，北京公布了中国西部陆海走廊计划，这在很大程度上被视为中国欠发达西部地区的又一项出口便利化和振兴举措。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国决策者对沿海工厂搬迁寄予厚望受政府激励措施和廉价劳动力成本的吸引，这些企业纷纷涌向内陆省份，同时通过与最近海港的快速交通连接仍可保持其竞争力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，铁路连接和基础设施项目已创建了一条贸易和物流通道架起中国西部与东南亚国家联盟的桥梁。而北部湾经济圈——又称北部湾——则是中国与东盟合作的见证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与之前上海或广州的航运选择相比，北部湾港口——钦州、防城港和北海——为这些地区的制造商提供了一条捷径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，像CNGR这样的许多中国企业急于在东盟国家附近建厂也反映出一个新的现实——劳动力数量不断增加- 自 2018 年以来，电子工厂等密集型制造商已转移到东南亚，以避免美国对中国商品征收惩罚性关税，而且华盛顿仍在努力在关键供应链中取代中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，努力在国际金融困难和疫情后经济复苏缓慢的情况下，进军美国或欧洲市场的努力受到“去风险”的阻碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“双方需要一个中国-东盟共同市场应对日益严重的逆全球化和地缘政治动荡带来的外部挑战。”香港中文大学深圳研究院全球与当代中国高级研究院院长郑永年表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑永年作为主张中国在全球舞台上崛起的政治学家，他是参加 2020 年 8 月习近平主席主办的研讨会的少数专家之一，该研讨会解释了中国向内向型“双循环战略”的转变——北京方面将采用这一术语经常使用来强调在面临令人担忧的内部和外部条件时自给自足的必要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济一体化将为中国企业提供更大的市场空间来吸收制造产能并促进使用中国制造5月下旬，郑在广州举行的中国-东盟经济关系研讨会上表示，资本、技术、管理和标准是20亿人口的共同市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东盟10个成员国——6亿人口的市场人民 - 已超过美国和欧盟，成为中国最大的贸易伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;前官员表示，中国与东盟的接触归结为经济收益&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;双方共同努力，可以确保郑补充说，亚洲经济体仍然处于全球货物贸易的中心，同时致力于稳定全球产业链、供应链和价值链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前商务部副部长魏建国在同一场研讨会上表示，亚洲共同市场” ”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是全球化的一大受益者，成为世界工厂。然而，地缘政治分裂——俄罗斯-乌克兰战争、北京和莫斯科之间的战略伙伴关系、美国和欧盟摆脱中国的风险——可能会重塑全球制造业、贸易和投资，有可能将全球生产分为三个次中心：北美、欧洲和亚洲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由 10 个成员国组成的东盟——一个拥有 6 亿人口的市场——已经超越美国和欧盟，成为中国最大的贸易伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，中国美国并不是该地区唯一的参与者，美国也在推动其印太经济框架（IPEF），该框架由 14 个亚太国家组成，包括越南、泰国、马来西亚、菲律宾、新加坡和文莱。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;推动区域基础设施互联互通，包括通过“一带一路”倡议和亚洲基础设施投资银行的努力，被认为在中国和东盟之间建立共同市场的提议中至关重要，特别是在预计中国与美国的关系将继续冷淡的情况下.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前的陆海走廊计划已经使中国西部省份与东盟成员国紧密联系，将货物运往107个国家和地区，是便利贸易、投资和运输的关键一步&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京表示，计划到2025年将区域海铁联运能力提高到50万个20英尺标准箱（TEU），同时将跨境货运列车总数提高到2,000列。到2025年，广西北部湾港口和海南省洋浦港的集装箱吞吐量将分别达到1000万标准箱和500万标准箱。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国以大量原油应对能源危机-石油加工&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;由于北部湾港口和整个广西地区处于中国国内和国际循环的交汇处，增强运输能力已成为北京的优先事项，预计一项新举措将引领国家发展和改革委员会新闻发言人孟伟在谈到该建设时表示：“它已成为西部地区经济发展和开放的重要引擎。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最高经济规划师誓言要尽快扩大大规模运输能力，包括陆海联运、公铁联运或国际铁路货运。它还承诺优化产业，促进走廊沿线经济一体化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要不断扩大影响范围，不断扩大朋友圈，”孟在北京举行的媒体吹风会上表示。 6 月 16 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贸易和投资往往紧随基础设施互联互通而来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至去年，中国与东南亚 10 国集团的贸易额已跃升至 9753 亿美元 –较2019年的6415亿美元大幅增长。两国作为彼此最大的贸易伙伴，通过贸易保持高度联系。 1-4月，东盟占中国国际贸易总额的15.7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国与东盟目前处于双赢局面”，中国贸促会研究员周金柱表示国际贸易部，一个在全球范围内促进中国贸易和投资的半官方机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东南亚对中国的主要出口包括电子电气设备、矿产和燃料，东盟则获得机械设备、电子产品、服装&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年前四个月，中国对东盟直接投资增长超过20%，超过20万家中国企业在该地区投资，为东盟提供了数十万美元的投资。周说，基础设施建设的推动还增加了边境地区的交通联系以及到达越南、柬埔寨和泰国的国际货运列车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些新的进展迹象正在出现&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近来，广西边境小城东兴的工业园区，已有十几家新企业落地。广西东兴口岸服务中心主任陈晓表示，去年，包括电子产品、环保板材、眼镜镜片制造商在内的企业合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国国务院总理李强会见越南总理促进合作&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;2018年以来，大量机电产品通过广西陆路口岸运往越南，然后在越南变成成品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;完成后，很多又被运回中国广西发展和改革委员会高级顾问黄永辉表示，预计贸易量将增加。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去，从中国西部经长江到达新加坡和重庆等东南亚城市，需要大约27天的时间， ”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国游客选择留在国内，削弱了东南亚的旅游业经济复苏&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;TWT Supply China的创始人Bob Wang在广西边境城市凭祥拥有3000多辆合同重型卡车，他表示，成品车和卡车的范围不断扩大。往返于中国和东盟国家之间的半成品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“水果、电子产品、新型跨境电商销售的产品、纺织品……同时，三星、苹果、耐克、阿迪达斯等的加工基地富士康现在位于越南北部，但他们的原材料、半成品和包装材料都离不开中国的供应，每天都需要从中国运来。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国像王这样的商人也在计划新的商机，以进军东盟成员国新兴的中产阶级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们创建了许多TikTok帐户，并通过分享各种翻译的中国电影和电视节目吸引了近5000万粉丝。我们很快就会直播中国商品，以吸引这些东南亚用户。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凭祥一位餐厅经理表示，每天越来越多的越南人跨境消费。 “随着越来越多的东盟发展中国家普通民众致富，我们期待跨境旅游业的蓬勃发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;‘只有穿鞋的人才知道鞋在哪里’：中国出口商的艰难时期&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;尽管北京对加强关系抱有极大热情，但东南亚集团仍应保持中立，以此作为实施近期与中国合作倡议的先决条件，例如东盟与中国之间的自由贸易区或由 15 个成员国组成的区域经济联盟印度尼西亚战略与国际研究中心研究员Veronika Saraswati表示，全面经济伙伴关系（RCEP）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美中竞争影响该地区的和平与稳定，并使东盟更加分裂而不是统一，越南社会科学院东南亚岛屿国家研究部主任 Duong Van Huy 上个月末在广州研讨会上表示，美国已经失去了在该地区的中心地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国仍然是一个他说：“中国是东南亚重要的安全提供者，而东盟经济在很大程度上依赖中国。因此，像越南这样的东盟成员国担心陷入地缘政治陷阱，而不是陷入地缘政治陷阱。”倾向于美国反对中国，反之亦然。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 15 Jul 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New York architect charged in decade-old Gilgo Beach serial killings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227800/new-york-architect-charged-decade-old-gilgo-beach-serial-killings?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.15 06:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/15/2aabc706-1a0f-4a91-9920-9e13a2ff9943_186830d5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周五，一名纽约建筑师因长期悬而未决的谋杀案被指控三名女性的尸体十多年前在长岛海滩附近被发现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;59 岁的雷克斯·休尔曼 (Rex Heuermann) 因 2009 年和 2010 年三名女性死亡而面临谋杀指控，是“主要嫌疑人”官员称，这起谋杀案涉及第四名妇女的谋杀案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“雷克斯·休尔曼是一个恶魔，”萨福克县警察局长罗德尼·哈里森告诉记者。 “一个毁掉家庭的掠夺者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;霍伊尔曼周四晚上在曼哈顿被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;霍伊尔曼住在吉尔戈海滩附近的小镇马萨佩夸公园，尸体就是在那里被发现的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据检察官称，所有四名女性——安布尔·科斯特洛（Amber Costello）、梅丽莎·巴泰勒米（Melissa Barthelemy）、梅根·沃特曼（Megan Waterman）和莫林·布雷纳德-巴恩斯（Maureen Brainard-Barnes）——都是 20 多岁，都是性工作者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“四名受害者被发现时都处于相似的位置，被捆绑着。美国地区检察官雷·蒂尔尼 (Ray Tierney) 表示，“用皮带或胶带以类似的方式，发现三名受害者被粗麻布类材料包裹着。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒂尔尼表示，针对 Heuermann 的案件是基于 DNA 证据从一个废弃的披萨盒中，找到了他与受害者的手机数据，并在一名被谋杀妇女的家中看到了他的车辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于每一起谋杀案，他都有一部一次性手机，并使用与受害者沟通，”蒂尔尼说。 “然后，在受害者死亡后不久，他就会扔掉一次性手机。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;沉迷于电视杀戮的韩国女子刺伤受害者，以“尝试谋杀”&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;Heuermann 还对谋杀案的调查进行了数百次互联网搜索，提出了诸如以下问题：“为什么长岛连环杀手还没有被抓获？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“除此之外，还有一个蒂尔尼说，在休尔曼的电脑上发现了很多酷刑色情内容，以及你认为的女性被虐待、被强奸和杀害的描述。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国检察官表示，休尔曼拥有 92 支枪支的许可证，在其中一名受害者失踪后，他还向一名受害者的妹妹拨打了“嘲讽电话”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，当他据称犯下谋杀案时，休尔曼的妻子和孩子总是在城外，这也是 2020 年一项谋杀案的主题。 Netflix 电影《迷失的女孩》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2010 年以来，在长岛同一片偏僻的海滨地带发现了至少 11 具尸体，但警方此前曾表示，他们并不相信所有案件已链接。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heuermann 是 RH Consultants and Associates 的所有者，该公司在其网站上自称为“纽约市首屈一指的建筑公司”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heuermann 去年接受了一次采访YouTube 节目名为“Bonjour Realty”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我是一名问题解决者，在长岛出生和长大，自 1987 年以来一直在曼哈顿工作 - 很长时间，”Heuermann 在采访中说道。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net NET&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/分区>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 15 Jul 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: Russia’s Wagner mercenaries emerge in Belarus as troop trainers after failed revolt]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3227799/ukraine-war-russias-wagner-mercenaries-emerge-belarus-troop-trainers-after-failed-revolt?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.15 03:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/15/7c860d38-314a-45e7-954b-2aa316a8190f_3e334a81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;瓦格纳雇佣兵已在白俄罗斯成为军事教官，这是该组织的第一个正式标志presence in the country since the mutiny in Russia that spiralled into the most serious threat to President Vladimir Putin&#39;s Kremlin rule.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Belarusian defence ministry posted a video on Telegram on Friday that showed territorial defence soldiers receiving instructions from Wagner trainers at a camp near Osipovichi, about 100km (62 miles) southeast of the capital Minsk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Their Soviet-style uniforms contrasted with the modern battle dress worn by the Wagner mercenaries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “This is a new way of training territorial troops,” Maksim Payevskiy, head of the Belarus General Staff&#39;s territorial forces department, said on the video. The training may be extended across the country in future, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Belarus President Alexander Lukashenko brokered the agreement that persuaded Wagner leader Yevgeny Prigozhin to end his brief rebellion June 24 after his mercenaries came within 200km (124 miles) of Moscow, meeting little resistance from army units.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin had vowed to oust Defence Minister Sergei Shoigu and Chief of the General Staff Valery Gerasimov, blaming them for failures in Russia&#39;s war in Ukraine and accusing them of seeking to “destroy” Wagner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin agreed as part of the deal to let Prigozhin go to Belarus with any Wagner fighters who wanted to join him, though the group has shown little intention of relocating to the neighbouring country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin has not been seen in public since the mutiny ended.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Putin hosted mercenary leader at Kremlin after aborted mutiny&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Kremlin disclosed on Monday that Putin held nearly three hours of talks with Prigozhin and 35 Wagner commanders five days after the rebellion that the president said had brought Russia to the brink of “civil war”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin said he had offered Wagner the option of continuing to serve as a single unit under their battlefield commander in Ukraine, nicknamed “Grey Hair”, but that Prigozhin had rejected the proposal, the Kommersant newspaper reported on Friday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 15 Jul 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia ‘not constructive’ at Asean talks, US says, shows no change on Ukraine]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227796/russia-not-constructive-asean-talks-us-says-shows-no-change-ukraine?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.15 01:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/15/800ab19b-79cd-4cc0-bba5-080f8c203d71_9c381917.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on Friday that his Russian counterpart Sergey Lavrov had not been constructive during this week&#39;s meeting between top diplomats from major powers and their Southeast Asian counterparts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking after the Asean Regional Forum – which involved the foreign ministers of Association of Southeast Asian Nations member states and key strategic partners such as China, the US, India and Russia – Blinken said Lavrov used his interventions to attack Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting in Jakarta marked only the second time Blinken and Lavrov have been in the same room since Moscow launched its invasion of Ukraine last year. They last saw each other in New Delhi in March, on the sidelines of a G20 meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He focused on the United States, unlike any other country, on a totally negative presentation agenda, in which he effectively attributed every problem in the world to the United States,” Blinken told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US-China relations: we must talk security, Wang Yi tells Antony Blinken&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“I didn&#39;t hear anything from Foreign Minister Lavrov that suggested any change in direction concerning what Russia is doing in Ukraine,” Blinken said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On China, Blinken reiterated Washington&#39;s oft-stated position that the US was “like many countries in the region … concerned by the PRC&#39;s growing assertiveness in the South and East China Seas and on the Taiwan Strait”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US diplomat met China&#39;s foreign policy chief Wang Yi on Thursday for more than 90 minutes, less than a month after his visit to Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a statement on Friday, the Chinese foreign ministry quoted Wang as saying the two countries should find ways to stop “grey rhinos” and handle “black swans” – high-impact or unexpected events – and create conditions to stabilise US-China relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US needs to take a rational and pragmatic approach, work with China in the same direction … expand communication channels in diplomatic and security fields, make their communication more effective, and promote smooth people-to-people exchanges,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to reporters in Jakarta, the European Union&#39;s foreign policy chief Josep Borrell also discussed Lavrov&#39;s presentation, saying the minister spoke “very aggressively” and vowed that Moscow&#39;s war in Ukraine would continue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lavrov said “everything is a &#39;West conspiracy&#39; and the war will continue … as Russia is not at all ready to stop the aggression and withdraw troops”, Borrell said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Russian foreign minister did not speak to the media following the meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China, Russia vow to work together to boost regional ties in Jakarta talks&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But in an interview with Indonesian media earlier this week, Lavrov stated that the war in Ukraine would not end until Western nations give up their efforts to “defeat” Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier on Friday, Blinken held talks with Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Yoshimasa and South Korea&#39;s top diplomat Park Jin, who were also attending the forum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken said at the start of that meeting that he had “lost count” of the number of times the three of them had met in the last two years, amid strengthening ties and increasing concerns about China&#39;s assertiveness and the threat posed by North Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s evidence of the fact that our three countries are joined in a common vision, a common approach to the future of the region that we share: a free and open Indo-Pacific; one that is secure, prosperous, connected, resilient,” Blinken said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With Pyongyang having tested a long-range ballistic missile this week – in the midst of the Asean meetings – Park said it was important for the three countries to “strengthen our resolve to respond firmly and resolutely, unequivocally, against North Korea&#39;s continuous provocations”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think that watertight coordination among the three countries will be essential to achieve the complete denuclearisation of North Korea,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Along with the Asean biannual summit of national leaders, the regional forum is among the highlights of the bloc&#39;s year-long meetings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An Asean-only meeting held earlier in the week was dominated by the internal crisis in Myanmar, where the ruling junta has remained intransigent about implementing a road map to democracy it agreed with Asean two months after staging a coup in February 2021.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 15 Jul 2023 02:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nato is clearly trying to start a cold war with China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227558/nato-clearly-trying-start-cold-war-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.15 01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/7a68713c-55ed-43f4-9ae0-dcfe09bd86d9_7cf79e5e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The so-called China challenge was expected to occupy a good chunk of the agenda at the recently concluded Nato summit in Vilnius, Lithuania. But the blunt language used to describe China in the final communique was still a surprise, and left no room for doubt that the US and its allies are trying to engage China in a new cold war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The People&#39;s Republic of China&#39;s (PRC) stated ambitions and coercive policies challenge our interests, security and values,” said the transatlantic security alliance. “中华人民共和国的恶意混合和网络行动及其对抗性言论和虚假信息针对盟友并损害联盟安全。” It even accused China of “coercive tactics and efforts to divide the alliance”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an immediate rebuttal, the Chinese mission to the European Union vehemently criticised the communique, denouncing it as replete with “repetitive rhetoric echoing the Cold War mentality and ideological bias”, saying it “deliberately smears China”. “As a product of the Cold War, Nato has a bad track record in history,” it said, adding: “We firmly oppose Nato&#39;s eastward movement into the Asia-Pacific region.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A faction within the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation, influenced by Washington, has been trying to intensify anti-China sentiment for quite some time. This clique has since put up an ostentatious display of radicalism, anxiety, aggression and impulsive meddling in the affairs of the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The leaders of Japan, South Korea, Australia and New Zealand, designated “partners across the globe” by Nato, were invited to the summit for a second consecutive year, sending a clear message of the military bloc&#39;s intention to expand its footprint into the Asia-Pacific. As part of efforts that appear to further encircle China, Nato signed an “individually tailored partnership programme” with Japan and hosted a leaders&#39; session with the “Asia-Pacific 4” – Japan, South Korea, Australia and New Zealand – on the second and final day of the Vilnius summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It would come as no surprise that the target of such moves is China. However, the intricate strategic manoeuvring being planned by Nato and the United States in this expansive game of chess is fraught with inherent risks and uncertainties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Back in December 2019, Nato Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg had expressed with certainty that Nato would not venture into the South China Sea, acknowledging, however, that China&#39;s increasing presence near Nato areas required attention.三年半过去了，跨大西洋安全联盟发现自己处于不同的位置，不再忽视亚太地区。 The reverberations of the Ukraine war have given Nato&#39;s leadership an excuse to explore deeper links between the Indo-Pacific and European security domains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Vilnius summit reflects Nato&#39;s evolving perspective and approach towards China.多年来，中国一直是一个遥远的关注点，甚至在北约 2010 年的战略概念文件中也没有提及。 But the Trump administration&#39;s incessant lobbying appears to have caused a gradual shift in perspective among some European allies, and China eventually appeared on Nato&#39;s radar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In December 2019, China was acknowledged in a Nato communique for the first time, marking a major shift in the military alliance&#39;s recognition of China&#39;s strategic significance. This was the initial step in Nato&#39;s official evolving stance on China, and subsequent months saw a progressive increase in its references to China, which were accompanied by a more assertive tone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the 2021 summit in Brussels, the Nato communique explicitly sounded the alarm, cautioning that China&#39;s “stated ambitions and assertive conduct” posed systemic challenges to the rules-based international order and to areas directly affecting the security of the alliance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the eruption of the Ukraine conflict in February last year, Nato had maintained a limited focus on China, primarily addressing its involvement in Europe.因此，围绕北约在印太地区角色的讨论很少。 But the escalating significance of China prompted a notable shift in Nato&#39;s 2022 strategic concept paper, which dedicated more attention to China than before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite Stoltenberg&#39;s earlier assertion that Nato would not venture into the South China Sea, recent actions indicate a different emerging reality.北约与其在印太地区的主要伙伴，包括澳大利亚、新西兰、日本和韩国，进行了频繁和持续的对话。 It even discussed plans to establish an office in Japan, although France has vetoed the move.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While there remains no discourse on integrating these partners into Nato&#39;s military plans, the conflict in Ukraine is being used to draw the alliance deeper into the Indo-Pacific sphere.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s “systemic challenges” were initially acknowledged in Nato&#39;s 2022 strategic concept paper.维尔纽斯峰会公报不仅保留了这一术语的使用，还谈到了中国对北约构成的具体威胁，以及北约应对这些威胁的准备。 Clearly, Nato&#39;s perception of China and its relationship with Beijing have undergone substantial changes over the past year, and the attitude looks increasingly confrontational.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This inclination is evident not just in official statements but also in Nato&#39;s actions, such as its heightened focus on the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Nato&#39;s attempt to establish a liaison office in Tokyo have not materialised, Nato might well pursue alternative approaches to assert its presence in the Asia-Pacific, including fostering substantial bilateral relations with its designated regional partners and even, potentially engaging in joint military operations. Such actions would only escalate tensions in the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 15 Jul 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Erdogan says Putin agreed to Ukraine grain deal extension]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3227794/erdogan-says-putin-agreed-ukraine-grain-deal-extension?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.15 00:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/15/7559d322-96d6-429f-a410-fa2b96fabe23_89a740ad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Russian President Vladimir Putin has agreed to extend the Black Sea grain deal which expires next week, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan said on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan told reporters he had spoken with his Russian counterpart about the crucial deal allowing for the export of Ukrainian grain to ease a global food crisis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deal, signed five months after the Russian invasion of Ukraine, is set to expire on Monday, and Putin has repeatedly threatened not to renew it because of obstacles to Russia&#39;s own exports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are preparing to welcome Putin in August and we agree on the extension of the Black Sea grain corridor,” Erdogan told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But when asked by Russian press agencies, the Kremlin spokesperson did not confirm Erdogan&#39;s claims. “There is no statement about this from the Russian side,” Dmitry Peskov said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking in Jakarta, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken called on Russia to extend the deal, warning that the most vulnerable countries would suffer without it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Developing countries including in the region will pay the price including quite literally with higher food prices, as well as greater food scarcity,” Blinken told reporters after Southeast Asian talks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres this week sent Putin a letter about the extension of the deal. He supports removing hurdles to Russia exporting its fertilisers – another element Moscow has complained is not being respected.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Ball&#39;s in Putin&#39;s court&#39;: China urged to push Russia to renew Ukraine grain deal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Erdogan said he hopes “that with this letter we will ensure the extension of the grain corridor with our joint efforts and those of Russia”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin on Thursday warned that “not one” of Moscow&#39;s conditions for the deal to function had been met.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I want to emphasise that nothing was done, nothing at all. It&#39;s all one-sided,” Putin said in a televised interview, adding: “We will think about what to do, we have a few more days.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deal, which Erdogan helped broker, has allowed Ukraine to ship more than 32 million tonnes of grain past Russian warships in the Black Sea.大部分粮食都用来养活非洲、中东和其他地区发展中国家的人民。 If the exports were again blocked, food prices could spiral even higher than they are now.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Travel chaos: hundreds of thousands face disruption at London’s Gatwick Airport this summer after strike vote]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227793/travel-chaos-hundreds-thousands-face-disruption-londons-gatwick-airport-summer-after-strike-vote?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.15 00:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/77fe23c6-707d-4dc9-b922-59f8bdc4ef0f_fc2feab0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hundreds of thousands of British holidaymakers face potential disruption to their travel plans at the start of the school summer break, after almost 1,000 workers at London&#39;s Gatwick Airport voted to strike in a dispute over pay.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Unite union said on Friday that members, including baggage handlers and check-in staff, who are employed by four private contractors will walk out for four days from July 28 and again for a subsequent four-day stretch from August 4.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The union said the action will “inevitably” cause disruption to flights at the height of the summer holiday season after the school year has ended. The airlines affected are British Airways, easyJet, Ryanair, TUI, WestJet and Wizz Air.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UK&#39;s Heathrow security staff call off summer strikes, averting travel chaos&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Gatwick, which is just south of the UK capital, is London&#39;s second-busiest airport after Heathrow, with a particular focus during the summer to Europe&#39;s beach resorts in the Mediterranean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 4,410 flights are expected to depart Gatwick across all the strike days, equating to more than 840,000 seats, according to aviation data company Cirium.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those involved in the dispute are employed by ASC, Menzies Aviation, GGS and DHL Services, which conduct outsourced operations for airlines including ground handling, baggage handling and check-in. Unite said it has been in negotiations with the four companies since January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As part of Unite&#39;s unyielding focus on the jobs, pay and condition of its members, the union has drawn a line in the sand and is committed to eradicating the scourge of low pay at the airport,” said Sharon Graham, the union&#39;s general secretary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Phil Lloyd, a senior vice-president at Menzies Aviation, one of the companies involved, said Unite rejected its offer for an 11 per cent pay rise for its ground services employees at Gatwick, which he added is on top of last year&#39;s 10 per cent increase.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are in continued discussions with our airline partners and remain committed to seeking a resolution,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Patient care &#39;on a knife-edge&#39; during UK doctors&#39; strike over pay&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Britain has witnessed a number of strikes over the past few months as workers across a range of sectors try to get wage raises that at least keep pace with inflation.尽管通货膨胀率已从峰值回落，但仍处于 8.7% 的高位。 Unite said most workers who are set to strike are paid less than £12 pounds (US$15.50) an hour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gatwick, like other airports in Europe, is already suffering major disruption because of air traffic control restrictions as a result of strike action, staff shortages and airspace closures related to Russia&#39;s full-scale invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are aware of the recent ballot result and will support our airlines with their contingency plans to ensure that flights operate as scheduled,” a spokesperson for the airport said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fans of Hong Kong pop star Coco Lee can bid farewell to singer at funeral service at end of month]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227791/funeral-arrangements-hong-kong-pop-star-coco-lee-announced-sister?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 23:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/d3e4caca-bb81-4724-a865-30eede30fbf8_f35a05b1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A public vigil for the late Hong Kong pop diva Coco Lee will be held at the end of the month, her family has said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nancy Lee, the singer-songwriter&#39;s older sister, said in a Facebook post on Friday that the funeral service would take place on July 31 and the procession on August 1 at the Hong Kong Funeral Home in North Point.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The funeral service at the grand hall will be open to the public from 6pm to 10pm on July 31, and remain closed for the rest of the time. Thank you for your kind attention,” she wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 30-second montage that showed several photographs of Coco Lee with her fans was attached to the post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nancy Lee earlier revealed that memorial services will also be held in mainland China and Taiwan in August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coco Lee, who had struggled with depression, died in hospital on July 5 after trying to take her own life. She was 48.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong may honour late singer Coco Lee on Avenue of Stars, authorities say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The star, Hong Kong-born and brought up in San Francisco from the age of nine, launched her career aged 18 when she won the first runner-up spot in broadcaster TVB&#39;s New Talent Singing Awards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She later became the first Chinese singer to be signed by record label Sony Music.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong diva Coco Lee dies; &#39;her rays of light will last forever,&#39; sisters say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;She was also the first and only Chinese artist to sing at the Oscars, where she performed “A Love Before Time” from Ang Lee&#39;s award-winning 2000 film Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you have suicidal thoughts, or you know someone who is, help is available. For Hong Kong, dial +852 2896 0000 for The Samaritans or +852 2382 0000 for Suicide Prevention Services. In the US, call the 988 Suicide &amp; Crisis Lifeline at 988 or +1 800 273 8255. For a list of other nations&#39; helplines, see this .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 23:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Young woman arrested in connection with  death of Robert De Niro’s grandson]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227790/young-woman-arrested-connection-death-robert-de-niros-grandson?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 23:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/90284c55-13f7-4c3f-9714-fc310eb395dd_5840fffa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A 20-year-old woman has been arrested in New York City in connection with the death of Robert De Niro&#39;s grandson, multiple reports have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leandro De Niro-Rodriguez – the son of De Niro&#39;s adopted daughter, Drena De Niro – was 19 years old when he died.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;De Niro-Rodriguez was found dead in his apartment in downtown Manhattan on July 2, law enforcement sources said. His mother announced her son&#39;s death on July 3 and said he died after he was sold pills.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m deeply distressed by the passing of my beloved grandson Leo”, De Niro, 79, said in a statement earlier this month. “We&#39;re greatly appreciative of the condolences from everyone”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An official cause of death has not been released.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Robert De Niro&#39;s grandson Leandro De Niro Rodriguez dead at 19&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Law enforcement sources said Sofia Haley Marks has been arrested in connection with De Niro-Rodriguez&#39;s death.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marks&#39; arrest on Thursday was part of a joint investigation by the New York Police Department, the Drug Enforcement Administration, and the Department of Homeland Security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The DEA and DHS did not immediately respond to requests for comment, and the NYPD said it had no information to provide on the reported arrest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marks will appear in federal court on Friday. It was not immediately clear if Marks had a lawyer.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>