<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Women, girls tell of horrific, traumatic rape, sexual assault in Sudan as conflict rages]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3228038/women-girls-tell-horrific-traumatic-rape-sexual-assault-sudan-conflict-rages?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 23:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/75ed3e3d-22f4-4110-a91d-37256ff1ad48_e73327db.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;5 月 9 日，也就是她 12 岁生日后不久，Muna 离开了喀土穆的家，步行到当地的商店。她经常独自跑腿，很快就会回到母亲身边。但这次不是。两名买烟的士兵注意到穆娜正在挑选面包，其中一人抓住了她的手臂，另一人则举起了步枪，威胁店主与其保持距离。他们将她拖到附近的一个建筑工地并强奸了她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些士兵是快速支援部队的成员，这是一个准军事组织，在过去三个月里一直在与苏丹军队作战，争夺首都的控制权。两人都享有可怕的名声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;穆纳被扔在路边，浑身流血，痛苦不堪，但在家族朋友店主的帮助下，穆纳回到了家。她的父母向司法当局提出投诉，司法当局将他们转介给一位心理学家，而心理学家则建议他们避开最近的医院，因为该医院由无国界医生组织控制。相反，他们在一家私人诊所检查了穆纳是否患有性传播感染，并向一家药房索要卫生巾和止痛药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几天后，一家人逃离了这座城市。在消失之前，穆娜的父母允许分享她的故事，但为了她的安全，她的真实姓名没有被使用。她的强奸行为——政府文件披露并得到两名援助人员证实——是苏丹冲突中士兵实施性暴力的更广泛模式的一部分。活动人士表示，在一个外国记者基本上被政府禁止的国家，许多案件都没有得到报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;联合国报告乱葬坑后，国际刑事法院正在调查苏丹达尔富尔地区的杀戮&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;四月，自十月政变以来一直统治苏丹的两位将军开始就一项国际支持的民主过渡计划争论不休。随着冲突不再成为媒体关注的焦点，邻国——乍得、中非共和国、埃及、厄立特里亚、埃塞俄比亚、利比亚和南苏丹——以及美国和沙特阿拉伯正在努力斡旋和平，以避免全面内战。战争跨越国界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自冲突开始以来，已有超过 290 万人离开家园，其中近 70 万人在该地区寻求庇护。根据美国研究组织武装冲突地点和事件数据项目的数据，约有 3,000 人被杀。无国界医生组织和苏丹军队都被指控犯有虐待行为，包括针对像穆纳这样的妇女和女孩的性暴力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国驻苏丹人权高专办表示，已收到关于 21 起与冲突有关的性暴力事件的可靠报告。至少 57 名妇女和女童遭受暴力侵害。社会发展部下属政府打击暴力侵害妇女行为处处长苏利玛·伊沙克 (Sulima Ishaq) 表示，她的团队已记录了 88 起事件，其中 42 起发生在喀土穆，其余发生在达尔富尔地区，这是出于种族动机的袭击事件。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;根据记录了穆纳袭击事件的伊沙克的说法，这些案件只占总数的一小部分。 “这些数字并不代表真正发生的事情”，她说。在这个以保守为主的国家，大多数权力职位都由男性担任，“性暴力存在很多耻辱，而且这一切都没有得到充分报道”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;至少 22 名平民在附近的空袭中丧生。苏丹喀土穆&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;卫生工作者和活动人士表示，绝大多数提出虐待指控的女孩和妇女都将矛头指向无国界医生组织。该准军事组织的发言人否认了所谓的毫无根据的指控，并补充说“无国界医生组织强烈谴责一切形式的不道德行为，并断然拒绝对我们部队的指控。”苏丹军队发言人没有回答问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冲突中迄今为止记录最严重的案件之一发生在 5 月 1 日，当时无国界医生部队士兵绑架了 25 名来自苏丹的妇女（年龄在 14 岁至 56 岁之间）。达尔富尔地区的尼亚拉，前往境内流离失所者营地。根据伊沙克所在单位撰写的一份事件报告，他们被带到一家酒店，在那里多次遭到强奸。伊沙克表示，七人拒绝医疗帮助，要么是因为他们害怕受到侮辱，要么是因为他们所遭受的创伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;战争期间的强奸和性侵犯旨在羞辱社区和个人，让他们完全屈服。 ，两者都被视为战争罪和违反国际人道主义法的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在苏丹，武装分子也犯下此类行为，试图迫使平民离开家园，他们占领了家园并将其用作避难所。为苏丹各地性侵犯受害者提供帮助的女权活动家埃纳斯·穆扎米尔 (Enas Muzamil) 表示，他们会在避难所或安置狙击手。她说：“除了抢劫、占领房屋和驱逐居民外，民兵成员还在喀土穆和达尔富尔犯下这些罪行。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在和平时期，医生和卫生工作者会帮助性暴力受害者，但他们的数量正在减少。据记录遇难医务人员的协会苏丹医生初步委员会称，自战斗开始以来，至少有 27 人死于枪击或炮击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一时期至少有 3 名医生被绑架。苏丹中央医生委员会高级成员阿卜杜勒·穆内姆表示，他们与亲民主抵抗组织有联系，或者照顾受伤的战斗人员。他说，由于大多数医疗用品都是通过卫生部分发给平民的，无国界医生组织也在抢劫和征用医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;苏丹战争导致达尔富尔地区战事激烈，导致超过 200 万人流离失所&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;剩下的选择就很少了。苏丹档案组织负责人马哈辛·达哈卜 (Mahasin Dahab) 表示，无数妇女和女孩正在转向社交媒体，该组织利用开源情报来记录侵犯人权的情况。她说，网上活动人士已将一些性侵犯案件提交给当地的非政府组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达哈布表示，无国界医生组织和军队的性侵犯都是历史上有罪不罚的结果。她说，“法律不支持我们关于性别暴力的主张”，并补充说，战前警察侵犯妇女的身体，但现在，“无国界医生组织将性别暴力用作战争武器”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Record 16 PLA warships sailed close to Taiwan in single day, island’s defence ministry says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3228029/record-16-pla-warships-sailed-close-taiwan-single-day-islands-defence-ministry-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/d1840cec-fbd3-41b6-90b0-01c7777e853c_e0bda82a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京上周单日派遣军舰数量创纪录，超过了去年美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台北期间创下的最高纪录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾国防部表示，周六凌晨 6 点之前的 24 小时内，解放军军舰在台湾附近航行了 16 次没有宣布附近有任何大型演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是向台湾派出的 14 艘军舰中数量最多的，因为北京认为台湾是一个分裂的省份，8 月份对佩洛西的访问做出了反应，在周围进行了数天史无前例的实弹演习&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，台湾总统蔡英文在加州会见佩洛西的继任者凯文·麦卡锡后，台湾在一天内派出了多达 12 艘军舰，作为另一场大规模演习的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;随着解放军活动的增加，美国海军巡逻机飞越台湾海峡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;近年来，北京几乎每天都派战斗机和军舰前往台湾自行宣布的防空识别区（ADIZ），因为中美关系在蔡英文的倾向独立的民进党 (DPP) 领导下，这种情况更加恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些访问在佩洛西访问后只会加剧，解放军喷气式飞机更愿意飞越台湾海峡中线，这是双方默认的边界几十年来，直到 2019 年，北京不再承认这条线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着台湾准备 1 月份的总统选举，届时蔡英文将达到其规定的两届任期限制，军事压力也随之增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;最新民意调查显示，民进党候选人赖清德领先，亲北京的国民党（台湾主要反对党）的侯裕义位居第三，落后于相对较新的柯文哲。台湾人民党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据台北国防部称，上周解放军在台湾周边的行动有所增加，每天派出数十架飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;解放军飞机包括轰炸机周三凌晨6点前的24小时内，无人机以及先进的Su-30和J-16战斗机进行了32次飞行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中一些从台湾西南部飞往南部，另一些则越过台湾海峡中线。随后，周四和周五分别有 33 架和 30 架航班沿类似航线飞行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中华民国武装部队已监测局势，并派出[战斗空中巡逻]飞机、海军舰艇和陆基导弹系统，台湾国防部在一份宣布入侵的每日声明中表示，该声明使用了台湾官方名称中华民国的首字母缩写。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六的航班数量降至 15 架，2019 年 10 架。周日和周一 11 点。国防部表示，自周日以来，没有解放军飞机越过中线或进入台湾防空识别区西南段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京国防部和解放军都没有宣布在台湾附近加强军事活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;前解放军教官宋忠平表示，这些航班和军舰的通过反映了解放军计划使台湾周边的演习正常化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此类行为被认为具有政治挑衅性，是北京抗议中美更密切接触的形式。台北和其他政府，特别是华盛顿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京反对台北与其他政府进行官方交往，并认为这种互动是对其主权的挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然美国是台湾的作为最大的非正式盟友，它与大多数国家一样，并不认为这个自治岛屿是独立的。然而，它反对任何强行改变现状的可能性，北京方面也不排除这种可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宋说，加强演习的原因之一可能是美国领导的西方国家最近的行动，包括周三北约公报称中国具有胁迫性，并对防务联盟的利益、安全和价值观构成挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“宣布军事演习并不总是必要的，”宋说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宋尽管财政部长珍妮特·耶伦最近的访问引发了美中经济对话复苏的希望，但美国最新对台军售以及更紧密的美日韩联盟是造成紧张局势的原因。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;总统蔡英文表示，美国的国防法案对台湾安全“至关重要”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新加坡拉惹勒南国际研究学院高级研究员科林·科林 (Collin Koh) 表示，解放军的活动可能与华盛顿的《2024 年国防授权法案》有关，该法案于周五在美国众议院获得通过，其中条款呼吁与台湾进行军事合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在台湾附近部署更多船只而不是在台湾附近投射力量。高说，飞机使解放军能够集中精力过度扩张该岛海军的资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“解放军一直……利用频繁的飞越来逐渐削弱中华民国空军的能力。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来发生的致命军用飞机失事事件揭示了台湾空军的捉襟见肘，他补充说，由于解放军的活动，台湾还不得不将更多的国防预算用于管理费用和维护。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果你是解放军的规划者，那么向台湾军队施压的下一个前沿是海军，这不是很合乎逻辑吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr >;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[President Macron to push French ‘alternative’ on Pacific trip amid rising China-US tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3228036/president-macron-push-french-alternative-pacific-trip-amid-rising-china-us-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/5ebb8a38-876b-4fbd-bfa1-6ca186253c8e_e4bb044e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;总统伊曼纽尔·马克龙下周将前往西南太平洋，提供“法国替代方案”他的办公室周一表示，该地区中美紧张局势不断升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙之行从新喀里多尼亚开始，新喀里多尼亚是法国的海外领土，在连续三次公投拒绝从法国独立后，该地区陷入严重分裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙的行程从新喀里多尼亚开始。 >;&lt;p>;一位官员表示，他随后将前往瓦努阿图和巴布亚新几内亚，这是此次旅程的“历史性”部分，因为没有一位法国总统曾访问过该地区的非法国岛屿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这位官员表示，马克龙将利用这两站来概述他的印度-太平洋战略，旨在让法国“重新承诺”该地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙去年在因取消与澳大利亚的潜艇合同而发生的激烈争吵，使法国成为中美争斗主导地区的制衡大国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不相信霸权，我们不相信霸权。”马克龙在 11 月亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会间隙表示：“我们相信对抗，我们相信稳定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度莫迪被法国马克龙授予最高荣誉&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;继澳大利亚时任总理斯科特·莫里森 (Scott Morrison) 于 2021 年取消了法国向堪培拉提供潜艇的合同，转而宣布购买美国或英国核动力潜艇的协议后，法国公开参与了该地区的事务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位爱丽舍宫官员表示，在中美对峙中，“我们提供的是另一种选择”。这将涉及法国增加参与，特别是在发展援助和帮助应对自然灾害方面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙对新喀里多尼亚的访问是在他上次访问新喀里多尼亚五年后，也是在新喀里多尼亚拒绝了 19 个月后根据关于该岛群未来的所谓努美阿协议，在第三次也是最后一次公投中宣布独立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙当时对投票结果表示欢迎，称“法国更美丽”，包括太平洋岛屿。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;但他也打开了“过渡时期”的大门。他说，该岛国和巴黎政府现在必须建立“一个共同项目”，“摆脱‘是’或‘否’的二元选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;支持独立的活动人士抵制了投票结果要求推迟，因为在冠状病毒感染人数众多的情况下，“公平的竞选”是不可能的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;投票结果加剧了种族紧张局势，较贫穷的土著卡纳克社区普遍支持独立，而不是较富裕的白人社区。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此时此刻，总统邀请新喀里多尼亚的所有政治代表与他讨论新喀里多尼亚的未来地位以及正在进行的谈判非常重要，”爱丽舍宫官员说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙还将前往新喀里多尼亚东海岸，提请人们注意那里的海岸侵蚀。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US climate envoy John Kerry and China’s Xie Zhenhua hold talks as rival powers seek to contain tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228035/us-climate-envoy-john-kerry-and-chinas-xie-zhenhua-hold-talks-rival-powers-seek-contain-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/1c0ac30e-acf2-479a-836f-40616e62dcb5_a7d2bc9a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国气候特使约翰·克里与中国气候变化特使解振华举行会谈，会谈持续数月周一几个小时，敌对大国在紧张局势加剧的情况下推动重新开放沟通渠道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京饭店举行的会面之际，双方在涉嫌中国间谍气球事件后试图让关系重回正轨。一月份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国家广播机构中央电视台表示，上午的会议持续了四个多小时，克里在晚上发推文称当天的会谈刚刚结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我已经刚刚结束在北京的第一天对话，全世界都在经历每日破纪录高温的现实。”他写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“气候危机要求世界最大的两个经济体共同努力限制气候变化。地球正在变暖。我们必须在多个方面采取紧急行动，特别是应对煤炭和甲烷污染的挑战。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至香港时间周一晚上，双方均未发表正式声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国首席气候谈判代表谢在开场白中表示，北京方面正在寻求本周进行“实质性对话”，两位特使可以为改善美中关系做出贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里，美国总统特使早些时候表示，美国和中国“必须”在今年晚些时候于迪拜举行的 COP28 气候谈判之前的几个月内“取得真正的进展”，同时敦促北京减少甲烷排放并减少煤炭的影响-发射电力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在接下来的三天里，我们希望能够开始采取一些重大步骤，向世界发出一个信号，表明中国和美国解决共同风险的严肃目的路透社援引克里的话说，人类自己对全人类造成了威胁和挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;气候特使约翰·克里能否降低美中关系的热度？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国外交部对讨论守口如瓶，称将“适时”发布信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中方将本着两国元首巴厘岛会晤的精神行事，外交部发言人毛宁在谈到去年11月习近平主席和拜登国家主席的会晤时表示，“中方愿与美方就气候变化相关问题深入交换意见，共同应对挑战”。 p>;&lt;p>;克里是近几周来第三位访问中国的美国高级官员，两国在贸易和先进技术等问题上寻求相互接触，以遏制历史性的紧张局势加剧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯上个月访问了美国，不到三周后，财政部长珍妮特·耶伦也访问了该国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯的访问因间谍气球事件而被推迟，这次访问被标记为会见包括国家主席习近平、外交部长秦刚和外交政策负责人王毅在内的中国高级官员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平当时告诉布林肯，世界需要稳定的美中关系，两国利益都符合应该受到重视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦表示，在本月早些时候结束访问时，她与中国新经济团队进行了“直接、实质性和富有成效”的讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;厄尔尼诺现象气候变化和气候变化共同使世界陷入热浪：科学家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;早些时候，美国国务院表示，克里于周日开始对中国进行为期四天的访问，旨在与北京合作“解决气候危机，包括…加强实施和雄心，促进 COP28 的成功”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，北京对当时的众议院议长做出了愤怒的反应，一系列交流被暂停，其中包括世界两大经济体和温室气体排放国之间的气候谈判南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 于 8 月访问台湾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但此后气候交流逐渐恢复，克里和谢在 5 月于柏林的全球论坛上举行了最后一次会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 2013年至2017年担任美国国务卿的克里在柏林表示，中国邀请他访问，是为了“找到前进的道路，以便能够以造福世界的方式进行合作”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;全球变暖和气候问题是中国政府的首要任务之一，习近平早些时候强调了各国之间合作的必要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二月份，习近平向共产党中央领导层表示，中国“应该扩大和发展气候变化”。深化……对气候变化、能源安全、生物安全和外层空间利用等全球问题的联合科学研究”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Food delivery giant Meituan adds more video features to app as Douyin marches into its market with Starbucks and Haidilao]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3228022/food-delivery-giant-meituan-adds-more-video-features-app-douyin-marches-its-market-starbucks-and?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/3102484f-496d-4ad9-a01f-cd8e1e33eb65_f6531a26.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着中国的食品配送服务巨头准备迎接竞争，美团正在其应用程序中添加视频功能抖音（中国版 TikTok）在在线本地服务领域的表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着字节跳动的抖音进军本地外卖市场，主导者美团效仿抖音，采用混合视频内容的方式从直播到短视频，在其平台上促进交易。分析师表示，此举可能有助于美团在沉迷于移动视频内容的年轻消费者中保持受欢迎程度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美团采取这一举措[推出视频内容]是为了迎合[中国]消费者不断变化的偏好查看和接收[在线]信息，”广州市场研究公司iiMedia创始人兼首席分析师张毅表示。 “中国年轻人已经习惯了……直播和短视频内容。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国咖啡巨头星巴克和本土火锅连锁店海底捞等品牌已迅速利用美团的直播能力，为他们的品牌做出了贡献。美团的一份声明称，线上销量增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;星巴克上个月尝试通过美团直播销售星冰乐饮料，上线当周全国销量同比增长 370%在应用程序上举办促销活动。根据美团提供的数据，海底捞的同期周销售额也增长了 51%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国总理在与阿里巴巴、美团的会面中支持大型科技公司&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美团的本地配送领域的主导地位正受到每日活跃用户超过 6 亿的抖音的挑战。自去年以来，字节跳动一直在添加视频链接，以利用本地按需服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抖音去年与京东的达达 Nexus 和顺丰的 SFTC 等按需快递服务公司达成了合作伙伴关系表达。它还与美团的主要竞争对手饿了么联手，后者得到了邮政母公司阿里巴巴的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次合作预计将使其能够接触到全国数百万快递员来完成食品配送订单。放置在短视频应用程序上，帮助其抢占美团的核心市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美团尝试直播流媒体之前，在线零售商、旅行社甚至金融科技公司也采取了类似的措施来吸引中国网民咨询公司100ec.cn的分析师陈立腾表示，消费者寻求省钱优惠或只是娱乐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美团在北京和深圳试行了名为“神强手”的促销活动，混合使用这家总部位于北京的公司联合创始人兼首席执行官王兴在第一季度财报电话会议上对分析师表示，他们通过“直播、短视频和其他形式”来销售限时优惠。他补充说，该公司将寻求在更多地区推出服务，并“进一步专注于直播”，以刺激消费者需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，尽管初步结果令人鼓舞，但分析师表示，美团的相对视频方面经验不足，品种缺乏，从长远来看可能会成为公司的障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与抖音相比，美团在视频内容制作方面，无论是创意还是内容都属于绿色。” iiMedia 的张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;电子商务咨询公司百联创始人兼首席分析师庄帅表示，美团需要更多种类的视频内容来吸引更多用户使用其平台。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;他表示，美团上的直播内容目前主要是销售优惠券和优惠，需要更多的多样性才能对平台产生更广泛的影响。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Does Taiwan risk being Russian ‘revenge target’ if retired missiles are sent to Ukraine?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3228027/does-taiwan-risk-being-russian-revenge-target-if-retired-missiles-are-sent-ukraine?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/08a3223d-d68e-4710-b8da-980740de4aee_3ac79af5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;据报道，美国计划从台湾回购数百枚“鹰”防空导弹台湾军方正式退役中程防空MIM-23第三阶段鹰导弹6 月 29 日，由美国武器制造商雷神技术公司制造。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周末，台湾新闻报道称，美国有兴趣回购这些武器，这些武器于 1960 年首次在台湾投入使用。从 1965 年到2017年，台湾空军已在41次作战演习中部署了“鹰”导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有报道称，美国有意回购上个月在台湾退役的“鹰”导弹，并将其提供给乌克兰”，作为美国军事援助计划的一部分，半官方的中央通讯社周六表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国计划向台湾出售 4.4 亿美元的武器和军车支持&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府资助的台北公共电视台表示，如果回购计划得到确认，并获得适当的发射系统，乌克兰将能够使用这些武器，前提是这些武器仍处于良好状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;援引据一位不愿透露姓名的台湾军方消息人士称，台湾《中国时报》报道称，台北和华盛顿在最近的一次安全会议上讨论了如何处理数百枚导弹退役后的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国同意消息人士在会后告诉《华夏时报》：“回购大部分系统并发往乌克兰以加强其防空能力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，该岛国防部拒绝证实或否认这一计划，但表示“军方退役和处置的所有武器都必须遵守相关规定”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，计划向乌克兰发送导弹以帮助阻止来自莫斯科的袭击，这引发了台湾可能会发动袭击的担忧。然后成为俄罗斯的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鹰式导弹能够在高达 20 公里（12.4 英里）的高度击中战机，如果它们击中俄罗斯关心的目标，台湾可能会成为其报复目标之一，”政治评论员、前议员郭朱利安警告说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，美国一直在从其他盟友那里购买老式、过时的常规武器，看到台湾提出类似的提议也就不足为奇了。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;台湾称在其东海岸发现两艘俄罗斯军舰&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;主要反对党国民党议员王鸿伟表示，由于美国是台湾最大的非官方盟友，台湾不太可能如果华盛顿要求回购导弹，我们可以拒绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了防止我们成为目标，我们应该确保回购的武器是由美国提供给乌克兰而不是台湾和台湾。”退役空军中将张彦廷表示，尽管这些导弹已在台湾服役 63 年，但不应被视为我们对乌克兰的军事援助。 ，它们的目标准确率仍然高达90.4%，这对于乌克兰抵抗俄罗斯军队来说将是一个有效的助推器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因为这些导弹不仅保养得很好，而且一直保持着良好的状态”张说，由于台湾已经退役了“鹰”导弹，美国可以“以极低的成本重新购买它们”。 ”，而该岛“不需要花费时间和金钱来妥善处置武器。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该岛国防部四月份的立法报告，军方原本计划编制一份预算，以让国立中山科学技术研究院在今年年底前销毁约 250 枚“鹰”导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一枚“鹰”导弹旨在应对 20 世纪 50 年代苏联制造的先进飞机构成的威胁，已投入使用1959 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冷战结束后，随着防空重点从飞机防御转向弹道导弹防御，美国退役了“鹰”系统。然而，更新后的 Hawk MIM-23 第三阶段仍在许多国家服役，包括日本和新加坡。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong should allow imported workers on smaller construction projects, as most firms benefit little in new scheme, contractor group says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3228034/hong-kong-should-allow-imported-workers-smaller-construction-projects-most-firms-benefit-little-new?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 22:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/3ed8c785-b648-4568-aa5c-d05ccdcd67e4_edeb5787.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一批香港承包商呼吁政府允许非本地建筑工人加入中小型私人项目，认为该行业的大多数公司从新的劳动力输入计划中受益甚少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港建筑承包商会周一发表了上述评论，这是第一轮申请&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;协会会长吴彩华表示：“计划仍有改进的空间，因为大部分承建商在首轮均未受惠。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港特首为工会成员罢工后输入劳工的计划辩护&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;发展局发言人表示，在启动当天尚未收到任何申请，但没有详细说明缺乏兴趣是否与大多数公司有关因八号台风警报而关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划的目标是在第四季度引进 12,000 名建筑工人（主要来自中国大陆）到该市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主要承包商可以为自己的公司或代表分包商提交申请，为 29 种技术工人和 18 种技术人员工作类型输入工人。该计划仅适用于建造业，该行业面临着各种规模项目的工人严重短缺的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但当局早前表示，第一轮输入劳工将主要分配给具有一定规模的公共工程项目。 contract value of no less than HK$1 billion (US$128 million).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng, from the association representing more than 200 member companies, said contractors had been struggling to hire workers even after raising salaries significantly.&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;He expected the government to roll out another round of applications for bringing in non-local workers, with no priority given to public works. “Otherwise the scheme will only favour the big construction companies, but leave small and medium businesses like ours helpless,” Ng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Construction Industry Council&#39;s manpower forecast report in February this year, the skilled labour shortage will worsen by 2027, as vacancies will rise from 15,000 to 40,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Importing labour to Hong Kong will ensure &#39;more flights, help bring down airfares&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The industry will face a shortage of more than 25 per cent for jobs such as welders, scaffolders and civil engineers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These jobs were added to the list for the imported labour scheme that includes bar benders and fixers, metal-steel workers, blasting workers, as well as technicians in fire services and site supervision.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bureau said earlier that bringing in workers was “necessary” to “fill in the temporary manpower gap” and avoid any bottleneck caused by a manpower shortage in economic and infrastructure development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong Ping, chairman of the Hong Kong Construction Industry Employees General Union, said hiring new workers had been “extremely difficult”. He noted this meant workers would not object to the new scheme as long as the newcomers were experienced and well equipped with safety training.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will importing 20,000 workers fix Hong Kong&#39;s labour woes?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wong said concerns were not raised by workers about the new arrivals competing with locals, as long as the imported labourers were not hired at salaries lower than the median wage for the position.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under these conditions, bar benders should receive an average of HK$37,800 per month and scaffolders about HK$27,300, according to the Development Bureau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Contractors who apply for the scheme should first try to recruit workers locally and confirm their needs cannot be met before submitting the application.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Development Bernadette Linn Hon-ho last week said it would take around two months to process the applications.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Labour imports for Hong Kong &#39;will not improve local wages, welfare&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ng, as a contractor himself, said he might file an application once the government relaxed the scheme to allow more workers to join smaller projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He explained the arrival of labour from the mainland could potentially solve the city&#39;s manpower shortage, following observations made during his visits to many construction sites over the border that workers there were qualified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have been waiting for quite some years, it&#39;s not an issue to wait another six months to see if the government will give us a quota,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s working population declined by 6 per cent to 3.46 million in 2022 from 3.68 million in 2018. The number of low-skilled workers also fell by 160,000 over the same period. The figures exclude foreign domestic helpers.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwanese presidential contender William Lai’s planned visit to US leads Beijing to lodge formal protest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228025/chinese-foreign-ministry-lodges-formal-protest-us-over-planned-visit-taiwanese-presidential?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 20:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/057c5a26-8431-4b17-9ae8-e5777c42812a_c9082991.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing has lodged a formal protest with Washington over a planned visit to the United States next month by Taiwanese presidential hopeful and vice-president William Lai Ching-te, vowing “strong and resolute” action in response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When asked on Monday about the planned stopover by Lai, the candidate of the independence-leaning Democratic Progressive Party, Chinese foreign ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning said Beijing has made “solemn representations” to the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China firmly opposes any form of official US-Taiwan interactions, firmly opposes Taiwan independence separatists visiting the US under any name or reason and firmly opposes the US indulging and supporting Taiwan independence separatists and their separatist actions in any form,” she told a press conference in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China will closely monitor the situation and take strong and resolute measures to defend national sovereignty and territorial integrity.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taipei has confirmed that Lai will pass through the US in mid-August en route to Paraguay for the inauguration of the new president Santiago Pena.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan defends new biolab, denies claims that US asked it to build bioweapons&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Taiwanese foreign vice-minister Alexander Yui Tah-ray said it was the norm for Taiwanese leaders to stop over in the US when visiting South and Central America.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ll follow the previous usual practice this time and handle vice-president Lai&#39;s transit with the principles of comfort, convenience, safety and dignity,” he told a press conference on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai&#39;s anticipated stopover to the US will come just five months before the 2024 Taiwanese presidential election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He will be the second presidential candidate to visit the US after Ko Wen-je of the Taiwan People&#39;s Party, who spent three weeks there in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai has consistently been leading the polls in the run-up to the election, leaving Ko and Hou Yu-ih, the candidate of the mainland-friendly Kuomintang, vying for second place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan is a long-standing source of friction in the relationship between Beijing and Washington, but in recent years it has emerged as one of the main sources of acrimony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The situation has also caused increasing alarm among US allies in the region, and on Monday New Zealand&#39;s Prime Minister Chris Hipkins became the latest leader to express concern about “rising tensions” in the Taiwan Strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Responding to Hipkins&#39;s comments, Mao said that “the Taiwan question is China&#39;s internal affair, and the most important and crucial thing to maintain peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait is to adhere to the one-China principle.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen visited New York and California, meeting House Speaker Kevin McCarthy on the latter leg of her journey, as part of a tour that also included visits to Guatemala and Belize.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsai&#39;s meeting with McCarthy prompted an angry response from Beijing – which regards any meetings between US government officials and Taiwanese officials as a breach of its sovereignty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It responded with a series of extensive military drills similar to those carried out last August when McCarthy&#39;s predecessor Nancy Pelosi visited the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing regards Taiwan as a breakaway province and has not ruled out the use of force to bring it under mainland control. Most countries, including the US, do not formally recognise the island as a sovereign state but oppose any forcible change to the status quo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pena visited Taipei last week and met both Lai and Tsai, while Beijing sent navy ships and a large group of warplanes including fighter jets and bombers toward the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US Navy patrol plane flies over Taiwan Strait amid increased PLA activity&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;When asked whether Taipei was worried about more military exercises due to Lai&#39;s trip, Yui played down the threat saying Taiwanese vice-presidents have made 10 such visits to the United States before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no reason or cause [for Beijing] to create unnecessary harassment,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 21:20:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Not enough being done’: South Korea tunnel tragedy, flood deaths cast doubt on readiness for extreme weather]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3228028/not-enough-being-done-south-korea-tunnel-tragedy-flood-deaths-cast-doubt-readiness-extreme-weather?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 21:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/cfc06f92-e2e8-4087-8af5-6ee3b402ad74_a129894b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A year after South Korea vowed to step up readiness for extreme weather driven by climate change, experts say not enough work has been done even as greater volumes of sudden and torrential rains are expected in coming decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At least 40 people lost their lives in less than a week of heavy rains – including 13 who died when floodwaters trapped them in an underpass in the city of Cheongju – casting doubt on the country&#39;s efforts to prepare for localised and intense downpours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts say the pledge for better preparation has not been followed by setting aside the monies needed, while spending remains too focused on recovery and not enough on prevention.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jeong Chang-sam, an engineering professor at Induk University in Seoul specialising in water resources, said prevention is crucial to minimising damage and the loss of lives, but it is often neglected because the benefits are not immediately obvious to politicians and those in government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“People like to use expressions such as rapid response, emergency recovery … but climate disasters are already under way”, Jeong said. “If you put money into prevention projects, you can do it at half the cost of recovery projects”, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jeong cited the example of a plan for installing remote-controlled access barriers at underpasses, set up after a flood in Busan trapped and killed three motorists in 2020. The plan never moved forward in many areas susceptible to flash floods, including Cheongju, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Yoon Suk Yeol on Monday echoed a call he made last year, when flooding in August from the heaviest rain to hit Seoul in 115 years paralysed commercial areas and inundated low-lying neighbourhoods in the affluent Gangnam district.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This type of extreme weather is going to become the norm so we need to manage it as the norm, and we totally need to get rid of the idea that we can&#39;t do anything about unusual circumstances,” Yoon told a disaster response meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials have promised to spend more on natural disaster prevention after the country committed about 2 trillion won (US$1.6 billion) in 2022, 20 per cent more than what was spent the previous year, according to the interior ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea is mountainous and urban development has left many regions vulnerable to landslides, while readiness to respond to extreme weather has not been up to speed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 2020 study by the Korea Meteorological Administration found that property damage costs and casualties from extreme weather have tripled compared to the yearly average of the previous decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheongju, where the flash flood killed 13, is a recent suburban development, a transport hub serving the administrative capital of Sejong. The area lies next to a river and on Saturday a levee broke in an spot slated for more construction.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Korea flood death toll rises to 39, Yoon blames botched responses&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Jung Ki-cheol, a hydro-engineer at the Korea Environment Institute, said while annual average rainfall is not expected to increase dramatically between 2021 and 2040, a sharp increase in “extreme downpours” is likely due to climate change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In particular, disaster damage due to floods will continue to increase as not only the extreme precipitation but also the number of days of precipitation increase,” Jung said in a report published in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The past week&#39;s victims include 20 killed or missing in mountainous North Gyeongsang province, many from landslides.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jeong of Induk University said authorities who were too slow to act on available information and who had not created a system to alert residents could be blamed for the casualties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee Su-gon, a former civil engineering professor at the University of Seoul, estimated there are “more than a million locations” in the country susceptible to landslides but said only a tenth of those are monitored by authorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee also said regional governments were more focused on spending on recovery than prevention when it comes to natural disasters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When it comes to allocating disaster budgets, local [South Korean] governments use 30 per cent of that for prevention measures and 70 per cent is used for recovery after disasters,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In advanced countries, they allocate 70 per cent for prevention and 30 per cent for recovery, prioritising recovery over prevention.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 21:20:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: SMIC names new chairman as mainland China’s top contract chip manufacturer faces further US semiconductor tech curbs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3228030/tech-war-smic-names-new-chairman-mainland-chinas-top-contract-chip-manufacturer-faces-further-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 21:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/d34b1c04-4627-4291-8ce2-d50fba332b27_12de0549.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC), mainland China&#39;s top contract chip maker, on Monday announced the appointment of a new chairman to replace Gao Yonggang, who resigned from all his corporate roles effective on Monday “due to job adjustment”, which the company did not elaborate on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai-based SMIC said 58-year-old Liu Xunfeng – who was “recommended” in May by the China Integrated Circuit Industry Investment Fund, also known as the Big Fund, to serve as the chip maker&#39;s vice-chairman – on Monday officially took over as the company&#39;s new chairman and head of its board&#39;s nomination committee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the SMIC announcement, Gao confirmed that “he has no disagreement with the board and that there is no information in relation to his cessation to serve as an executive director that needs to be brought to the attention” of the company&#39;s shareholders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest executive reshuffle at the top of SMIC&#39;s senior management reflects how Beijing is exerting greater control over the Shanghai- and Hong Kong-listed company, as China deals with increased pressure from Washington in terms of new curbs on semiconductor equipment exports and a possible US ban on mainland investments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu has had more than 30 years of experience in corporate management, according to the SMIC announcement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He concurrently serves as vice-chairman of the Shanghai Chemical Industry Park Development Co, a member of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, vice-president of China Petroleum and Chemical Industry Federation, and president of the Shanghai Society for Advanced Materials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, Liu holds a doctorate in management science and engineering from Xian Jiaotong University, a master&#39;s degree in business administration from China Europe International Business School, and a master&#39;s degree in chemical engineering from the Chemical Engineering Department of East China Institute of Chemical Technology, which is now known as East China University of Science and Technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s top foundry SMIC says profits halved in first quarter&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Gao, who had served as SMIC&#39;s chief financial officer since 2014, was named company chairman in March last year, months after Zhou Zixue – who had served as chairman since 2015 – resigned owing to “health reasons”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SMIC, which was started in a Shanghai rice field by a group of Taiwan executives and engineers led by Richard Chang Rugin in the early 2000s, has witnessed several rounds of boardroom changes in its brief history.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With US sanctions hindering its development of advanced semiconductor nodes below 10 nanometres, SMIC has sharpened its focus on capacity expansion of mature nodes. It is currently building three 28-nm foundries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite being on a US trade blacklist for more than two years and being restricted from importing advanced chip-making equipment, SMIC last year recorded 33.6 per cent year on year revenue growth to US$7.2 billion and achieved a net profit of US$1.8 billion, both record amounts, according to its annual report.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 21:20:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Typhoon Talim: Hong Kong woman, 70, injured by falling mosaic tiles as storm passes city]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3228023/typhoon-talim-hong-kong-woman-70-injured-falling-mosaic-tiles-storm-passes-city?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 20:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/7471e5e6-cd21-46e5-91f9-1956ea9e3be1_43752818.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;An elderly woman in Hong Kong was injured when she was struck by tiles that fell from a residential building as the city felt the effects of Typhoon Talim on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mosaic tiles peeled off the walls of Yat Wo House in Tai Po&#39;s Po Nga Court and fell as the woman passed by at 3pm, when a No 8 typhoon warning signal was in force.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Building safety in Hong Kong is responsibility of owners, John Lee warns&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The 73-year-old was struck on her head and arms, suffering several lacerations. A passer-by contacted emergency services after witnessing the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman received first aid from paramedics before she was taken to the nearby Alice Ho Miu Ling Nethersole Hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Emergency responders have cordoned off an area around the housing block.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Concrete chunks fall off Hong Kong building, hitting Mercedes-Benz on road below&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, concrete chunks fell off a 17-storey block in Mong Kok Road twice in four days, prompting authorities to step up enforcement action against homeowners who fail to carry out mandatory structural inspection.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chunks as big as “fists” broke off the 57-year-old Po On Building on 30 Mong Kok Road during one incident. The other case resulted in falling concrete hitting a truck and injuring its driver.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>