<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[EU unveils plan to de-risk ties with China, but faces fight to get members on board]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224789/eu-unveils-plan-de-risk-ties-china-faces-fight-get-members-board?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 21:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/c81dd428-e82a-489d-b6d8-ea504a0e51fb_57e82e53.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;布鲁塞尔周二公布了一项计划，为与北京的经济联系注入一些钢铁，但面临说服欧盟成员国控制对中国的投资和出口是一个好主意的斗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟的第一个经济安全战略旨在限制独裁政府获得欧洲技术作为经济安全的关键，例如量子计算和人工智能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年俄罗斯入侵乌克兰，这表明其对俄罗斯能源的依赖以及在这方面痛苦的部分脱钩，欧盟因此采取了行动由于对中国与莫斯科的密切关系感到恐惧，它已匆忙调查其对中国的依赖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着地缘政治紧张局势加剧和全球经济一体化比以往任何时候都更加深入，某些经济流动和活动可能对我们的安全构成威胁”，该战略写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然它没有直接点名中国，但与经济安全相关的决策将经过地缘政治过滤，而北京肯定是这种思考的关键。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“当我们在与国家无关的情况下使用这种地缘政治过滤器时，显而易见的候选人是中国和俄罗斯，”欧盟竞争主管玛格丽特·维斯塔格 (Margrethe Vestager) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，它可以被视为欧盟委员会主席乌尔苏拉·冯德莱恩“去风险化”概念的首次具体化，这个词在过去三个月中主导了西方对中国的政策辩论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vestager 表示该战略“完全吻合” ” 冯德莱恩在 3 月份发表的关于中国的演讲中首次宣布了该战略。然而，包括冯德莱恩本人在内的其他高级官员试图淡化这种联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们拥有整个经济领域，我想再次强调，与中国的绝大多数贸易和经济关系是&#39;一切照旧”，这位德国人说，并补充说，“确保”欧洲不会“增强一些国家的军事能力”也很重要。年列入高科技产品清单，欧盟公司在某些国家的公司可以与成员国一起进行筛选。同样，中国在这方面没有被点名，但它坚定地处于欧盟的关注范围内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它希望收紧关于外部购买欧盟关键公司和基础设施的现有规则，确保所有成员国实施其外国2020 年推荐的直接投资筛选工具。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还希望扩大欧盟的出口管制套件，以防止具有间谍和军事用途的商品进入敌对政府，或阻止它们被&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但要让欧盟 27 个成员国授予布鲁塞尔对这些传统上由其首都控制的地区更多权力，该提案面临着一场艰苦的战斗。一些成员也反对被视为向华盛顿倾斜和经济政策的“国家安全化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国准备在今年审查新的 AI 立法&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;“我们是欧洲，而不是美国”，这是一位官员在 6 月初听取该计划简报时的反馈，当时邮报报道。一位西欧外交官将他们的观点总结为：“国家安全就是国家安全。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;强调布鲁塞尔与一些大成员国之间的距离，该文件是在德国和中国政府举行磋商的当天发布的在柏林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当委员会提议去风险时，德国总理奥拉夫·舒尔茨正在为中国总理李强自今年早些时候上任以来的首次出访铺开红地毯。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;成员们的冷淡反应意味着这份 14 页的文件被视为“对话的开端”，一位相关官员表示，这将有助于引导长期努力，以降低与中国经济关系的风险。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;欧盟委员会的消息人士表示，他们理解一些疑虑，但表示鉴于笼罩在欧洲上空的地缘政治乌云，现在就必须就这些话题展开讨论——无论这可能会多么痛苦。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;据欧盟内部人士称，阻力源于未能就欧盟在经济方面面临的风险达成一致。因此，该计划缺乏具体立法。相反，它提出了下周欧盟领导人将在布鲁塞尔进行辩论的想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该战略指出了供应链、关键基础设施和电信网络中的差距，独裁者可能会在这些方面将依赖性武器化，而且还不到一周前，布鲁塞尔敦促成员国将中国公司华为和中兴踢出他们的 5G 网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该委员会将寻求与“志同道合的伙伴”合作，例如印度、日本、美国和&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在上周五的一次采访中，中国驻欧盟大使傅聪警告布鲁塞尔不要在其新计划中“将经济安全与国家安全混为一谈” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们理解欧盟各国政府对弹性供应链的渴望，[但]我们不应该过分强调安全概念，以至于它们成为开放和自由贸易的障碍，即坦率地说，我们的担忧，”傅告诉邮报和其他两家媒体。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;华为回击欧盟对其 5G 设备的禁令&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们还想说，去风险化不应该成为脱钩的另一个名字。坦率地说，最近的事态发展非常令人担忧，”傅补充说，他指的是禁止华为和中兴通讯的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“到目前为止，他们没有提供任何证据，没有一丝证据支持他们的说法。毫无根据的指控，但他们仍然继续这样做——如果我们正确理解目前的情况，几乎是全面禁止。在我们看来，这违背了公平竞争、公平竞争和自由贸易的精神，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong vows to regulate stablecoins, explore rules for virtual asset derivatives to protect investors]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3224783/hong-kong-vows-regulate-stablecoins-explore-rules-virtual-asset-derivatives-protect-investors?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 21:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/7469d1d7-d9d5-4872-b692-1b2728785b98_5a161a97.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港官员表示，他们承诺在审查规则的同时，到 2024 年引入稳定币法规在加密货币衍生品方面，随着香港努力加强其虚拟资产许可制度并成为全球 Web3 中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金融服务及库务局局长许清宇在《南华早报》上表示中国会议：香港 2023，该市将遵循“类似风险，类似监管”的原则，继续寻求对数字资产的全面和可预测的监管方法，该原则描述了监管类似于金融市场的加密空间的规则的必要性.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，香港推出了加密货币零售交易规则和许可指南，这是世界上最严格的集中式加密货币交易所监管框架之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加密货币行业已经新制度得到广泛支持，一些行业领导者呼吁监管机构加快行动，扩大合法虚拟资产活动的范围，以包括衍生品和稳定币，这些加密货币与另一种资产（通常是法定货币）挂钩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;香港金融管理局 (HKMA)，即香港事实上的中央银行，于 1 月宣布计划对与稳定币相关的活动实施强制许可制度，并表示将要求平台为代币持有完全支持的储备。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Hui 表示，监管机构正在制定该制度，预计将于明年实施。 “我们已经做了并将继续做的事情是建立一个可持续的监管框架，以便我们能够发展这个市场，同时确保相关风险得到管理，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;负责执行香港新虚拟资产交易制度的证券及期货事务监察委员会 (SFC) 牌照主管 Elizabeth Wong 在同一活动中表示，该机构也在制定自己的稳定币政策，并将与金管局合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在与他们合作，以确保我们的制度之间没有太多重叠，如果有重叠，请弄清楚我们将如何处理，”她说。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Wong 表示，证监会还在审查是否允许在持牌虚拟资产交易平台上交易虚拟资产衍生品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了我们的目的，我们需要获得我们的利益冲突”，因为虚拟资产平台可以同时扮演衍生品发行人和市场参与者的角色，她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港一直在推进其成为国际虚拟资产中心的雄心尽管从 2022 年 5 月 Terra Luna 稳定币的崩溃到 11 月前世界最大的加密货币交易所 FTX 的破产，该行业经历了一系列崩溃后的“加密货币冬天”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管香港的举措似乎与中国大陆禁止加密货币交易的政策有所不同，但 Wong 表示，香港的做法一直是“为保护投资者而进行监管”，而不是“将执法作为推动良好行为的工具”。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“我认为加密冬天确实证明了这种方法是正确的......因为我们看到的加密冬天引起的问题主要是由于缺乏监管而产生的，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fewer Australians see China as a threat as negative public opinion may have ‘bottomed out’: survey]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3224748/fewer-australians-see-china-threat-negative-public-opinion-may-have-bottomed-out-survey?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 20:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/3a6266d0-61a6-4598-8b8f-f09208a6c4a5_8271d9b9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚对中国的看法有所改善，而现在更多澳大利亚人反对购买洛伊研究所 (Lowy Institute) 对澳大利亚进行的最新年度民意调查显示，通过 Aukus 计划购买核动力潜艇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的民意调查结果显示，与去年相比，澳大利亚人对中国的态度略有软化在双边关系改善的情况下，今年的民意调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然对中国的感觉仍然不冷不热，但接受调查的澳大利亚人较少——在 3 月份接受调查的 2,077 名澳大利亚人中，有 52% 的人将中国视为威胁。这与去年的 63% 相比下降了 11 个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“过去的心态”：Aukus 颠覆了澳大利亚试图进行的美中平衡行动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;更多澳大利亚人还将中国视为一个经济伙伴今年的比例为 44%，而去年为 33%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在堪培拉推动对冠状病毒的起源进行独立调查引发北京的愤怒之后，两国的关系在 2020 年急转直下&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 Anthony Albanese 政府的友好外交缓和了紧张局势，恢复了中国施加的一些非正式贸易封锁，并增加了两国之间的部长级接触。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“这项调查有迹象表明，公众对中国的负面看法可能已经触底，”洛伊研究所公众舆论和外交政策项目主任瑞安·尼拉姆说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但这在很大程度上取决于接下来发生什么。在经济胁迫和外交压力最终损害了中国在澳大利亚的形象之后，球落在了北京的一边，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管情绪在过去一年有所改善，但接受调查的澳大利亚人比例相同– 四分之三的人认为中国在未来 20 年内将成为澳大利亚的潜在军事威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，民意调查还显示，更少的澳大利亚人（46% 的受访者）认为Aukus 与美国和英国的安全合作——澳大利亚将购买核动力潜艇——以此作为让亚太地区更安全的一种手段。去年，这一比例为 49%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议被广泛认为是对中国在该地区雄心壮志的反击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约 31% 的受访者反对购买核动力潜艇，而不是去年的 28%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aukus 潜艇交易可能使澳大利亚纳税人损失约 3680 亿澳元（2450 亿美元），该交易于 2021 年首次宣布，并于 3 月完成，尽管它不会是直到 2050 年代，八艘潜艇舰队才完全交付。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚的 Aukus 潜艇了解什么以及它为何在亚洲引起焦虑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;洛伊研究所表示，虽然民意调查显示强劲尽管公众支持潜艇协议，但澳大利亚人现在不太清楚该协议将如何影响地区安全或是否物有所值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;执政的工党内部对 Aukus 的不满情绪也在不断上升&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民意调查显示，大多数澳大利亚人仍然认为澳大利亚和美国之间的联盟很重要，尽管这一比例从 87% 的历史高位下降了 5 个百分点，降至 82% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，更少的受访澳大利亚人（57%）表示他们支持允许美国在澳大利亚驻军。去年，63% 的人表示支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 44% 的人将日本称为“澳大利亚在亚洲最好的朋友”，其次是印度，16% 和新加坡，分别是 15% 和 15%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;洛伊研究所表示，自去年以来，选择印度的澳大利亚人数量增加了一倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度是四方机制的成员，四方机制是另一个安全联盟，被视为遏制中国在亚洲的野心的一种手段地区。其他成员是澳大利亚、日本和美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继艾博年 2 月访问印度和莫迪上个月访问悉尼之后，堪培拉和新德里的关系在最近几个月得到加强，当时他做了将近一个小时的访问-在前奥林匹克体育场向大约 20,000 人发表的长篇演讲。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In era of streaming, fans try to ‘game system’ to save shows on platforms like Netflix, Prime]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224767/era-streaming-fans-try-game-system-save-shows-platforms-netflix-prime?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 20:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/f2d80c48-590f-4242-8b86-6768f6c90c54_2d03bdd7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;纽约居民尼基·罗德里格斯希望 Netflix 续订奇幻剧集《影与骨》——所以以至于她已经看了 15 遍第二季。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在社交媒体上宣传粉丝视频以吸引新观众。她还创建了一个 Change.org 请愿书，获得了大约 1,800 个签名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不幸的是，他们让粉丝们等了这么久，”47 岁的罗德里格斯说，自最近一次以来一直处于困境剧集于三月首播。 “我们真的很团结，希望节目能续订。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，粉丝们采取了严厉的措施来防止他们最喜欢的节目被取消。去年，一架飞机飞过 Netflix 的办公室，上面写着“拯救明日传奇”的横幅，试图在 CW 网络取消后挽救 DC 超级英雄节目。一位粉丝绝食抗议 Netflix 的科幻剧集 The OA。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两种努力都失败了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;弄清楚什么指标使流媒体节目成功可以迷惑球迷。是人们看节目的时间吗？或者有多少观众看完了这一季？社交媒体的嗡嗡声算不算数？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多好莱坞作家在不断罢工以寻求与制片厂达成更好的交易时也想知道这一点。问题是，除非该节目很受欢迎，否则这些数据大多是对公众隐藏的，因此很难计算节目或电影的市场价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然测量公司尼尔森计算流媒体节目的观看时间和电影，它只发布每个类别中任何给定一周的前 10 名影片的数据。 Netflix 在网上发布了自己的排名，详细说明了每个节目的观看时长——但仅限于其最受欢迎的节目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有一个黑匣子，这是流媒体控制的数据，他们不会与之共享……重视艺术家和重视供应商，因为他们衡量成功的方式非常独特，”前工作室和网络主管汤姆·努南 (Tom Nunan) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“Netflix 效应”将 K-content 推向了超级巨星。但这会带来回报吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;传统的广播和有线网络根据尼尔森收视率来确定节目是否热门，该收视率揭示了收看的平均家庭数量、该节目在其时段内的电视收视份额和受众人口统计数据。一个节目的成功通常是在它首次亮相后的几天内就被判断出来的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于流媒体来说，它是不同的，并且因公司而异。一些流媒体，如 Netflix，会观察节目在其存在的头 28 天内的表现如何。其他人则考虑更长的时间段——在某些情况下，75 天和 80 天，对于每周发布一集的节目，而不是一次发布整个季节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netflix 表示，它向节目主持人提供观看指标，更多比公开可用的内容要多，但拒绝透露具体细节。亚马逊表示，它为节目主持人提供了对表演的洞察力，但拒绝详细说明。 Hulu 和 Warner Bros Discovery 拒绝就他们如何看待指标发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;流媒体使用各种指标，包括人们观看给定节目的时间以及观看该系列节目的百分比。高管们还将制作和营销成本考虑在内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个关键变量是一个节目带来了多少订户。流媒体服务需要有足够引人注目的内容来吸引广泛的观众，并让消费者在他们的应用上花费更多时间，而不是 TikTok 和 Fortnite 等竞争对手的娱乐目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就内容投资是否获得回报而言，流媒体正面临越来越多的审查。在多年来主要关注订阅者增长之后，华尔街对流媒体服务增加了增加利润的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们在问尖锐的问题，而在问尖锐的问题时，你必须更加严谨，更研究公司 Parrot Analytics 的应用分析副总裁 Alejandro Rojas 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在亚马逊，关键指标包括观看时间以及节目是否吸引新会员加入 Prime，Prime 提供音乐流媒体等福利，访问原创节目和免费送货。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与大多数流媒体一样，亚马逊有选择地披露收视率统计数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;仅限一个家庭：Netflix 密码打击在全球范围内扩展&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据知情人士透露，去年亚马逊工作室推出了迄今为止最昂贵的电视节目《指环王：权力之戒》，第一季花费超过 7 亿美元，包括电视转播权。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;该节目在第一天就打破了收视记录，有超过 2500 万人收看。亚马逊表示，超过 65% 的《权力的指环》观众在美国以外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年早些时候，亚马逊推出了由理查德·马登和朴雅卡·乔普拉·乔纳斯主演的间谍惊悚片《城堡》，这家科技巨头称这是其在全球范围内观看次数第三多的新原创剧集。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;匿名行业博客 the Entertainment Strategy Guy 将此类比较测量称为“datecdotes”，因为它们缺乏具体数字。在上映的前三周，Citadel 并没有进入尼尔森流媒体收视率的前 10 名，该收视率衡量的是美国在电视机上的收视率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该剧的制作成本估计为 2.5 亿美元，吸引了新的观众Prime 会员遍布全球，包括印度、南非和新西兰等国家/地区。亚马逊没有给出具体数字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当你查看有多少人注册了这项服务时，在美国以外的一个国家又一个国家，这个数字是巨大的，”亚马逊负责人 Vernon Sanders 说。亚马逊和米高梅工作室的电视。 “在我们的一些全球支柱上，我们在美国以外的观众是美国国内观众的数倍。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;观众数据和财务考虑因素以外的其他因素也会影响节目制作决定。这些可能包括与顶级创作者保持关系的愿望，以及赢得著名奖项的诱惑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社交媒体热议的好处难以解释。虽然推文和 TikToks 可以帮助吸引流媒体节目的注意力，但它们并不总能转化为更多的观众。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，热情的粉丝在推特上热情地谈论 Netflix 的 Warrior Nun。与 Netflix 的一些更受欢迎的节目相比，一小群粉丝发布的关于该系列的推文更多。但这并没有为该剧集带来足够的收视率，据一位未获授权发表评论的熟悉该剧制作的人士称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netflix 超过一半的美国英语剧本剧集每年都会续订，该公司表示。一些人活下来而另一些人没有活下来的不透明原因可能会在网上引发争议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当吸血鬼剧集“首杀”被取消，而成人爱情故事《竭心杀手》被续订时，粉丝们提出了抗议。然而，知情人士表示，与 Heartstopper 相比，First Kill 的完成率要低得多，而且制作成本要高得多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那么这对于潜在的《影与骨》第 3 季意味着什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Netflix、Amazon、Disney+ 等流媒体服务将何去何从？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;首先，回顾过去。根据全球观看时长，《影与骨》第 2 季连续五周登上 Netflix 英语剧集电视排行榜前 10 名。它还在包括美国在内的 86 个国家/地区按观看时间排名前 10 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然进入 Netflix 的每周前 10 名名单是一项成就，但这并不能保证任何事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Netflix 表示，续订与取消的区别通常在于节目在前 10 名榜单上停留的时间长短及其国际影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这项工作中最困难的部分之一就是决定什么时候播出取消节目，”Netflix 美国和加拿大剧本系列副总裁彼得·弗里德兰德 (Peter Friedlander) 说。 “每部剧都是幕前幕后人员多年辛勤工作的结果，因此我们不会轻率地做出这些决定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Netflix ‘完成了缩水’，提前增加了订阅者广告支持的流媒体&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Friedlander 补充说：“我知道与角色和故事联系在一起然后在没有更新时感到失望的感觉。我们做出这些决定的方式与几十年来的做法相同——相对于成本而言，这个节目是否有足够多的观众，最重要的是，创意方向和愿景是什么。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Diehard Shadow and Bone 的粉丝们渴望提升该剧的统计数据，并采取了创造性的策略来提高它的成功率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些粉丝鼓励人们在背景静音的情况下重播第二季，以争取更多的观看时间显示，根据滚石。但两名接受《洛杉矶时报》采访的前 Netflix 员工怀疑这种策略是否有效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netflix 在全球拥有大约 2.33 亿订户。前员工说，对于 Shadow and Bone 的超级粉丝来说，招募新观众比通过同一个帐户反复观看第 2 季更有效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你不能玩弄这个系统，”其中一位前工作人员说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netflix 表示尚未就《影与骨》第 3 季做出决定。公司发言人表示，与整个娱乐行业的许多节目一样，由于编剧罢工，节目制作对话被搁置。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Influencer Andrew Tate charged with human trafficking, rape in Romania]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224785/influencer-andrew-tate-charged-human-trafficking-rape-romania?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 20:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/b86ae6c5-b09e-41f9-a605-0ebb0e0826fb_bff805a9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;网红 Andrew Tate、他的兄弟和两名罗马尼亚妇女在罗马尼亚被指控犯有人类罪检察官周二表示，在他们被拘留六个月后，他们被指控贩运和强奸罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反有组织犯罪检察部门 (DIICOT)“下令起诉”四名被告，罪名包括“设立有组织的犯罪集团……贩卖人口……强奸”，他们说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗马尼亚警方去年年底逮捕了 36 岁的泰特和他 34 岁的兄弟特里斯坦，以及两名罗马尼亚妇女。他们起初受到预防性拘留，三月底被软禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们否认所有指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“据认为，在 2021 年初，四人被告组成了一个有组织的犯罪集团，目的是在罗马尼亚境内以及其他国家（例如美国和英国）犯下贩卖人口罪，”DIICOT 在一份声明中说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;披萨盒和有毒的男子气概：安德鲁·泰特是谁，他为什么被捕？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;除了贩卖人口和强奸罪外——这两项指控都是“持续不断的”——这四人还被起诉“非法访问计算机系统，改变计算机数据的完整性，煽动攻击或其他暴力行为和殴打或其他暴力行为”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DIICOT 称，兄弟俩及其同伙涉嫌贩卖、招募和剥削妇女强迫他们在网上“制作和传播此类材料”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为调查的一部分，罗马尼亚警方搜查了与泰特兄弟有关的几处财产并没收了资产，包括一系列...他出现在英国的“老大哥”真人秀节目中，但在一段显示他攻击一名女性的视频出现后被删除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他转向社交媒体平台来宣扬他的分裂观点。他目前在 Twitter 上拥有 690 万粉丝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的视频提供了如何获得成功的秘诀，以及厌恶女性和有时暴力的格言，使他成为世界上最知名的影响者之一。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese student accuses hotel butler of sexual assault at luxury 5-star resort in the Maldives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224771/chinese-student-accuses-hotel-butler-sexual-assault-luxury-5-star-resort-maldives?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/474f3d8f-054a-48f1-9975-43124a837ce2_b8bcf275.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名中国学生指控一名酒店管家在期间对她进行了可怕的性侵犯她住在马尔代夫的一家五星级度假胜地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名独自旅行的受害者在社交媒体上详细描述了她的遭遇，并表示中国驻印度洋岛国大使馆已通过电子邮件发送她说他们已敦促地方当局进行调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称性侵犯和强奸未遂事件发生在两周前的法里岛丽思卡尔顿度假村。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名成员拒绝透露姓名的丽思卡尔顿马尔代夫营销团队向《南华早报》证实，警方正在对这名女子的指控进行调查，但拒绝进一步置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地媒体报道，据媒体报道，没有人被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称受害人于 6 月 18 日在她的推特和小红书社交媒体账户上详细讲述了她的遭遇，甚至还点名并张贴了她据称的照片&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还张贴了似乎是马尔代夫警方和马累环礁度假村附近一家健康中心的文件，以证实她对 6 月 11 日发生的袭击事件的指控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这名妇女说，她所谓的袭击者进入她的房间，借她的手机——在她不小心弄坏了她的手机之后——就在这时，所谓的袭击开始了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称受害人立即通知酒店工作人员并声称在警察到达之前，一些物品已从现场移走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，警察从她的嘴里采集了拭子，加上度假村从现场移走的物品，并告诉她返回她正在学习的澳大利亚。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称受害者已返回澳大利亚，她呼吁马尔代夫当局确保伸张正义，并要求度假村道歉。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China publishes white list of deep fake providers to preserve national security and ‘core socialist values’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3224775/china-publishes-white-list-deep-fake-providers-preserve-national-security-and-core-socialist-values?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/e8e05e88-6941-4041-b665-b9370fcedfc5_8b349df7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国互联网监管机构发布了首批“深度造假”技术获批供应商名单随着当局寻求将快速发展的技术纳入国家安全保护伞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国家互联网信息办公室 (CAC) 周二发布的“白名单”列出了 41 种算法的所有者，其中包括技术巨头腾讯、百度和拥有南华早报的阿里巴巴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些算法是根据 1 月 10 日生效的《互联网信息服务深度合成管理规定》备案的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该法规涵盖可以影响公众舆论或社会的深度合成服务提供商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深度合成通常被称为“深度伪造”——“深度学习”和“伪造”的结合。中国监管机构将其定义为使用技术（包括深度学习和增强现实）生成文本、图像、音频和视频以及创建虚拟场景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CAC 敦促深度合成服务提供商尽快注册。名单显示，已备案的数十家企业涉及文本生成图片、客户上传图片或视频剪辑、智能客服等业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白名单包括有关他们的算法、公司名称、产品名称和用途以及备案号的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“严厉处罚”即将到来，因为中国旨在制定打击网络欺凌的新规则&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京出台据 CAC 称，该条例旨在加强对深度合成服务管理的监管，弘扬“社会主义核心价值观”，维护国家安全和公共利益，保护公民和企业的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是其中之一of the first countries to move to regulate the rapidly-developing artificial intelligence sector amid concerns about AI&#39;s potential biases as well as its role in the spread of misinformation and deep fake images.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During tensions with the US-led Western countries, China has turned national security into a key paradigm that permeates all aspects of governance. Under the umbrella of “comprehensive national security” that was introduced in 2014, there are 16 types of security covering aspects from politics, economy, defence, culture and ecology to cyberspace.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a meeting of the National Security Commission last month, President Xi Jinping warned that China faced more complex and difficult national security concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He urged officials to be ready to deal with “worst-case and most extreme scenarios”, so they could withstand “high winds and waves, and even perilous storms”, according to state news agency Xinhua.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid its technology war with Washington, Beijing has prohibited its key infrastructure operators from buying products made by US memory chip maker Micron Technology, citing “relatively serious” cybersecurity risks.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Fake or real? AI sparks fears for US 2024 White House race&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“While deep fake technology can benefit humanity, it also brings risks and threats to national security,” Liu Guozhu, a professor with the Centre of American Studies at Zhejiang University, wrote in the Journal of International Security Studies in May last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The main challenge from deep fake to China&#39;s politics is reflected in the penetration and separation activities by religious extremists and national separatists,” Liu wrote while noting Xinjiang and Hong Kong issues for which the West accuses China of human rights violations, while Beijing denies.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blinken’s China trip could pave way for Xi-Biden meeting at Apec summit, analysts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224782/blinkens-china-trip-could-pave-way-xi-biden-meeting-apec-summit-analysts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 20:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/af2b2f6f-828d-4459-886a-53e9bc9aa462_2f05f6c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US Secretary of State Antony Blinken&#39;s critical China visit could pave the way for a possible Xi-Biden meeting and a thaw in trade ties after Beijing and Washington signalled mutual commitment to continued high-level engagement, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken&#39;s long-awaited trip to China, the highest-level engagement between the US and China since presidents Xi Jinping and Joe Biden met in Bali last year, was recognised by both sides as candid, in-depth and constructive as relations between the two superpowers have been strained over tariffs, tech restrictions and military activities in the Indo-Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts noted the positive exchanges during Blinken&#39;s visit raised hopes for a meeting between Xi and Biden during the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (Apec) summit in November, but more work was needed to make the talks happen.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Wang Yi urges US to make Apec summit reset in Indo-Pacific strategy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lu Xiang, an expert on US-China relations at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences (CASS), said Xi&#39;s meeting with Blinken could be interpreted as both countries having reached a “tacit agreement” for Xi and Biden to meet during the Apec meeting in San Francisco.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think the two sides may have reached an internal consensus for the two leaders to have a smooth and constructive meeting in November. And there may be even an official visit to the United States by President Xi,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the two sides can make breakthroughs on specific issues during the next four months, then we can have more optimism about China-US relations.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pang Zhongying, an international relations professor at Sichuan University, said Blinken&#39;s visit, as well as the meeting between China&#39;s top diplomat Wang Yi and US National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan in Austria last month, were both partly about making preparations for the leaders to meet at the Apec summit in November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From the perspective of diplomacy, if [Chinese Foreign Minister] Qin Gang paid a visit to the US before the summit, hopefully in autumn, the chance of Xi and Biden meeting will be significantly higher,” Pang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Xi&#39;s attendance [at Apec] would show China is very serious about promoting healthy relations between the two countries. If he is absent, it will indicate bilateral relations have gone off the rails,” Pang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken met top Chinese officials during his two-day trip to Beijing, including a last-minute meeting with Xi, and spent more than 10 hours in separate discussions with top diplomat Wang and foreign minister Qin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both sides agreed to advance consultations through joint working groups to resolve “specific issues” in their relations, including a group to address the international trafficking of fentanyl – a key item on Blinken&#39;s agenda after the US announced sanctions against Chinese companies for shipping chemicals to make the drug last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But they did not achieve any breakthroughs on human rights, the detention of US citizens or restoration of a military communication channel between the two sides, which has been suspended since former US House Speaker Nancy Pelosi&#39;s controversial visit to Taiwan in August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu Feng, an international affairs professor specialising in US-China relations at Nanjing University, called the dialogues during Blinken&#39;s visit “the most constructive” since the Xi-Biden meeting last year, indicating a commitment from both sides to continue high-level dialogues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Both sides are generally satisfied with the resumption of high-level dialogues and contacts,” he said, but added that what was most important was not resuming dialogues, but whether there could be a dialogue mechanism and channels for the two sides to communicate and resolve major concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Xi and Blinken cap China trip with vow to steady ties to ward off conflict&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yun Sun, director of the China programme at the Washington-based Stimson Centre, said the Blinken trip itself was “progress”, which had been postponed since the balloon incident in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said his visit opened the door for future communications, but she did not expect immediate breakthroughs, especially on “structural challenges” such as tech competition and Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This visit starts possibilities for discussion down the road, but I don&#39;t think we should expect concrete major deliverables at this point,” she said. “None of the problems between the US and China affords [an] easy quick fix.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US has ramped up tech restrictions against China, including lobbying its allies in limiting semiconductor exports – a key element for Beijing&#39;s military development – to the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Military tensions have also increased, with a Chinese warship accused of an “unsafe” close encounter with an American destroyer earlier this month and Washington continuing arms sales to Taiwan, the self-ruled island claimed by Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the need for improved crisis communications and military-to-military channels, which Blinken raised repeatedly during the trip, made no progress. “China has not agreed to move forward with that,” Blinken said in a press conference before he wrapped up his trip on Monday evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the US did not seek to “decouple” from China but would need to safeguard its own interests by not providing technology to Beijing “that could be used against us”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Taiwan, Blinken said he reaffirmed that the US was committed to its “one-China” policy and did not support Taiwan&#39;s independence, but would stick to its pledge to Taipei under the Taiwan Relations Act to make sure the island had the ability to defend itself.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chong Ja Ian, an associate professor specialising in US-China relations at the National University of Singapore, said the basic US and Chinese positions continued to diverge on these issues, and there was “still some distance to go before any major changes”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said resuming dialogues was “a start”, but “talking alone does not guarantee that relations will improve”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Wang Yi&#39;s readout blamed the US for current Washington-Beijing tensions. Xi&#39;s public remarks to Blinken suggest that he expects that the US side will work harder to repair ties. That, of course, leaves Beijing off the hook,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang, who is Xi&#39;s top foreign policy adviser, urged the United States to “reflect deeply” and manage differences with Beijing, while attributing the worsening ties to Washington&#39;s “erroneous perception” of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He asked the US to lift its “illegal and unilateral” sanctions and stop technology containment against Beijing, while stressing China will not compromise on Taiwan, “the core of its core interest”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;It may take more than Blinken&#39;s visit to Beijing to ease US-China tensions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Xi, in his meeting with Blinken, urged Washington to adopt a “rational and pragmatic attitude” when dealing with Beijing and to put their positive statements into action and work towards stabilising and improving US-China ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lu of CASS said Beijing used the meetings to convey its “strategic clarity” to the US, including on Taiwan, and the “specific issues” China referred to could point to their trade disputes, which he expected could soon yield progress compared to other unresolved issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken said more senior US officials could visit China in the coming weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen and Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo are widely expected to travel to China soon. Commerce officials from the two countries have started to re-engage recently as the US reviews whether to keep Trump-era tariffs imposed on a large number of Chinese goods.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Taiwan would remain a thorny issue that requires better understanding from both sides, Lu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Both sides have expressed enough [about their stances] on Taiwan. China has already said what should be said … it needs the US to show a kind of restraint in its actions.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan’s export orders fall for ninth straight month in May, but chip sales to India, Malaysia, US offer hope]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3224772/taiwans-export-orders-fall-ninth-straight-month-may-chip-sales-india-malaysia-us-offer-hope?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/41a0d9a6-60c3-4f88-b9c6-7eb81475d462_5169dcd0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Orders for Taiwan&#39;s exports, which run on global purchases of its hi-tech hardware such as semiconductor chips, fell for a ninth straight month in May because of weak overseas demand, according to data released on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The value of export orders last month declined by 17.6 per cent, year on year, to US$45.68 billion, the Ministry of Economic Affairs said. The figure had fallen by 18.1 per cent in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is because the orders from China and Hong Kong, North America, and the European Union are even lower in May,” said Hu Jin-li, a professor with the Institute of Business and Management at the National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University in Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Export orders for semiconductors [and] electronics are still at low levels.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Orders from mainland China and Hong Kong declined by 20.9 per cent in May, while orders placed by European buyers fell by 34.9 per cent, the ministry data showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deals in the United States to buy Taiwanese goods fell by 22.9 per cent, although it remained Taiwan&#39;s largest export order source in May at US$14.6 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Commitments to buy Taiwan&#39;s consumer electronics, the top category with US$15.47 billion in sales in May, fell by 16.6 per cent, year on year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Orders for information and communication products fell by 9.5 per cent to US$12.62 billion, while plastic and chemical orders each declined by more than 30 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Work from home is here to stay and will reverse PC sales slump, Acer CEO says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tech makes up 30 per cent of Taiwan&#39;s US$820 billion economy, and the island supplies around 60 per cent of the world&#39;s semiconductor chips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Demand for tech hardware tapered off in much of the world after the first two years of the coronavirus pandemic, during which consumers bought extra PCs, tablets and phones for work and study at home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inflation, high interest rates and fears of recession have chilled consumer sentiment since last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US economy will grow a scant 0.1 per cent in 2023, the Congressional Budget Office forecasts, though outside analysts have predicted a shallow recession.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan lures more Japanese investments amid China tensions, supply-chain fears&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The European Commission says economic growth within the bloc should reach 1 per cent this year, while analysts estimate China&#39;s gross domestic product will grow around 5 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s cabinet said earlier this month that it had set a goal of boosting annual trade by 10 per cent to US$1 trillion by seeking new markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said it would pursue its goal by “opening new world markets” for exports to offset falling demand from mainland China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And buyers in India, Malaysia and the US have raised their total amount spent on Taiwanese semiconductor chips since at least the start of 2021, Ministry of Finance data from Taipei showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan&#39;s migrant-worker reputation hit as Greenpeace flags labour violations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Purchases from the US rose from US$204.7 million in January 2022 to an estimated US$296.4 million last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sales to India jumped from around US$30 million to US$145 million over the same period, while Malaysian buyers picked up US$751.6 million worth of Taiwanese chips last month compared to US$668.3 million in January 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India is stepping up its value-added electronics manufacturing for export as well as its own market, while Malaysia is developing a domestic tech hardware sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US is trying to realign global supply chains away from mainland China, but while remaining close to Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But “structural shifts in general take more time as factories take time to be set up”, said Heron Lim, an economist with Moody&#39;s Analytics in Singapore, earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Lim said Taiwan “will not see a big revitalisation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mass production of 2-nanometre chips – the world&#39;s most advanced because of power saving and speed – should eventually lift Taiwan&#39;s exports worldwide, said Alicia Garcia-Herrero, Asia-Pacific chief economist with Natixis Corporate &amp; Investment Banking in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, the world&#39;s largest contract chip maker, expects to start mass production of 2-nanometre chips in 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Existing advanced chips are not lifting export orders, Garcia-Herrero added, because of US and Taiwanese curbs on exports to mainland China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Orders to China have already shrunk due to the chip ban,” she said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Boss of missing Titanic submersible once called his industry ‘obscenely safe’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224779/boss-missing-titanic-submersible-once-called-his-industry-obscenely-safe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/0ca0d8ae-ea53-44a9-a952-c5f2eeaeb1fc_e9274709.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The founder of the company behind the Titan submersible has previously described his industry as “obscenely safe” and complained that passenger vessel regulations held back innovation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the time of publication, OceanGate CEO Stockton Rush is understood to be aboard the Titan, the submersible that lost contact with the surface on Sunday, prompting fears for his safety.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vessel, which set out with four other passengers to view the wreck of the Titanic, was believed as of early Tuesday to have between 70 and 96 hours of oxygen left, according to the coastguard.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rush&#39;s efforts to advance the commercial submersible industry – which is distinct from the world of submarines – have been well documented in the media.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Who is on board missing Titanic tour submersible?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Describing the industry in a 2019 interview, Rush said that there have been no injuries in the field for decades, adding: “It&#39;s obscenely safe, because they have all these regulations. But it also hasn&#39;t innovated or grown – because they have all these regulations.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OceanGate did not immediately respond to Insider&#39;s request for comment, sent outside working hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But its website describes a commitment to “high-level operational safety” and the Titan&#39;s “unparalleled” hull monitoring safety system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The profile of Rush, which appeared in the Smithsonian Magazine, described his efforts to expand human exploration of the deep, calling him a “daredevil inventor.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It chronicles Rush&#39;s passion for exploring, and his efforts to energise the market in private submersibles, which had long been dampened by the number of industrial accidents happening in offshore submarine work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 1993 regulation put strict new controls on safety standards and who can pilot a submersible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rush called these developments “understandable but illogical,” saying he felt the law is well-meaning but lamenting the stifling effect it put on commercial innovation, per the magazine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His remarks on safety came as part of a wider set of regrets about how little the US government prioritises ocean research.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Rescue teams race to find Titanic tour sub missing in Atlantic&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Rush&#39;s company began to advertise commercial trips in the Titan to see the famed wreck the Titanic in 2019, touting an experimental design whose carbon fibre hull is considerably lighter than other vehicles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, trips were postponed, according to the magazine, after the company failed to get the proper permits for its contracted research support vessel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of Tuesday, efforts to locate and contact the Titan were still under way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the original article on &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Use the law to tackle terrorism in Xinjiang, China’s security chief says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3224769/use-law-tackle-terrorism-xinjiang-chinas-security-chief-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/43339d1e-9e33-43b4-9d12-cf3fe7bc1302_3eb6745e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Security personnel should make use of China&#39;s legal infrastructure to counter terrorism and extremism in the country&#39;s far western region of Xinjiang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That was the message Communist Party security chief Chen Wenqing delivered during a five-day trip to the region that ended on Sunday, according to state news agency Xinhua.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Authorities should] resolutely combat terrorist and extremist crimes in accordance with the law,” Chen said on his first visit to the region since becoming head of the party&#39;s Central Political and Legal Affairs Commission late last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[We should] strengthen the construction of supporting laws and regulations, and promote the resolution of enforcement and judicial issues at the institutional level,” he said, stressing the need for a “scientific” approach to legislative tools.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[We should promote] strict law enforcement and skilfully use legal tools to maintain stability and combat crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[We should] advance impartial justice, enabling people of all ethnicities to have faith in the rule of law.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said counterterrorism efforts should be “normalised” and authorities should guide people of all ethnicities to consciously build up “national consciousness, civic consciousness, and legal consciousness”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen was promoted the top security role and the Politburo – the party&#39;s 24-member inner circle – during the 20th party congress in October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As head of the commission, he oversees the country&#39;s police, prosecutors, judges, prison and top spy agencies. Before his October promotion, Chen was the country&#39;s state security minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese government has been accused of conducting a widespread campaign of persecution against Uygurs and members of other ethnic Muslim groups in Xinjiang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Beijing has denied those accusations and insisted that security measures in the region are necessary to clamp down on terrorist attacks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China introduced its first counterterrorism law in 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The following year Xinjiang issued specific directives for implementing the legislation in the region. Regional authorities also released regulations on “deradicalisation” efforts for the region in 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite international criticism of the Chinese government&#39;s actions in Xinjiang, President Xi Jinping hailed Beijing&#39;s policy in the region as “totally correct” in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing maintains that there have been no terror attacks in Xinjiang since 2017. But from 1990 to 2016, there were “thousands of terrorist attacks” in the region, resulting in the death of “hundreds of innocent people and police officers”, according to Chinese officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From 2016 to 2021, the region was overseen by Chen Quanguo, the former party boss of the Tibet autonomous region known for his hardline approach to security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Quanguo was one of a number of Xinjiang officials sanctioned by the United States in 2020 over “serious human rights abuses”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Human rights has remained an issue on the diplomatic agenda for many developed countries in their meetings with Chinese officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Secretary of State Antony Blinken raised the matter during his two-day visit to Beijing, which ended on Monday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>