<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Chinese trust firm clients say Zhongrong International Trust delayed wealth product payout]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3230944/chinese-trust-firm-clients-say-zhongrong-international-trust-delayed-wealth-product-payout?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 17:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/6e20c894-fd91-4a7c-ac64-da8859143b13_bcb96d68.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国信托公司中融国际信托的两名客户表示，该公司延迟支付到期财富有报道称，大股东的流动性存在担忧，这是中国金融业动荡的最新迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nacity Property Service 和 KBC 在周五晚间的声明中首先宣布了延迟付款的消息。碳产品制造商 KBC 在向上海证券交易所提交的一份声明中表示，延迟付款与中融投资的 6000 万元人民币（830 万美元）相关，不会影响公司运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中文资产管理公司中植企业集团是中国的金融巨头，其业务涉及信托公司、私募股权和财富管理，拥有中融的股权。据财新报道，上周晚些时候，有人猜测延迟付款与中植的流动性危机有关，该公司管理着约 1 万亿元人民币的资产。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;碧桂园将至少暂停交易10 只境内债券&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周日非工作时间未能联系到中融代表置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中融推迟派息的消息传出之际，投资者最近因健康担忧而感到紧张。中国经济和金融市场。中国最大的开发商之一碧桂园控股公司(Country Garden Holdings)上周因违约担忧而引发市场动荡，该公司报告称，该公司上半年亏损严重。碧桂园房地产集团表示，将从周一开始暂停近十只境内债券的交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，信托业也受到中国房地产危机的压力，企业投资产品出现违约。过去与房地产开发商挂钩。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港股市因中国房地产困境和经济放缓担忧而限制了每周跌幅&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;包括中融和五矿信托在内的公司购买了至少 10 个房地产项目的股份到 2022 年，押注未完工的房屋最终将产生现金，以偿还他们向投资者发行的 2300 亿美元房地产支持基金中的部分资金。股权和财富管理。该行业的企业汇集家庭储蓄来提供贷款并投资于房地产、股票、债券、大宗商品甚至高粱酒。金融行业中没有其他公司经营所有这些资产类别。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= “color:orange” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 17:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia state polls: Results a ‘huge blow’ for PM Anwar Ibrahim despite apparent status quo, analysts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3230941/malaysia-state-polls-results-huge-blow-pm-anwar-ibrahim-despite-apparent-status-quo-analysts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 17:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/d0150894-f907-464d-9fb6-073b2ff29f17_d80bfd2e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周六马来西亚地区民意调查的结果被解读为对总理的打击分析人士称，安瓦尔·易卜拉欣的执政联盟首次受到选民的真正考验，尽管投票结果表面上维持了现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国 13 个州中，有 6 个州的州议会席位争夺战基本上以如下方式进行：预计，安瓦尔领导的联盟将保住森美兰、槟城和雪兰莪的控制权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以强硬伊斯兰伊斯兰党为首的马来民族主义国民联盟（PN）保住了对吉打、吉兰丹的控制权&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国盟在竞选中认为安华忽视了马来穆斯林占多数，但在全面取得重大进展：赢得了 146 个席位，即 245 个选区中的 60%。 ”在六个州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为这是一个巨大的打击，因为它表明在九个月的时间里，联合政府无法用他们的治理说服选民，”Syaza Farhana Mohamad Shukri 说，马来西亚国际伊斯兰大学政治学系主任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这意味着安瓦尔和他的政府需要快速找出其他一些东西。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于反对派未能改变州选举现状，马来西亚领导人安瓦尔松了口气&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔领导的政府自称为“团结政府”，其中包括他来自希盟（PH）集团的长期盟友以及马来民族主义巫统党的主要竞争对手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，国盟主席兼前总理穆希丁·亚辛周六晚间表示，选举结果是人民发出的明确信号，表明他们不希望安瓦尔及其领导者&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“安瓦尔·易卜拉欣和扎希德·哈米迪必须承担道义责任并辞去职务，”他说，指的是副总理兼巫统主席艾哈迈德·扎希德·哈米迪，以支持者的欢呼声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔联合政府领导下的政党在国盟控制的三个州几乎被消灭。这一结果在人们广泛的预期之中，反映了去年 11 月大选以来所谓的绿潮（伊党的政党颜色）的趋势，该趋势使反对派在议会中获得了强大的全马来少数股权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更多然而，引人注目的是，国盟在雪兰莪州和槟城州的影响力不断扩大，这两个州是我国最富有和最发达的州属，长期以来被视为安瓦尔和他的多种族希盟盟友所代表的更进步政治的堡垒。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在雪兰莪州，国盟在马来人占多数的非城市选区以及城市选区取得了重大进展。总的来说，它赢得了 56 个州议会席位中的 22 个，比上一届仅获得两个席位大幅提高，有效地否定了安瓦尔的希盟在过去 15 年中享有的绝对多数席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔的集团保留了下来它在槟城连续第四个任期获得三分之二多数，但就像在雪兰莪一样，失去了大片马来人的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚观察家长期以来一直关注二马东保县三个议席选区的选民”选民并反驳国盟关于他的政府忽视马来人的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的联邦政府似乎也更加保守，打击公开展示同性恋和支持 LGBTQ 群体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 7 月，交通部下令取消为期三天的音乐节，该音乐节开幕当晚，当时英国乐队 1975 的主唱在舞台上亲吻了他的男贝斯手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，就在投票前一天，内政部宣布瑞士钟表制造商斯沃琪 (Swatch) 生产的一系列骄傲手表为非法，并警告称，即使佩戴这些手表，个人也可能被罚款和监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据马来西亚法律，同性恋是犯罪行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“现在很明显，采取社会保守政策不会为他们赢得更多选票。他们或许应该专注于扩大自己的基础，”政治风险咨询公司 BowerGroupAsia 的马来西亚董事 Adib Zalkapli 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在州选举已经结束，联合政府可以专注于治理和经济，改善民生。也许这是赢得更多选票的更好方法。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安华在雪兰莪州的支持者也赞同这一观点，他们帮助刺激希盟在该州混合种族城市选区的据点中获得更强大的多数席位。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“这表明希盟需要只关注他们的基础选民和[中间派]选民，而不是迎合伊党选民，”在联盟的武吉加星堡垒投票的马来裔律师伊尔凡·哈希姆(Irfan Hashim)说。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;州选举的结果也缩小了安华的战略选择范围，因为原本应该领导联合政府抵制“绿色浪潮”的巫统在其所选举的 108 个议席中只赢得了 19 个席位。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚民族主义政党几十年来一直享有该国自然执政党的地位。然而，在 2018 年，由于生活成本上涨以及领导人（尤其是现已名誉扫地的前总理纳吉布·拉扎克）腐败猖獗的民众愤怒，该党被选民毫不客气地抛弃了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“更大的问题是巫统的价值，因为结果表明，保留[希盟]关键州属的驱动力来自希盟的支持基础，”政府事务咨询公司 Vriens &amp; Partners 副总监 Shazwan Mustafa Kamal 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“州选举结果与去年 11 月的联邦选举结果相差不大。显而易见的是，巫统正在苦苦挣扎，并依靠希盟的支持基础来赢得席位。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管巫统未能兑现承诺，但专家一致认为，它不会改变安华政府的现有安排。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;安华在周六比赛结果后的深夜讲话中几乎没有任何迹象表明要调整路线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经过艰苦的战斗，也许气温会变得相当炎热。现在是全民、各方团结起来、维护民族和谐、集中精力改善国家和人民状况的时候。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong customs arrests man at airport for allegedly smuggling cocaine worth HK$2.1 million hidden in three book covers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3230943/hong-kong-customs-arrests-man-airport-allegedly-smuggling-cocaine-worth-hk21-million-hidden-three?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 17:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/98f70a1d-3dff-4f01-8bba-886ec19ec5ff_35bba0dd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港海关拘捕一名从埃塞俄比亚抵港的65岁男子，涉嫌涉嫌当局周日称，贩运了 2 公斤（4.4 磅）可卡因，价值 210 万港元（268,623 美元），藏在三本书的封面中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该旅客于 2019 年从埃塞俄比亚亚的斯亚贝巴抵达香港国际机场。周五，在过海关时被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关人员在该男子背包内的三本书封面衬里发现藏有2公斤怀疑可卡因，市值210万港元，并将该男子拘捕。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;他被控一项贩运危险药物罪名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;案件将于8月14日星期一在西九龙裁判法院提堂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海关表示，随着来港旅客人数增加，将继续重点甄选来自高风险地区的旅客通关，打击跨国贩毒活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拘捕人数随着航空旅行接近大流行前的水平，最近查获的毒品数量急剧增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港国际机场海关人员在今年首六个月逮捕了 30 名抵港旅客，高于 7 名&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方在公屋查获价值 1,850 万港元的可卡因&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他们走私近 46 公斤毒品，价值 3,900 万港元，而去年同期为 5.7 公斤去年上半年，价值590万港元的毒品被拘捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年全年共拘捕20人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月，至少两名游客涉嫌贩运藏于饼干罐内的毒品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名从澳门抵港的26岁男子因藏于四个饼干罐内走私6.3公斤怀疑可卡因被捕，价值约690万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;海关拘捕一名涉嫌以饼干罐走私可卡因进入香港的男子&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该男子从土耳其伊斯坦布尔前往埃塞俄比亚亚的斯亚贝巴，然后抵达澳门。随后，他乘坐渡轮前往香港，并在上环港澳客轮码头被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一起案件中，一名从丹麦哥本哈根飞抵香港的62岁女子在当局在她的一个塑料袋内的三罐饼干和三盒薯片中发现怀疑可卡因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毒品重约6.5公斤，估计价值700万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;香港海关在传动轴内检获价值1,600万港元的氯胺酮&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当局还在上月初从德国运抵机场的12个传动轴内检获价值1,600万港元的氯胺酮。一名35岁女子因涉案被控走私30公斤毒品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据《危险药物条例》，贩运危险药物属严重罪行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;一经定罪，最高刑罚为罚款 500 万元及终身监禁。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong patient group launches city’s first registry for people with ALS, in bid to gather data about rare motor neurone disease]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3230942/hong-kong-patient-group-launches-citys-first-registry-people-als-bid-gather-data-about-rare-motor?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 16:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/d866547f-b08b-4875-b700-0c918d1d9c0d_3eaac142.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周日，香港的一个患者组织启动了该市首个肌萎缩症患者登记处侧索硬化症 (ALS)，旨在收集有关罕见运动神经元疾病及其患者需求的数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一阶段登记收集了 46 名患者的信息，约占其中的四分之一在城市里患这种疾病，发现他们平均要等一年才能被诊断出来。据香港神经肌肉疾病协会称，三分之二的人被认为“严重残疾”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会的社会工作者 Jintana Sae Sow 表示，该协会正在寻求在登记的基础上提供以下服务：为其他神经肌肉疾病患者提供同样的服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望建立其他神经肌肉疾病的登记处，以便我们可以收集其发病数据并进行分析，”她说。 “政府还需要有数据来了解患者的需求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;想象一下听到“没有可用的治疗方法”：罕见疾病之战&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该注册表是与在当地医学院学生 Minnie Au 和 Marina Chan Hoi-ching 的帮助下，他们在 2022 年 6 月至 2023 年 8 月期间采访了第一批患者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ALS，也称为卢伽雷氏病，是最常见的疾病运动神经元疾病的一种形式，早期症状包括僵硬、肌肉抽搐、逐渐衰弱和肌肉萎缩。有些人还会出现四肢无力、说话或吞咽困难的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;退行性疾病会导致肌肉失去控制，许多人最终会因痰液积聚而死于呼吸衰竭，例如肺炎。在他们的气道或肺部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有十分之一的 ALS 患者可以确定遗传原因，而其余的患者则未知其起源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有治愈或有效的治疗方法&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会顾问医生郭子坚表示：“大多数患者虽然思维能力正常，听觉、视觉不受影响，但只能眼见病情恶化。” 、嗅觉和味觉。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对新登记系统的分析发现，在疾病首次发病后，患者需要去看四位医生，并等待一到两年才能得到诊断。那时，三分之二的患者可能已经出现严重残疾，例如说话能力下降、吞咽和呼吸困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究结果还显示，病情恶化后，大约一半的患者在不到时间内死亡接下来的九个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“她说我应该自杀”：患有罕见疾病的香港老师&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;每月平均医疗费用也达到 13,068 港元（1,670 美元） ，包括监督护理和租用生命支持设备，自付费用达港币90,000元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;用于帮助病人排出呼吸道中痰液（唾液和粘液的混合物）的抽吸装置据协会社工介绍，单张的费用可能高达 6 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ALS 患者及其护理人员也表示，政府没有提供足够的经济帮助或医疗照顾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑55 岁的金峰表示，他于 2021 年被诊断出患有 ALS，很快就失去了吞咽食物和呼吸的能力。随后，他的妻子成为郑先生和三个孩子的唯一经济支柱。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;质子治疗中心为香港癌症患者提供更有针对性的治疗&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;郑先生每月花费港币3,000元购买呼吸机，这没有补贴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府的伤残津贴不足以支付医疗费用，”她说。 “我们目前使用的呼吸机无法获得补贴。我们只能自费租用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会表示，在建立登记处后，政府可以改善患者护理，并为神经肌肉疾病患者设立专科诊所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;邮报已联系医院管理局征求意见。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 16:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China ‘winning lion’s share’ of construction projects in Africa, study finds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3230790/china-winning-lions-share-construction-projects-africa-study-finds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/13c9dfeb-0045-437b-8d52-55064270a3a3_59dde2a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;20 世纪 90 年代，非洲基础设施建设合同中约有十分之八被赢得” >;&lt;p>;根据亚洲慈善组织辛里奇基金会的一份新报告，到 2013 年习近平就任中国国家主席时，西方公司运营着 37% 的非洲基础设施项目，而中国公司则运营着 12%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，情况发生了转变。关于非洲在全球贸易和地缘政治中日益增长的影响力的研究发现，到 2022 年，在价值 5000 万美元或以上的非洲基础设施合同中，中国公司占 31%，而西方公司这一比例为 12%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京庞大的“一带一路”倡议的推动下，中国公司在非洲大陆建设了价值数十亿美元的项目，包括港口、铁路、高速公路、桥梁和水电大坝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是与 1990 年相比的巨大变化，当时美国和欧洲公司赢得了非洲85%的建筑合同。”高级研究员、前世界贸易组织总干事基思·罗克韦尔（Keith Rockwell）的研究显示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗克韦尔表示，在“一带一路”战略下“一带一路”倡议于 2013 年启动，中国资助了价值数十亿美元的大型项目，例如肯尼亚和埃塞俄比亚的铁路以及吉布提和尼日利亚的港口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，全球通过该倡议的参与额已超过 1 万亿美元，根据上海复旦大学绿色金融与发展中心的估计。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗克韦尔指出，中国也是非洲最大的贸易伙伴，2021 年贸易额为 2500 亿美元，而美国为 620 亿美元。非洲贸易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究发现，过去两年中国在撒哈拉以南非洲的基础设施项目总计达 1550 亿美元，这些投资使北京对非洲政府产生了影响力。相比之下，2021 年美国对非洲的外国直接投资总额达到 448 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“凭借如此密切的贸易和商业关系，中国赢得大部分基础设施项目合同也就不足为奇了，”罗克韦尔”说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;非洲矿产巨头的目标是在中国与西方的资源竞赛中获得更大的利益&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;撒哈拉以南非洲地缘经济分析师阿里-汗·萨楚 (Aly-Khan Satchu) 表示，中国在矿产资源方面更具创新性。融资，并且在向非洲大陆实施战略重心方面“速度显着加快”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然，这一重心存在细微差别。在早期阶段，非洲的资产负债表正在经历重组和债务减免，因此存在很大的空间，而中国的贷款在其“激进”的初始阶段就反映了这一点，”Satchu 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，罗克韦尔指出，中国在与非洲打交道时遇到了一些阻力。他表示，包括肯尼亚铁路和加纳交通照明项目在内的项目一直存在争议，并引起了公众的负面反应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，从 2021 年到 2022 年，“一带一路”对美国的贷款下降了 55% 75 亿美元，而总体贷款从 2016 年的 284 亿美元下降到 2020 年的 19 亿美元。“部分原因是一些非洲国家在履行债务方面面临困难，”罗克韦尔补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，他表示，中国与非洲的关系“广泛而深厚”，并且可能在很多年里保持强劲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据这项研究，中国在非洲政治和经济关系的大国竞争中明显处于领先地位。非洲。在唐纳德·特朗普时代，美国背弃非洲，而欧洲与其前非洲殖民地的关系则恶化，中国“急于填补空白”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这包括勘探和开采非洲资源。钴和锂等关键金属是制造为电动汽车和太阳能电池板提供动力的可充电电池的重要原材料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究指出，中国企业在金属加工方面领先于美国和欧盟竞争对手为电池原材料。中国公司目前从津巴布韦和纳米比亚采购锂，而刚果民主共和国和赞比亚是钴的主要来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在全球锂精炼产能中所占份额为 58%，直到类似设施在欧洲投入运营之前该研究援引国际能源署的话说，无论是美国还是非洲本身，中国将成为非洲锂的主要客户。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;非洲将中国的军事学校视为“西方培训”的替代品&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;但报告指出，布鲁塞尔和华盛顿正在迎头赶上。为了对抗中国的“一带一路”计划，美国及其七国集团去年承诺在五年内向全球基础设施和投资伙伴关系提供6000亿美元的资金。非洲可能是这些资金的主要接受者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国已承诺资助洛比托走廊铁路线的建设，以将矿物从刚果民主共和国和赞比亚运输到安哥拉大西洋沿岸的港口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;欧盟还在 2021 年推出了全球门户，旨在在 2021 年至 2027 年间动员高达 3000 亿欧元（3300 亿美元）的投资，以对抗中国对包括非洲在内的发展中国家的投资。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Satchu 表示，中国在非洲拥有“无可争议的领先地位”，经过二十多年的接触，在当地拥有大量“资产”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国和欧洲都需要认识到这一点。党在矿产争夺战的背景下，这将为新经济提供动力，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shifting gears in life: why mainland Chinese are eager to move to Hong Kong and get behind the wheel of minibuses]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3230930/shifting-gears-life-why-mainland-chinese-are-eager-move-hong-kong-and-get-behind-wheel-minibuses?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 16:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/13/b3241454-394d-4527-aa60-c2295401d2af_0ff541f3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;39岁的深圳跨境卡车司机乔李志平渴望搬到在香港，他是一名小巴司机，对更高的薪水和城市生活方式的渴望所吸引。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李目前每月收入约 7,000 元人民币（895 美元），养活他的妻子和三个孩子。但在香港，根据香港引进小巴和长途汽车司机的特别计划，他作为一名小巴司机每月可以赚取约 20,000 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我渴望在香港工作。俗话说：人往高处走，水往低处走。我希望能赚到更高的收入，让家人过上更好的生活。”他用流利的粤语说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我很喜欢香港，这里有独特创新的文化和高效的政策。我会竭尽全力为香港人民服务，严格按照香港的行事方式。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李先生是数百名通过以下途径申请在香港担任小巴司机的内地司机之一。内地职业介绍所。这些申请是政府引进 20,000 名工人以缓解该市建筑、航空和运输行业人员短缺问题的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该政策，交通运营商最多可招聘 900 名小巴司机和 800 名长途汽车司机，大部分工人可能来自大陆。第一批预计年底抵达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一第一轮结束后，交通运输部门已收到118份申请，业内人士申请引进1,600名内地小巴和长途客车司机，占1,700名配额中的94%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该计划雇用的人员的月薪必须不低于每日工作八小时的小巴司机的工资中位数14,300港元。但运营商表示，算上加班补贴，小巴司机每月收入轻松可达2万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港运输运营商申请引进1,600名内地司机&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但政策引起了公众的批评。一些人表示，具有讽刺意味的是，该行业愿意为外地工人支付住宿和培训费用，却不愿意为本地工人提供更多资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管有报道称，内地人在香港偶尔会受到歧视，但李说。他并不担心搬家，因为他多次到访香港，从未感受到任何偏见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港人非常友善、友善和直率。我从未经历过他们的任何敌意，”他说。 “我会照顾好乘客，安全是第一要务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于在多次参加招聘会和交通运营商面试后在香港获得第一份工作的李来说，这是他唯一的经历。担心的是，两年后合同到期，他能否留在这座城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我只是担心两年后，如果我不续约，我将被迫回城。”他说：“我在大陆找不到这样的高薪工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港领导人为工会成员罢工后输入劳工的计划辩护&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;候选人刘伟斌是一名46岁的长途汽车司机，来自广东韶关，月薪6000元，他也被香港更高的工资和更自由的生活方式所吸引。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港的薪资确实很有吸引力。一系列的当地美食、购物体验、夜生活活动和便捷的交通让这座城市令人难以抗拒。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我对在香港工作没有任何担忧。作为一名经验丰富的驾驶员，我始终把安全放在第一位。而且我学会了在与乘客打交道时保持乐观的情绪，避免与他们发生争执。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我可能有点担心香港高昂的生活成本，但我会尽量减少他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小巴营运商陈志辉经营着超过60辆小巴的车队，共有120名年龄在57岁至82岁之间的司机，他已申请从内地聘用约20名司机.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去几周，他参加了多个跨境招聘会，面试了约 50 名司机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈承认从香港以外地区雇用司机会推高运营成本，因为他必须为他们提供住宿，并支付他们的城市驾驶考试和培训费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“雇用每名新工人将额外花费3万至4万港元。新移民在抵达后的第一个月内、通过驾驶考试和公司培训之前将无法工作。” “我们预计每个外地司机每月要支付超过2,000港元的租金。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他承认，由于香港劳动力老龄化以及缺乏新人加入，他的人手选择有限。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管我们开出了高得多的薪水，每月超过25,000港元，但在过去10年，我们一直无法聘请到足够的人手。年轻人对加入这个行业不感兴趣。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，大多数内地求职者是被较高的工资和城市的生活方式所吸引。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“求职者大多是中年人，年龄在30多岁到50多岁之间，”他说。 “我的基本要求是粤语流利、交通安全意识强、驾驶态度好、服务乘客有礼貌。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;输入2万名工人能解决香港的劳工问题吗？&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;合发小巴拥有90辆小巴和140名司机，其中大部分年龄超过60岁，老板谢卓宇申请引进20名内地工人，因为他的公司面临20%的人力短缺。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他从200多人中采访了大约70人，并筛选出其中约20人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们中的大多数人都渴望在香港获得更好的收入，因为在大陆生活变得更加困难，他们不介意远离家乡工作。这说明内地经济越来越差。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢还要求内地司机必须能说一口流利的粤语。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们都渴望在内地工作。这座城市，”他说。 “每个人都告诉我，他们不怕在香港努力工作。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 16:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In Australia, a Sri Lankan refugee’s long ‘Walk for Freedom’ spotlights plight of persecuted asylum seekers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3230800/australia-sri-lankan-refugees-long-walk-freedom-spotlights-plight-persecuted-asylum-seekers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/11/cf0f47c0-2d2e-4cd7-b3b0-9ce279a6b59a_2648acc5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这只是斯里兰卡难民 Neil Para 1,000 公里（620-英里）步行去见澳大利亚总理安东尼·艾博内斯（Anthony Albanese），当时他开始起可怕的水泡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，与在澳大利亚没有签证生活了 11 年（这意味着他无法工作或入境）的痛苦相比，这种不适根本算不了什么。免费医疗服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2014 年他和家人的过桥签证被无故吊销且从未更换以来，帕拉陷入了该国复杂的难民处理系统，他正在步行以提高人们对他和数千人困境的认识&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的家人是逃离 1983-2009 年斯里兰卡内战的泰米尔人，他们表示由于担心受到迫害而无法返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们感到愤怒、沮丧，抑郁并有很多心理健康问题。我们在任何一天都有如此多的感受，”帕拉告诉《亚洲周刊》，并补充说，家人甚至一度集体考虑过自杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，这位 44 岁的老人仍心怀感激。 not to be back in his home country.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UN criticises Australia&#39;s &#39;punitive approach&#39; to boatpeople and warns of rise in hate speech&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“There may not be a war there now, but there&#39;s a lot of racism and discrimination,” he said. “There is no stability.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Para is using his 40-day “Walk for Freedom” from his home in the town of Ballarat, Victoria state, to Albanese&#39;s constituency office in the Sydney suburb of Marrickville, New South Wales, to petition Canberra.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He&#39;s collected more than 16,000 signatures since the walk began on August 1, with supporters joining him for sections of the journey to raise banners and cheer him on. His target is 25,000 signatures.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Para and his family fled Sri Lanka for Malaysia in 2008 before reaching Australia in 2012 on a fishing boat carrying around 200 other refugees, including ones from Iran, Iraq and Afghanistan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia&#39;s navy intercepted the vessel and the Para family were first placed in a detention centre on Christmas Island, before being moved to Darwin and Dandenong, and eventually settling in Ballarat with bridging visas in 2013.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Para suspects the revocation of his family&#39;s visas in 2014 was a result of domestic Australian politics. The government of then-Prime Minister Tony Abbott came to power in 2013 after campaigning on a turn-back-the-boats platform that led to Australia&#39;s current Operation Sovereign Borders refugee policy aimed at stopping maritime arrivals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former colonial master Britain has since adopted a similar policy, and this month started housing refugees on a residential barge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United Nations has decried the “cruel and deadly practice” of pushing back refugee boats for heightening the risk of further human-rights violations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Maybe refugees are powerful people who can decide who is [in] the government,” Para said sardonically. “And, if the government gives refugees visas, [they think] they may lose their power.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia&#39;s zero-tolerance approach toward refugees has led to a “legacy caseload” of thousands on temporary visas – or none at all – with few prospects of securing permanent permission to remain.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia produced fake horoscopes to deter Sri Lankan asylum seekers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the detention centre on Naura, some 3,000km off the Australian mainland – which was finally emptied in June but remains standing – the humanitarian organisation Medecins Sans Frontieres assessed the suffering as “some of the worst it had ever encountered, including in victims of torture”, according to a brief by Sydney&#39;s Kaldor Centre for International Refugee Law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Albanese&#39;s Labor government, elected last summer, has said it will allow 19,000 refugees on temporary visas to apply for permanent ones.但这不包括像帕拉一家这样根本没有签证的人。 A spokeswoman for Immigration Minister Andrew Giles said the government does not comment on individual cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a statement, Australia&#39;s Department of Home Affairs said refugees who aren&#39;t invited to apply for permanent visas but think they merit one can ask for ministerial intervention.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And that&#39;s just what Para has been doing – repeatedly calling the home affairs department and immigrant minister at regular intervals over the past decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ultimately the government hopes that people who have been rejected and forced to live as an underclass in Australia will be forced to return to their home countries,” said Ian Rintoul, spokesman for the Refugee Action Coalition, adding that all the country&#39;s major political parties see “harsh anti-asylum seeker policies” as an electoral advantage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fabia Claridge of the People Like Us advocacy group said a lack of political leadership had fed the narrative in many Australians&#39; minds of “any non-Anglo person on the bus” being a refugee “who will take their bus seat, job and a lot more”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Such lack of leadership is based on winning votes … it also sends a message to racist voters that the government is tough on non-whites, non-Christians,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Claridge&#39;s NGO is one of many charity and community groups that supports Para and his family, helping to pay their rent, food, and other living expenses. Para currently volunteers as a firefighter, but hopes to become a policeman, while his wife Sugaa volunteers at aged care facilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Margaret O&#39;Donnell from Rural Australians for Refugees, a group of residents in Ballarat helping the family, said that at one point, the Para children were even confronted with the prospect of having to pay “foreign student fees” for attending school.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The family] put off seeing a doctor or a dentist when the rest of us do,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China urges Australia to close offshore detention centres&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“[Once] I grizzled [moaned] about having to work a night shift and Neil replied, &#39;at least you are allowed to work&#39;,” O&#39;Donnell added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have heard it said many times from refugees that no one can walk in their shoes as it is impossible.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s July automobile exports jump 63 per cent, helping extend the lead over Japan as the world’s biggest vehicle-exporting economy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3230935/chinas-july-automobile-exports-jump-63-cent-helping-extend-lead-over-japan-worlds-biggest-vehicle?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 15:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/8b7b6b32-cdb9-49a1-851b-1d5f8ef0a586_25e8ac9b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s home-grown marques delivered more automobiles abroad in July, driving a two-thirds jump in monthly exports that extended the nation&#39;s lead over Japan as the world&#39;s largest vehicle exporter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;July&#39;s overseas shipments jumped 63 per cent to 310,000 vehicles from a year ago, raising the total to 2.65 million units in the first seven months of the year, according to data compiled by the China Passenger Car Association (CPCA). Local brands made up 248,000 units, or 80 per cent, of July&#39;s exports, CPCA said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Carmakers maintained a growth trajectory for exports and rising demand for Chinese vehicles are encouraging assemblers to ramp up production,” said Gao Shen, an independent analyst in Shanghai. “More Chinese automotive firms are now looking to bolster sales in overseas markets.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest numbers widened China&#39;s 15.8-per cent lead over Japan.上半年，中国出口汽车234万辆，超过日本汽车工业协会（JJAMA）报告的日本品牌202万辆。 Japan exported 3.5 million vehicles in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To be sure, China&#39;s July exports growth slowed by 24.4 per cent compared with June&#39;s shipments of 410,000 units. Still, analysts said growth may pick up over the coming months as Chinese-made vehicles are increasingly well received by consumers in some developing countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some assemblers in China – a left-hand drive market – are developing right-hand drive vehicles for exports. Hozon New Energy Automobile of Shanghai and Great Wall Motor in the Hebei provincial city of Baoding announced plans last week to ship right-hand drive vehicles to Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hozon has begun taking orders for its flagship Neta S electric sedan, and the compact sports-utility vehicles (SUV) Neta U-II and Neta V. Great Wall, China&#39;s largest maker of SUVs, said it would sell several models including the Tank 500 and Haval H6 models in Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CPCA did not disclose the number of EV exports in July, but Canalys predicted in June that China&#39;s overseas sales of pure electric and plug-in hybrid vehicles are expected to reach 1.3 million units in 2023, almost double the number of 679,000 units last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They will contribute to a surge in combined exports of petrol and battery-powered vehicles to 4.4 million units from 3.11 million in 2022, the research firm added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The war for domination in the world&#39;s No 1 electric car market&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chinese EVs are “value for money and high-quality products, and they can beat most of foreign brands,” Canalys said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is the world&#39;s largest automotive and EV market where about 200 EV assemblers are competing against each other to develop green and smart cars that can define the future of mobility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EV sales in mainland China will rise by 35 per cent this year to 8.8 million units, UBS analyst Paul Gong forecast in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s buoyant car exports stood in a contrast to the country&#39;s falling exports of commodities so far this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July, China&#39;s exports fell for the third straight month, with a 14.5 per cent drop from a year earlier to US$281.76 billion, the deepest year-on-year slide since February 2020, according to Chinese customs figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Go back to original Kai Tak plans to fix cruise terminal transport fiasco]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230770/go-back-original-kai-tak-plans-fix-cruise-terminal-transport-fiasco?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 15:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/11/03203258-4836-42b1-a053-df27dd6f6529_7559a5b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“If a picture paints a thousand words...”, wrote David Gates of the pop group Bread in 1971. Unsurprisingly, it was a hit for the band. Such powerful imagery explains why most languages have a similar expression and concept: words, spoken or written, do not have the same impact.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That is why the recent images of well-heeled tourists queuing outside the Kai Tak Cruise Terminal waiting for a taxi sparked such a strong reaction. Within days, the government had convened an urgent, high-level meeting to establish what went wrong and what could be done about it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After all, it doesn&#39;t matter how many good stories there are about Hong Kong or how well we tell them, the local and overseas media will always be on the lookout for a negative one, especially if there is a good picture to back it up. The truth is this has been a public relations fiasco just waiting to happen for more than a decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For me, the story began in May 1999 when – much to everyone&#39;s surprise, including my own – I was appointed as Hong Kong&#39;s first commissioner for tourism. I was already a director in the Financial Secretary&#39;s Office, the schedule of which had recently been expanded to include negotiations with the Walt Disney Company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first step was to set up a tourism strategy group to bring together the big beasts of the industry and thrash out some ideas. One that emerged early on was a proposal for a purpose-built, world-class cruise terminal to manage the larger vessels rather than the smaller type of ships which Ocean Terminal could handle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Up until then, much of the emphasis in marketing Hong Kong as a tourism destination was on our reputation as a “shoppers&#39; paradise”.尽可能长时间地保持这一势头很好，但最终竞争目的地可能会迎头赶上，迪拜和海南已经这样做了。 Even if we could maintain our edge, there was surely no harm in having an extra string to our bow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong is ideally located to be the hub for the cruise industry in Asia.向北前往日本的 7 天航程可以在台湾、上海或韩国中途停留，或者向南前往新加坡，可以在海南、越南或泰国停留。游轮乘客可以从香港出发，从另一端飞回家，或者从这些城市出发，在这里结束。 Cruise passengers are almost by definition relatively well off, exactly the kind of leisure visitors destinations seek to attract.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thereafter, the cruise terminal project became part of the Kai Tak development planning proposals.从很多方面来说，这是一个理想的安排：海港本身就是香港的主要景点之一，因此大型游轮停靠在海港的中心将为游客带来美妙的景色。 The deep water alongside the old runway was ideal for a berth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The overall plans for the area included many compatible uses that would complement each other. The downside was that any rethinking of parts of the area&#39;s development or delays in providing infrastructure would have an impact on terminal operations, which is more or less what happened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cruise terminal itself opened in 2013, but many planned roads in the vicinity have still not been completed.单轨铁路的想法被废弃了，没有公共交通交汇处，停车位也有限。配套设施根本看不到。 The terminal is served by a single road – an accident on it on the day the mega ship arrived effectively blocked access in and out for a couple of hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The terminal operator and the cruise lines are familiar with the situation and have introduced several workaround solutions. On the day in question, around two-thirds of the passengers were transported smoothly away from the terminal on prearranged coaches and other forms of transport.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Hong Kong-based transport expert, Alok Jain, told the RTHK Backchat programme last week that other temporary solutions were also feasible, for example gazetting and preapproving special bus services to kick in automatically on vessel arrival days. Jain also strongly endorsed the original package of transport arrangements drawn up by government planners.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong cruise terminal operator rejects commercial revamp, stresses role as port&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But the problem of insufficient taxi numbers remains.一些额外的激励措施正在出台，但这些本质上都是姑息措施。 We want our tourism sector to be flourishing, not clinging on for survival.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We should revert to the original development package and see how many items can be restored quickly.附近有空地可供停车，相邻的一块土地可以出售用于酒店开发。 If the monorail will not go ahead, then we need a quick decision on an alternative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In conclusion, we have a situation where the tourism strategists were right to anticipate challenges to our status and the need to expand the tourism product.一旦世界一流的设施到位，交通规划者对乘客需求的评估是正确的。 We now need to improve implementation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Ecuador became one of the most violent countries in Latin America]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3230933/how-ecuador-became-one-most-violent-countries-latin-america?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 14:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/6b086e15-f0f4-4bb7-b5ed-022528cfcf49_40523641.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Only a few years ago, Ecuador was an island of peace wedged between Colombia and Peru, the world&#39;s largest cocaine producers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But since 2018, drug seizures and homicides have increased alarmingly, blamed widely on transnational organised crime groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The assassination on Wednesday of centrist candidate Fernando Villavicencio – up to then second in polls ahead of the August 20 presidential election – has shaken the country to its core.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Six Colombians have been arrested in connection with the shooting attack outside a campaign rally, and a seventh died in a gun battle with security agents.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Colombian hitmen in spotlight after slaying of Ecuador presidential candidate&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Drug-linked violence in Ecuador last year propelled the homicide rate to 26 per 100,000 inhabitants, nearly double the previous year&#39;s level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Guillermo Lasso, who has been battling the drug gangs but been unable to stem the rising violence, has accused “organised crime” of killing Villavicencio, a former journalist who had denounced corruption and received death threats from the drug gang known as Los Choneros.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ecuador on Saturday transferred Los Choneros leader Jose Adolfo Macias, alias “Fito”, to a maximum security prison via a massive military and police operation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lasso announced on social media site X, formerly known as Twitter, that Fito had been transferred to La Roca, a 150-person maximum security prison that is part of the same penitentiary complex where the gang boss was already being held.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fito was accused of threatening Villavicencio before he was slain. Villavicencio had earlier told a local programme that an “emissary” for Fito had contacted him and told him to stop talking about the gang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If I continue ... mentioning Los Choneros, they are going to break me,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Interior Minister Juan Zapata has said there are more than 13 organised crime groups operating in Ecuador, the oldest and most powerful of which is Los Choneros, now allied with the Sinaloa cartel of Mexico.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the country&#39;s military intelligence says it has identified as many as 26 active narcotrafficking gangs, which are heavily armed and with numbers that experts said could perhaps rival Ecuador&#39;s 60,000-strong police forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts say the wars on drugs in Mexico and Colombia have put pressure on the cartels in those countries – as well as Albanian mafias – prompting them to set up operations in Ecuador.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the narcotraffickers, Ecuador&#39;s ports on the Pacific provide useful points from which to export cocaine to Europe and the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gangs were attracted as well by the country&#39;s porous borders, dollarised economy, widespread corruption and lack of money-laundering controls, the experts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Presidential candidate in Ecuador assassinated at campaign event&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Jorge Restrepo, director of Colombia&#39;s CERAC think tank, said the cartels can operate in Ecuador “at a lower production cost”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ecuador has a policy of fighting organised crime that has not prevented government forces and judicial organisations from being infiltrated by drug-linked organised crime,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luis Cordova Alarcon, who heads a programme on conflict and violence at the Central University of Ecuador, dates the beginning of “extreme criminal violence” to a deadly car bombing in January 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The attack partly destroyed a police headquarters and wounded 23 people in a town on the border with Colombia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was blamed on a dissident of the Colombian guerrilla group FARC, who murdered three journalists working for Quito&#39;s El Comercio newspaper and was killed that year by Colombian security guards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The car bomb attack was followed by bloody prison massacres between rival drug gangs that left 430 inmates dead over the following three years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Much like in Mexico, Ecuadorans began to see dismembered bodies left in the streets, corpses hanging from bridges, and kidnappings-for-ransom in which captors cut off their victims&#39; fingers or ears.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the victims of violence in Ecuador have been mayors, judges, prosecutors and dozens of innocent civilians.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cocaine seizures, meantime, have steadily risen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts say the growing number of seizures, and police crackdowns in the prisons from which many drug-gang leaders operate, have only made things worse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ecuador is becoming increasingly violent because of the way the state intervenes through its security forces, capturing the ringleaders and increasing cocaine seizures,” said Cordova Alarcon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The criminals grow more violent as they defend their business, as well as other illegal activities like illicit gold mining and arms trafficking, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Organised crime is already taking over the state,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesian domestic helpers in Hong Kong protest against agencies ‘overcharging’ practices outside consulate]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3230936/indonesian-domestic-helpers-hong-kong-protest-against-agencies-overcharging-practices-outside?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.13 15:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/13/a88699c1-b56e-4f25-baaf-2f4b47c7d689_1ce916c2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Dozens of Indonesian domestic helpers protested at their country&#39;s consulate in Hong Kong on Sunday morning, demanding the government tackle placement agencies&#39; “overcharging” practices affecting themselves and their employers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rally came amid confusion over who will have to bear extra costs after the Indonesian Manpower Placement Agency Association (Aspataki) said it would enforce rules introduced by Jakarta in 2020 and last year that employers must foot the administrative bill when hiring new helpers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, details on whether local bosses would have to pay the full HK$20,000 (US$2,558) remained unclear as of Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Indonesian consulate and Hong Kong&#39;s Labour Department said existing policies would stay unchanged. On Thursday, Secretary for Labour and Welfare Chris Sun Yuk-han also added Aspataki did not represent the Indonesian government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Domestic helper Leni Sumarti, who has been working in Hong Kong for 20 years, was among the around 50 Indonesians protesting at the consulate in Causeway Bay on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong residents still unsure if they must pay more for Indonesian helpers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The 43-year-old said she was rallying for workers and employers against agencies asking for more fees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are here today because we want our money back,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They suddenly implemented this without consulting us, but we are the ones who have to live and work with our employers every day. We feel like we are being traded like commodities.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fellow protester, who only gave her nickname Bimo, also 43, claimed recruitment firms would continue to demand fees from workers before they come to Hong Kong, despite collecting the full administrative fee from local employers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Actually, even though employers have to pay the agency about HK$20,000, we also still have to pay more than we used to,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So in Indonesia, we have overcharging, and employers also get overcharged.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;No rule change for Hongkongers hiring Indonesian domestic helpers: labour chief&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Bimo called on Indonesian and Hong Kong authorities to ensure both sides were not overcharged any more.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The domestic helper also asked for greater transparency on what employees and employers paid the agencies for.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For many years, there were no details,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I know this because I asked my employer: &#39;When you hired me, did the agency tell you what this money was for?&#39; She told me they didn&#39;t say.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The confusion began earlier this month when Indonesian agencies met Hong Kong labour officials and said they would enforce the new “zero fee” regulation for workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong minister meets country officials over plan to bring in more helpers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The regulations meant local employers needed to shoulder the full recruitment cost instead of paying their current share of HK$7,000 to HK$13,000. Helpers, meanwhile, would supposedly only have to pay for training costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It warned employers who failed to follow the regulations may not have their applications processed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Immigration Department, there are about 338,000 foreign domestic helpers in the city, with Filipinos accounting for more than 190,000 in 2022.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 13 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>