<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[European leaders close ranks against Russia at Moldova summit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3222644/zelensky-warns-doubts-about-ukraine-nato-membership-will-endanger-europe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 20:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/55046987-80e7-4d40-8d5b-608c60d6d1da_38ce2e92.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;面对俄罗斯对乌克兰和摩尔多瓦的侵略，欧洲领导人誓言保持团结星期四，在欧洲大陆的政治前线举行了一次战略峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着又一次致命的导弹袭击基辅，莫斯科声称击退了乌克兰“入侵”俄罗斯领土的企图，45 位领导人在脆弱的摩尔多瓦举行了会议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧洲政治共同体峰会的举办地位于该国东部的 Castle Mimi 酒庄，距离饱受战争蹂躏的乌克兰边境仅 20 公里（12 英里），增加了欧洲政治共同体的象征意义&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰总统弗拉基米尔·泽连斯基率先抵达，短途旅行前往他的小邻国，而他自己的首都基辅则在计算俄罗斯又一晚发动袭击的代价：三人死亡，其中包括一名儿童。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;马亚桑杜总统在北约预警机巡逻的湛蓝天空下，一一迎接领导人，希望提升摩尔多瓦作为寻求欧洲支持和保护的亲西方民主小国的地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “乌克兰人正在为自由、欧洲价值观和我们大陆的未来而战，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她称这次峰会“清楚地表达了我们作为一个整体共同行动的团结、力量和决心&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，泽伦斯基警告说，关于乌克兰加入欧盟和北约的雄心如何以及多快跟进的持续辩论将鼓励俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须记住，我们在欧洲这里表现出的每一个怀疑都是俄罗斯肯定会试图占领的战壕，”他说，并呼吁欧洲立即提供安全保障，并向北约成员发出“明确邀请”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两者基辅和基希讷乌希望今年开始加入欧盟的谈判，尽管莫斯科持续入侵乌克兰并据称企图破坏摩尔多瓦的主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EPC 峰会也在距离独立的摩尔多瓦地区不到 10 公里的地方举行俄罗斯“维和部队”占领的德涅斯特河沿岸地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它处于严密的安全保护之下，北约的 Awacs 侦察机飞越邻国罗马尼亚上空，覆盖这个前苏联小共和国的领空。&lt;/​​p>;&lt; p>;欧洲政治共同体由来自欧盟内外的 47 个欧洲国家组成，不包括俄罗斯和白俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有很小的圣马力诺和土耳其，其新当选的总统雷杰普·塔伊普·埃尔多安正在为他的就职典礼做准备... – 成为欧盟和/或北约正式成员的潜在垫脚石。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们还必须考虑更广泛的欧洲，”法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙在布拉迪斯拉发告诉记者，他率先提出了成立 EPC 的想法在峰会前夕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须在北约框架内而不是简单地在欧盟框架内从安全角度考虑我们的欧洲。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;摩尔多瓦峰会召开之际，包括美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯在内的北约部长开会讨论联盟下一次峰会的议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月 11 日在维尔纽斯举行的北约峰会将讨论正式会议的正式程度。就加入联盟的方式和时间向基辅作出承诺，但在此期间，欧洲热衷于表示支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙表示，盟国应该找到一种方式，向乌克兰提供“有形和可信的安全保证” ”，而欧盟和北约成员资格的最终问题悬而未决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爱沙尼亚总理卡亚卡拉斯走得更远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从长远来看，唯一真正有效的安全保障是结束欧洲的灰色地带，这意味着唯一的安全保障真的是北约，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在峰会期间，马克龙和德国总理奥拉夫舒尔茨将在亚美尼亚总理尼科尔帕希尼扬和阿塞拜疆总统之间会面伊尔哈姆·阿利耶夫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃里温和巴库为纳戈尔诺-卡拉巴赫有争议的领土争斗了几十年，但随着华盛顿和布鲁塞尔推动达成和平协议，他们都被邀请参加 EPC。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个长期存在的欧洲冲突，即塞尔维亚和科索沃之间的对峙，将提上议程，来自普里什蒂纳和贝尔格莱德的领导人面临缓和紧张局势的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然会谈进行，但战斗仍在继续在乌克兰，俄罗斯别尔哥罗德地区的州长表示，越境发射的火箭弹造成八人受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，莫斯科国防部表示，它已经“挫败”了一次入侵俄罗斯西南部的企图它说是两个用坦克加强的乌克兰机动步兵连。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EV makers BYD, Li Auto set monthly sales records as price war in China’s car industry shows sings of abating]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3222647/ev-makers-byd-li-auto-set-monthly-sales-records-price-war-chinas-car-industry-shows-sings-abating?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 21:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/e08ddb35-5343-4a7f-9172-af8a37a0cabf_1dd7d9f1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国两大电动汽车 (EV) 制造商比亚迪和理想汽车，设置5 月份创下新的月度销售记录，这得益于消费者需求在竞争激烈的行业经历了长达数月的激烈价格战后复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于深圳的比亚迪是全球最大的电动汽车制造商，根据提交给香港证券交易所的一份文件，上个月向客户交付了 240,220 辆纯电动和插电式混合动力汽车，打破了去年 12 月创下的 235,200 辆的纪录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这代表了 14.2%较 4 月增长 1%，同比增长 109%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内地领先的高端电动汽车制造商理想汽车 5 月向国内客户交付 28,277 辆，连续第二年创下销量新高&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，这家总部位于北京的汽车制造商报告销量为 25,681 辆，成为第一家突破 25,000 辆大关的本土高端电动汽车制造商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比亚迪和李Auto 在去年 10 月卷入了特斯拉引发的价格战后，上个月停止了对他们的汽车提供折扣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多一直在观望以期进一步降价的驾车者决定在他们意识到派对即将结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“销售数据进一步证明价格战可能很快就会结束，”总部位于上海的电动汽车数据公司创始人张法特说提供商 CnEVpost。 “在许多汽车制造商停止提供折扣后，消费者又回来购买他们梦寐以求的电动汽车。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于广州的小鹏汽车 5 月份交付了 6,658 辆汽车，比一个月前增长 8.2%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总部位于上海的蔚来是中国唯一一家在 5 月份出现环比下滑的主要电动汽车制造商。其销量下降 5.7% 至 7,079 辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;理想汽车、小鹏汽车和蔚来汽车被视为特斯拉在中国的主要竞争对手。他们都开发价格超过 20 万元人民币（28,130 美元）的电动汽车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比亚迪去年取代特斯拉成为全球销量最大的电动汽车公司，主要组装价格在 10 万元至 20 万元之间的车型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;尽管中国乘用车协会 (CPCA) 提供了估计值，但特斯拉作为中国高端电动汽车领域的领先者并未报告其在中国的月度交付量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，根据 CPCA 的数据，这家美国汽车制造商在上海的超级工厂交付了 75,842 辆 Model 3 和 Model Y 汽车，包括出口车型，比上月下降 14.2%。其中，39,956 辆卖给了中国大陆客户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月中旬，中信证券在一份研究报告中表示，中国汽车行业的价格战有减弱的迹象，因为汽车制造商不再提供更多产品&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主要汽车制造商——尤其是那些生产传统汽油车的汽车制造商——在报告 5 月第一周的交付量激增后停止降价以相互竞争说，并补充说一些汽车的价格在 5 月份已经反弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉在 10 月下旬为其上海制造的 Model 3 和 Model Y 提供大幅折扣，然后在今年 1 月初又开始了价格战。年。这种情况在 3 月和 4 月升级，一些公司将其汽车的价格削减了 40%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，较低的价格并没有像汽车制造商希望的那样推动在中国的销售。相反，精打细算的驾车者决定不买车，预计随后会进一步降价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行业官员曾预测，价格战要到今年下半年才会结束，因为疲软消费者需求阻碍了销售。黄河科技学院客座教授 David Zhang 表示，一些面临低利润率的公司最早将不得不在 7 月停止提供折扣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“被压抑的需求仍然很高，”他说。 “一些确实需要新车的客户最近做出了购买决定。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Purchase platform says Hong Kong cinema has cancelled private documentary screening, after ‘advice to avoid public gatherings on June 4’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3222648/purchase-platform-says-hong-kong-cinema-has-cancelled-private-documentary-screening-after-advice?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 21:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/47b74683-9443-4478-9ed3-40e42e2cbaf9_da23e834.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港某热门团购平台透露，私下放映一部纪录片6月4日的放映已被取消，业内人士建议影院在天安门镇压纪念日当天避免公众集会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;团购平台AsOne表示很遗憾地告诉大家，私人放映一部关于娱乐大亨的纪录片《待续》已被取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经过慎重考虑，它决定取消私人放映，”它在周三晚上在 Facebook 上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这真是一个特别的日子，连去看电影都不可能。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;香港安全局局长在 6 月 4 日周年纪念日之前警告滋事者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该平台表示不知道该活动是否会重新安排。会继续与院线沟通及通报消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;未完待续联合导演蔡黛玲对纪录片未能在金景影城放映深感遗憾和失望6月4日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“影片自4月份上映以来，周末一直是观众观影的热度。两位导演只能在周末出席和与观众见面。过去两个月一直如此。我们期待在未来继续与大家互动，”Choi 告诉邮报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Golden Scene 的一位女发言人告诉邮报，其重点主要是电影发行和宣传，而不是影院运营。它补充说，Golden Scene Cinema 没有就此事作出回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该邮报已联系香港戏剧协会和该市的主要电影院以征求意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及时如果警方在6月4日下令取消私人电影放映或是否会对私人聚会采取任何行动，警队发言人说：“在进行任何行动时，警方将根据实际情况并依法行事。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“警方将根据对公共安全、公共秩序和国家安全的威胁，作出适当的行动部署。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邮报查询金景影院脸书账号发现评论将私人放映与该市纪念 1989 年 6 月 4 日在北京举行的天安门广场镇压的年度守夜活动联系在一起，该守夜活动现已停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有些人在有关取消的消息宣布前几天发布了他们的评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;由于公园整修，香港 6 月 4 日守夜活动可能连续第四年暂停&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“终于，有一个地方可以纪念 6 月 4 日了，”一位 Facebook 用户周二表示。 “当时看到观众中的每个人都拿着蜡烛，真是太棒了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“带上鲜花。带上蜡烛和其他您觉得难忘的东西。永远不要忘记，”另一个人在周三下午 3 点左右说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几十年来，铜锣湾维多利亚公园每年 6 月 4 日都会举行烛光守夜活动，直到 2020 年，当时当局以新冠肺炎疫情为由拒绝批准。 19大流行。北京于当年同月对香港实施了国家安全法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出于同样的健康原因，2021 年的守夜活动未获得许可，而没有任何组织试图在 2022 年举办该活动。这今年，26 个亲北京联合会将于周六至周一在公园联合举办嘉年华。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港电影人总会主席田启文表示，取消私人放映是奇怪的是这部纪录片是由电影报刊物品管理办公室颁发的电影公开放映证书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这部纪录片已经获得了放映所需的证书，我不知道为什么现在有一个问题。这很奇怪。我不明白为什么日期对放映很敏感。这只会让人们在停止放映时想象一些不同的东西，”Tin 告诉邮报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果确实建议剧院做出这个决定，我真的很想知道为什么那些行业代表正在打电话，他们是谁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;待续故事从北角历史悠久的州立剧院在几年前易主后面临拆迁的故事开始。保护组织介入并揭开了剧院的历史。它继续探索剧院创始人哈里奥德尔作为娱乐大亨对香港文化的贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;这部电影是写给香港及其“第一任经理”哈里奥德尔的情书&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这部纪录片追溯了他从开罗家乡出发的航程，并突出了他在中年进入香港娱乐业的故事。一路上，它跟随各种人物，包括在剧院演出的国际知名音乐家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超早些时候在周日的镇压周年纪念日之前警告说，警方将采取措施打击违法者，而不是具体说明个人的纪念行为是否违法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安全部长克里斯·邓炳强表示，人们可能想利用“一个非常特殊的时刻”做一些可能威胁国家安全的事情，包括宣传香港香港独立或寻求颠覆国家政权，警告那些试图进行此类行为的人，如果找到足够的证据，将被逮捕或起诉。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong raises record US$6 billion from green bond offering as city pushes ahead with its sustainable finance hub ambitions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3222612/hong-kong-raises-record-us6-billion-green-bond-offering-city-pushes-ahead-its-sustainable-financing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 18:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/3aed6e12-d161-4f7a-b2a6-7ea3ae29ee1e_1eca8719.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港发行了规模最大的绿色债券，以多货币形式筹集了 60 亿美元这笔交易是政府推动将该市建设成为国际绿色融资中心的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次发行包括价值 22.5 亿美元的三年期、五年期和十年期美元债券、15 亿欧元（16 亿美元） ) 的四年期和九年期债券以及 150 亿元人民币（22 亿美元）的两年期、五年期和十年期票据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次发售超过了该市 57.5 亿美元的多货币绿色债券发行1 月，这是当时亚洲最大的环境、社会和治理债券发行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称，此次发行受到广泛欢迎，吸引了近 300 亿美元的投资者认购。作为政府代表参与此次发行的香港金融管理局周四晚发表声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“全球投资者对香港绿色债券的热情表明他们认可香港在绿色和环保方面的努力可持续发展，”财政司司长陈茂波周四在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此次发行包括我们的首支 10 年期人民币绿色债券，这有助于延长离岸人民币收益率曲线，并继续丰富离岸人民币产品种类，有序推进人民币国际化。” “我们将继续定期发行绿色债券，以推动市场的创新和进一步发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;绿色债券预计将于6月7日结算，并在香港联交所上市，同时据香港金管局称，伦敦证券交易所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财政司司长陈茂波在 2 月的 2023 年财政预算案中表示，政府计划发行 150 亿港元（19 亿美元）的零售绿色债券在 4 月 1 日开始的财政年度。政府去年通过出售此类债务筹集了 200 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国农业信贷银行和汇丰银行担任所有项目的联席全球协调人、联席牵头经办人和联席账簿管理人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;绿色债券是固定收益证券，旨在为环境友好型项目提供资金。根据 2021 年 10 月公布的气候行动计划，香港计划在未来几年增加风能、垃圾发电和太阳能发电的使用，作为到 2050 年实现碳中和的努力的一部分。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;财经事务及库务局局长许清宇上个月在一次行业会议上表示，自 2019 年首次交易以来，香港政府已发行近 160 亿美元的绿色债券。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2 月，香港发行了价值 8 亿港元的代币化绿色债券，这是全球首例政府发行此类债券，为香港数字债券发行铺平了道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，香港金管局还发布了一份讨论文件，以收集利益相关者对制定本地“绿色分类法”框架的反馈意见，该框架用于对被认为环境友好或可持续的经济活动进行分类。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本地市场采用的绿色分类框架将“有助于巩固香港在连接内地与世界其他地区之间的绿色金融流动方面发挥重要作用，从而加强香港作为国际绿色金融中心的地位，”根据香港金管局题为香港绿色分类框架原型的讨论文件。 &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 20:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China seeks stronger economic ties with Saudi Arabia beyond crude oil as Middle East seeks ‘ideal partner’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3222615/china-seeks-stronger-economic-ties-saudi-arabia-beyond-crude-oil-middle-east-seeks-ideal-partner?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 20:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/fd209793-2f91-4900-9bf7-bf9ea4e2a1db_6920362a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国在改善与沙特阿拉伯的外交和经济关系方面取得的迅速进展增添了绿色能量，学者和分析人士表示，随着中东寻求“理想合作伙伴”以帮助其发展，金融、基础设施和信息技术向传统的石油和天然气合作转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京通过沙特阿拉伯关注中东将他们补充说，这也有助于中国填补美国留下的空白，美国一直在转向印太地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继习近平主席 12 月访问该地区和北京-商务部副部长李飞在 3 月促成伊朗与沙特阿拉伯达成和平协议，周二会见了石油和天然气巨头阿美公司的高管。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他强调了中国“巨大的市场和合作机会”，同时也欢迎来自沙特阿拉伯的进一步投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“安全的石油供应是中国最重要的利益，”华盛顿中东研究所非常驻学者奥利弗·约翰说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“从沙特阿美的角度来看，中国是一个重要且不断增长的市场……占沙特原油出口量的四分之一以上。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙特阿拉伯去年是中国最大的原油供应国，出货量为 8750 万公吨海关数据显示（6.41 亿桶），占全国原油进口量的 17.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙特阿美 3 月还与中国合作伙伴签署了在中国东北建设炼油厂的协议，同时还宣布了计划购买在深圳上市的熔盛石化 10% 的股份。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄乌战争对中国的能源安全意味着什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但中国也可以发挥至关重要的作用北京人民大学国际关系教授王义伟表示，沙特阿拉伯在从石油和天然气等“传统能源”向涉及更多可再生能源的低碳经济转型中扮演着重要角色。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中东必须找到一个理想的合作伙伴来发展人工智能、数字经济、新能源和太空探索，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国现在更加关注印太地区，它没有不要把重点放在中东，中东需要‘看东’以实现其发展愿望。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙特阿拉伯可追溯到 1980 年代的经济和工业多元化计划也将提供合作空间除了石油，北京大学国际关系学院教授查道炯表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;哪些 8 个国家更多地使用人民币，这将如何影响美元？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“可再生能源是沙特的追求和中国的产能可以完美契合的领域，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“除了太阳能和风能行业，绿色氢能是另一个有前景的合作领域。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国与阿拉伯国家和海湾合作委员会（海合会）的关系将在北京优先发展与沙特阿拉伯的关系，特别是在中东的外交之后发挥“战略作用”，国家支持的新华社在习近平去年底访问该地区后进行了报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中东研究所的约翰补充说，沙特阿拉伯和阿拉伯联合酋长国对中国的信息技术感兴趣，以支持他们的发展经济多元化和各种智慧城市项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们也在寻求中国在关键领域的投资，特别是在本土生产能力方面，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“例如，沙特阿美， Public Investment Fund 和宝钢刚刚签署了一项协议，将在沙特阿拉伯建立海湾合作委员会的第一家综合钢铁制造厂。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该合资企业预计将位于港口城市拉斯al-Khair，是公共石油和天然气公司、沙特阿拉伯的主权财富基金和中国国有钢铁公司于 5 月签署的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙特阿拉伯也在考虑增加其对人民币参与双边能源交易，同时据报道它计划加入总部设在上海的新开发银行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该多边开发机构由巴西、俄罗斯、印度、中国和南非等金砖国家共同出资.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果可能的话，中国将与中东国家进行经济接触，并努力解决它们之间的分歧，”巴基斯坦伊斯兰堡国立现代语言大学国际关系讲师 Fazal Shahid 说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;中国在中东取得的进展也与其“一带一路”倡议有关，这是习近平于 2013 年 9 月公布的北京雄心勃勃的发展战略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一带一路倡议成立 10 周年。今年的道路倡议，”中国人民大学的王补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国和阿拉伯世界已经建立了一个合作机制，将能源和金融的发展结合起来，包括使用人民币进行石油交易。 ”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 20:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[90 per cent of Hong Kong primary pupils secure place at preferred public schools amid reduced competition for classroom spaces]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3222643/90-cent-hong-kong-primary-pupils-secure-place-preferred-public-schools-amid-reduced-competition?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 20:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/a42197fa-7ead-435d-b2d5-393efa562288_87af0dd1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;超过 90% 的香港学生已在其中一所学校获得一席之地公立小学前三名，16 年来最高的比率，教育当局表示，随着教室空间竞争的缓解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港，公立学校小一教室的座位分配使用两个-阶段过程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023-24 学年第一阶段（自主录取阶段）的结果已于 11 月公布，而第二阶段的结果将于下周三公布。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;教育局周四表示，两个阶段的整体成功率均达到 91.2%。该数字是自 2008-09 学年分配以来的最高比率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着目前参与分配过程的 6 岁儿童人数从 2018 年 12 月 17 日降至 43,755 人，对小一教室空间的竞争有所减少。在移民浪潮和出生率下降的双重影响下，2022-23 年报名的 48,080 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港学生将受益于新措施，使学校免于削减补贴&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;作为全权录取阶段的一部分，去年 11 月共有 21,724 名学生被分配了学校名额，而另外 20,355 名学生在最初未能获得名额后参加了中央分配活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约 82% 的学生参加第二阶段的学生在他们的前三名学校选择之一中获得了名额，此前参加人数比之前的分配减少了约 2,500 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据信其余学生已经退出分配过程中，一些可能在私立或直接补贴计划学校注册或已经离开城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该局将分配时间段让家长在 6 月 13 日或 14 日到他们孩子的分配学校注册。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对结果不满意的家长可能会发现今年更难转学，此前当局在本周早些时候表示，他们将在“敲门”的情况下非正式地减少可用的教室名额”做法。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港家长获准为子女报读任何一所英才学校&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在新安排下，资助小学的名额将会减少25 名学生的班级人数从 2 人减少到 1 人，而 30 人的班级将从 3 人减少到 2 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市的公立学校目前开设了 1,700 多个小学一年级班级。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;代表教育界的立法会议员朱国强表示，尽管当局减少了上门名额，但他相信失望的家长仍会选择直接联系学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;注册他们喜欢的学校，虽然我认为今年大多数家长会很高兴，”同时也是小学校长的朱说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，立法者指出，大约有 42,000 名六年制学生- 在公立学校就读的老年人远远少于 2017 年记录的 56,000 多出生人数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朱说，他希望该局能为包括小学在内的学校提供​​更明确的指导，以帮助他们解决入学不足问题该市学生人数减少导致的问题。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 20:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China pledges support for Sri Lanka through ‘difficult times’, renews promise to develop ports through belt and road]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222628/china-pledges-support-sri-lanka-through-difficult-times-renews-promise-develop-ports-through-belt?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/050c66fd-530a-47b6-aeb0-c9eebfd9da22_1849aa94.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国承诺支持斯里兰卡度过“困难时期”，同时重申其发展承诺随着科伦坡继续与严重的经济危机作斗争，该岛国最大的贸易港口通过“一带一路”倡议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在来访的中国外交部副部长孙卫东与斯里兰卡外交大臣阿鲁尼·维杰瓦尔丹的会谈中，双方重申了对一带一路的承诺，这是中国耗资数十亿美元的连接亚欧非的基础设施互联互通计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国愿与斯里兰卡加强各层级交流，据中国外交部称，孙宇晨周二表示：中国，特使说&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自 2009 年结束长达 26 年的内战以来，中国已向斯里兰卡的基础设施投资数十亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科伦坡港口城，也称为科伦坡国际金融城是位于首都的一个占地 269 公顷（665 英亩）的项目。 2014年开工，2041年竣工，预计总投资150亿美元。 5 月，国有企业招商局集团宣布将在该港口投资一个大型物流中心，预计建设成本为 3.92 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个南亚国家的第二大港口是汉班托塔国际港口，自 2017 年签署 11 亿美元的交易以来，招商局港口已与招商局港口签订为期 99 年的租约。该航运公司经营该港口，并正在将附近 6,070 公顷的土地开发成一个经济区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙北京还将扩大与科伦坡在金融、投资、能源、物流和旅游等领域的合作。斯里兰卡驻中国大使馆及其旅游部上周举行了一次会议，以提高中国游客的兴趣。当局表示，超过 100 万斯里兰卡人以旅游业为生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2019 年以来，该岛国一直面临高额财政赤字、前所未有的通货膨胀和基本商品价格飙升等问题政治挑战。由于储备枯竭，科伦坡去年 4 月宣布暂停支付外债。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时，该国的外债总额为 348 亿美元，其中近一半来自市场借款，其最大的贷方是亚洲发展银行银行、中国和世界银行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但科伦坡正寻求在违约后启动其经济复苏。 An online meeting initiated by creditor nations Japan, India and France was held in early May, with China attending as an observer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun said China would “continue to firmly support Sri Lanka in safeguarding its sovereignty, independence and territorial integrity, support the Sri Lankan government and people in collectively improving and overcoming difficult times, and support Sri Lanka in exploring a development path that suits its own national conditions”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun, who also met Sri Lankan Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena on Tuesday, is expected to wrap up his visit on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Sri Lankan foreign ministry, Wijewardane expressed appreciation for China&#39;s help during the “challenging period” and sought China&#39;s support in expanding Sri Lankan exports to China, especially in Ceylon cinnamon, seafood, fruit, vegetables and gemstones.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Observatory of Economic Complexity, a site for international trade data, Sri Lanka&#39;s exports to China increased from US$1.95 million in 1995 to US$491 million in 2021 at an average annual rate of 23.7 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“During the consultations, Sri Lanka and China pledged to further consolidate bilateral ties for the mutual benefit of the peoples of the two countries,” the Sri Lankan foreign ministry&#39;s statement concluded.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia says US accessed thousands of Apple phones in spy plot]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3222639/russia-says-us-accessed-thousands-apple-phones-spy-plot?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 20:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/01/3efb33f3-a30c-45ec-8a98-89de90fe42e7_c96b5733.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s Federal Security Service (FSB) said on Thursday it had uncovered a US National Security Agency (NSA) plot using previously unknown malware to access specially made so-called back door vulnerabilities in Apple phones.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The FSB, the main successor to the Soviet-era KGB, said that several thousand Apple phones had been infected, including those of domestic Russian subscribers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Russian spy agency also said telephones belonging to foreign diplomats based in Russia and the former Soviet Union, including those from Nato members, Israel, Syria and China, had been targeted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The FSB has uncovered an intelligence action of the American special services using Apple mobile devices,” the FSB said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neither Apple nor the NSA immediately responded to emailed requests for comment outside usual US business hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russian &#39;spy&#39; whale surfaces in Sweden&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The FSB said the plot showed the close relationship between Apple and the NSA, the US agency responsible for US cryptographic and communications intelligence and security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The hidden data collection was carried out through software vulnerabilities in US-made mobile phones,” Russia&#39;s foreign ministry said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US intelligence services have been using IT corporations for decades to collect large-scale data of internet users without their knowledge,” the ministry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United States is the world&#39;s top cyber power in terms of intent and capability, according to Harvard University&#39;s Belfer Centre Cyber 2022 Power Index, followed by China, Russia, the United Kingdom and Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Soon after Russia sent its troops into Ukraine last year, US and British spies claimed a scoop by uncovering – and going public with – intelligence that President Vladimir Putin was planning to invade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is still unclear how that intelligence was gained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials in Russia, which Western spies say has constructed a very sophisticated domestic surveillance structure, have long questioned the security of US technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin has always said he has no smartphone, though the Kremlin has said the former KGB spy does use the internet from time to time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, the Kremlin told officials involved in preparations for Russia&#39;s 2024 presidential election to stop using Apple iPhones because of concerns that the devices are vulnerable to Western intelligence agencies, the Kommersant newspaper reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a Kremlin-organised seminar for officials involved in domestic politics, Sergei Kiriyenko, first deputy head of the presidential administration, told officials to change their phones by April 1, Kommersant said, citing unidentified sources.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Asia climate woes mount as heat shatters May records]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222633/asia-climate-woes-mount-heat-shatters-may-records?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 19:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/01/0f1664a4-fbff-446f-8450-1597792434a3_79e7334e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Countries across Asia have been hit by another round of extreme heat that has toppled seasonal temperature records throughout the region, raising concerns about their ability to adapt to a rapidly changing climate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After punishing heatwaves struck large parts of the continent in April, temperatures spiked again in late May, normally the start of the cooler monsoon season.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seasonal highs were registered in China, Southeast Asia and elsewhere, and experts warned that there was more to come.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We can&#39;t say that these are events that we need to get used to, and adapt to, and mitigate against, because they are only going to get worse as climate change progresses,” said Sarah Perkins-Kirkpatrick, a climate scientist with the University of New South Wales in Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Extreme weather events&#39;: Asia set for supercharged heat as El Nino looms&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The heatwave in Vietnam, expected to last well into June, has already forced authorities to turn off street lights and ration electricity as air conditioning demand threatened to overwhelm the power grid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country recorded its highest temperature ever on May 6, at 44.1 Celsius (111.4 Fahrenheit), in Thanh Hoa province, about 150km (93 miles) south of Hanoi. Another province came close to the record on Wednesday, hitting 43.3C.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vietnam&#39;s national weather forecaster warned on Thursday of residential fire risks due to high power consumption. With temperatures set to range from 35C and 39C in the coming two days, it also warned of the risks of dehydration, exhaustion and heatstrokes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In China, Shanghai endured its hottest May day in more than a century on Monday. A day later, a weather station in the southeastern tech manufacturing hub of Shenzhen also set a May record of 40.2C. The heatwave is set to continue across the south for a few more days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India, Pakistan and Southeast Asia already experienced a punishing heatwave in April, causing widespread infrastructure damage and a surge in heatstroke cases. Bangladesh was also at its hottest in 50 years, while Thailand hit a record 45C.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seasonal temperature records also continued to tumble through May, with steamy Singapore at its hottest for the month in 40 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The April heatwave was “30 times more likely” because of climate change, a team of climate researchers said last month, and the current temperature spike “is likely to be caused by the same factors,” said Chaya Vaddhanaphuti from Thailand&#39;s Chiang Mai University, who was part of the team.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India and other countries have established protocols to deal with the health risks arising from extreme heat, opening up public “cool rooms” and imposing restrictions on outdoor work, but Vaddhanaphuti said governments need to plan better, especially to protect more vulnerable communities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Researchers from the University of Bristol warned in a paper published in April that regions with little prior experience of extreme heat could be most at risk, identifying eastern Russia as well as the Chinese capital Beijing and surrounding districts among the more vulnerable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for countries like India, where humidity is already pushing “wet bulb” temperatures to unsafe levels, preparing for the worst might not be enough, said Vikki Thompson, the paper&#39;s lead author.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At some point we get to the limit of humans actually being able to cope with the temperatures”, she said. “There could be a point where nobody could cope with them”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As many as 2 billion people will be exposed to dangerous heat if the world remains on its current track to rise an average 2.7C this century, with India likely to be the worst hit, scientists warned in another study published last week.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan’s growing problem with ‘trash homes’ prompts questions about lack of social support]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3222587/japans-growing-problem-trash-homes-prompts-questions-about-lack-social-support?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/01/d2e1c931-378b-433f-9ed4-86920afe4200_6c00e17a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Japan has a garbage problem, and it has a name – gomi-yashiki – or rubbish houses, local eyesores whose owners spill mounds of rubbish onto the streets and surrounding properties, attracting pests, causing problems for local governments across the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One specific three-storey family home in Yokohama&#39;s Isogo district has boxes, furniture and plastic bags stacked to the roof of the built-in garage. Crates are also piled haphazardly on the pavement, along with shopping baskets, folding chairs, tarpaulins, and scattered pieces of wood. The debris even encroaches onto the neighbour&#39;s parking space.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That dwelling is one of more than 5,200 trash houses identified as being of particular concern to local communities, according to the first ever nationwide study of the problem conducted by the Environment Ministry. The largest number of properties overflowing with rubbish were in Tokyo, with 880 cases, followed by Aichi Prefecture in central Japan with 538 problem properties and 341 in Chiba Prefecture, east of Tokyo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While a separate study in 2017 reported problems from 250 municipalities nationwide, the ministry&#39;s report indicates 661 municipalities are currently struggling with how to encourage – or force – homeowners to tidy up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An editorial in the Yomiuri newspaper on Monday called on the national government to pass new legislation to address what “has now become a national concern”, rather than leaving the matter to local authorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local residents complain of foul odours emanating from some properties inundated with trash, especially during the hot summer months, while others become breeding grounds for vermin such as cockroaches and rats. Elsewhere, untended gardens can spill over into neighbouring properties and there is even the possibility of older, wooden homes collapsing under the weight of rubbish piled up inside.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ministry&#39;s study received replies from more than 1,700 municipalities, of which 101 said they had local ordinances in place requiring homeowners keep their properties tidy. While 114 have established programmes to help people whose hoarding habits have got out of hand, including providing financial support or having municipal workers dispose of excess trash.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adachi Ward in Tokyo has set up a dedicated section within its environment division to tackle the problem, with a phone number and email address where residents can report problems with trash homes and people who find themselves overwhelmed with debris can obtain advice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, other local governments say that laws on property-owners&#39; rights often make it difficult for them to intervene, even in the most dire of cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is a house near my parents&#39; home that is something of a problem,” said Makoto Watanabe, a professor of media and communications at Hokkaido Bunkyo University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The parents who lived there with their son died and now he lives there alone and things have got quite bad,” he said. “Nobody cares for the house or the garden and it has become completely overgrown to the point that it is going over the fences into other people&#39;s gardens.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Bin there, don&#39;t do that: Japan&#39;s complicated garbage rules&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Studies on hoarders conducted in the United States suggest it is related to obsessive-compulsive disorder. However, the team at the University of Iowa was unable to pinpoint the trigger and find a way to control the compulsion to gather.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Watanabe said he believes most trash houses are the result of people being affected by some kind of change and simply not being able to cope with the new situation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is an increasing number of people who need support in their daily lives for any number of reasons,” he said. “It can be that they are elderly, that they are isolated, that they have a mental or physical handicap.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And as Japanese society has changed so rapidly in such a short time, these people find that the families or close community they would have been able to rely on in the past for help are no longer available,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is also likely that gomi-yashiki are becoming more of an issue simply because it has become a buzzword reported in the media, Watanabe said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These houses were there before these reports but once the term started being used and the media began to report on the problem, peoples tend to see them more,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Macau casinos hit the jackpot as return of mainland Chinese tourists fuels fourfold surge in revenue]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3222622/macau-casinos-hit-jackpot-return-mainland-chinese-tourists-fuels-fourfold-surge-revenue?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.01 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_coronavirus_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/01/ef0f51bd-039c-47c1-906d-530d9c61abb6_89b63fbc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The return of mainland Chinese tourists boosted Macau casino revenues to 15.6 billion patacas (US$1.93 billion) in May, more than four times what they earned a year ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On a monthly basis, the latest earnings were about 6 per cent higher than the 14.7 billion patacas Macau&#39;s most important industry generated in April, according to government data. Since the start of the year, Macau&#39;s casino revenues have amounted to about 65 billion patacas, nearly three times the 23.8 billion patacas registered in the same period a year ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest total, however, is still just about half of the 125.7 billion patacas that Macau&#39;s casino industry earned in the same period in 2019, the last full year before the coronavirus pandemic struck.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The comparison with last year will be amazing because of the low base,” said Louis Tse Ming-kwong, managing director of Hong Kong-based broker Wealthy Securities. “In the medium term, the city and casino operators have to widen the business as encouraged by the central government. It will take time [for a full recovery of the gaming segment] and will require a stronger recovery by the Chinese economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Macau eyes tech including AI in evolution from gaming spot to innovation hub&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Besides Chinese tourists, inflows of tourists from other countries should also be increased, so casinos must do more promotion work.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macau – the world&#39;s largest gaming hub – is the only place in the whole of China where casinos are allowed. About half a million mainland travellers went to the special administrative region for the Labour Day holiday, a five-day break that began on April 29. It was the first “golden week” break in China since Beijing shelved its zero-Covid strategy in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The former Portuguese colony was among the top holiday destination preferences for consumers in China, Hong Kong and Taiwan, according to a study released by credit-card giant Visa in February. It was the eighth most-likely destination for mainland tourists and seventh for those from Hong Kong, according to the poll, which was conducted with more than 4,000 respondents in autumn last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest revenue figures bolster a market consensus that casinos&#39; earnings are likely to beat expectations this year. Casino operators have reported improved revenues so far this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sands China, controlled by New York-listed Las Vegas Sands, for instance, reported that its net revenue in the first quarter rose by 132 per cent from a year ago, to more than half of its pre-Covid-19 levels. Meanwhile, Galaxy Entertainment Group, controlled by the family of Hong Kong property tycoon Lui Che-woo, said revenue increased 72 per cent to HK$7.05 billion (US$900. 06 million) in the same three-month period. Galaxy Entertainment has four properties in Macau – Starworld Hotel, Galaxy Macau, Broadway Macau and City Club.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ex-boss of HKEX links overseas investors to mainland China&#39;s small firms via Macau&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;MGM China, meanwhile, reported a 131 per cent year-on-year gain in net revenue to HK$4.84 billion in the first quarter. Melco International Development recorded a 51 per cent year-on-year increase in total operating revenue to US$716.5 million. Wynn Macau&#39;s total operating revenue doubled to US$600 million in the first quarter, while SJM Holdings saw its net revenue increase 57.6 per cent to HK$4 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a sign that the casino hub was back to business, British football superstar David Beckham last week led the opening of The Londoner Macao as a brand ambassador following its redesign.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The casino segment&#39;s apparent recovery is also being viewed as good news for the six operators, which will invest a combined amount of more than 100 billion patacas in Macau over the next decade. Most of the amount pledged will be used for non-casino businesses as the city seeks to diversify its economy away from gaming.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 01 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>