<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China investigates CEO of Shanghai news portal The Paper for alleged corruption]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3227709/china-places-ceo-shanghai-news-portal-paper-under-corruption-probe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 17:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/d46d1e15-0ba4-4cf5-8114-45e4b4f19a59_0292775d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;上海领先媒体集团高管、知名新闻媒体澎湃新闻首席执行官&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海联合报业集团副总经理程峰涉嫌严重违纪违法，目前正接受组织调查。通常官方对腐败的委婉说法。没有提供其他细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公告是在上海市最高立法委员董云虎接受中共中央纪律检查委员会调查后不到 24 小时发布的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;董前上海宣传部长，是自 10 月召开的党的二十大以来首位被清洗的正部级官员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五年一度的全国代表大会闭幕，习近平主席历史性地第三次连任。誓言“廉洁奉公，坚决反腐”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;51岁的程先生自2013年成立以来一直在国有上海联合报业集团工作。据中国企业注册平台天眼查称，他还担任该组织的法定代表人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;程是上海人，拥有工程学和MBA学位，在大学时就加入了该党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;程是上海人。 >;&lt;p>;他还是中国领先的数字新闻媒体澎湃新闻的首席执行官，该媒体是联合传媒管理的十几家门户网站之一，其中包括英语版《第六声》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澎湃新闻成立于 2014 年，随着纸质报纸收入开始下降，Paper 旨在吸引在线读者。根据其网站去年发布的社会责任报告，截至 2021 年底，其用户群已达 1.972 亿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017 年，国家新闻出版总署对澎湃新闻给予高度评价。提供有关政治和共产主义意识形态的“高质量原创新闻”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的所有新闻媒体都受到政府机构的监管，并接受当局的直接命令。大多数完全依赖国家资助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在加入媒体之前，程从事外贸和技术工作，并在上海市政府晋升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;程是其中之一自习近平 2012 年上台并发起标志性反腐败运动以来，多位中国顶级媒体高管因“违纪行为”受到调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年，资深记者、前《新闻周刊》出版人戴自耕热门新闻媒体《新京报》被指控“严重违纪违法”。他于2020年被捕并被起诉，此后就没有在公开场合露面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2015年，广州21世纪传媒集团前总裁沉浩因涉嫌违法犯罪被判处四年有期徒刑。与新闻报道、“强迫交易”和贪污有关的勒索和勒索。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该集团拥有《21世纪经济报道》，这是一份当时以其激进的调查报道而闻名的财经报纸。沉在警方拘留期间向官方媒体电视认罪，承认了这些指控。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 17:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong authorities create HK$2 million online platform to remotely monitor public housing projects in real time]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3227732/hong-kong-authorities-create-hk2-million-online-platform-remotely-monitor-public-housing-projects?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 17:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/2b32791d-7cd8-443c-8003-311ad0bc9ffe_c300190d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港房屋署已投资至少200万港元创建网上平台有助于避免建设项目延误并缓解劳动力短缺问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该署副署长梁健文周五表示，新“信息管理和分析平台”的实际成本仍有待确定。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于我们要兴建大量公营单位，很多项目没有足够的人手来处理规划和建设”梁说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个系统让我们能够用有限的人力处理更多的事情。这是一项值得的投资。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府已确定足够的土地在未来十年兴建36万套公屋，其中三分之二将在后五年交付。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;部门表示，该系统可以实时监控工地安全，同时列出工程信息，包括施工进度、财务状况和事故情况，以密切关注可能出现的延误和问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港家庭会不会15岁以下的儿童会优先入住公屋吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;位于屯门业旺路的四座公营房屋项目是第一个计划于2024-25年分阶段兴建3,300间房屋的项目。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该平台很快将覆盖东涌的一个公营房屋用地，预计到2024-25年将提供4,800个单位，以及另一个将提供1,400个单位的资助项目。建于观塘安达臣道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;申诉专员应减少香港共享设施单位的空置&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;梁表示希望通过监督两个项目的物流来测试新平台&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MiC采用独立式集成模块，在从工厂运输到项目现场安装之前经过质量检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;该署表示已于去年10月开始要求承建商提交工地资料，以便该系统日后可应用于所有公营房屋项目。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 17:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI-powered brain surgery becomes a reality in Hong Kong after launch from state-run research centre]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3227676/ai-powered-brain-surgery-becomes-reality-hong-kong-after-launch-state-run-research-centre?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 17:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/d151ac95-30fb-4105-ab60-9e702126f792_f2a170bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国科学院 (CAS) 旗下香港研究中心，尽管面临人才和人工智能 (AI) 芯片短缺的挑战，中国国家研究院仍计划在不久的将来推出用于脑外科手术的机器人系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人工智能与机器人中心 (CAIR)该中心执行主任刘洪斌在周四接受《华盛顿邮报》采访时表示，成立于 2019 年的 MicroNeuro 机器人已成功完成了三项尸体试验，该机器人可以“以微创方式”进行深部脑部手术。 p>;&lt;p>;当今的主要方法需要外科医生使用刚性工具进行手术，并在患者头皮上打开大窗口，刘说，这会损害大量健康的脑组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“脑部手术是一种类型最需要技术的手术，因为这是一个非常危险的手术，”刘说。 “外科医生确实希望利用人工智能和技术创新来使此类手术的侵入性比现在小得多。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CAIR 的机器人系统允许外科医生使用微型灵活的仪器和由人工智能驱动的导航系统他补充说，增强现实可以减少至少 50% 的脑组织损伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与香港威尔斯亲王医院进行的试验表明，该机器人可以进行微创脑部手术称为内窥镜第三脑室造口术和松果体活检，用于治疗大脑中心的肿瘤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CAIR 目前正在对机器人系统进行微调以符合法规，并希望在一些情况下开始临床试验刘说，在获得市医院管理局批准后，将于明年的某个时间推出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CAIR 是由北京国营的 CAS 和香港的 InnoHK 计划资助成立的，是中央政府发展南部地区计划的一部分。据刘介绍，商汤科技推出了可以玩中国古代围棋游戏的消费机器人，该中心受益于香港的大学，这些大学生产刘说，有很多“非常有才华的年轻研究人员”。但他补充说，香港缺乏懂得如何设计电子产品和编写专业软件的经验丰富的工程师，因此 CAIR 正在寻求将大陆工程师转移到香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CAIR 还面临着人工智能计算能力的挑战，因为刘表示，在美国收紧芯片出口规则以涵盖用于训练人工智能模型的最先进芯片后，它“不能完全依赖英伟达的人工智能服务器”。该中心目前正试图通过与华为技术公司合作来降低风险，看看这家中国科技巨头的人工智能计算服务器是否可以用于 CAIR 的研究。但他表示，与英伟达的产品相比，华为的产品“相对较新”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在不久的将来，我认为如果我们试图与该领域的国际厂商竞争，我们将面临一些挑战。”刘说。 “但我认为从长远来看，中国企业最终会迎头赶上。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 17:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong court orders retrial of 4 defendants acquitted of rioting during 2019 protests, saying judge adopted unrealistic approach]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3227735/hong-kong-court-orders-retrial-4-defendants-acquitted-rioting-during-2019-protests-saying-judge?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 17:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/c590152e-9a4a-4513-bb93-950d150d6e6c_38ffde8d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港法院下令对四名参与骚乱的被告进行重审发现主审法官在处理案件时采取了不切实际和投机性的方法后，2019年发生了反政府抗议活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上诉法院周五裁定地方法院错误地适用了法律，得出了“不正当”的结论宣布四人无罪，其中包括一名社会工作者，他敦促警方停止对抗议者使用武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被同一名初审法官宣判无罪的另外九人之所以免于重审，只是因为他们都在接到通知之前离开了香港法院表示，可以向他们提出检察官的上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五的裁决标志着自终审法院概述了无罪判决的标准以来，这是上诉法院首次撤销骚乱审判中记录的无罪判决。在 2021 年底的一项具有里程碑意义的裁决中证明了这一罪行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该判决明确规定，检察官必须在审理参与骚乱的案件之前证明嫌疑人参与或“参与意图” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，即使被告在示威活动中没有表现出暴力行为，如果法院确信他们通过服装、防护装备鼓励其他人参加非法集会，他们仍然可以被定罪。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最高法院作出裁决之前，13 名被告在已退休的沈少文法官监督的两次独立审判中被无罪释放。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一宗案件中，沈氏以缺乏证据证明五男两女于2019年8月31日在湾仔被捕前的所作所为为由，免除了他们的骚乱罪名。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;香港保安局局长敢于要求维权人士罗冠聪在市受审&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;法官进一步裁定，检方未能对第八名被告、社会工作者陈鸿秀立案。 ” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;潘伟昌法官和彭宝琴法官也批评岑子杰同情在骚乱期间被捕的人。 2019年的抗议活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，岑说一些被告可能只是想见证“一个罕见而特殊的历史时刻”，这纯粹是猜测。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“称之为骚乱” “一个‘罕见且特殊的历史时刻’是完全不合适的，”首席法官说。 “更不用说骚乱不是需要观察员的场合。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;6 香港人因 2019 年商业区骚乱被判入狱最高 49 个月&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;岑子杰认为潘说，有些人可能会遮住脸，以免与暴徒混淆，这是“牵强”且“完全脱离现实”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岑还错误地认为检方缺乏证据来指控社会暴力。首席法官表示，被告可能是在煽动骚乱参与者，让骚乱持续下去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在第二起案件中，沈氏清除了三名男子和两名女子共谋参加骚乱的罪名。岑表示，该组织在 2019 年 10 月 1 日附近的一次抗议活动中意图使用在湾仔公寓中发现的危险物品制造骚乱，并强调缺乏证据。示威前被捕，不应仅因当天发生的事情事后定罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港男子因2019年抗议期间警方缴获武器库而入狱&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;然而，法官并不相信这一推理，称 10 月 1 日的骚乱是沙姆应该考虑的令人信服的证据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈和她的案件中的其他三名共同被告现在需要出庭受审。由另一名法官重审。上诉法院亦撤销沈氏在审讯中要求检方承担陈律师费用的裁决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;潘强调，其余九人，包括面临共谋指控的五人，如果他们没有离开香港，将会再次受审在检察官提出上诉之前。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 17:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s Modi awarded top honour by France’s Macron for ‘unwavering friendship’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3227721/indias-modi-awarded-top-honour-frances-macron-unwavering-friendship?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 17:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/1757be4d-1cb8-4d7b-acf1-e92eff175f1f_a291890e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;法国总统将国家最高荣誉授予印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪周五，他是巴士底日庆祝活动的特邀嘉宾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊曼纽尔·马克龙 (Emmanuel Macron) 向莫迪授予了法国荣誉军团勋章 (Legion d&#39;Honneur) 大十字勋章，这是法国勋章的最高等级，总统府在一份声明中表示，“向总理在将法国和印度团结在一起的良好友谊和信任关系中所发挥的作用致敬”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我怀着极大的谦卑接受荣誉军团勋章莫迪在一条法语推文中说道，并附上了他和马克龙在周四晚上在爱丽舍总统府举行的颁奖典礼上的照片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是 14 亿居民的荣幸他说，感谢马克龙和法国人授予这一荣誉，并称这“表明了他们对印度的深厚感情以及与我们国家友谊的延续”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种亲密关系不仅限于莫迪表示：“这实际上体现了印法两国坚定不移的友谊。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;莫迪出访法国，潜艇、喷气机和中国问题成为焦点&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;今年授予莫迪的荣誉反映了法国和印度之间日益加深的关系，两国正在纪念“战略伙伴关系”25周年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国荣誉军团勋章授予军事和平民的成就和服务&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它的历史可以追溯到 1802 年，由拿破仑·波拿巴提出，有五个等级，从骑士级开始，到大十字级结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪总理将成为周五法国巴士底日庆祝活动的主宾，该庆祝活动将于骚乱席卷全国两周后在严密安全的情况下举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当晚，全国将部署约 45,000 名警察，同时出售烟花爆竹已被禁止，因为政府旨在防止六月底警察杀害一名青少年后发生的城市暴力事件重演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一年一度的巴士底日庆祝活动，标志着攻占巴士底狱1789 年法国大革命爆发时，监狱的早晨以传统的阅兵式拉开帷幕，超过 5,000 人将在香榭丽舍大街上游行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度国防部周四宣布，打算采购另外 26 架法国制造的阵风战斗机以及另外三艘鲉鱼级潜艇，这笔交易预计价值数十亿欧元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管在乌克兰战争和印度人权问题上存在紧张局势，但仍存在分歧，西方民主国家正在向莫迪和印度示好，作为对中国的军事和经济制衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙的红地毯欢迎几周前，莫迪获得了在华盛顿（他所在的城市）举行白宫国宴的罕见荣誉。曾被禁止访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙周四晚在军事领导人会议上表示，印度是“世界历史上的巨人，将对我们的未来发挥决定性作用”。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt; hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Long after we are gone, a remote Canadian lake will show how we set about destroying Earth as a habitat]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3227591/long-after-we-are-gone-remote-canadian-lake-will-show-how-we-set-about-destroying-earth-habitat?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 16:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/6ed0795b-f2a8-4b06-9f0e-aaa378b22445_d397b1c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;想象一下 50 万年后外星人登陆地球。到那时，人类很可能早已消失，并因二氧化碳产生、环境破坏和污染的狂欢而引发的全球变暖而灭绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周，默默无闻的国际地层委员会在法国里尔举行了会议。一直在举行第四次大会，重点关注对来访外星人具有巨大价值的工作：地质记录中是否有任何东西表明我们曾经在这里？如果是这样，那么设定人类开始破坏温和平衡的“金钉子”的时间和日期是什么？在全新世时期的 11,700 年间，这种平衡使智人得以繁衍生息并独特地塑造了世界？&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;所有这一切都围绕着地质学家和气候学家之间的激烈争论，即人类是否对地球产生了如此强大的影响，以至于我们已经从全新世进入了人类世，这是由诺贝尔化学奖获得者保罗·克鲁岑在二十年前创造的.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在里尔大会的核心，一个名为“人类世工作组”的小型但极具影响力的团体报告了这两个巨大的地质问题。他们的结论是什么？是的，我们在全球留下了标记，这些标记可能在 50 万年后仍然清晰可见；我们从全新世转变为人类世的日期应该定在 1950 年代初。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在检查了世界各地 12 个地点的候选名单后，这些地点可以提供这一转变的最清晰标记，并确定人类对人类的影响。在地球上，他们同意关注克劳福德湖，这是一个位于加拿大多伦多以西约 60 公里处的偏远小湖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克劳福德湖很特别，因为湖底的沉积物提供了关于环境的精美记录。数千年来的变化，使我们能够看到地球地质历史的逐年变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科学家表示，该湖具有非凡的特征。由于湖小而深，湖水不易混合。附近岩石中的钙和碳酸盐溶解在水中，并在温暖的天气中结合形成晶体，沉淀在地板上，定义了每个季节，深入人类历史。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岩心样本显示，随着地质变化，1950 年左右发生了变化。人类活动的影响变得更加普遍：这标志着人类世——人类时代的开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当然，智人的第一个证据可以追溯到至少 315,000 年前的摩洛哥，那里有火和猎人- 大约 17 万年前记录的采集者活动。但这些人类社区的来去并没有对全球生态系统造成太大干扰。直到 1950 年左右，我们才看到“大加速”，一系列人类活动对全球产生了如此重大的影响，以至于全新世的相对稳定性被严重打破。这与二氧化碳排放和全球变暖有关，但还涉及更多：几千年来的变化将留下不可磨灭的地质足迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人类世的第一个清晰而普遍的标记是一层薄薄但独特的地层。钚是 1952 年底在太平洋马绍尔群岛埃尼韦塔克环礁开始的氢弹试验中产生的。这种情况持续了十多年，直到 1963 年全球禁止核试验。这创造了一个独特的、特定时间的全球标记，该标记将在数千年中保持清晰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，全球燃煤发电站产生的粉煤灰激增提供了另一个独特的标记，其日期非常精确到 20 世纪 50 年代初。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后出现了塑料和微塑料、重金属、工业化学品和混凝土。从今天起，地质学家开始发现融合了塑料和新矿物（如 Simonkolleite（风化锌渣））的彩色石头，这些矿物是污染和人类活动的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地质学家警告说，其他独特的标记将定义我们对人类的影响。英国地质调查小组计算出，无论是城镇还是公路和铁路的建筑活动，在环境表面移动的物质是世界河流流入海洋的所有物质的 24 倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，人类每年产生约 3160 亿吨沉积物（相当于一个 150 公里 x 150 公里的巨大立方体，如果你能想象这样的事情的话）。 “遥远的未来”的侵蚀和隆起将使这些“目前看不见的活动”暴露出来。这也可能会让任何来访的外星地质学家感到困惑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人口爆炸和我们对消费的贪得无厌，在世界各地创造了垃圾填埋场，这些垃圾填埋场很可能经受住地质时间的考验，像史前的垃圾填埋场一样被压缩和复合。森林被掩埋并最终转化为煤炭、石油和天然气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个独特的标志可能是鸡骨头。直到 20 世纪 50 年代初，我们才开始大规模消费鸡肉。如今，根据联合国粮食及农业组织的数据，我们每年消耗约 730 亿只鸡（以及 15 亿头牛和 35 亿头猪）——这一习惯可能会为 50 万年后的外星人提供丰富（也可能令人困惑）的数据。其中更细心的人还会在化石记录中注意到野生动物和自然生物多样性的大规模崩溃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到明年八月在韩国举行的国际地质科学联盟会议上，世界领先的地质学家将决定一个正式的新人类世时代是否已经开始，以及克劳福德湖是否应该被接受为“金钉子”。无论结论如何，人类世工作组都提供了一个重要的提醒：我们人类现在是一个“地质超级大国”，正在永远改变我们的星球，而且不是为了变得更好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 16:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US-China relations: we must talk security, Wang Yi tells Antony Blinken]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227695/us-china-relations-we-must-talk-security-wang-yi-tells-blinken?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 16:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/a2027047-60eb-4038-a810-2f6f60188afc_ff9e0b46.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国外交政策负责人呼吁与美国加强外交和安全沟通，称两个敌对超级大国需要消除绊脚石，以改善关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅在雅加达东南亚国家联盟会议期间与美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯会谈时传达了这一信息。周四。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周五的一份声明中，中国外交部援引王毅的话说，两国应该找到阻止“灰犀牛”并处理“黑天鹅”（高影响或意外事件）的方法，以及为稳定美中关系创造条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美方需要理性务实，与中方相向而行……拓展外交、安全领域沟通渠道，让双方沟通更加顺畅” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交部表示，王毅应美国特使要求会见了布林肯，会谈“坦诚、务实、富有建设性”。双方同意在会后保持沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次会面是两人在大约一个月内第二次会面，就在布林肯对中国进行为期两天的访问（其中包括与总统举行会谈）几周后习近平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅表示，布林肯会见习近平后，中美双方达成“一些共识”，称这是“校准中美关系巨轮的重要一步”。&lt;/p>;&lt;下一步关键是采取实际行动，让双边关系重回正轨。美国需要反思导致中美关系严重困难的原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅还强调了北京在台湾问题上的立场，敦促华盛顿避免干涉北京的内政或损害其主权。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将自治的台湾视为一个等待与大陆统一的叛徒省份，并且不排除使用武力控制台湾。与大多数国家一样，美国不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对使用武力改变现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅表示，美国应停止“打压”中国，解除“非法和违法行为”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京和华盛顿作为势力范围巨大的大国，都应尊重地区国家的努力，“避免将争议和复杂因素”带入区域合作”，王说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务院发言人马修·米勒表示，布林肯利用这次会议来推进华盛顿的利益和价值观，并“直接提出美国及其盟友和伙伴对[北京]行动的共同担忧”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在讨论中，布林肯强调维护台海和平稳定的必要性，并明确表示美国及其盟友和伙伴将推进建立自由、开放和基于规则的国际体系的愿景&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次会议 — — 美国称其为“坦诚和建设性” — — 是华盛顿努力维持开放沟通渠道的一部分，以“通过减少误解和误判的风险来负责任地管理竞争”，米勒&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是世界对美国和中华人民共和国的期望，”他指的是中华人民共和国。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国、俄罗斯誓言共同努力新加坡南洋理工大学外交政策助理教授迪伦·洛 (Dylan Loh) 表示，这次会议表明美国热衷于为与印尼的关系设置“底线”中国，但两国借机表达关切并不奇怪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“双方都希望取得一些进展，但没有一方愿意先妥协，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这类似于向前移动两步并后退一步半。尽管如此，任何向前的进展都是好的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;骆表示，会谈将有助于两国​​之间恢复对话和重建信任，他期待习近平和美国总统拜登之间有更多互动并最终举行会面。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果没有这些会议，就很难看到双方关系的进展或改善。中国社会科学院美中关系专家卢翔表示，这次会议没有取得突破性进展，但它确实发出了需要避免危机的强烈信号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“良好的态度并不等于具体的结果。中美关系在务实领域仍处于僵局。我们需要看到贸易等领域的进展才能证明双边关系取得了进展。”卢说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 16:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong authorities to reduce number of bins on streets to encourage residents to take garbage home]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227675/hong-kong-authorities-reduce-number-bins-streets-encourage-residents-take-garbage-home?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 15:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/f9ec9a21-5178-448f-aa40-3db78f831454_419caf63.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港当局表示将逐步减少街头垃圾桶的数量帮助居民养成把垃圾带回家的新习惯，同时承诺不会再推迟拟议的垃圾税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但环境生态局局长谢展云周五向立法会环境事务委员会表示，政府不会同时实施这两项政策，因为担心人们“不太适应”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们会逐步减少街上的垃圾桶数量，希望改变每个人的生活习惯。”习惯，”谢告诉立法者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们旅行时，我们会看到许多国家拿走路边垃圾桶，并要求每个人将垃圾带回家、住的酒店和工作场所。我们已经看到了良好的结果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新的政府统计数据显示，2018 年香港约有 40,000 个路边垃圾桶，而纽约的 850 万人口有 23,000 个，首尔的 980 万居民有 1,000 个。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会事务委员会周五还批准从 4 月 1 日开始对居民废物征税，谢承诺启动日期将于 10 月刊宪，不会进一步推迟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划是近二十年前提出的，旨在改革该市的生活垃圾管理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在环卫工人提出要求后，政府上周宣布将征税计划从今年年底推迟到 4 月 1 日启动。团体警告说，原定开始日期将与寒假期间最繁忙的季节相冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;有关香港按垃圾付费计划的所有信息&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该计划何时实施4 月生效后，香港居民每扔一升垃圾，需缴纳 11 港分（1.4 美分）的费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们必须将垃圾存放在政府指定的袋子中，袋子有九种尺寸， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;征费后会有半年的宽限期，在此期间，官员将主要给予verbal warnings to people who fail to comply with the scheme. After which, a failure to dispose of waste in designated bags will incur a HK$1,500 fine.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong &#39;should delay waste-charging scheme until spring to prevent build-up&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Tse also warned that the government would “strictly enforce” the law against littering. The penalty would be doubled to HK$3,000 on October 22 after securing a green light from the legislature on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The penalties for unlawful shop extensions and illegal dumping of construction waste will be raised to HK$6,000, up from the current HK$1,500.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tse explained that if residents were found to discard their garbage on the street, even with a designated bag, they would be regarded as littering and fined HK$3,000.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong student among 6 arrested as police clamp down on cross-border syndicate laundering HK$100 million]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3227679/hong-kong-student-among-6-arrested-police-clamp-down-cross-border-syndicate-laundering-hk100-million?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 15:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/5a930d58-7f0c-4b70-bd20-830d09b2e10d_749aafee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Hong Kong postsecondary student was among six people arrested when police clamped down on a cross-border syndicate that laundered more than HK$100 million (US$12.7 million) in suspected crime proceeds, the force on Friday said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to police, the student was suspected of helping the group to launder illegal funds by using e-wallet accounts to trade cryptocurrency, concealing the origins and flow of crime proceeds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Senior Inspector Chu Ming-man of the Hong Kong Island anti-triad squad said the digital coins were ultimately transferred to e-wallet accounts overseas to evade detection.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“An investigation showed the syndicate had handled more than HK$1 million [in crime proceeds] a day and laundered more than HK$100 million [in three months],” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police arrest 19 in crackdown on money laundering syndicate&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The force began investigating the syndicate in late April after receiving intelligence, prompting officers to seek help from their mainland Chinese counterparts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The syndicate set up bank accounts on the mainland to collect crime proceeds generated through various scams. Members then used debit cards to launder illegal funds by purchasing valuables such as gold ornaments and watches in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chu said the group took the proceeds from reselling the valuables and bought digital coins, creating an extra layer of transactions to conceal the flow of illegal funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was a well-organised syndicate with a clear division of work, and used multilayered approaches to increase the difficulty of police investigation,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After gathering evidence, officers arrested the five men and one woman in a series of raids across the city on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The six local residents, aged from 22 to 36, included its alleged ringleader, two core members and an employee at a watch shop.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the force, the student was one of the two alleged core members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The other two were accused of helping the syndicate to use bank cards to make purchases in the city, police said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The group was detained on suspicion of conspiracy to launder crime proceeds and defraud.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officers seized more than HK$1 million in cash and valuables such as watches and gold ornaments, along with debit cards, during the operation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong customs smashes US$91 million money-smuggling racket, arrests 23&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The suspects were still in police custody as of Friday afternoon. The force said its investigation was ongoing and further arrests were possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to the student&#39;s arrest, Senior Inspector Chu urged young people to be extra vigilant when taking on summer jobs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also reminded merchants that “if a customer makes multiple purchases of the same item or frequently uses different debit cards for payment, they should pay attention to the client&#39;s purpose and background, and verify the authenticity of the buyer&#39;s identity and bank cards”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Hong Kong, money laundering is punishable by up to 14 years in jail and a HK$5 million fine.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US records 28 mass killings in first half of 2023, a ‘ghastly milestone’ and ‘staggering statistic’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227669/us-records-28-mass-killings-first-half-2023-ghastly-milestone-and-staggering-statistic?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 15:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/d7d153f9-9951-41c4-b83f-b86be32ca5fc_4800733b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Slain at the hands of strangers or gunned down by loved ones. Massacred in small towns, in big cities, inside their own homes or outside in broad daylight. This year&#39;s unrelenting bloodshed across the US has led to the grimmest of milestones: the deadliest six months of mass killings recorded since at least 2006.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From January 1 to June 30, the nation endured 28 mass killings, all but one of which involved guns. The death toll rose just about every week, a constant cycle of violence and grief.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Six months. 181 days. 28 mass killings. 140 victims. One country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What a ghastly milestone,” said Brent Leatherwood, whose three children were in class at a private Christian school in Nashville on March 27 when a former student killed three children and three adults. “You never think your family would be a part of a statistic like that.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leatherwood, a prominent Republican in a state that hasn&#39;t strengthened gun laws, believes something must be done to get guns out of the hands of people who might become violent. The shock of seeing the bloodshed strike so close to home has prompted him to speak out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You may as well say Martians have landed, right? It&#39;s hard to wrap your mind around it,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;On US Independence Day, Biden denounces wave of shootings&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A mass killing is defined as an occurrence when four or more people are slain, not including the assailant, within a 24-hour period.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A database maintained by Associated Press and USA Today in partnership with Northeastern University tracks this large-scale violence dating back to 2006.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unlike the Gun Violence Archive it does not include non-fatal shootings. The database also does not include homicides caused by driving under the influence or accidental fires due to lack of intent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 2023 milestone beat the previous record of 27 mass killings, which was only set in the second half of 2022. James Alan Fox, a criminology professor at Northeastern University, never imagined records like this when he began overseeing the database about five years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We used to say there were two to three dozen a year,” Fox said. “The fact that there&#39;s 28 in half a year is a staggering statistic.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the chaos of the first six months of 2023 doesn&#39;t automatically doom the last six months. The remainder of the year could be calmer, despite more violence over the July Fourth holiday weekend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hopefully it was just a blip,” said Dr Amy Barnhorst, a psychiatrist who is the associate director of the Violence Prevention Research Programme at the University of California, Davis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There could be fewer killings later in 2023, or this could be part of a trend. But we won&#39;t know for sometime,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts like Barnhorst and Fox attribute the rising bloodshed to a growing population with an increased number of guns in the US. Yet for all the headlines, mass killings are statistically rare and represent a fraction of the country&#39;s overall gun violence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We need to keep it in perspective,” Fox said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Parents fret as Winnie the Pooh book teaches kids about US school shootings&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But the mass violence most often spurs attempts to reform gun laws, even if the efforts are not always successful.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tennessee Governor Bill Lee, a Republican, had urged the General Assembly in the wake of the Nashville school shooting to pass legislation keeping firearms away from people who could harm themselves or others, so-called “red flag laws”, though Lee says the term is politically toxic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Getting such a measure passed in Tennessee is an uphill climb. The Republican-led Legislature adjourned earlier this year without taking on gun control, prompting Lee to schedule a special session for August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leatherwood, a former executive director of the Tennessee Republican Party and now the head of the influential Southern Baptist Convention&#39;s public policy arm, wrote a letter to lawmakers asking them to pass the governor&#39;s proposal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leatherwood said he doesn&#39;t want any other family to go through what his children experienced at the time of the shooting when they were in kindergarten, second grade and fourth grade. One of his kids, preparing for a recent sleepaway camp, asked whether they would be safe there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our child was asking: &#39;Do you think that there will be a gunman that comes to this camp? Do I need to be worried about that?&#39;” Leatherwood said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Nashville shooter, whose writings Leatherwood and other parents are asking a court to keep private, used three guns in the attack, including an AR-15-style rifle. It was one of at least four mass killings in the first half of 2023 involving such a weapon, according to the database.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Texas shooting victims include Korean-American family, engineer from India&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Nearly all of the mass killings in the first half of this year, 27 of 28, involved guns. The other was a fire that killed four people in a home in Monroe, Louisiana. A 37-year-old man was arrested on arson and murder charges in connection with the March 31 deaths.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the unprecedented carnage, the National Rifle Association maintains fierce opposition to regulating firearms, including AR-15-style rifles and similar weapons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Joe Biden and Kamala Harris&#39; constant efforts to gut the Second Amendment will not usher in safety for Americans; instead, it will only embolden criminals,” NRA spokesman Billy McLaughlin said in a statement. “That is why the NRA continues our fight for self-defence laws. Rest assured, we will never bow, we will never retreat, and we will never apologise for championing the self-defence rights of law-abiding Americans.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tito Anchondo&#39;s brother, Andre Anchondo, was among 23 people killed in a 2019 mass shooting at a Walmart in El Paso, Texas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gunman was sentenced last week to 90 consecutive life sentences but could face more punishment, including the death penalty. The prosecution of the racist attack on Hispanic shoppers in the border city was one of the US government&#39;s largest hate crime cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Andre Anchondo and his wife, Jordan, died shielding their two-month-old son from bullets. Paul, who escaped with just broken bones, is now four years old.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tito Anchondo said he feels like the country has forgotten about the El Paso victims in the years since and that not nearly enough has been done to stem the bloodshed. He worries about Paul&#39;s future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I hope that things can drastically change because this country is going down a very, very slippery slope; a downward spiral,” he said. “It&#39;s just a little unnerving to know that he&#39;s eventually going to go to school with kids that also may bring a gun to school.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Beijing urges more cooperation with Hanoi as disputes simmer over South China Sea]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227664/beijing-urges-more-cooperation-hanoi-disputes-simmer-over-south-china-sea?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 15:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/60e2bbc5-9d96-4e1c-912b-69e023ebf9b7_38b2708b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing and Hanoi should make joint efforts to manage their disputes in the South China Sea, China&#39;s top diplomat has said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the sidelines of a regional foreign ministers&#39; meeting in Indonesian capital Jakarta on Thursday, Wang Yi, Beijing&#39;s foreign policy chief, also said China was willing to import more goods from the Southeast Asian neighbour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The two sides should follow the important consensus … on the proper handling of maritime issues, actively put it into action, pay more attention to mutually beneficial cooperation, give full play to the role of the existing mechanisms, manage the situation well and promote cooperation, so as to provide stable expectations for the development of China-Vietnam relations,” Wang told Vietnamese Foreign Minister Bui Thanh Son.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said China was “ready” to work with Asean members for an early conclusion of the code of conduct (COC) for the South China Sea, a set of rules aimed at managing behaviour and minimising the potential for conflict in the resource-rich waters. The region is criss-crossed by overlapping claims from China as well as Vietnam, Malaysia, the Philippines, Brunei and Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, China would continue to improve its communication with Vietnam to “consolidate strategic mutual trust and expand cooperation of mutual benefit”, Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thursday&#39;s meeting came after fraught tensions over the disputed waters boiled over again.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week, Hanoi banned the movie Barbie produced by Warner Bros over an illustration in the film that allegedly depicts the nine-dash line, a controversial symbol Beijing has used to claim as much as 90 per cent of the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The territorial disputes have become a mounting source of friction between the two neighbours despite their shared political ideologies and structures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a milestone during long-delayed talks, China and Asean announced on Thursday the conclusion of the second reading of the COC, paving the way for negotiations on more contentious issues, including if the rules would be legally binding and the geographical scope they would be applied to.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, Wang urged that China and the Association of Southeast Asian Nations “further facilitate bilateral trade and investment” by coordinating each other&#39;s development strategies and improving connectivity infrastructure, including the east line of the Pan-Asian Railway, a planned railway to connect China, Vietnam, Cambodia and Thailand.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US-China rivalry, Ukraine war in spotlight at Asean security talks&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“China is willing to import more marketable Vietnamese products,” Wang told Son.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a readout from the Vietnamese side, Son said his country would work with China to keep pushing forward their comprehensive strategic partnership.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vietnam is keen to boost exports to China, and is willing to manage issues including the maritime disputes, he said, according to the Chinese readout.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, diplomats from China and Vietnam met in the southern Chinese city of Guangzhou for the latest round of consultations for maritime joint development, their first in-person meeting since 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Health reasons&#39;: Chinese Foreign Minister Qin Gang to miss Asean meeting&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to the Chinese readout, the two sides agreed to speed up talks on a new fisheries cooperation deal in the Gulf of Tonkin, and promote oil and gas cooperation in “non-disputed waters” in the South China Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But observers said there was little room for compromise on oil and gas cooperation, and that hopes between the two rival claimants remained dim given their long-standing disputes.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>