<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Japan PM Kishida willing to meet North Korea’s Kim Jong-un over kidnappings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222059/japan-pm-kishida-willing-meet-north-koreas-kim-jong-un-over-kidnappings?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 21:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/eff33ea-9fcb-44c6-8727-8e2f18c089ab_4e511cdb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;首相岸田文雄周六表示，他希望在两国之间建立高层谈判日本和朝鲜争取早日安排与朝鲜领导人金正恩就日本被绑架者返回问题举行首脑会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在东京寻求日本人返回的集会上发表讲话对于在 1970 年代和 80 年代被朝鲜绑架的国民，岸田重申他致力于“尽早”与金正恩实现无条件会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的政府将致力于安排与平壤的谈判“在高位Kishida 补充说，“我直接控制的级别”为与朝鲜领导人的会谈铺平了道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;86 岁的日本妈妈失去了看到女儿平壤在 1977 年被绑架的希望&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;日本政府已正式确认其 17 名国民被朝鲜绑架，并怀疑平壤参与了许多其他失踪事件。虽然 2002 年有 5 人返回，但另外 12 人下落不明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岸田还告诉与会者，与平壤建立富有成效的关系将“对双方都有利，并对地区发展做出巨大贡献稳定与和平。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位政府消息人士称，首相已表明“他已准备好与朝鲜对话。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着许多失踪者的家人现在年事已高，在 2021 年成为首相的岸田担任首相期间，这个问题变得越来越紧迫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在政策转变中，为实现其目标而妥协的意愿增强，全国救援日本人协会被绑架朝鲜在 2 月表示，如果这意味着被绑架者将被遣返，它不会反对对该国的人道主义援助。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China and Congo agree to regular checks on mining deals]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222042/china-and-congo-agree-regular-checks-mining-deals?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/4c7daade-5534-4f07-b1c4-650d59c62fbf_cab41929.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国和刚果民主共和国总统同意定期评估采矿根据周五的联合声明，合作符合两国的长远利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在刚果领导人周三抵达中国首都推动他认为在他的前任约瑟夫·卡比拉领导下“谈判不力”的采矿合同的全面改革。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tshisekedi 还寻求吸引更多中国投资进入这个资源丰富的非洲国家，并获得中国的帮助以打击 M23 反叛分子&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，在人民大会堂会谈之前，习近平在天安门广场以仪仗队和 21 响礼炮欢迎刚果总统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平表示，中国愿加强与金沙萨的伙伴关系，加大对这个中非国家的投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国领导人还同意将双边关系提升为全面战略合作伙伴关系，这是双边关系的最高水平&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国公司与刚果钴矿达成特许权使用费协议，松了一口气&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;刚果民主共和国正在重新评估的其中一项采矿交易是价值 62 亿美元的中刚合资企业 Sicomines ，这是刚果民主共和国 2008 年与中国公司签署的以矿产换基础设施的合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为钴和铜的回报，中国公司同意投资 30 亿美元在矿产资源丰富的采矿项目加丹加省，以及 32 亿美元的一般基础设施建设。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在 2 月，刚果金融总监察局发布了一份报告，称该国没有为其贡献的铜和钴储量得到充分补偿.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，中国企业开采了约100亿美元的矿产，但仅建设了价值约8.22亿美元的基础设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国驻刚果民主共和国大使馆和Sicomines大使馆强烈反对这份报告，称该报告“充满偏见”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刚果官员在北京表示，谈判正在进行中，有望在年底前签署该项目的新采矿协议&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国矿业合资企业正在成为刚果的政治棋子吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周五，习近平表示，中国将继续鼓励中国企业加快实施商定的基础设施项目，加强&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据联合声明，中方将鼓励中国企业投资刚果（金）新能源电池价值链开发项目，支持刚果（金）产业链升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;两国元首还一致认为，合作中出现的问题可以“通过友好协商解决”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国将“按照市场化原则”推动投资高质量发展以及合同精神”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国也将参与建设基础设施，但项目将由刚果民主共和国制定。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;刚果民主共和国军官因谋杀2 中国工人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但刚果民主共和国必须改善商业环境并保护在该国经营的中国公司的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国公司过去曾抱怨过不公平待遇，特别是在税收问题上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在刚果民主共和国东部、加丹加和卢阿拉巴，中国工人也成为袭击和绑架的受害者，中国公司在这些地方拥有采矿权益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上次局势恶化时今年，中国公安部派出一个专家小组帮助寻找解决安全问题的办法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;齐塞克迪政府正在与刚果民主共和国东部的 M23 叛乱分子作战，金沙萨声称该组织得到了卢旺达的支持 – claims卢旺达予以否认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平周五表示，中国支持“恢复刚果东部和平与安全”的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国谴责各种武装分子实施的暴力和侵犯人权行为习近平说，支持重建信任与和平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;齐塞克迪感谢中国长期以来对刚果经济社会发展的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“刚果愿意与中国深化在经贸、资源、基础设施、医疗卫生等领域的合作，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国元首见证了合作协议的签署，其中包括关于开采自然资源、数字经济的发展、信息交流、绿色增长和电视网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刚果民主共和国对中国向绿色能源转型具有重要战略意义——该国供应了中国 60% 以上的钴，是电动汽车和电子产品电池的关键部件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国国家统计局的数据，2022 年与刚果民主共和国的双边贸易额达到 219 亿美元，比上年增长 51.7% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从北京出发，Tshisekedi 和他的团队将访问上海、深圳和香港。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Iraq bid to link Asia and Europe in US$17 billion road and rail project]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3222057/iraq-link-asia-and-europe-us17-billion-road-and-rail-project?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 21:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/f11b29e2-9f3c-4073-9946-102fd24d84a8_40dfa4e9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;伊拉克周六启动了一项耗资 170 亿美元的项目，以连接其主要商品港口南部海岸通过铁路和公路通往与土耳其的边界，此举旨在在经历了几十年的战争和危机后改变该国的经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发展之路旨在连接伊拉克盛产石油的大法奥港南至土耳其，通过缩短亚洲和欧洲之间的旅行时间，将土耳其变成一个中转枢纽，以与苏伊士运河相媲美。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“发展之路不仅仅是运送货物或乘客的道路。这条道路为伊拉克广大地区的发展打开了大门，”伊拉克港口总公司总干事 Farhan al-Fartousi 告诉路透社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊拉克政府设想高速列车运送货物和货物以每小时 300 公里（186.41 英里）的速度运送乘客，与当地工业中心和可能包括石油和天然气管道的能源组成部分相连。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;伊拉克的古老宝藏因气候变化而被喷砂&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;这将标志着与该国现有陈旧交通网络的重大转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊拉克的火车服务目前运营着几条线路，包括慢速石油货运和从巴格达到巴士拉的单程过夜客运列车，需要 10 到 12 个小时才能完成 500 公里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法尔图西说，十多年前设计的大法奥港已完成一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊拉克与伊拉克之间的客运欧洲回顾了 20 世纪之交的宏伟计划，即打造一条从巴格达到柏林的快车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将再次启用这条线路，并将其与其他国家联系起来，”Fartousi 说道，并指出了计划运送游客和朝圣者前往伊拉克的什叶派圣地和沙特阿拉伯的麦加朝圣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该项目于周六在一次会议上宣布，旨在吸引阿拉伯海湾国家、叙利亚等阿拉伯国家的兴趣和乔丹。一位政府高级助手表示，区域投资已经摆在桌面上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊拉克的发展承诺由来已久，但即使总理穆罕默德什叶派苏丹政府推动重建道路，基础设施仍然破旧不堪&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但官员们表示，发展道路是基于一些新的东西：自去年年底以来的一段相对稳定的时期，他们希望能够维持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果明年工作早点开始一年，该项目将在 2029 年完成，Fartousi 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“即使伊拉克缺席一年或两年或十年或两年，它也必须有一天或另一天返回。希望这些天是伊拉克回归的开始，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: China’s peace envoy pushes political settlement in Moscow meetings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222047/ukraine-war-chinas-peace-envoy-pushes-political-settlement-moscow-meetings?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 20:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/2d57b6b9-fc50-4b45-ba66-d13cd8acc2d7_e6f890c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京和莫斯科誓言加强联系并改善沟通以政治解决战争周五，中国欧亚事务特使李辉与包括外交部长谢尔盖拉夫罗夫在内的俄罗斯外交官在乌克兰举行会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为北京推动其和平计划的努力的一部分，李在俄罗斯首都进行了会谈并在结束访问包括乌克兰在内的其他五个欧洲国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[中国将]加强与包括俄罗斯在内的各方的交流与对话，并为实现政治目标做出具体努力。乌克兰危机的解决，”中国外交部援引这位特使的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前驻俄罗斯大使李说，北京一直坚持“客观公正”的立场，积极促和谈判，据报道&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;波兰敦促中国和平特使俄罗斯撤军&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;波兰外交部表示，双方同意中国国家主席习近平的3月对俄罗斯的访问“进一步加深了政治互信”，为中俄合作“注入了新的强劲动力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方表示要加强双边和多边战略协作，加强交流与合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄方表示，将继续坚持政治解决方向，继续加强同中方沟通协调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;中国将自己描绘成冲突中的中立方，但由于北京与莫斯科的密切关系以及不愿谴责俄罗斯入侵乌克兰，其立场遭到了西方的质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京放2 月份提出了一项含糊的 12 点和平建议，呼吁停火与和平谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在上个月习近平与乌克兰总统沃洛德米尔·泽伦斯基 (Volodymyr Zelensky) 进行了期待已久的电话通话后，李克强访问了欧洲。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;据俄罗斯外交部称，拉夫罗夫在与李辉的会晤中欢迎中国在乌克兰危机上的“平衡”立场，并称赞两国的密切关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉夫罗夫“感谢据俄罗斯国营塔斯社报道，中方感谢中方在乌克兰危机上的平衡立场，并称赞北京愿意在解决问题上发挥积极作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉夫罗夫证实了莫斯科对政治和外交的承诺解决冲突。他指责“乌克兰方面及其西方操纵者”为恢复和平谈判制造了“严重障碍”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，在李克强访问乌克兰、波兰、德国、比利时和法国期间，他受到来自欧洲官员利用北京在俄罗斯的影响力来说服它停止战争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟负责政治事务的副秘书长恩里克莫拉周四在布鲁塞尔告诉李，欧盟希望中国发挥作用“建设性作用”并维护联合国宪章和国际法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李说，中国和欧盟就冲突达成了一些共识，北京支持欧洲国家加强“战略自主”，根据一位来自北京的声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国和平特使再次告诉北京必须推动莫斯科结束对乌克兰的入侵&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;李在他的访问期间从其他欧洲官员那里收到了基本一致的信息。波兰外交部副部长 Wojciech Gerwel 告诉李克强，乌克兰的和平只能通过撤出俄罗斯军队并归还“非法占领的领土”来实现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华尔街日报》周五援引匿名西方官员的话报道在访问期间，李呼吁立即停火，让俄罗斯控制其新地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样在周五，俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京告诉巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦，俄罗斯“就政治和外交解决方案开放对话”。但他在电话中坚称，这种努力遭到了基辅及其“西方支持者”的阻挠。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李在本月早些时候访问该国期间告诉乌克兰官员，“解决问题没有灵丹妙药” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“各方要从自身做起，积累互信，为止战和谈创造条件。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore court rules Credit Suisse owes millions to a billionaire ex-prime minister]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222048/singapore-court-rules-credit-suisse-owes-millions-billionaire-ex-prime-minister?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 20:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/03cf42ad-2e9d-480d-adba-82e70c84e7a0_662fbeb3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;瑞士信贷欠格鲁吉亚前总理 Bidzina Ivanishvili 数亿美元，因为它未能做到一家新加坡法院裁定，保护这位亿万富翁的资金存放在一名经理窃取的信托基金中，这是这家瑞士银行的最新丑闻，该银行多年的问题迫使其被竞争对手收购。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ivanishvili 在 2004 年投入的资金超过美国新加坡国际商事法庭表示，11 亿美元投入由该银行新加坡子公司 Credit Suisse Trust Limited 监管的信托基金，管理该信托基金的员工在被捕并入狱前的九年里“挪用了数百万美元”。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;这位亿万富翁商人在 2012 年至 2013 年担任格鲁吉亚总理之前在俄罗斯积累了一笔财富，他起诉这家瑞士银行要求赔偿约 12 亿美元，称其未能妥善管理信托并确保其资产安全。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天公布的判决是错误的，并构成了非常重大的法律问题”，瑞士信贷在一份声明中表示。 “Credit Suisse Trust Limited 打算积极提起上诉”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在瑞银收购之前从 Credit Suisse 撤回了超过 680 亿美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该银行此前承认，它没有采取合理的措施截至 2008 年底采取措施保护信托资产，并同意在去年的和解中支付超过 7940 万美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“被告有责任赔偿原告的损失”，其中有Patricia Bergin 法官在一项裁决中表示，减去和解金额后的计算金额为 9.26 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，百慕大相关案件中的任何支出都必须减少，这样就不会出现“双倍” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该银行已对百慕大最高法院的一项裁决提出上诉，该裁决认为瑞士信贷未能在其子公司瑞士信贷人寿保险公司购买的两份人寿保险单中阻止 Ivanishvili 资产的“欺诈性管理不善”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ivanishvili 在该案中要求赔偿近 5.54 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家曾经备受尊敬的瑞士银行多年来经历了一系列令人痛心的丑闻从对冲基金的错误押注到未能阻止保加利亚可卡因集团洗钱，以及它没有报告美国富人用来逃避美国税款的秘密离岸账户的指控，不一而足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在瑞信股价暴跌且客户迅速撤出资金后，瑞士政府在 3 月仓促安排了瑞银以 32.5 亿美元收购瑞信，因为担心其崩溃可能会在两家美国银行倒闭后进一步扰乱全球金融市场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;瑞银正试图尽快完成交易，欧盟行政部门周四签署协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一天前，瑞银董事长科尔姆凯莱赫表示，瑞士最大的银行“担心文化污染”并使用他称之为“文化过滤器”的方法来确定从瑞士信贷引进的人选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;收购“伴随着巨大的整合风险，但我们认为一旦我们度过难关，明确的价值在于可以创造是非常明显的，”他在伦敦华尔街日报 CEO 委员会峰会上说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesia’s antitrust body fines cooking oil firms for restricting supply]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222046/indonesias-antitrust-body-fines-cooking-oil-firms-restricting-supply?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 20:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/7c5125cf-2899-445c-bad1-7bc97d289c60_c35863a4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚反垄断机构（KPPU）责令七家食用油公司缴纳罚款去年因供应短缺而限制销售而高达 280 万美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，在印度尼西亚政府对必需产品的零售价格飙升设置临时上限后，KPPU 对食用油公司的行为展开了调查以及后来为期三周的棕榈油出口禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚是世界上最大的棕榈油生产国，通常用作食用油。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度尼西亚人因棕榈油腐败入狱&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;KPPU 小组主席 Dinni Melanie 说，在 27 家接受调查的公司中，有 7 家被发现在零售价格上限于 2022 年初实施时限制其品牌食用油的分销。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这七家公司包括印度尼西亚最大的食品公司 Indofood Group 的子公司 Salim Ivomas Pratama，以及 Wilmar Group 的两家子公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些公司被勒令支付 10 亿卢比（68,050.36 美元）不等的罚款) 至 409 亿卢比（278 万美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wilmar 周六表示对这一决定感到失望，并认为 KPPU“可能误解了”事实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在相关时期......我们的食用油业务，特别是我们的行业，受到严重的供应链问题的影响，这些问题影响了食用油的交付，”Wilmar 的发言人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Salim Ivomas 没有回应请求以征求意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;KPPU 调查的所有 27 家公司均因操纵价格指控被宣告无罪。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Travel chaos: Delays for arrivals at UK airports due to passport e-gate failure]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222045/travel-chaos-delays-uk-airports-due-passport-e-gate-failure?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 19:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/50fecaff-acaf-454e-961a-570c7e029f8f_0d60e997.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英国机场的护照电子门系统故障导致那些人长时间延误随着公共假期假期的开始，抵达该国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅客在社交媒体上描述了在包括希思罗机场和盖特威克机场在内的许多机场排了几个小时的队，因为抵达者需要人工检查他们的护照，而不是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问题来了，因为预计本周末将有数百万人上路和乘坐公共交通工具。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位抵达希思罗机场的旅客在 Twitter 上发帖说：“刚降落到一片混乱的场面。 2小时的队列只是为了到达真正的队列。门坏了。”盖特威克机场的另一名乘客将这种情况描述为“彻头彻尾的笑话”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;盖特威克机场的一位发言人表示，问题从周五晚上开始出现，但周六的排队情况有所缓解。他说：“由于英国边境部队电子门在全国范围内存在问题，一些乘客可能会在入境时遇到延误。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的工作人员正在与英国边防部队合作——他们负责包括电子门在内的护照检查– 在必要时为乘客提供帮助。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;至少有 50 架国泰航空航班因香港机场系统故障而延误&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;希思罗机场在 Twitter 上发布：“我们知道全国范围内的影响由边防部队运营的电子门的问题。这个问题影响了一些入境口岸，并不是希思罗机场特有的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的团队正在与边防部队密切合作，以帮助尽快解决这个问题，我们还有其他同事在场管理队列并提供乘客福利。对于这对乘客旅程造成的任何影响，我们深表歉意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内政部发言人表示，边防部队已经制定了“强有力的计划”来部署官员，以尽量减少干扰和等待时间。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;自动电子门系统适用于 12 岁以上的英国公民和来自欧盟的公民，以及来自澳大利亚、加拿大、美国、日本和新西兰等其他几个国家的公民。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;女发言人说：“我们知道全国范围内的边境系统问题会影响到英国的入境者。我们正在努力尽快解决这个问题，并与港口运营商和航空公司保持联系，以尽量减少对旅客的干扰。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国航空公司周四因 IT 故障不得不取消 175 个航班后出现了问题&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，多佛港排起了长队，也遇到了 IT 问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多佛港在 Twitter 上发帖称：“感谢您的耐心等待，因为我们赶上了较早前边境管制的 IT 问题已经解决。现在通过边界的交通处理得很好。现在，汽车和长途汽车的平均等待时间为 90 分钟。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;RAC 估计，周五至周一期间，英国各地的司机将进行 1920 万次休闲汽车出行，使其成为自 2019 年以来最繁忙的 5 月下旬银行假期。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运输数据公司 Inrix 警告说，在 M25 的某些路段上行驶的时间将比平时长三倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它们包括从 Hatfield 的 23 号交叉口顺时针到 Chelmsford 的 28 号交叉口，并逆时针方向朝向达特福德十字路口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;萨默塞特郡的 M5 以及柴郡和大曼彻斯特的 M6 预计也将出现长时间延误。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获得更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Cantopop singer and opposition supporter Anthony Wong says venue booking for August concert cancelled without reason]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3222041/hong-kong-cantopop-singer-and-opposition-supporter-anthony-wong-says-venue-booking-august-concert?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 18:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/688a2171-6048-4127-9d48-7a01d83814b7_e1d38322.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港会议展览中心已撤回歌手和反对派支持者黄秋生的许可根据表演者的说法，耀明将在 8 月举办一场音乐会，但没有给出任何理由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong 周五在他的 Instagram 帐户上发布了一封来自该设施的信，称该设施“无法继续进行” ” 以及承办歌手演唱会的合同义务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这封信还附有 Wong 的制作公司支付的 463,000 港元（59 美元，097 美元）押金的退款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我觉得[会展中心]的管理层欠香港市民一个交代。一个热爱这座城市的市民，怎么会被剥夺为香港人表演的权利呢？”王在 Instagram 上写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据这位歌手说，他在该场地租用音乐厅的申请已于 1 月获得批准。此前，他在 2021 年 12 月作为粤语双人组合达明对的成员在香港举行的最后一场演出后，他尝试预订场地的尝试均未成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我想向购买机票的朋友道歉演唱会。我们还在考虑下一步，请给我们一些时间，[我们]深呼吸，重新唱歌。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8月的节目是歌手全球个人巡演的一部分，踢了1 月在台北停演，随后本月在曼彻斯特、伦敦、阿姆斯特丹和柏林演出。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港图书馆应“公开被审查的书籍，确保作者可以上诉”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作为回应在邮报的询问中，场地管理方表示不会对个别活动发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文体旅游局表示没有参与该决定，并拒绝发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;《邮报》已联系与政府共同拥有该场馆的香港贸易发展局征求意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;60 岁的达明派主唱 Wong 升至在 1980 年代成名，是该市为数不多的在 2019 年反政府抗议活动中公开支持反对派人士的艺术家之一。他还是性少数群体权利的积极分子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2014 年大规模的公民抗命运动“占中”期间，黄之锋在抗议地点表演以表达他对这项事业的支持。据报道，他随后被禁止进入中国大陆，他的音乐也被从流媒体网站上撤下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他继续表达对反对派人士的支持，并参加了 2019 年的几次抗议活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021 年 8 月，他被廉政公署逮捕，并被控在 2018 年立法会补选期间，通过在竞选活动中的现场表演，诱使他人投票给前立法会议员区诺轩。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;指控随后被撤销，黄之锋被判 18 个月缓刑，并被罚款 2,000 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位粤语流行歌手并不是香港唯一一位被当地音乐会场地拒绝的活跃政治艺术家.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港维权人士涉嫌违反保释条件被捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;歌手何韵诗曾在2014年和2019年的社会运动中积极支持抗议者，被迫取消她的身份2021 年在香港艺术中心举行的音乐会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在 9 月 6 日首场演出前几天预订了位于湾仔的寿臣剧院，当时该中心表示何违反了第 22 条(c) 其租用协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该条款，如果“在表演过程中会危及公共秩序或公共安全”，管理层可以取消已确认的预订和租用场地，恕不另行通知.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;场地既没有解释公共安全问题是什么，也没有具体说明何未达到的规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;何的团队曾向中心寻求进一步的解释，但只被告知管理层“有义务密切关注社会和相关法律的最新发展”。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How to get laughs in Hong Kong: veteran comedian Steven Lee talks about living with disability, building audiences and dealing with ‘internet mobs who hurt free speech’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3222043/how-get-laughs-hong-kong-veteran-comedian-steven-lee-talks-about-living-disability-building?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 19:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/7309fcf3-d9b9-4216-904e-a885f28b2a55_591bb5b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;表演者 Steven Lee 从拐杖上松开一只手抓住麦克风，打开了他周四晚上在香港一家喜剧酒吧的演出中讲了一个笑话，为涉及个人斗争以及社会和种族问题的例行公事定下了基调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我没有残疾，只是我的手臂是中国制造的，”这位 46 岁的年轻人告诉人群，人群大笑起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位会说三种语言的喜剧演员在香港表演了 10 年后，正在为自己树立名声好莱坞，直到 2020 年冠状病毒大流行期间才重返这座城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;史迪仔中的 B*****：香港的女性漫画响亮、自豪且有趣&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;李是那些希望喜剧在香港变得更受欢迎的人，尤其是在大流行结束后社交距离规则被取消的情况下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港的喜剧圈真的很小。在大城市，通常可以找到七八个全日制 [喜剧] 俱乐部，但香港只有一个，”李在本周早些时候告诉邮报，指的是该市的 TakeOut Comedy Club。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;该表演者表示，未开发的喜剧场景可能是由于表演者在主要电视网络上的播出时间很少、香港人快节奏的生活方式和众所周知的长时间工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在纽约，有业余爱好者来不时出去打麦克风。这是一个传统。但与亚洲，尤其是香港相比，中国人以加班而闻名，而且大多没有 [额外] 报酬，所以业余爱好者的数量​​要少得多，”他解释道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他的日常工作中，Lee谈到在香港长大，他是在父母从中国大陆非法越境进入香港后出生的。他还向观众讲述了自己被诊断出患有发育不全的情况，这种疾病通常始于子宫并影响四肢肌肉的发育。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么香港的单口喜剧界不是闹着玩的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; As a boy, Lee attended Hong Kong Red Cross John F. Kennedy Centre, a special education school in Sandy Bay, before his mother encouraged him at 17 years old to apply for an exchange programme to the United States, run by international NGO AFS Intercultural Exchange.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1993, the comedian was one of few Hongkongers and only one of two applicants with a disability to be selected for the programme that year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As part of the exchange, Lee spent 10 months living with a family in Kansas and attending school there. While introducing himself during art class, he said he had a life-changing experience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I said I came from a school for the disabled, and my teacher asked me why I defined myself like this. I realised then that I was in a place where people think about me differently and that my disability did not need to define me,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than a decade after his first visit, Lee successfully applied for permanent residency in the United States and headed back in 2009. To keep himself busy, he took up performing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I actually started doing comedy as a way to get out of the house when I was in America,” Lee said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Honing his routine by attending classes and performing across Los Angeles, Lee&#39;s career picked up when he was asked to bring his act to The Comedy Store, a venue on Sunset Boulevard that has hosted some of America&#39;s comedy greats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After his father died in 2019 and his Hollywood gigs were all cancelled during the pandemic, Lee decided to return to Hong Kong, where he now cares for his mother, who has dementia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked if he felt comedians needed to choose their words carefully while doing gigs in the city, he said veteran performers had always done so in both the US and China to ensure they could be booked at professional clubs or events.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier in May, a Chinese entertainment group was fined 1.3 million yuan (US$184,000) after one of their performers made a joke that likened the People&#39;s Liberation Army to dogs chasing a squirrel, casting a shadow over the country&#39;s comedy scene.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities also banned artists with Shanghai Xiaoguo Culture Media from performing in Beijing, while Li Haoshi, the comedian who told the joke, is being investigated by police.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Race traitors&#39;: are Chinese diaspora comics &#39;discrediting the motherland&#39;?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;However, Lee said he was more concerned by the worldwide phenomenon of the “internet mob”, with comedians getting “trashed online” by social media users posting controversial clips of performances from a long time ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There&#39;s no fair trial where you can defend yourself. You don&#39;t know who they are but they know who you are. That&#39;s hurting freedom of speech way more,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee also said it would be good for the local comedy scene if Hong Kong continued to hold off from having an official censorship body.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Agreeing with Lee, an award-winning Hong Kong comedian Vivek Mahbubani said: “I think giving people rules of what they can and cannot say will definitely affect the comedy scene. It is going to instil self-censorship and people might be afraid to try in case they get in trouble.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While stand-up comedy had never taken root in Hong Kong culture before, Mahbubani said, he could sense a change was under way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We never grew up watching it on television like people in the West. But there&#39;s a big appetite for it right now. On Netflix and YouTube, there are a lot more Asian people doing stand-up comedy, it will not be long before comedy here is on a par [with the West],” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fellow comic Nina McGrath, who followed Lee&#39;s most recent set at The Upper House, a restaurant and bar in Admiralty, said she also felt comedy was gaining traction locally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Both the English and Cantonese comedy scenes are thriving,” she said. “There are more comedy events and more people wanting to perform.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Christians caught with Bible in North Korea face death, prison – including children]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222040/christians-caught-bible-north-korea-face-death-prison-including-children?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 18:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/27/c440c9df-96e3-452b-8716-ece016f5b71f_131a21c5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;North Korea is notorious for the cruelty it inflicts on people deemed undesirable by the state. In the Hermit Kingdom that prizes weaponry over its own people, many of whom are starving and live in abject poverty, tens of thousands of Christians are said to be languishing in prisons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A recently released Department of State report notes that while North Korea constitutionally allows for religious freedom, there is no such thing in practice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The constitution vaguely states that religion must not harm the state or social order, giving authorities room to target those who seek to openly follow their faith.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report from the State Department&#39;s Office of International Religious Freedom, citing research conducted by non-governmental organisations which have gathered testimony from defectors, says as many as 70,000 Christians have been imprisoned in camps along with those believers from other religions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UN says &#39;reasonable grounds&#39; to believe crimes against humanity in N Korea&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;One NGO, Open Doors USA, has reported that for Christians in North Korea, life is a “constant cauldron of pressure” and “capture or death is only a mistake away”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As State highlights in its report, North Korean government documents state that “freedom of religion is allowed and provided by the State law within the limit necessary for securing social order, health, social security, morality and other human rights.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anything beyond that can land citizens in deep trouble.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People who have been arrested for religious crimes have reportedly faced detention and forced labour, torture, sexual violence, and death.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Christians are considered a “hostile class” in the songbun system, in which people derive status from loyalty to the state and its leadership. Christians, ODUSA reported, are regarded as the lowest in society and are constantly “vulnerable and in danger.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Department of State, pulling from information collected by NGOs, noted that an entire family, including their two-year-old child, was imprisoned following the discovery of their religious practices and possession of a Bible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family, which was most likely targeted by the Ministry of State Security that handles roughly 90 per cent of these cases, was sentenced to life in prison.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A report from the NGO Korea Future documented a shocking incident in which a man caught praying was nearly beaten to death by guards. Another incident involved a Korean Worker&#39;s Party member who was found with a Bible, taken by authorities out to an airfield, and executed before a crowd of thousands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;North Korea celebrates the Kim family, specifically the current ruler, Kim Jong-un, and his late father and grandfather, Kim Jong-il and Kim Il-sung, above all, recognising the Kim dynasty or Mount Paektu bloodline in ways reminiscent of deification.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The State Department report, pointing to Korea Future&#39;s research, says that the state ideology “Kimilsungism-Kimjongilism” has “many hallmarks of religion”. It notes the state regards the two previous leaders as “extraordinary beings”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ODUSA has reported that Christian materials, including Bibles, are leftovers from the early 20th century up to World War II and are passed among believers. Though there have been reports of underground churches, it is unclear if these are active given that, as one defector said, “meeting other Christians to worship is almost impossible.” Some even fear being reported by their own family members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This situation has long been a problem in North Korea, and State noted that “multiple sources indicated the situation had not fundamentally changed since” the 2014 UN Commission of Inquiry report on human rights in the in North Korea was published. That report found that North Korea “denied the rights to freedom of thought, conscience, and religion” and engaged in “crimes against humanity.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Woman in China rejects multiple wedding invites from old school friend suspecting he wants ‘cash gift’, trends online]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3221522/woman-china-rejects-multiple-wedding-invites-old-school-friend-suspecting-he-wants-cash-gift-trends?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.27 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/25/5efef1f2-f36a-41bc-8d4c-cda1651b27a8_53a898cc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A woman in China who believed a request from a long-lost school friend to join his wedding was to obtain a cash gift has gone viral on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman, Cui, shared on social media that an old friend from primary school tried to add her on WeChat several times, but she suspected he was seeking money as a wedding gift, local media reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She did not reveal where she was from or where the two went to school together.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eventually, the PhD student accepted the request from the schoolmate, who was not identified in the reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, she did not chat with him initially on the app as they had not been in touch for many years. The schoolmate then sent her an invitation to his wedding.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cui immediately believed he intended to solicit cash, as another old friend had recently done the same thing, and after she sent cash as a wedding gift, that friend disappeared from her social media circle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She ignored the invitation, but the old friend continued asking whether Cui would be free to join his wedding the following month, and he highlighted that the rest of their schoolmates had promised to participate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cui remained unconvinced and said that she would not be free until August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s a pity,” he said in a message to Cui.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I won&#39;t join. Thanks for the invitation, and congratulations on your happy wedding,” Cui replied.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After their conversation ended, Cui shared her annoyance online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s ridiculous. Why doesn&#39;t he launch a crowdfunding campaign for his wedding?” Cui said in her post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story has caused debate on mainland social media, with some people applauding Cui for refusing. Still, others felt the schoolmate wanted to invite her without ulterior motives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “I would not delete him on WeChat, but I would not reply to his message.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person, who said she had invited her schoolmates to her wedding, commented: “He may think that his wedding can help reunite schoolmates. Cash gifts are not necessary.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stories about amusing and ridiculous wedding events regularly appear online in mainland China. Earlier this month, a newlywed couple in central China started a new trend after they turned an electric public bus into their “wedding car”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February this year, a groom was at the centre of a trending story in China after a number of his ex-girlfriends showed up at his wedding to protest his treatment of women and threatened to “destroy” him.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 27 May 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>