<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Is China’s economic course correction too late, or is it too early to tell without the specifics being ironed out?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3228886/chinas-economic-course-correction-too-late-or-it-too-early-tell-without-specifics-being-ironed-out?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/25/89bd19e3-323e-411e-b623-ba37e7a491fd_d0343c51.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国对“波浪型”“锯齿型”经济表现的认识和决心完善房地产、债务减免和资本市场政策引发了人们的希望，即未来几个月将推出更积极的政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然大多数经济学家排除了所谓的火箭筒式刺激措施，但周一的政治局声明也提出了有关政策制定者将采取哪些措施来支撑疫情后的经济复苏的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国共产党最高决策机构发布的声明，政策制定者承认宏观环境更具挑战性，并承诺“加强逆周期支持”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一修正评估——尽管没有详细阐述具体的宽松措施——是在第二季度经济数据令人失望的情况下做出的，这引发了人们对中国经济增长失去动力的担忧&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦格理集团(Macquarie Group)首席中国经济学家胡拉里(Larry Hu)表示，这是自2019年以来首次在政治局会议上提到“逆周期”，这意味着宽松偏见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“亮点是与房地产和地方政府债务相关的政策基调转向促增长。短期政策立场也变得更加积极主动。”胡锦涛说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;24名政治局委员五年来首次删除了“房子是用来住的、不是用来炒的”这句话。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而是谈到“及时调整和优化房地产政策”，因为房地产业已成为中国经济的最大拖累。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国将加快基础设施建设胡补充道，“将推出更多房地产宽松政策，以支持开发商融资和住房需求”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于中国现金短缺的国家来说，经济学家表示，会议提出，当务之急不再是去杠杆，而是防止信心危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这进一步支持了我们的观点，即北京可能会增加对地方政府的转移支付，这似乎是截至 6 月，中国正在努力管理 86 万亿元人民币（12 万亿美元）的巨额债务余额，特别是考虑到土地出让收入大幅下降，”野村证券首席中国经济学家陆挺表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内需不足大中华区经济学家辛艾琳表示，声明称，经济增长被认为是主要挑战之一，同时也表明财政政策将带头刺激消费，而已经非常宽松的货币政策将采取宽松的政策。辛说：“重点仍然是扩大内需，主要是通过有针对性的消费政策、对私营部门的支持和基础设施支持。”而不是广泛的现金正如许多发达经济体在 Covid-19 大流行期间所看到的那样，为了刺激消费，政治局此前宣布了针对汽车、电子产品和家居相关商品以及体育、休闲活动和旅游服务的零碎、有针对性的政策。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;周一的会议誓言要通过增加居民收入来扩大消费，并首次提出“要把稳就业提高到战略高度”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丁爽，中国首席经济学家，中国经济研究院大中华区经济学家渣打银行表示，今年早些时候设定的全国城镇调查失业率5.5%左右的目标已成为北京的新底线。 6月份这一数字保持在5.2%不变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果整体失业率开始上升，而不仅仅是青年失业率，那么可能会出台更大的刺激措施。 “现在仍然是相对克制的刺激。”6月份16-24岁年龄段失业率创历史新高21.3%后，丁表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议还承诺支持私营企业和企业。增强商业信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但经济学家表示，这些信号不太可能起到推动作用，因为中国的私营部门仍然受到监管打压的影响，这些监管打压对包括科技、房地产和私人辅导在内的行业造成了灾难性影响。麦格理的胡补充道：“政策制定者如果想重燃私营企业家的动物精神，就必须更加大胆和更具创造力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朱利安·埃文斯-普里查德 (Julian Evans-Pritchard)，凯投宏观中国经济主管表示，尽管政治局会议采取了鸽派基调，并明确表示领导层认为需要采取更多措施让经济复苏重回正轨，但会议并未发布任何重大新公告。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“政治局会议确定了政策的总体方向，并将具体细节留待其他地方解决。因此，也许这些承诺将在未来几个月内带来有意义的政策变化。但在现阶段，现在判断影响会是什么还为时过早，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“缺乏任何重大公告或政策细节确实表明缺乏紧迫性，或者政策制定者正在考虑采取行动。”努力想出适当的措施来支撑增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论怎样，短期前景都不是特别令人放心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href= “https://feedx.best” style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As US urges China to rein in North Korea, Beijing’s reluctance to act could backfire, analysts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228895/us-urges-china-rein-north-korea-beijings-reluctance-act-could-backfire-analysts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/25/965215f7-6c9c-40f3-b060-0cf8f8f20577_37533119.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯敦促中国帮助遏制朝鲜核计划分析人士警告说，缺乏遏制平壤的行动最终可能会损害北京的安全利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯周五表示，中国对朝鲜拥有“独特的影响力”，华盛顿希望北京利用其影响力以获得平壤的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在科罗拉多州阿斯彭安全论坛的炉边谈话中，布林肯强调，北京不采取行动将促使美国加强与韩国和日本的防务联盟，并“采取行动”并非针对中国，但中国可能不会喜欢的步骤”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“朝鲜所做的一切以及中国无法帮助我们采取行动，我们将继续将事情转移到朝鲜”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;如果中国干预朝鲜失败，美国将采取行动：布林肯&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国已向朝鲜半岛派遣了越来越多的战略资产继美国总统乔·拜登和韩国总统尹锡烈于四月份宣布《华盛顿宣言》之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该宣言成立了核协商小组，这是首尔和华盛顿之间的核与战略规划机构，这增强了美国在朝鲜半岛周边战略资产的可见性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首尔梨花女子大学朝鲜研究教授朴元坤表示，布林肯的声明表明北京不愿干预平壤核计划发展促使华盛顿推行“综合威慑”——增加其在亚太地区的军事存在，并加强与首尔和东京的防务关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于中国来说，它将感受到压力......朴槿惠表示，朝鲜在亚太地区是加强综合威慑的动力和理由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但这对中国来说很不方便。美国认为综合威慑的核心目标是中国，并试图遏制中国。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国正在迅速与朝鲜、俄罗斯、伊朗等国家‘结盟’……同时开始将[朝鲜]半岛无核化视为中国半岛政策的主要组成部分，”北京人民大学国际关系教授时殷弘表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中美之间的面对面交流自平壤在 Covid-19 大流行开始时关闭边界以来，朝鲜首次显示出恢复的迹象。中国新任驻朝鲜大使在空缺两年后于 3 月抵达平壤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜领导人金正恩也是向中国国家主席习近平致贺电的少数领导人之一。 6月是70岁生日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和朝鲜周一还宣布，由中共24名决策机构政治局委员李鸿忠率领的中国代表团将访问该国周四参加庆祝朝鲜战争停战协定 70 周年的庆祝活动，平壤称之为“伟大的祖国解放战争的胜利”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李将是最高级别的人物之一自平壤于2020年关闭边境以来，中国官员陆续入境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部发言人毛宁表示，此次邀请表明双方“高度重视巩固和发展中朝关系”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;毛泽东补充说，这次访问将有利于促进地区和平与稳定，为“政治解决半岛问题”创造条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国研究教授姜俊英韩国外国语大学教授表示，华盛顿正在向北京施压，要求其在朝鲜这个隐士王国的核进展变得“无法控制”之前采取实质性措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国最担心和讨厌的是朝鲜引进朝鲜核技术。”美国在朝鲜半岛的战略资产。但对美国来说，发送这些武器的原因是朝鲜的核发展，”康说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，华盛顿发出了双重信息：如果北京发挥适当作用，阻止朝鲜的扩张朝鲜核问题，其安全威胁也将减少。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国专家小组获悉，逃往中国的朝鲜人可能会被送回严酷的命运&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;上周，肯塔基号航空母舰抵达韩国釜山海军基地，成为自1981年以来第一艘停靠在韩国东南部港口城市的美国弹道导弹潜艇。安纳波利斯号核动力潜艇也于周一抵达济州岛海军基地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;康表示，美国已开始对中国提出更强硬的要求，并警告说，如果北京不试图遏制平壤的核计划，局势可能会失控，导致朝鲜逃离中国的势力范围。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;“如果朝鲜成功发展核武器，可能会推动要求日本和韩国拥有核武器的声音，”康说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国处于两难境地。”如果中国放任朝鲜不管，朝鲜将进一步推进其核计划和导弹计划，而平壤也不会听北京的话。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Baby’s face is red and swollen’: Chinese man self-films slapping attack on infant son, sends video to estranged mother in sick bid to get her back]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3228500/babys-face-red-and-swollen-chinese-man-self-films-slapping-attack-infant-son-sends-video-estranged?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/24/6fd29dcb-a61c-45a6-a840-b5188251b941_aebc11b6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;大陆社交媒体上因一名男子拍摄视频而引发愤怒浪潮他自己打了他的小儿子几十个耳光，然后将这段令人作呕的视频发送给他分居的女朋友，也就是孩子的母亲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国南部广东省湛江市政府的一份声明，该男子姓氏。据吉木新闻报道，本月早些时候，邓与陈姓女友发生争吵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 7 月 4 日拍摄的一段令人痛心的自拍照视频中，可以看到邓在婴儿儿子的脸上打耳光。半分钟30次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着男婴的哭声，残酷的父亲继续打他，直到他的脸红肿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频显示，邓某当局在声明中称，陈某离开后不得不独自照顾这对夫妇的儿子，显然对此感到不安，然后将视频发送给她，希望她能被迫返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名婴儿遭受了痛苦报道称，邓某因受到虐待，身体并未受到长期伤害，目前正在当地政府处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邓某已被警方拘留，案件仍在调查中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地的一个半政府组织妇女儿童联合会告诉集目新闻，他们也在调查这起事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;河南泽金律师事务所律师傅健，向该报表示，邓的行为已构成虐待罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这段令人震惊的视频在大陆社交媒体上热传，并引来众多愤怒的评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为一个母亲，看到这个视频我哭了。我为宝宝感到心痛。这种人应该受到严厉的惩罚。这不应该是一个人做的事情。”一位人士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当局应该取消他作为父亲的权利，否则孩子将来会受到更多虐待。”另一位在线观察者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“男孩的母亲也必须承担一些责任。她不应该把孩子留给他的父亲，而忽视他的生活。”第三位人士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;暴力虐待儿童的故事经常在大陆社交媒体上流行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在本月初，西北甘肃省一名妇女因虐待七岁继女，强迫她吃生辣椒、将她的手放入开水中、殴打她、用棍子打她的私处而被拘留。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月，中国东部江西省的一家法院将一名10岁男孩的父母关进监狱，他们将孩子殴打并饿死。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[An unfair system? How threat of readmission to psychiatric care leaves Hong Kong mental health patients living in angst]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3228858/unfair-system-how-threat-readmission-psychiatric-care-leaves-hong-kong-mental-health-patients-living?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/25/ce7b639e-7964-4d2a-9248-9a8743156541_a64c6b41.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港会计师夏志伟在焦虑中生活了10年，担心一旦与人发生争执，就会被送进精神病院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;20世纪90年代，他被诊断出患有精神分裂症和妄想症，在一家香港医院的精神病房里住了两个月。 2010年，在中国大陆的一次事件中遭到殴打后，他被送往香港公立医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出院后，他收到了一份条件清单，包括必须每月去看精神科医生并服用强制药物。如果他违反了任何条款，他就面临着重新入院的危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管他是一名模范病情轻微的患者，从未违反过条件，也没有复发，但有条件出院的状态却在他身上挥之不去长达十年之久。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了每个月要去看精神科医生五分钟外，他的人身自由受到限制，也影响了他的心理健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有一次，一个年轻人在路上撞到了我。现年 58 岁的哈回忆道，“他什么也没说就走了。知道自己是有条件出院，我只能咽下当时的感受。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有一次，一名男子不小心踩到了哈的脚，却斥责了他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我什么也没做，”他说。 “如果他诉诸暴力，而人们因为我患有精神疾病而指责我怎么办？医生可能会说我旧病复发。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港考虑对社区精神病病例制定新规则&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港约有 1,300 名精神疾病患者生活在同样的条件下出院状况悬而未决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据《精神健康条例》，被拘留并有“犯罪暴力病史或实施此类暴力倾向”的患者，在以下情况下可能会受到特定条件的约束：出院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们可能需要居住在特定地点、前往医院或诊所求诊、服用处方药物并接受社会福利署署长的监督。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;如果他们不遵守条件，或者医院认为“为了患者的健康或安全，或者为了保护其他人而有必要”，他们将面临重新入院的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当精神状态不佳时，他们将面临重新入院的风险。卫生专家认为该机制有用，社会工作者和法律学者则表示这是一个有缺陷的系统，患者可能会受到虐待。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“容易被困，很难逃脱”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; 6月初，政府精神卫生咨询委员会提出了10项改善本市公共精神卫生服务的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括审查有条件出院制度和探索为患者引入社区治疗令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;委员会预计将于本周召开会议，了解医院管理局的最新情况，医院管理局已对有条件出院机制进行了审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家希望此次审查能为患者制定更明确的门槛有条件释放，并注明时间限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;六月，两名妇女在钻石山一家购物中心发生疯狂刺伤事件后，委员会采取了行动。嫌疑人为一名39岁男子，据报是一名精神分裂症患者，在公立门诊接受治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，患者可要求精神健康复核审裁处复核其有条件出院状况。 ，但不能在最后一次请求后 12 个月内提出上诉。如果主治医生认为适当并得到医院负责人的批准，也可以取消其地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;负责监管香港公共卫生机构的医院管理局表示，没有相关数字的统计数据上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多患者不知道他们有上诉的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ha说，他与医生和社会工作者进行了四年的定期随访，才得知&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2015 年之前，我感觉自己在黑暗的房间里尖叫，没有人听到我的声音，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在 2015 年至 2019 年间上诉了四次要求撤销他的有条件释放，但没有成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在2019年的裁决中，仲裁庭成员李永明博士支持撤销哈的条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;商场袭击事件引发对香港的呼吁彻底改革精神卫生服务&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她指着他​​的病历，其中提到他第一次入院前“在精神影响下与三个陌生人打架了三遍”，但没有提供任何细节或证据。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈坚称这些打斗从未发生过，警方也没有记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭报告援引李的说法：“没有确凿的证据证明他袭击了他人，而且根据“排除合理怀疑证明有罪之前假定无罪”的公平原则，将他归类为有暴力史并不合理。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港将在男子患“精神分裂症”后检讨精神健康服务” 杀死 2&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;注意到没有迹象表明 Ha 会对自己或他人造成直接或严重的伤害，她说保留这些条件将“损害他的精神健康”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但其他法庭成员表示反对，Ha的上诉被驳回，称如果他的身份被撤销，他可能会跳过治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后，在2020年，医院打电话告诉他他有条件出院的情况被解除了，但没有给他进一步的解释。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对他来说是一个转折点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我只是希望正常地生活。我希望我能找到一个值得爱的人。”他说。 “我也把帮助有条件出院的病人社区作为我一生的使命。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“一直感到压力和焦虑”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;社会工作者周祥顺支持精神疾病患者的协和互助俱乐部联盟表示，一些人告诉他，他们没有清楚地了解有条件出院的含义，也没有被告知可以上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“护士会告诉他们，如果他们签署一些文件，他们就可以出院，但他们不知道有条件出院会对他们的生活产生如此巨大的影响。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周说医生可以强制有条件出院。仅仅在被告知患者有自杀或暴力倾向且没有证据的情况下才下令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于严格的规则和重新入院的威胁笼罩着他们，患者生活在忧虑之中，并对他们告诉自己的事情保持警惕。 ”香港大学（HKU）法学助理教授张天幕（Daisy Cheung Tin-muk）同意实施该命令的理由尚不清楚，她说：“只要病历中有人提到患者参与过暴力事件，包括匿名账户，就足以下达命令。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;精神卫生法专家兼副手香港大学医学伦理与法律中心主任张表示，这种机制未能保障患者的权利，因为容易受制于它，但难以摆脱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，在其他国家，措施与有条件释放类似，通常都会有一个期限，要延长命令，就必须提供证据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在施加命令时，也应该考虑社会工作者的意见，而不是仅仅由社会工作者来决定。她补充说，法庭也没有义务不时审查患者的案件，而且现行法律没有赋予医生取消命令的明确权利。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;“约16%的香港年轻人可能存在心理健康问题”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她还表示，海外研究表明有条件出院对于防止再次入院的效果较低。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;在决定是否保留该机制时，她表示政府应考虑如何提高其有效性，包括明确患者有条件出院的具体标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于是否保留该机制政府应该将有条件出院制度扩大到那些自愿去医院的人，她说她担心这会阻止人们寻求医疗帮助，因为他们可能害怕恶劣的条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;精神科护士艾米陈*说，她跟踪了 30 多名从严重精神疾病中康复的患者，其中大多数已获得有条件出院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在她担任个案经理的四年里，她没有遇到过任何一位患者有条件出院。成功解除有条件出院。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方在患者担心遭到殴打后展开调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她说，考虑到患者的背景，没有多少医生愿意这样做冒着取消限制的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她也对永久保留这些限制提出质疑，问道：“有人一生都要承受这种限制公平吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;一个必要的工具，但可以改进&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港大学心理健康教授谢树基为捍卫现行政权表示，有条件释放是一个“必要的工具”，特别是对于患有严重精神疾病的人来说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为心理健康咨询委员会的成员，他表示该机制“稳健”，但还可以改进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，有一个值得研究的领域， &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港当局将研究修复精神科护理漏洞&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“如果病人不必留院并可以接受治疗，在另一个环境中接受治疗，在那个环境中是否有足够的支持？”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有些人可能会因入住中途宿舍而受益，但他表示，香港没有足够的地方让精神病康复者重新融入社会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据社会福利署部门数据显示，2021-22年度中途宿舍共有1,594个名额，平均轮候时间为4.2个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢表示，市政府需要加强对康复患者的支持，并希望辅导员能够纳入公营机构及非政府机构的标准人手编制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示康复不只是吃药或打针，辅导可以帮助病人重建信心和能力，重获新生，学习如何生活。与他人和睦相处。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港精神科护理方面的差距能否通过对患者加强控制来弥补？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这不仅关系到朋友之间的关系，还关系到家人和配偶之间的关系，”他说。 “专业咨询可以就与日常生活密切相关的事务提供建议。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学法律系首席讲师Patricia Ann Ho，专门研究公民利益和公共政策的司法审查，她也认为，有条件出院可能对患者和公众有利，但认为目前的情况存在“程序上的不公正”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她表示，对患者权利的保护有限，政府在审查该机制时，应确保社工或律师能代表病人出庭，协助与医院商讨最佳安排。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果单纯依靠医生和护士，就会出现利益失衡，他们可能会寻求帮助。” ”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“假出院在很大程度上影响患者的人身自由，更需要平衡利益。由于他们可能变得非常脆弱，因此需要适当的代表。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;精神科医生曾繁光同意有条件出院制度是必要的，但表示对这群病人的人手和支持不足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“例如，对于那些风险较高的人，可以每两周安排一次探视，而不是每两个月一次，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，如果政府决定扩大探视范围， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他认为，心理健康相关措施的资源或变化“就像牙膏一样被一点一点地挤出来”。每当精神疾病患者与暴力事件有关时，政府都会发出这样的声音。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，香港需要的是一个经过深思熟虑的精神健康政策路线图。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;* 应受访者要求更改姓名。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Top US Republican Kevin McCarthy ponders Joe Biden impeachment probe]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228925/top-us-republican-kevin-mccarthy-ponders-joe-biden-impeachment-probe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 07:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/6bc41ab9-cff8-40fa-91d0-e8357a1ecb20_7186fc9e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国会共和党领袖周二表示，他可能会发起弹劾调查如果政府未能提供调查总统及其家人的委员会寻求的信息，就会向民主党总统乔·拜登进行调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共和党控制的众议院的三个委员会正在调查拜登未经证实的财务不当行为指控，他的儿子亨特·拜登和其他家庭成员，白宫将其斥为“疯狂的阴谋论”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在发生的事情是司法委员会正在继续调查，”众议院议长凯文·麦卡锡告诉记者。 “如果政府部门……拒绝让我们获得我们所要求的信息，就会引发弹劾调查。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫发言人卡琳·让-皮埃尔 (Karine Jean-Pierre) 周二否认了这种可能性弹劾调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他关注的是美国家庭，但他们也想关注他的家庭。他们可以做任何他们想做的事，但我们将保持专注，”让-皮埃尔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡锡的共和党核心小组成员在赢得选举后不久就开始提出弹劾拜登的想法。在 11 月的选举中以微弱优势获胜，一些人呼吁投票“消除”对共和党前总统唐纳德·特朗普的两项弹劾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡锡在亨特·拜登预计将认罪的前一天对记者发表了讲话。轻罪指控故意不缴纳所得税，也不签订一项可以避免对枪支相关指控定罪的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在其他指控中，共和党人声称司法部进行了干预以限制亨特·拜登调查，尽管特朗普在该案中任命的检察官表示他没有受到限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着亨特·拜登达成认罪协议，看看他麻烦不断的过去&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;涉及众议院的调查自 6 月份特朗普联邦大陪审团起诉以来，监督、司法和筹款委员会加强了监督。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院共和党人指责拜登将司法部“武器化”，以应对不当行为的指控，为特朗普辩护。 2024 年共和党白宫候选人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，众议院监督委员会听取了两名国税局举报人的证词，他们表示司法部在亨特·拜登的调查上拖延，首席调查员、美国检察官大卫·韦斯 (David Weiss) 被剥夺了特别检察官的授权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韦斯预计将于今年晚些时候在国会作证，他在给共和党参议员林赛·格雷厄姆 (Lindsey Graham) 的一封信中否认司法部的干预，并表示他从未寻求特别检察官地位。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共和党对拜登及其家人的一些指控涉及乌克兰能源公司 Burisma，该公司在特朗普 2019 年首次弹劾中发挥了关键作用，因为特朗普涉嫌向乌克兰施压，要求其调查拜登家族并帮助他获胜连任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共和党占多数的参议院后来宣判特朗普无罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡锡引用了联邦调查局的一份报告，其中包含一位身份不明的线人的说法，该线人称布里斯马官员试图向拜登父子支付 500 万美元2015 年和 2016 年，他们帮助驱逐了一名调查该能源公司的乌克兰检察官。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;共和党人试图以史无前例的举动消除特朗普的弹劾&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对拜登不当行为的指控in Ukraine have been contradicted by former Trump insider Lev Parnas, who helped former New York mayor and one-time Trump lawyer Rudy Giuliani try to dig up damaging information about the Bidens in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no evidence of Joe or Hunter Biden interfering with Ukrainian politics, and there never has been,” Parnas said in a July 18 letter to the House Oversight Committee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parnas, a Ukrainian-American businessman, is serving out a 20 -month sentence under house arrest for defrauding investors in a sham company and making illegal donations to US political candidates on behalf of a Russian oligarch.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong tourism desperately needs a boost in the changed post-Covid landscape]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3228763/hong-kong-tourism-desperately-needs-boost-changed-post-covid-landscape?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/007fcb9f-a7c8-4a3f-8963-b982c491cdf3_6d00fa76.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Even as Hong Kong&#39;s tourist arrivals signal a slower than expected recovery, more Hongkongers are crossing over to Shenzhen to spend money than the other way around.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month, 2.75 million tourists visited Hong Kong, with mainlanders making up 2.15 million, according to preliminary Tourism Board data.半年总量近1300万，其中超过1000万来自内地。 Although arrivals have improved, mainland visitors remain lower than many had anticipated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, there have been numerous media reports of a surge in Hongkongers taking day trips to Shenzhen for food and recreation. The plodding recovery of Hong Kong tourism is being overshadowed by these northbound crossings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This lopsidedness is reflected in second-quarter data collected by Alipay: the amount of spending and the number of payment transactions by Hongkongers in the mainland have increased by more than threefold from the previous three months.其他旅行和消费数据也显示出类似的趋势。 Hong Kong people are pouring into Shenzhen and the surrounding cities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why has the lifting of Hong Kong&#39;s Covid-19 curbs not ushered in a surge in “revenge” tourism from the mainland? The question we should ask is, if Hong Kong is not even attractive enough for more of our own people to spend their leisure time in, how can it attract holidaymakers from the mainland?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People in Shenzhen used to be keen to go on a shopping spree in Hong Kong.在旅游业最繁荣的时候，深圳人甚至下班后还乘地铁去香港买酱油。 They did it because they could save money while getting better-quality goods.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Hong Kong&#39;s shopping discounts are no longer as tantalising and the city has few new and emerging tourist attractions.内地购物平台的快速发展也为中国消费者提供了更多的选择和优惠。 When so many international brands and goods are available at the click of a mouse, shopping in Hong Kong becomes less attractive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the Covid-19 epidemic, the mainland&#39;s tourism industry experienced enormous challenges, prompting tourism practitioners to work even harder and make deep adjustments to reshape their businesses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Product supply, user preferences, booking behaviour and market environment have all undergone tremendous changes. Yet most people in Hong Kong&#39;s tourism sector do not appear to have sufficiently caught up on the changes in the global tourism market and among millennial holidaymakers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most holidaymakers around the globe are becoming more eco-minded and adventurous;越来越多的旅行者正在寻找适合他们身心的活动和事物，例如艺术、文化和体育。 Therefore, boosting Hong Kong&#39;s image as a hub of art and culture and increasing the recreational activities on offer could recapture the new and younger generation of tourists, not only from the mainland but the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What can Hong Kong improve upon to attract more mainland tourists? Perhaps, we can see a possible way from a very small example.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At present, there are not many exclusive local cultural and creative products at the Hong Kong Palace Museum available for tourists for buy – most of them are from the Beijing Palace Museum and available online. This weakens mainland tourist spending at the Hong Kong Palace Museum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although this seems trivial, it reflects a need for Hong Kong&#39;s cultural and creative tourism to work harder to make sure that visitors, whether from the mainland or elsewhere, see Hong Kong as an exciting and rewarding travel destination. It is necessary to focus on the integration of culture and tourism to attract tourists to come to Hong Kong and get to know it better.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;To bring tourists back, Hong Kong must focus on the authentic and unique&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Of course, we should also be well aware that it is challenging to lure Western visitors, given the hostility and distrust displayed by some countries towards mainland China and Hong Kong. To counter this, Hong Kong must continue to work on public relations in these markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We should explore other sources of visitors such as the Middle East, Southeast Asia and South America while working to roll out more high-profile cultural and entertainment events. After all, arts, entertainment and sporting events can be an effective way to transcend geopolitical hostility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s military AI advances likely to raise risk of US conflict, could yield ‘revolutionary’ changes: report]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3228924/chinas-military-ai-advances-likely-raise-risk-us-conflict-could-yield-revolutionary-changes-report?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 06:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/26/c09be4a1-088c-440e-ba06-ddf029c62fa5_fde08dbb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s advances in military AI, though incremental and narrow for the most part, could yield revolutionary changes and are likely to increase the risk of armed conflict with the US, a report by an American think tank warned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These possibilities call for the US to get ready countering such risks as its rivalry with China is poised to intensify, according to the Washington-based Centre for a New American Security, which focuses on US national security and defence policies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the near- and midterm, most of the changes AI will usher in will be incremental and narrow. But in the mid- to long-term, some could be revolutionary and general,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China provides little transparency on its military modernisation efforts, including for AI, which could someday lead to strategic surprise for the United States if Beijing manages to make breakthroughs in secret,” the report added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both China and the US are moving quickly to integrate artificial intelligence technologies into their militaries amid bilateral tensions involving their respective strategies in the South China Sea and Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AI plays “a key role” in China&#39;s military ambitions, especially its goal of becoming a “world-class military” by midcentury, according to the report, which said Beijing was proceeding in part through “intelligentization”, a term that refers to integrating AI and other emerging technologies into its armed forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If, when improvements in military AI across every area are added together, the US-China military balance turns in Beijing&#39;s favour, then the risks of conflict could rise,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing could eventually outpace the US and its allies by developing and fielding technologies such as military AI that give it a substantial advantage, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Military experts say PLA rolling out longer-range missiles near Taiwan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;However, the report cited several obstacles China could face in its quest for military AI supremacy, including technology controls imposed by the US and its allies. These “could hamper Beijing&#39;s ability to develop and operate AI-enabled systems at scale”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In earlier stages of its military modernisation, China could imitate the United States, Russia, and other advanced militaries,” the report stated. “By contrast, intelligentization requires pioneering totally new military technologies and operational concepts for how to use them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In October last year, the Biden administration announced sweeping new limits on the sale of semiconductor technology to China meant to restrict the country&#39;s military development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report on Tuesday outlined five categories that the authors called “pathways” through which applications of military AI could undermine stability and heighten the risks of armed conflict or the threat of nuclear war between Washington and Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China says &#39;a certain country&#39; is hindering the tech development of others&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For example, it said an AI decision-making application could generate bad information leading policymakers to wrong decisions, and the application of AI for uncrewed autonomous systems might drive up the odds of deliberate, inadvertent, or accidental escalation, especially in times of crisis, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In a potential future Taiwan contingency in which high-end US-China combat is a live possibility, there is no guarantee that actions against robotic systems, especially if armed, will be met with such restraint,” it stated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response, US policymakers should take bold action to stem China&#39;s progress in AI for military purposes, and negotiate risk reduction and confidence-building measures with China related to military AI, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Assessing and managing the resulting strategic risks will require keeping a close watch on Beijing&#39;s civilian and especially military AI activities … Reducing strategic risks will ultimately require a combination of competition and selective engagement with China.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Propeller wounds on whale spark calls for Hong Kong public to stay away from mammal]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3228916/propeller-wounds-whale-spark-calls-hong-kong-public-stay-away-mammal?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/26/39e22362-ed91-42e0-8e48-1ed8d3c20722_851380a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Marine experts have appealed to Hongkongers not to go whale watching in waters off Sai Kung after a giant mammal seen earlier this month was spotted with propeller wounds on its back.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A picture taken on Saturday by a member of the public and obtained by the Ocean Park Conservation Foundation showed at least two deep cuts on the whale&#39;s back.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Amazed onlookers spot whale feeding in Hong Kong&#39;s eastern waters&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The mammal, believed to be a Bryde&#39;s whale measuring about seven metres (23 feet) in length, was first spotted off the coast of Rocky Harbour near Millionaire&#39;s Beach, or Nam Fung Wan, and the nearby waters in Sai Kung in mid-July. The sighting sparked huge interest locally, with people heading out in boats to look for it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It disappeared for days until it was seen in Port Shelter off the University of Science and Technology at the weekend, with some members of the public reporting that it opened its jaws to feed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marine biologist Taison Chang Kai-tai, chairman of the Hong Kong Dolphin Conservation Society, on Tuesday said based on the photo he was almost 100 per cent certain the wounds were caused by ship propellers, as shown by their parallel pattern.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He urged the public not to rent boats to go whale watching to avoid causing further injuries to the animal. Chang also said the whale might have lost its way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With the injuries, it will face bigger difficulties in finding its way out [to its habitat],” Chang said, adding that it was also facing more challenges in feeding.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s second whale sighting in 2 days as experts say give animals peace&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The society earlier said the whale might have got lost in its navigation and entered Hong Kong waters, which were not its usual habitat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ocean Park and the Ocean Park Conservation Foundation said a crowd was spotted approaching the whale over the weekend, which could cause it stress and lead to life-threatening consequences such as an inability to rest or feed and trauma.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They reiterated their calls for people to refrain from approaching the whale on their vessels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compass Chan, the foundation&#39;s scientific officer, said: “Whales are sensitive creatures and can be easily affected by loud noises, sudden movements and human interference.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The park and the foundation said they would continue to work with the Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation Department to assess the whale&#39;s condition and determine the best approach to help it.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US House passes bill to hold Chinese officials accountable for spread of fentanyl]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3228922/us-house-passes-bill-hold-chinese-officials-accountable-spread-fentanyl?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 05:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/26/8db2b9be-94d2-4095-ae34-d4d90ed5bb23_b41e61d3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The US House of Representatives passed a bill Tuesday to hold Chinese officials accountable for the spread of fentanyl and other synthetic opioids in the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The opioid bill, called Stop Chinese Fentanyl, redefined “foreign opioid trafficker” in a fentanyl sanctions law passed in 2019 to include Chinese entities and government officials who fail to take steps to prevent opioid trafficking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese Communist Party plays a prominent role in every step of the fentanyl crisis, from producing precursor chemicals to transferring expertise to laundering cartel profits who illegally traffic it into the United States,” said the bill&#39;s sponsor, Representative Andy Barr, a Kentucky Republican and member of the House select committee on China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tuesday&#39;s bipartisan vote came as the US and China weigh a deal on fentanyl. According to The Wall Street Journal, the White House is considering lifting sanctions on a Chinese police forensics institute to secure Beijing&#39;s cooperation on counter-narcotics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two sides had revived drug control talks ahead of Secretary of State Antony Blinken&#39;s trip to China in June, where Blinken raised synthetic opioids as a “priority”. During the visit, creating a working group for the issue was discussed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese embassy rejects US claims, says chemicals for Mexico fentanyl not from China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But since then, Beijing had hit back at US efforts to prosecute and sanction Chinese individuals and manufacturers allegedly involved in trafficking fentanyl precursors. Nor has it accepted Washington&#39;s invitation to join a US-led global coalition to address the threat of synthetic drug, which began this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China had been considered the main source of fentanyl entering the US until 2019, when Beijing imposed stricter export controls at Washington&#39;s request.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet China remains the main source for key ingredients, according to US officials, with end-stage production capacity having largely moved to countries like Mexico, from where the finished product can be smuggled into the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The House also passed a bill on Tuesday directing the US State Department to report on China&#39;s efforts to undermine Taiwan in international organisations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To become law, the bills must also pass the Senate, then be signed by US President Joe Biden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Senate is currently deliberating over the National Defence Authorisation Act, an annual must-pass Pentagon bill, which now includes more than 120 mentions of Taiwan and China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The House narrowly passed its version of the NDAA this month.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s navy includes civilian ferry in military transport drill]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3228861/chinas-navy-includes-civilian-ferry-military-transport-drill?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/d74399e6-d826-4ab9-8036-74c438dcb7aa_9d28675a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s navy deployed a civilian ferry to transport troops and trucks in a test of amphibious warfare skills seen as key to an attack on Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;State broadcaster CCTV reported on Saturday that the Chang Shan Dao ferry transported equipment and personnel between Lushun New Port to the Port of Dalian on the Bohai Sea to develop the troops&#39; ability to transport supplies at sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This ferry delivery exercise aimed to explore and test the efficiency of the combined forces&#39; long-distance supply operations, to clear barriers in the joint military-local logistics mechanism, and to optimise coordination,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report did not say when the exercise took place, but according to ship-tracking website MarineTraffic the Chang Shan Dao sailed between ports in the city of Dalian on July 19.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amphibious warfare would be central to an attack on Taiwan, the self-ruled island Beijing claims as its territory.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has never renounced using force to unite the island with mainland China. Most countries do not regard Taiwan as an independent state, but many oppose taking the island by force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The People&#39;s Liberation Army has been developing a “military-local logistics mechanism” to try to get supplies to front lines more efficiently.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chang Shan Dao can carry 1,400 people, has 2km (1.2 miles) of “driveway” for vehicles to park on and has a displacement of 23,000 tonnes, according to its state-owned operator Cosco Shipping Ferry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PLA has used civilian ferries built by state-owned enterprises to help it transport supplies in drills in the past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2011, the military used the Bohai Zhen Zhu, or “Bohai Pearl”, to move troops and equipment in a drill, the first time a civilian ship with a displacement of more than 10,000 tonnes had been deployed in such an exercise, a 73rd Group Army officer told state media at the time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vessel was operated by Bohai Ferry Group, a company directly owned by the state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PLA has also used civilian ferries to move troops, equipment and supplies across greater distances.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According MarineTraffic, the Bohai Jing Zhu ferry diverted from its usual route in the Bohai Sea in September last year, sailing from Lianyungang south of the Shandong peninsula to Nanjing, an inland port.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Bohai ferry Ji Long Dao also took part in loading military vehicles during a major live-fire drill targeting Taiwan in August 2022, according to a CCTV report. The exercise followed a visit to Taiwan by then US House speaker Nancy Pelosi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a report for the US Naval War College in January, Michael Dahm, a retired US Navy commander, said the August drills showed that the PLA had made significant progress in large-scale lift of troops and equipment into undefended ports, which could help it attack Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Twelve civilian ferries and cargo ships sailed 82 times between 11 ports in a separate five-week exercise in July-August last year, he said, basing his findings on satellite imagery and ship movements tracked by MarineTraffic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 8,500 military vehicles and 58,000 troops were transported in those drills, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Lu Li-shih, a former instructor at Taiwan&#39;s naval academy, said the PLA&#39;s use of civilian ferries was not necessarily aimed at Taiwan because Beijing also claimed many artificial islands in the South China Sea that could benefit from expanded logistics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These drills not only train PLA troops but also the civilian crew of the roll-on/roll-off ships,” he said, referring to vessels designed to carry vehicles with wheels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said roll-on/roll-off ferries would already be in position if drafted by the PLA into military action, allowing a quicker start to an operation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he said satellite images could not show how far the PLA&#39;s logistical ability had advanced with such drills. Information from state media would conceal weaknesses in the training, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Poor data quality and low auction levels are key hurdles for China’s national carbon trading market, experts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3228893/poor-data-quality-and-low-auction-levels-are-key-hurdles-chinas-national-carbon-trading-market?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/381f64e6-e2a4-472d-8993-26938c4cc63f_7017e975.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Poor quality data and supply shortages remain key barriers for China&#39;s national carbon emissions trading scheme (ETS), with the world&#39;s largest carbon market seeing lower-than-expected trading volume and weak carbon prices in the past year, according to climate experts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s carbon market – responsible for a seventh of the world&#39;s greenhouse gas emissions – is expected to see more liquidity later this year with the injection of new carbon allowances to emitters and the relaunch of China&#39;s suspended voluntary carbon market, the China Certified Emission Reduction (CCER) scheme, said experts. Nevertheless, carbon prices will remain relatively low due to government management.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The national ETS wrapped up its second year of operation on July 16 with the cumulative transaction volume of carbon emissions allowances reaching 239.9 million tonnes, and market value reaching 11.03 billion yuan, according to the Shanghai Environment and Energy Exchange, the department that oversees the national ETS.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Key challenges for the national ETS include the Covid pandemic [which] postponed release of key policies and added to more market uncertainties, opaque fundamental data, and measurement, reporting, and verification (MRV) issues,” said Tan Luyue, carbon analyst at data provider Refinitiv.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trading activities slowed down in the second year compared to the first trading year for the national ETS.从2022年7月到2023年7月14日最后一个交易日，碳配额仅转手4590万吨，对应市值为25.4亿元。 This means that over 80 per cent of total trading volume on ETS and market value come from the first trading year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China will determine its own path to carbon reduction: Xi Jinping&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Carbon prices on the national ETS closed at 60 yuan per tonne on July 14, the last trading day before the national ETS wrapped up its second year of trading, compared to 51.23 yuan per tonne on its first trading day on July 16 in 2021, and below the 65 yuan per tonne forecast from Refinitiv in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The national ETS, which currently covers 2,532 key emitters from China&#39;s power generation sector that contributed to around 4.7 billion tonnes of carbon emissions in 2022, has continued to battle low prices and sluggish trading. This has hindered its role in helping China, the world&#39;s largest carbon emitter, reach a net-zero emissions goal by 2060.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials at China&#39;s Ministry of Ecology and Environment (MEE) have highlighted the widespread problem of data fraud among power plants and consulting firms, which has helped emitters falsify emissions figures. The national ETS was expected to expand to the cement and aluminium sectors last year, but this has been delayed to this year at the earliest, due to data quality issues, according to state media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC), China&#39;s central economic planner, said in a report to the annual parliamentary gathering in Beijing in February that it will improve statistics and accounting of carbon emissions and “crack down on data fraud.” However, more stringent rules for the MRV process have slowed down the release of new carbon allowances to emitters this year, and led to a supply shortage in the primary market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The current design of the national ETS, which distributes carbon allowances to emitters without charge, and a lack of an allowance auctioning mechanism like the EU ETS, has contributed to the illiquidity and inefficiency at the national ETS, according to Tan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A healthy ETS needs auctioning from the primary market to add to market supply and help balance the needs of corporations [covered entities that must comply their trading],” said Tan, adding that she expects auctioning to be introduced before 2025, starting with auctions for 3-5 per cent of the total allowances of key emitters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Market expansion will be one of top priorities for the national ETS in 2023, and the long-awaited relaunch of the CCER scheme will also boost market liquidity, said Liu Hongming, director of carbon markets at environmental non-government organisation Environmental Defence Fund (EDF), which has been advising China on the launch of its national carbon market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a survey jointly released by EDF this month of 465 stakeholders in China&#39;s national ETS, including government officials, industry associations, key carbon emitters, reserach institutions and companies providing carbon market-related services, carbon prices are expected to reach 87 yuan per tonne in 2025, 130 yuan per tonne in 2030, and 239 yuan per tonne by mid-century.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, others see carbon prices being kept at acceptably low levels via government management of carbon allowances and emission targets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The government has stated that the national carbon market is just one of the tools for them to decarbonise the Chinese economy, so they will not use a high carbon price to incentivise investment,” said Lucas Zhang Liutong, director of Hong Kong-based consultancy WaterRock Energy Economics.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>