<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong leader John Lee expected to be banned from Apec meeting by US in move strongly condemned by Beijing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3229190/hong-kong-leader-john-lee-expected-be-banned-apec-meeting-us-move-strongly-condemned-beijing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 10:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/656db08f-feaf-4966-a590-0a01ef20c14b_04055aec.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国预计将禁止香港特首李家超入境&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》周四援引三位消息人士的话说，白宫已决定不允许李在镕出席在旧金山举行的亚太经合组织(APEC)峰会，此举遭到北京方面的强烈谴责。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据新闻报道，香港仍可派出其他代表参加峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港特区政府发言人刘鹏宇中国驻华盛顿大使馆表示：“我们对美方不邀请中国香港特首李家超出席亚太经合组织领导人非正式会议的计划表示强烈反对。这违反了APEC规则，也违背了美国做出的承诺。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，美国作为今年的东道国，有责任确保“各成员代表顺利参加会议” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“APEC 会议的组织有一套规则，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国作为今年 APEC 的东道主，已承诺履行其义务遵守APEC相关规则和程序，为APEC各成员代表参加在美国举行的活动提供便利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国国务院收回APEC对香港领导人的邀请&lt;/ h3>;&lt;p>;香港政府周五上午还呼吁美国“切实履行东道主的基本责任”，按照惯例邀请香港领导人出席峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“亚太经合组织会议不属于任何国家、任何经济体。”发言人表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“东道国有责任向成员经济体领导人发出邀请函，并为成员经济体领导人出席会议提供便利。会议……特区政府已多次公开表达上述立场。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》称，同样被禁止参加峰会的还有俄罗斯总统普京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报称，中国人预计习近平主席将出席此次会议，并补充说，他可以在国内经济逆风中恢复全球投资者的信心以及修复与华盛顿的关系方面发挥主导作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国必须“按照惯例行事” ”，邀请香港参加亚太经合组织：李&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港前全国人民代表大会常务委员会代表谴责了报道中的禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治重量级人物谭耀-chung 周五警告说，此举如果得到确认，可能会违反亚太经合组织规则，因为这不是美国会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示，北京和香港将反对这一决定，并呼吁亚太经合组织香港政府与中央当局讨论反制措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京在香港实施国家安全法后，美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普制裁了包括时任保安局局长的李光耀在内的 11 名香港政府官员。 2020 年 6 月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谭还于 2021 年受到华盛顿制裁。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China tops agenda as Italy’s Meloni meets with Biden at White House]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229193/china-tops-agenda-italys-meloni-meets-biden-white-house?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 10:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/c523e2c1-8d81-47fe-8358-c78baa4796da_f40ad07e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登周四在白宫会见了意大利总理乔治亚·梅洛尼，誓言要深化经济联系，加强合作应对中国带来的挑战，但回避了 LGBTQ 权利问题上的分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意大利第一位女总理去年 10 月上台，并在制定计划时在海外发挥了自信的作用。意大利即将在 2024 年担任七国集团 (G7) 主席国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅洛尼和她的右翼联盟在堕胎和 LGBTQ 权利问题上的立场与民主党人拜登的立场截然不同。去年的意大利选举结果是一个警告其他自由派人士世界民主国家面临危险的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，拜登对梅洛尼表示欢迎，并表示他们已经“成为朋友”。梅洛尼后来告诉记者，她对共和党有明显的偏好，但这并不会阻止她与拜登建立“良好的关系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，两位领导人讨论了意大利参与中国“一带一路”倡议（一带一路），但华盛顿的做法并不是决定意大利对华政策。她说，没有人问她有关 LGBTQ 权利的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的关系很牢固，”梅洛尼在椭圆形办公室与拜登会面时说道。 “无论其政治色彩如何，他们跨越政府并保持坚定。我们知道在困难时期谁是我们的朋友。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;意大利总理梅洛尼寻求合作，遏制移民流向欧洲&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;梅洛尼还利用她第一次访问华盛顿的机会，花了一些钱在国会山，她的会见包括访问共和党众议院议长凯文·麦卡锡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗马和华盛顿都强调这次访问是重申两国之间牢固伙伴关系的一个机会，包括超过数十亿美元的合作伙伴关系自2022年以来，西方在乌克兰与俄罗斯的激烈战争中向乌克兰提供了数美元的军事和其他援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在向记者开放的会议的一小部分时间里，拜登称赞意大利的强硬立场关于乌克兰。梅洛尼说，她为意大利帮助捍卫国际法感到自豪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿希望西方联盟反对俄罗斯入侵乌克兰，这将有助于阻止中国改变民主统治的台湾的现状，中国声称台湾是自己的领土以及更广阔的太平洋地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国领导人在会后发表的联合声明中强调了合作与团结的领域，誓言将继续支持乌克兰，并就“机遇”加强对话。以及中华人民共和国带来的挑战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅洛尼将在未来几个月内面临一个决定，即是否继续保留意大利在北京“一带一路”基础设施计划中的成员身份，而华盛顿一直在努力应对这一计划。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;拜登表示，意大利和美国的相互贸易只会增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在谈论我们不断深化的经济联系，这种联系去年推动了超过 1000 亿美元的贸易额，”拜登在白宫会议上表示。 “在我看来，这一数字没有理由不能增加。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登带了一些主要负责经济事务的官员参加会议，其中包括他的商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多（Gina Raimondo），他的部门负责牵头出口控制向中国出售高科技产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意大利于 2019 年成为第一个也是迄今为止唯一一个加入中国重大基础设施倡议的 G7 国家，批评者称这种伙伴关系将使中国能够控制敏感的技术和重要基础设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意大利被认为极不可能在该协议于 2024 年 3 月到期时续签该协议，梅洛尼在 5 月份表示，即使不加入该协议，也有可能与北京保持良好关系。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;意大利前总理贝卢斯科尼在他赚了数十亿美元的城市举行国葬&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;梅洛尼表示，她计划在下一次外交任务期间访问中国，并可能会进行一对一会面- 与中国国家主席习近平的一次会面，尖锐地将美国描述为“我们在欧盟以外最重要的贸易伙伴”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还针对损害工人权利和安全的贸易行为，并呼吁“贸易专家认为这是对北京的又一次攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;七国集团去年正式启动了全球基础设施和投资伙伴关系，作为“一带一路”倡议的替代方案。七国集团国家 5 月在日本举行的领导人峰会上表示，他们正在努力“减少对其他国家的过度依赖”，但“不会脱钩或转向内向”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登与梅洛尼会面不到 20 分钟。一周前，她在罗马主持了一场关于移民问题的国际会议，当时意大利正在努力应对从北非乘船抵达的大量移民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意大利正计划与美国讨论如何支持梅洛尼办公室表示，非洲的发展和稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭博社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s border security interests make Asean’s Myanmar peace plan a ‘second-rank concern’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3229157/indias-border-security-interests-make-aseans-myanmar-peace-plan-second-rank-concern?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/95ddada3-63f8-4cbd-9ed4-15f1aac8d053_bab5cf44.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度愿意与缅甸军政府打交道 - 与所采取的方法形成鲜明对比分析人士表示，大多数东南亚国家的这种做法源于对边境安全的担忧，以及缅甸军方即使不再掌权仍将保持影响力的计算。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候在湄公河恒河合作会议期间印度外交部长苏杰生 (S. Jaishankar) 在曼谷会见了泰国、柬埔寨、老挝和越南的官员。 >;两国外长讨论了有关共同边界的问题，苏杰生表示印度对缅甸人道主义局势的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在中国、印度和日本的推动下，东盟继续推动缅甸和平&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;根据政治犯权利组织援助协会的数据，截至上个月底，政变以来共有 3,736 人被杀，其中 411 人是儿童。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平民已被抓获军方和亲民主反对派团体之间的冲突不断升级，但有很多指控称他们有时是军政府的专门针对的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;已有超过 23,000 人被捕，截至 6 月仍有超过 19,000 人被拘留30. 去年，在暂停执行数十年后，该国恢复了死刑，导致数人在虚假审判后被处决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，印度仍继续向军政府出售武器。联合国 5 月份的一份报告称，自政变以来的销售额为 5100 万美元，包括武器、原材料和武器制造的制造设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东盟解决危机的主要战略是五点共识，其中包括：缅甸军队于 2021 年 4 月同意。其中包括立即停止暴力、各方之间对话以及任命特使。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东南亚国家联盟的大多数成员（东盟）的 10 个成员国一直避免与军政府接触，因为对缅甸在过去两年中缺乏与和平计划的合作感到沮丧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，泰国继续与缅军接触，吸引了批评破坏东盟的努力。近几个月来，它就缅甸问题举行了多次非正式会议，包括部长级会谈，缅甸政府以及柬埔寨、老挝、中国和印度等其他国家的代表出席了会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰国与缅甸的会谈是“公然企图”破坏东盟的中心地位&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;印太地缘政治分析师、独立政策顾问阿卡什·萨胡 (Akash Sahu) 表示，印度与缅甸的持续接触是出于其东北边境的安全担忧萨胡说：“缅甸的合作对于打击叛乱、毒品和人口贩运具有重要意义。”他补充说，除了军方之外，缺乏处理这些事务的中央机构，因此印度有必要&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;萨胡指出，印度支持东盟在解决缅甸危机方面发挥领导作用，并表示区域组织内部对危机的不同看法反映了“问题的敏感性和复杂性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “与破坏[东盟]的努力相反，印度将有助于鼓励东盟采取集体做法，例如提供人道主义援助，”萨胡说。例如，在 5 月摩卡飓风期间，德里向缅甸提供了 40 吨人道主义援助和救灾物资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国华盛顿威尔逊中心南亚主任迈克尔·库格曼 (Michael Kugelman) 表示，虽然印度可能会担心关于军政府行动对边境安全造成的不稳定影响，它还将缅甸军方视为边境合作和互联互通项目的重要合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论缅甸是否由军队统治，武装部队库格曼表示，印度仍将是一个重要的政治和外交角色。他补充说，这就是印度愿意与之接触的原因，即使这样做“传达了合法化的信息”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;库格曼表示，印度拥有强大的实力渴望加强与东盟国家的关系，不仅是为了对抗中国的影响力，也是为了加深贸易和能源联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但归根结底，印度并不是东盟的正式成员，而且因此它不会让东盟目标妨碍其自身利益。”库格曼说，这意味着与军政府保持“可行的关系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;独家：在中国无法无天的诈骗中心内幕缅甸&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新加坡尤索夫伊萨东南亚研究所东盟研究中心高级研究员兼协调员 Sharon Seah 表示，根据印度的邻里优先政策 — — 该政策的重点是改善与近邻的关系 — — 德里对缅甸的看法首先是邻国，其次是东盟的朋友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为近邻，印度希望确保缅甸不会出现可能无意中影响其国家安全的恶性循环，”Seah 说道，并补充道缅甸对东盟的义务“对印度来说是次要的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，通过支持泰国发起的会议，目前尚不清楚印度 — — 印度已表示支持东盟对缅甸的和平计划 — —实际上是支持的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为东盟的对话伙伴，Seah 表示，印度可以提出弥合差距，如果它认真地想发挥作用，它应该咨询东盟轮值主席国印度尼西亚，“或者至少鼓励泰国”与所有东盟成员国开始适当的磋商进程”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为缅甸最近的邻国之一，印度有责任说服缅甸与东盟的五点共识合作，”Seah 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为缅甸最近的邻国之一，印度有责任说服缅甸与东盟的五点共识合作。” >;&lt;p>;德里贾瓦哈拉尔·尼赫鲁大学国际研究学院教授斯瓦兰·辛格表示，印度过去几十年对军政府的“谨慎培育”导致了“缅甸的逐步民主化”，这一过程现在已成为现实。 “短暂逆转”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然而，印度仍然希望如此谨慎培养军政府能够重启民主化进程，这仍然是印度的主要目标，”辛格说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 1990年昂山素季领导的全国民主联盟（NLD）赢得选举后，军政府拒绝承认结果并继续统治国家。 2010年再次举行选举，但民盟被禁止参加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2015年选举，民盟再次获得绝对多数。虽然昂山素季根据宪法被禁止担任总统，但她担任了国务委员的角色。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2020 年的民意调查中，全国民主联盟的绝对多数遭到军方指控欺诈，导致广泛调查和内乱，并最终导致政变。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;萨胡表示，如果印度不向缅甸出售武器，军政府将不得不完全依赖中国和俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;他说：“这种关系不仅可以对军政权产生一定的影响力，而且还为人道主义努力创造了空间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辛格表示，印度一直将其对缅甸的军事供应限制为辅助（后备）和非致命防御装备，并补充说，与近年来其武器出口总额的增长相比，德里向该国的武器销售一直缓慢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“（这）表明印度在与缅甸军方接触时持谨慎态度”辛格说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管印度的武器出口额从 2013 年的 8200 万美元增至去年的 19 亿美元，但它在 2009 年至 2013 年间是世界上最大的进口国之一，主要从俄罗斯进口据斯德哥尔摩国际和平研究所称，印度、美国和以色列。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而印度已承诺促进本国国防制造和武器出口，目标是将年出口额增加到 50 亿美元该研究所表示，到2025年，德里仍是2018年至2022年全球最大进口国，占全球进口量的11%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Camels not on strike’: rides at Silk Road tourist site in China resume after break  as authority denies claims some animals ‘died of exhaustion’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/environment/article/3228835/camels-not-strike-rides-silk-road-tourist-site-china-resume-after-break-authority-denies-claims-some?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/41ad4166-7d42-4003-9548-c94871b3be8e_0b0a53f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在镜头显示骆驼用于游客后，中国著名的丝绸之路遗址遭到炮轰网上出现了骆驼被工作人员拖过沙地时无法站立、痛苦哭泣的画面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;骆驼的悲惨镜头是在中国西北部甘肃省敦煌市鸣沙山拍摄的，并发布在网上本月早些时候。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这引起了公众的担忧，为游客提供骑骆驼服务，动物们过度劳累。不过，据新闻网站澎湃新闻报道，有关部分骆驼因此死亡的报道已被当局否认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月18日该站点暂停骑骆驼活动引发进一步恐慌，有网友在网上表示关于骆驼“罢工”的黑色幽默。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“连骆驼也是赚钱的工具。请大家关心、爱护他们。骆驼也是生物。”一位内地社交媒体评论道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“天气很热，骆驼很可能会中暑。请善待那些动物朋友。”另一位网友说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了保护野生动物的法律外，中国还没有立法来保障其他动物的权利，比如家养宠物、农场动物、动物园里的动物。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该景区一位不愿透露姓名的官员表示，从7月18日起，骆驼骑行活动暂停了一天，以便清理骆驼上山的路线。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“路上有很多骆驼粪便。由于现在天气非常热，路上臭气熏天。所以我们需要清理粪便。”该官员告诉澎湃新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该官员承认，这也让骆驼得到了休息，因为有些骆驼因为承载了太多游客而变得虚弱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“今年夏天我们接待了非常多的游客。大约有2万到3万名游客参观了该景点，几乎每个人都希望骑一匹骆驼，但这里只有1000头骆驼。”该负责人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月21日，敦煌文旅局该局否认了一些骆驼死亡的说法，称没有任何动物因精疲力竭而死亡，对视频片段的调查也没有发现任何虐待行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据我们的调查，骆驼发出呜呜声并不是因为它们该局的声明称，他们感到疲倦或受到虐待，但因为工人们用来牵骆驼的鼻绳让他们感觉不舒服。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，为了避免一天中气温较低的时间，由于海拔太高，骆驼的工作时间为早上 7 点至上午 10 点、下午 5 点至晚上 9 点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鸣沙山的骑骆驼服务每人 100 元（14 美元），载游客翻越沙山一次。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有时景区内游客太多，导致骆驼交通堵塞，动物们不得不沿路排队等候。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;敦煌被认为是是古代丝绸之路贸易路线上的重要历史遗迹，也是中国西北地区的热门旅游目的地。除鸣沙山外，还包括莫高窟，石窟内藏有中国古代建筑、雕塑和绘画的宝库。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Deputy head of official Hong Kong think tank withdraws signature from 1,400-name petition urging lawmakers to reject bill overhauling Chinese University governing body]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3229167/deputy-head-official-hong-kong-think-tank-withdraws-signature-1400-name-petition-urging-lawmakers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/22a0c521-25b3-4404-99b6-93dfaf4256b5_b792448d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港官方智库副主任撤回请愿书签名包括学者和公众人物在内的 1,400 多人签署了该法案，呼吁立法者否决一项旨在限制中文大学理事会成员和学者影响力的法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周四晚发布的一份声明中行政长官政策组表示，副组长关家明已主动撤回在请愿书上的签名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为大学校友，关家明对拟议修正案的关注和表达个人意见声明称，对大学治理的质疑是可以理解的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，有人担心该事件可能反映了政府的立场。为消除不必要的疑虑，关先生决定撤回请愿书中的签名。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;立法会阻止香港就中文大学校董会变动举行公开听证会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;立法会委员会将周五开会讨论由三名议员提出的私人议员法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推动废除该提案的团体周四在三份报纸上刊登了整版广告，列出了名单包括关在内的校友在请愿书上签名。岭南大学校长郑国汉教授也在签名者之列。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被问及关先生在请愿书上签名一事时，该智库早前表示此事与关先生的个人事务有关，不予置评.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案最著名的支持者之一是前市领导人梁振英，他特别批评了大学副校长兼校长段崇智。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“2019年黑人暴力事件后，院校自治和学术自由遭到滥用，”梁振英在Facebook上写道，指的是当年席卷整个城市并蔓延到校园的反政府抗议活动。 “这正是改革中文大学校董会并罢免段崇智的必要性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;段崇智曾因在社会动乱期间同情学生抗议而受到建制派批评。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;争议的焦点是《2023年香港中文大学（修订）条例草案》，该条例草案由三名获委任为校董会议员的议员——张宇人、邓家标和刘国勋发起&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们提议将理事会成员从 55 名削减至 34 名，同时增加外部代表的比例，以便他们在管理机构中占据主导地位。该法案还寻求将校董会决定大学校长的投票门槛提高至四分之三，而不是简单多数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前行政长官还贴出了梁英伟的一封信，一名校董会成员兼该校新亚书院董事局主席向条例草案委员会送交，表示希望条例草案能尽快获得通过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很多委员委员会成员是大学职员，其晋升由校长决定。”梁乃光说。 “该委员会是一个支持校长的橡皮图章机构。请愿活动的组织者之一向树辉表示，校友团体已向委员会提交了约1,400个签名，其中大多数签名是由校长和管理层监督的。其中包括大学毕业生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们认为，你们向[大学]强加了一些不符合学院最佳利益的做法，我们对此表示反对，”向说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;他说，校友认为改革应该基于2016年制定的理事会改革计划。该提案建议将机构成员缩减至29名，其中内部成员占11个席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中文大学校董会成员敦促香港立法会议员推迟改革法案&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该法案获得三人支持香补充道，立法会议员无视先前计划中包含的协议，并推动从未提交给立法会议员讨论的变革。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在线请愿活动的组织者之一、立法会议员杨宇明，建议将理事会中的议员人数从三名减少到两名，同时将决定副校长等人选的投票门槛设定为三分之二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;签署请愿书的其他校友包括：斯坦利许汉忠，香港机场管理局前行政总裁；香港故宫文化博物馆馆长吴志华；及政府流行病顾问许树昌教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港天文台前助理台长梁永武、前商务及经济发展局副局长梁敬国及同席议员林娜恩厚-yee 也是签署者之一。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong set to cancel all typhoon alerts as Doksuri drifts away]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3229187/hong-kong-set-cancel-all-typhoon-alerts-doksuri-drifts-away?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 09:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/411b65a4-8f15-4d99-a157-75bf84fe4a89_9089314e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;此故事已作为公共服务免费提供给我们的读者。请考虑在 之前支持《南华早报》的新闻报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着多克苏里逐渐远离城市且对居民的威胁减弱，香港天文台将于周五取消所有台风警告信号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天早上，多克苏里已经采取了更偏东的路径，位于香港以东约 500 公里处，”天气预报员于早上 7 点 45 分表示，一号警告信号仍然有效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据目前预计，“多克苏里”将在未来几个小时内在福建厦门附近登陆。其后将向内陆移动并逐渐减弱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，天文台指出，台风带来的骤雨及狂风雷暴仍会影响广东沿岸及附近海域。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;洪香港远足专家告诫徒步者“倾听身体的声音”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;预计周五香港天气非常炎热。但今天晚些时候和周六，西南气流将逐渐带来更频繁的阵雨，并伴有狂风雷暴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Doksuri”（韩语，意为“鹰”）是“塔利姆”袭击后两周内第二次袭击中国的台风。上周一进入广东。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，多克苏里带来了强风和暴雨，袭击了菲律宾北部海岸线，造成至少六人死亡，数千人断电。降雨和强风还导致马尼拉附近的一艘渡轮倾覆，造成至少 25 人死亡。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump accused of asking staff member to delete footage in bid to obstruct classified documents investigation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229184/donald-trump-faces-new-charges-documents-case-mar-lago-worker-indicted?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 06:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/28/e0af5223-9260-4234-936e-b3c7d0b58426_993b7850.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;唐纳德·特朗普要求一名工作人员删除他佛罗里达州庄园的摄像机镜头根据周四公布的最新起诉书，该起诉书增加了对前总统的新指控，并指定了另一名被告，以阻碍联邦调查他持有机密文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;起诉书包括新的妨碍司法罪名和故意犯罪罪名保留国防信息，加剧了特朗普的法律危险，尽管他正准备在华盛顿因他试图推翻 2020 年总统选举结果的行为而受到额外起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;额外指控凸显了今年的严重程度对特朗普进行的长期调查于上个月首次提出指控，对特朗普及其贴身男仆沃尔特·诺塔 (Walt Nauta) 提出了 38 项起诉书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普发言人驳回了这些新指控，称其“只不过是持续不断的”拜登政府“不顾一切地试图骚扰特朗普总统及其周围的人”并影响 2024 年总统竞选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些机密记录是特朗普在离开后带到海湖庄园的2021 年 1 月向白宫提起诉讼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;替代起诉书指控特朗普另有一项罪名，即故意保留与前总统在 2021 年 7 月在白宫接受采访时讨论美国攻击另一个国家的军事计划有关的国防信息。新泽西州贝德明斯特，高尔夫俱乐部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次采访是为了他的前幕僚长马克·梅多斯 (Mark Meadows) 撰写的回忆录，他在随后的书中将这个国家命名为伊朗。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;佛罗里达州法官设定唐纳德·特朗普的秘密文件审判将于 2024 年 5 月 20 日开始&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据起诉书，特朗普将这份被标记为绝密且未获准向外国人展示的文件归还给2022 年 1 月 17 日向联邦政府提起诉讼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这标志着检方对特朗普案件态度的显着转变，指控他保留一份文件，据称这位前总统在离任后知道该文件高度敏感 - 并且不仅仅是因为在被要求时未能将其归还给政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普和诺塔都表示无罪。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s concertgoers splash the cash, but is revenge spending sustainable to rock the economy?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3229131/chinas-concertgoers-splash-cash-revenge-spending-sustainable-rock-economy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/023f367e-5710-48fe-b31c-1ecfdd03c362_b1e0a441.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这是关于 2023 年上半年动荡的经济陷阱和逆风的第五篇文章这让中国难以摆脱多年来由新冠病毒引发的锈迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自中国去年 12 月取消与冠状病毒相关的限制并再次允许娱乐场所开业以来，面对面的活动已经被禁止需求量很大，歌迷们疯狂地寻找多余的音乐会门票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就像一种重新发现欣赏的感觉，是一种报复性消费，”应届大学毕业生刘英说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这位 22 岁的年轻人今年已经参加了三场音乐会，门票花费超过 7,000 元人民币（980 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在大流行之前，我认为没有必要，但后来，我realised that opportunities such as attending concerts and travelling can sometimes be once-in-a-lifetime,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The pandemic] made me realise that life is about living in the present and embracing as many experiences as possible.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Concerts have been relentlessly trending on Chinese social media in recent months, and in the first half of the year, more than 500 large-scale gigs and music festivals were held in China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And they combined to rake in 2.5 billion yuan (US$350 million) in ticket sales, with more than 5.5 million tickets sold, according to the China Association of Performing Arts.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39; Recovery is going from bad to worse&#39;: 6 takeaways from China&#39;s economic data&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The three months of the second quarter alone accounted for nearly 90 per cent of the ticket sales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More broadly , the number of for-profit performances - including pop concerts, dance shows and operas - in the first six months of the year surged by 400 per cent to 193,300, while ticket sales jumped by 673 per cent to 16.8 billion yuan and attendances increased by more than tenfold to over 62 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But while the concert market is experiencing a significant boom, it stands as an outlier to the broader economic recovery, which has been gradually losing steam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The stark contrast has pointed to the uneven path to recovery across sectors and raised concerns about whether consumption alone can be relied upon as a primary driver for China&#39;s economic recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the week-long Labour Day holiday in May, concerts and music festivals generated more than 1.2 billion yuan of consumer spending – excluding ticket sales – including transport, hotels, dining services among others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As the impact of the pandemic eases, there is a sudden release of emotions that have been suppressed for three years and a strong desire to temporarily break free from the current state,” said 28-year-old Shi Xiangyu, who now works in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shi has attended three concerts this year and has two more lined up in the coming month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s almost like an experiment to validate the right to freedom through travelling and attending concerts,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“However, frequent and high levels of spending may not be sustainable. I believe it is important to balance spending capability with needs.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese city plans months of rock &#39;n&#39; roll events to crank economy to 11&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Similar revenge spending has been seen in other sectors, with long queues in front of restaurants, packed sporting events, crowded tourist attractions and skyrocketing hotel and flight ticket prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in contrast to the robust rebound in some consumer sectors, there is a sluggish recovery of consumer durables – including vehicles and household goods and depressed property sales amid China&#39;s post-reopening economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Real estate investment dropped by 7.9 per cent in the first six months of the year, while weak demand is further slashing property prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That, in turn, has pushed down big budget spending on construction, furniture, as well as household appliances.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Concerts are high-end consumption, targeting urban middle class whose income was affected less during the Covid years,” said Wang Dan, chief economist at Hang Seng Bank China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The exceptionally high stress in the job market also means people are willing to spend more to relax. This is a typical lipstick economy phenomenon – during severe economic downturns, consumption of things that can provide emotional value tends to go up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“However, income growth has permanently slowed, the hype in concert spending is therefore not sustainable.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s recovery has been hit by domestic and international headwinds, including a curtailed property market, as well decreasing demand for exports, as well as weak confidence in the private sector dampening consumer confidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the second quarter, China&#39;s economy grew by 6.3 per cent, year on year, although analysts pointed to the low base from last year, when the economy stalled amid nationwide lockdowns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, rising uncertainties in the job market, overshadowed with pessimism and unease, have also prompted residents to cut spending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jobless rate for the 16-24 age group reached an unprecedented 21.3 per cent in June, having been on an upwards trajectory since 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is expected to rise further in July and August, as a record 11.58 million university graduates are set to leave campus and flood the job market this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fears over widespread lay-offs, pay cuts and age discrimination against workers as young as 30 are also seen to have stopped consumers from overspending.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s middle-age jobseekers face &#39;notorious glass ceiling of 35&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;And one or two policies will not be able to stimulate spending, while consumers&#39; income and confidence are the key to boosting consumption, said He Jun, a researcher at Anbound, an independent think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“People will naturally spend more if their income increases; people will dare to spend and even borrow to increase spending if they have confidence in the future, because they believe in their ability to repay the debt,” He said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The recovery of consumption cannot be realised through macro economic control, but are results of economic improvement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Difficulty in employment will significantly suppress consumption, with more individuals opting for a lying flat mentality.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lying flat movement represents the mindset of lying down instead of studying hard, finding a high-paid job, buying a home or even starting a family early in life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Policies aimed at supporting and stimulating consumption will be implemented, but it is crucial for these policies to identify the root causes,” added He.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that even if the government opted for unconventional helicopter money, also known as a helicopter drop where large sums of money are printed and distributed to the public to spur economic growth, individuals lacking confidence and income may not necessarily increase their consumption even after receiving the cash.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They will primarily satisfy basic needs and allocate the funds to debt repayment, thereby reducing their personal balance sheets,” said He.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has been offering tax cuts and discount coupons in an attempt to boost spending, but the results have been inconspicuous.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But despite the government&#39;s goal to prop up the economy with consumption, it will be hard to realise, said Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform, a think tank connected to the provincial government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Peng added that consumption has been the weakest among the three pillars of China&#39;s economy, which also include investments and exports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Currently, China&#39;s foreign trade is flopping, investment in real estate is weak, and low-cost consumption dominates consumer spending,” Peng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As a result, without economic recovery, it is difficult for consumption to thrive comprehensively. The relationship between consumption and the economy should be mutually reinforced.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China adds lipstick to gloomy economic recovery with domestic summer travel boom&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Consumption accounted for 32.8 per cent of China&#39;s gross domestic product growth in 2022, down from 54.5 per cent in 2021, and still short of over 80 per cent for many developed countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And while quick fix solutions, such as cash transfers to low income families or just a general transfer, would be effective, it is not a monetary tool the Chinese government is used to, added Wang at Hang Seng Bank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now the economic policies still focus on economic security and long term strength in the supply chain. The short-term stimulus for consumption or investment will not be prioritised,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the next two to three years, household consumption will command a higher share of the economy than investment, said Xu Tianchen, an economist with the Economist Intelligence Unit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the trend will be primarily driven by a decline in investments – especially as governments and property developers deleverage – rather than Chinese consumers getting richer and becoming more willing to spend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Technically, the government is supposed to increase expenditure to bridge the shortfall in private demand, for example by handing out cash transfers. But now its ability to act is being constrained by fiscal strains and perhaps the prioritisation of debt resolution in the agenda,” said Xu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This partly explains why government commitment to boosting income and consumption hasn&#39;t met with actual deeds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Against that backdrop, policymakers are mostly likely to let things run their own course – with limited support provided – and consumers will rely on their own means.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba’s Taobao to live stream Tencent’s Honour of Kings in rare partnership of China’s top tech giants]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3229152/alibabas-taobao-live-stream-tencents-honour-kings-rare-partnership-chinas-top-tech-giants?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/27/fb52b375-f2af-406a-84f7-4e516db71df4_8a22ac0b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Group Holding and Tencent Holdings are joining forces to promote their flagship brands in a rare collaboration between China&#39;s two largest technology companies, as the local race to attract eyeballs online heats up amid a slowing economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba&#39;s e-commerce platform Taobao and Tencent&#39;s hugely popular mobile game Honour of Kings are launching an invitation-only competition, with the finals to be broadcast on live-streaming service Taobao Live on August 5, according to a press release by Taobao and Tmall Group on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taobao, whose parent owns the South China Morning Post, said it is calling on “gamers from all walks of life” to start streaming on the platform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move marks Taobao&#39;s debut in the esports live-streaming sector, which has been dominated by a handful of video platforms including Bilibili, as well as Tencent-backed Huya and Douyu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba&#39;s China commerce business, which accounts for a large part of the group&#39;s total revenue, has suffered under weak retails sales nationwide. During the March quarter, sales in that segment fell 3 per cent year on year, Alibaba&#39;s financial statements showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In that same quarter, Tencent – operator of the world&#39;s largest video gaming business by revenue – saw its domestic gaming sales rise 6 per cent, the Shenzhen-based company reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, which has eased its years-long crackdown on the video gaming industry, has been promoting esports to boost its soft power ahead of the coming Asian Games, where esports will become a medal event for the first time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Honour of Kings, which is one of the seven esport titles to be featured in the Games, has operated an official Taobao store for more than four years, but it has never sponsored any video gaming live streams on the Alibaba platform until now.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Esports has become “an emerging sport with truly global influence” and has entered a critical “shaping period” in its development, said Mark Ren Yuxin, Tencent&#39;s chief operating officer, earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new partnership between the two tech giants comes as Taobao and Tmall fight to retain their user base and search for new growth. The subsidiary will be the only one of six business units to remain wholly owned by Hangzhou-based Alibaba after an ongoing restructuring announced in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an informal meeting in May, Alibaba founder Jack Ma advised the company&#39;s e-commerce executives to refocus on Taobao and its consumers to survive brutal competition and weather China&#39;s economic slowdown, Chinese media LatePost reported last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma reportedly said that Alibaba could not take its dominant position in China&#39;s e-commerce market for granted and must stay alert to business failure risks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cooperation with Honour of Kings has helped Taobao accelerate the pace of its content transformation by pushing its live streams to focus on not just online shopping, but also esports, the company said in its statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;User numbers on Taobao Live have grown 70 per cent year-on-year so far this year, while the growth of small and medium-sized live streamers has sped up, the firm added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Views of China ‘broadly negative’ in India and Brazil, survey finds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3229183/views-china-broadly-negative-india-and-brazil-survey-finds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/57fe9cad-6d57-4a98-be6f-241959fa5be7_4c3b4b53.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Negative perceptions of China have soared in India and Brazil, two of the biggest members of the Brics group, a Pew Research Centre study released on Thursday revealed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Views of China that are “broadly negative” in both Brazil and India surged by 21 percentage points, according to the survey&#39;s results. The increase was pegged at 5 percentage points for South Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Conducted between February and April, the survey by the Washington-based think tank comprised interviews of more than 30,000 respondents across 24 countries, including 2,611 in India, 1,044 in Brazil, and 1,502 in South Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly half the Brazilian respondents – 48 per cent – held negative impressions of China, up from 27 per cent in 2019, the last time Pew polled middle-income nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the same period, the proportion of Indians harbouring unfavourable views of China surged from 46 per cent in 2019 to 67 per cent. In South Africa, negative sentiment towards China rose from 35 per cent to 40 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The share of those in India and South Africa who felt China disregarded their national interests had vastly increased over the past decade, according to Laura Silver of Pew Research Centre and the study&#39;s principal researcher.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Silver believed concerns about China&#39;s human rights policies might be contributing to the negative perceptions among Brics countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“India has experienced a considerable negative shift in its views, distinctly standing out among the middle-income countries we surveyed,” said Silver. “Brazil&#39;s views have also grown more negative, but remain somewhat divided between favourable and unfavourable.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese-Americans regard Taiwan more favourably than China: Pew survey&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In contrast, sentiments in South Africa showed only a slight shift. While 40 per cent of respondents voiced negative views of China, 49 per cent said they still saw the Asian giant favourably. The South African respondents also took a more positive outlook towards other issues raised in the survey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brazilians and Indians appeared to be more sceptical of China&#39;s contributions to global peace and stability, with 62 per cent and 56 per cent expressing negative views, respectively. Conversely, South Africans were more optimistic, with 47 per cent adopting a favourable stance of Beijing&#39;s role.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Similarly, while 67 per cent of Indians and 57 per cent of Brazilians distrusted Chinese leader Xi Jinping&#39;s ability to make the right decisions, 47 per cent of South Africans were confident in him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“South Africa&#39;s opinions of China are comparatively positive and have changed minimally over a time period where sentiments in many other countries have drastically turned negative,” Silver said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She believed the results reflected that South Africans tended to see Chinese investments, soft power and its global role “more positively”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Silver also suggested that an assortment of factors could have spurred the sharp rise in negative views in India, including conflicts along the China-India border in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the other hand, in Brazil the data seemed to indicate that views of China fell along domestic political lines: 45 per cent of respondents who backed the incumbent left-wing governing coalition in Brazil had a favourable view of China, as opposed to 36 per cent who did not back President Lula da Silva.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The survey results for India were unsurprising as deaths in border conflicts with China in 2020 were “politically used to exacerbate Hindu nationalism and consolidate the influence of the partisan group led by [Indian Prime Minister Narendra] Modi”, said Karin Costa Vazquez of India&#39;s OP Jindal Global University as well as the Beijing-based think tank Centre for China and Globalisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Brazil, the coronavirus pandemic and former president Jair Bolsonaro&#39;s linking it to China may have fuelled negative views of the country, Vazquez said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China wants new Brics members, but India, Brazil worry about &#39;losing influence&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Jair Bolsonaro actively contributed to the construction of narratives such as &#39;Chinese virus&#39;, &#39;ineffective Chinese vaccine&#39;, aligned with the anti-China sentiment of the Trump administration and inertially reproduced by the Brazilian media.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vazquez said the results cast doubt on China&#39;s ability to consolidate cooperation with the Brics countries, guided by the economy, security and people-to-people exchanges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For years the Chinese government has fostered relations with civil society, pinning its hopes on person-to-person connections to forge understanding, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When people turn their backs on this type of initiative, as is happening in India, dialogue becomes more difficult and relationships more prone to hostility.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The recent Pew data illustrated a stark reality that despite Beijing&#39;s cultural initiatives intended to build global understanding of China, only a quarter of respondents regarded its films, television series and music positively, said Paulo Menechelli of the Brazilian think tank Observa China.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Foreign filmmakers offer advice on making China&#39;s message more appealing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;This contradicted a current rising fascination with Asian cultural artefacts, Menechelli said, particularly those from Japan and South Korea. It also contrasted with the Chinese embassy in Brazil&#39;s deepening investment in areas like film festivals, book clubs, Chinese language course promotion and the celebration of Chinese holidays.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He suggested that Beijing&#39;s tight controls of cultural output could be influencing how these efforts were perceived.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Xi Jinping consistently emphasises the need to &#39;tell China&#39;s stories well&#39;, yet what are these stories?” Menechelli asked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Censorship in China, especially around topics the political establishment and party leadership find even slightly controversial, directly hampered the ability to export these products, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Menechelli said many Brazilians were familiar with the American political system due to TV series like House of Cards, in contrast to their limited exposure to the Chinese system and its lack of transparency. This contributed to ignorance and subsequent unease, leading to more negative opinions about China not just in Brazil but globally.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Western officials make a beeline for Indo-Pacific to counter China’s influence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229182/western-officials-make-beeline-indo-pacific-counter-chinas-influence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.28 05:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/28/584e086c-74cd-43a3-90d2-714ffde6ac8d_4cc7d3bd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A major diplomatic counteroffensive against Beijing&#39;s influence in the Indo-Pacific is fully under way, and there&#39;s no better sign than Western leaders visiting the region&#39;s once-neglected islands – all at once.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most prominent figures island-hopping this week include French President Emmanuel Macron and US Secretary of State Antony Blinken. And US Secretary of Defence Lloyd Austin also travelled to Papua New Guinea, while Britain&#39;s Armed Forces Minister James Heappey stopped in Fiji.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Creating the most buzz among the Western guests is Macron, who during a visit to the nickel-rich French overseas territory of New Caledonia warned of “Chinese naval bases tomorrow” if the strategically located archipelago gained independence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If independence means that tomorrow you&#39;ll decide to have a Chinese base here, or to be dependent on another maritime fleet, good luck with that – that&#39;s no independence,” he said on Wednesday in Noumea, the New Caledonian capital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He called on pro-independence indigenous Kanaks to accept the pro-France third and final self-determination referendum of 2022. The Kanaks boycotted that vote and the negotiations on the territory&#39;s status under France remain deadlocked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We need to come out of the face-to-face tensions, which is the only way that will allow the path of the future of New Caledonia in the republic and in the Pacific,” Macron urged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;France maintains naval bases in New Caledonia, which was declared a French convict colony by Napoleon III in 1853. The first two independence votes, held in 2018 and 2020, favoured French rule. However, pro-independence votes have increased over time with recent gains in the Kanak population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron&#39;s efforts to preserve the vestiges of France&#39;s colonial empire were on full display in New Caledonia, but during his visit to Vanuatu he cautioned against “new imperialism”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Blinken in Tonga calls out &#39;predatory&#39; China&#39;s &#39;problematic behaviour&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Vanuatu was jointly ruled by Britain and France until it gained independence in 1980. With his visit, Macron also became the first sitting French president to set foot in an independent Pacific country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is in the Indo-Pacific, and particularly in Oceania, new imperialism appearing, and a power logic that is threatening the sovereignty of several states – the smallest, often the most fragile,” Macron said on Thursday in Port Vila.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though he didn&#39;t name it, China remains deeply involved with the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s development financing in the region peaked in 2016, according to a report by the Lowy Institute, a Sydney-based think tank. But it remains a major infrastructure lender to Pacific island nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vanuatu took new loans with China between 2017 and 2021, and Reuters reported that China&#39;s Export-Import Bank is also the country&#39;s largest creditor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pitching France&#39;s Indo-Pacific strategy in Port Vila, Macron claimed that it was aimed at defending “through partnerships the independence and sovereignty of all states in the region that are ready to work with us”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;France relaunched its Indo-Pacific strategy last year to reclaim its stake in the region after Australia ditched a French submarine contract in favour of joining the Aukus alliance and the British and American nuclear-powered submarines it would provide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron&#39;s trip to Vanuatu overlapped with Austin&#39;s visit to Papua New Guinea, which is the French leader&#39;s next stop.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Austin, the first Pentagon chief to visit the island nation of 10 million people, announced that the US would deploy a coastguard cutter to Papua New Guinea – but hastened to add that Washington was not looking to establish a permanent military base there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A key Pacific battleground during World War II, Papua New Guinea has become a focus of geopolitical rivalry between China and the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Western powers question New Zealand&#39;s &#39;reliability&#39; amid wavering China stance&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;And while Austin was busy securing deeper defence ties with Papua New Guinea, Blinken – the top US diplomat – didn&#39;t rule out a possible expansion of Aukus during a joint press conference with New Zealand Foreign Minister Nanaia Mahuta in Wellington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to a question about New Zealand joining the alliance, Blinken said that “the door is very much open for New Zealand and other partners to engage, as they see appropriate, going forward”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His remarks came just days after he warned South Pacific islands, during his visit to Tonga, of “predatory” China&#39;s “problematic behaviour”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As China&#39;s engagement in the region has grown,” Blinken claimed, it had engaged in “some predatory economic activities, and also investments that are done in a way that can actually undermine good governance and promote corruption”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken will head next to Australia, where he and Austin will meet with Penny Wong, the Australian foreign affairs minister, and Richard Marles, its defence minister, on Friday and Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gathering follows Heappey&#39;s trip last week to Fiji, where he visited the Fiji Naval Base and discussed Britain&#39;s role in Pacific security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local media reported that Britain had confirmed greater cooperation with the Fijian military, with more British warships coming to the Pacific island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though other leaders&#39; itineraries were restricted to the Pacific, Macron is taking his outreach to the Indian Ocean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a first by a sitting French president, he will travel to Sri Lanka, which is located at the crossroads of Indian Ocean trade, on Friday to hold talks with his Sri Lankan counterpart Ranil Wickremesinghe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters and AFP&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 28 Jul 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>