<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Beijing’s top envoy in UK lodges formal protest against Britain’s accusation of Hong Kong staging ‘campaign of fear’ through national security law raid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3227640/beijings-top-envoy-uk-lodges-formal-protest-against-britains-accusation-hong-kong-staging-campaign?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 11:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/9bbc08a5-53cb-4a9d-a522-44831e3b268f_d699c6d7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京驻英国特使就英国指责香港问题提出正式抗议在该市警方突袭了一名被列入通缉名单、现居住在英国的前议员的家后，他们发起了一场“恐惧运动”来恐吓活动人士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，两国政府就这一问题发生了争执。香港国安警察两天前采取的行动。警方突击搜查了活动人士罗冠中在东涌的家，并带走了他的父母和哥哥进行审问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方早些时候宣布悬赏 100 万港元（127,730 美元），以征集每名逮捕的线索。包括劳在内的八名嫌疑人被指控违反北京颁布的国家安全法，当局坚称该法具有域外效力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国外交部长安妮-玛丽·特里维廉 (Anne-Marie Trevelyan) 周四向议会表示，正式抗议将向中国大使提出。她警告说，她的政府不会容忍香港旨在通过八名通缉犯的家人进行恐吓和噤声的“恐惧运动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国安警察突袭逃亡者罗冠聪的家中&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;她表示，此类行为只会进一步损害香港的国际声誉和地位，英国政府不会容忍中国大陆或香港当局恐吓或压制该国任何人的企图。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对此，中国驻伦敦大使馆表示，郑泽光大使已于周四向外交英联邦和发展办公室“有关官员”作出“严肃交涉”，对“错误言论”表示强烈不满和坚决反对。他表示，香港警方的执法行动“公正、必要、合法”，维护了香港的法治和稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑在一份声明中告诉英国官员他们“没有地位，也没有权利对香港的执法行动发表不负责任的言论”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;8 香港通缉活动人士应该被视为“街上的老鼠”：李约翰&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;“英方对香港特区警方的执法行为指手画脚，公开为反中分子说话，为他们提供避风港。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“英方的所作所为颠倒黑白，不尊重法治，粗暴干涉中国内政。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，香港政府也表示强烈反对和谴责英国官员和政客试图“妖魔化”合法警察行动，重申国家安全立法的适用范围符合国际法原则和其他司法管辖区采用的实践。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港特区政府严正敦促英方认清事实、辨别谬误，立即停止对国家安全法及其实施的肆意诽谤和抹黑。”政府发言人周四晚在声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国安警察逮捕另一名前众志成员罗先生，周四年满30岁，据信在2020年6月30日国家安全法生效前离开香港。他现在居住在英国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;劳共同创立的已解散反对党众志的五名前成员在过去一周因涉嫌向他提供经济支持而被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他现居海外的通缉反对派人物包括前立法会议员郭永亨、许志峰、工会成员蒙少达、律师任建峰，以及活动人士刘祖德、郭凤。 -yee 和 Elmer 袁恭义。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 11:50:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Syria says UN can deliver aid through shuttered Turkey crossing for 6 months]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3227641/syria-says-un-can-deliver-aid-through-shuttered-turkish-crossing-6-months?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 11:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/3369a22f-7c11-4af6-b32d-3a948a407850_8cb13ae5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;叙利亚政府周四表示，联合国可以利用土耳其的过境点在安理会未能延长行动授权后，继续向叙利亚西北部提供援助六个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国援助的交付必须“与叙利亚政府充分合作和协调”，路透社看到，叙利亚驻联合国大使巴萨姆·萨巴格在周四致安理会的一封信中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国安理会批准了土耳其的援助行动，为叛军控制的叙利亚西北部的数百万人提供帮助周一到期，成员国努力说服俄罗斯将其延长六个月以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯周二在联合国安理会否决了延长九个月的授权，然后又在自己的六个月授权申请中失败。该行动自 2014 年以来一直在提供包括食品、药品和住所在内的援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯曾推动将行动期限延长 12 个月。联合国发言人斯蒂芬·杜贾里克 (Stephane Dujarric) 表示，叙利亚的信件已收到，联合国正在对其进行研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据联合国的授权，巴布·哈瓦 (Bab al-Hawa) 对援助进行黄金标准监控，以确保援助不被滥用。”英国驻联合国大使芭芭拉·伍德沃德在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;叙利亚阿萨德在多年的孤立之后在阿拉伯峰会上受到热烈欢迎&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“在没有联合国监督的情况下，这条重要生命线的控制权已被交给了她说，叙利亚总统巴沙尔·阿萨德是对叙利亚人民的苦难负有责任的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，首要任务是迅速让援助再次流向需要援助的人，然后，行动的未来具有确定性，并补充道：“我们会毫不犹豫地将此事提交给安理会”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;需要安理会授权，因为叙利亚政府不同意联合国的行动。它最初于2014年授权从伊拉克、约旦和土耳其的两个地点向叙利亚反对派控制地区运送援助物资。但俄罗斯和中国将其缩减为土耳其的一个：Bab al-Hawa。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯驻联合国副大使德米特里·波利安斯基 (Dmitry Polyanskiy) 表示，现在安理会无需就任何跨境援助授权进行投票由于叙利亚政府已经亲自批准，这条途径“正式死亡”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“将另一份草案付诸表决的一切努力都只不过是政治游戏，”他在推特上发帖说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯和叙利亚认为此次行动侵犯了叙利亚的主权和领土完整。他们表示，应该从国内提供更多援助，这引发反对派担心粮食和其他援助将落入政府控制之下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“阿拉伯叙利亚共和国政府已做出主权决定，向联合国提供援助及其专门机构允许使用 Bab al-Hawa 过境点，”萨巴格写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们将被允许“与叙利亚政府充分合作和协调，向叙利亚西北部有需要的平民提供人道主义援助，为期六个月，从 2023 年 7 月 13 日开始，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月份土耳其和叙利亚发生地震导致 5 万多人死亡后，阿萨德允许联合国额外使用从土耳其出发的两个过境点派遣援助物资。该批准将于 8 月 13 日到期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2011 年阿萨德对和平民主抗议者的暴力镇压导致了内战，莫斯科支持阿萨德，华盛顿支持反对派。数百万人逃离叙利亚，还有数百万人在国内流离失所。此后，随着阿萨德重新控制叙利亚大部分地区，战斗有所减弱。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 11:50:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fukushima discharge row: is Hong Kong’s ban on Japanese seafood imports an overreaction or one grounded in science?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3227630/fukushima-discharge-row-hong-kongs-ban-japanese-seafood-imports-overreaction-or-one-grounded-science?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/fa97f863-2e74-413c-b81c-0796d6284f7f_f697f6ec.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本计划向大海排放超过130万吨处理后的核废水未来三十年的气候变化促使香港提议禁止进口国内10个地市的水产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然目前官方确认的排放日期尚不清楚，但当地餐饮业领导人表示，根据该禁令，该市日本餐馆的生意将减半，其中约 30% 可能会关门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》探讨了政府的海鲜进口禁令将​​如何影响该市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;1。到目前为止，香港针对排放计划做了什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府周三建议，一旦该国开始向太平洋倾倒经处理的水产品，就禁止从包括东京都市区在内的10个县进口水产品。用于冷却 2011 年福岛地震受损核反应堆的废水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除东京外，其他受影响的县包括福岛、千叶、栃木、茨城、群马、宫城、新泻、长野和埼玉，其中禁令涵盖所有活的、冷冻的、冷藏的、干的和腌制的海鲜、海盐、海藻及其他衍生产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;如果日本证明福岛排放的安全性，香港可能放宽海鲜禁令&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;拟议的禁令是自核泄漏以来目前涵盖福岛、千叶、栃木、茨城和群马的进口管制措施的升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港环境局局长谢展云周四强调，拟议的措施是“预防措施”，并补充说，如果东京能够证明其排放计划是安全的，当局将考虑放宽规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的日本餐馆对福岛海鲜禁令的未来感到不确定&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港政府已成立跨部门专责小组，由环境生态局牵头，其他部门包括食物安全中心、天文台、卫生署及政府化验所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢曾多次向日方表达关注对食品安全和环境的影响，敦促国家暂缓排放，直至国际社会达成共识。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2．拟议禁令背后的理由是什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府表示，是在考虑了国际原子能机构的最终报告以及日本当局的信息后制定了这些限制措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府在周三的一份声明中表示，拟议的措施是基于确保所有来自日本的食品适合消费的“预防原则”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此次排放计划是史无前例的，将持续 30 年，”一位发言人说。 “在这么长的时间内，如果净化系统无法有效运行，可能会对食品安全和海洋生态造成重大风险。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;3。这在科学上合理吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一些专家质疑涉及10个县（其中4个是内陆县）背后的理由。前香港大学地理讲师梁启智表示，他很困惑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“东京被禁，但神奈川为什么不被禁？海水必须经过神奈川才能到达东京。”他在脸书上说道。 “同样的理由也适用。如果新泻被禁，新泻与福岛之间的海路仍会经过岩手、青森、秋田、山形。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环境生态局解释称，在制定之前已参考了其他经济体的管制措施。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管联合国批准，香港仍对日本放射性水排放计划保持警惕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“香港自2011年起对日本水产品实施的进口管制措施发言人指出，栃木县和群马县等两个内陆县也已实施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;食物环境卫生咨询委员会主席梁美仪警告说，辐射可能会累积并通过沿着食物链，从而危及公共健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们没有数据表明海洋生物即使在低辐射剂量下是否真的安全，”他周一在广播节目中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;4.香港和日本就福岛核电站排放问题最新发生争执？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港政务司司长陈国基和谢霆锋周三会见了日本总领事冈田健一和其他相关官员。在会谈中，市政府重申，在国际社会达成共识之前，东京不应开始排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本内阁官房长官松野博和周四上午表示，他对进口禁令“极为遗憾”敦促香港取消限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本驻香港领事馆告诉《华盛顿邮报》，该国将与香港官员保持沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“香港人对日本食品的信任度可能会下降”如果废水处理计划继续进行&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;日本媒体《日经亚洲》周二援引日本副总领事中原直人的指责，称香港旨在“从北京赢得加分”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示，领事馆已“转变态度”反驳香港政府的说法，以“保护在香港销售日本食品的人的利益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;针对批评，谢&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港拥有高度自治权，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;5．禁令对业内人士和消费者有何潜在影响？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港是日本农渔业的第二大进口地，仅次于中国内地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府数据显示，主要去年从日本进口的食品约占该市食品供应总量的2%，当地消费的所有海鲜中有6.75%来自日本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;食品环境卫生数据核查部门周四显示，约有 2,200 家持牌餐厅已获准在香港销售生鱼片，占全市 17,200 家持牌餐厅的 12.8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港日本料理协会主席 Dennis Wu 表示，该禁令将这对进口商和日本餐馆造成了严重打击，尤其是提供 omakase 的高级餐馆，这是一种由厨师挑选并采用新鲜食材烹制的菜肴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多日本食品进口商一直在寻找其他日本食品九州等低风险地区的供应商应避开被禁地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港餐饮联业联会董事会成员陈强 (Martin Chan Keung) 表示，表示该市多达 30% 的日本餐馆将因禁令而关门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“后疫情时代的生意已经很困难了，”他警告说。 “如果实施禁令，由于消费减少，可能会增加成本和运费，前景将更加黯淡。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;6。周边地区对计划的废水排放反应如何？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;日本首相岸田文雄周三表示，他将坚持该计划，并补充说具体排放时间将在确保安全和消除谣言后确定。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;国际原子能机构总干事拉斐尔·格罗西上周访问韩国时表示，如果按计划执行，此次释放“符合国际安全标准”。&lt;/p>;&lt;中国外交部发言人汪文斌周二表示，核监督机构的报告“仓促发布”，片面且有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还警告日本不要利用这一批准作为借口。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国海关总署上周对东京等10个县的水产品实施进口禁令，并规定来自日本其他地区的食品必须全部接受抽查。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳门还表示，一旦日本开始排放废水，将立即加强进口管制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾敦促东京按照国际标准和规范进行排放作业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾敦促东京按照国际标准和规范进行排放作业。 >;&lt;p>;韩国表示尊重该机构的报告，并表示计划中的排放对该国的水质影响不大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首尔仍维持对来自受损核电站周围地区的食品的禁令，但如果发布计划有任何变化，我们将进行额外检查。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Solomon Islands tells critics China police deal not a ‘threat to Pacific region peace’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3227633/solomon-islands-tells-critics-china-police-deal-not-threat-pacific-region-peace?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 10:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/59e4d357-531e-4400-ad79-65eebebb5c79_e87f67ec.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;所罗门群岛否认了澳大利亚和其他国家的建议，其与北京的警务协议是“一个威胁太平洋地区和平”，并表示中国将增强其 1,500 名警察的网络安全和社区警务能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国、澳大利亚和新西兰呼吁所罗门群岛“立即”公布细节周一，在总理玛纳西·索加瓦雷对中国进行为期一周的访问期间，在北京签署了为期三年的警务协议，担心该协议将引发进一步的地区竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和所罗门群岛警察部长会面据中国媒体报道，周二，索加瓦雷办公室承诺“将中国的警察和执法合作提升到新的水平”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周五的一份声明中，索加瓦雷办公室表示，这个太平洋岛国正在扩大其安全伙伴关系，并且中国警方将增加现有的澳大利亚和新西兰警务支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有人能够垄断知识。所罗门群岛与中国及所有合作伙伴的合作基于平等以及尊重主权和领土完整的原则。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚人看到了与中国牢固关系的好处，但希望禁止中国应用程序：民意调查&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤表示，她周四晚在雅加达与中国最高外交官王毅会面时“传达了澳大利亚对太平洋安全的明确看法”。澳大利亚和新西兰表示，太平洋地区的安全需求应在该地区得到满足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所罗门群岛政府未能看到霍尼亚拉（所罗门群岛皇家警察部队）交通控制和管理系统的改进、提供索加瓦雷办公室的声明称：“警察装备或法医尸检实验室的落成对太平洋地区的和平与安全构成威胁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年首都霍尼亚拉发生的骚乱暴​​露了岛屿治安方面的漏洞&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚和新西兰警察应索加瓦雷的要求部署到所罗门群岛应对骚乱，此前他们曾在内部冲突后领导一支长达十年的国际安全部队维持和平。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;在访华前一周，索加瓦雷宣布将审查澳大利亚的安全条约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所罗门群岛于 2022 年与中国达成安全协议。这是该协议签署后索加瓦雷首次访问北京承诺支持中国的全球发展倡议和全球安全倡议政策，将中国的基础设施投资与安全结合起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所罗门群岛拥有70万人口，是一个在太平洋群岛中占据战略地位的群岛，对于美国在第二次世界大战中向西跨太平洋解放菲律宾至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾的紧张局势引起了华盛顿和堪培拉对中国在该地区海军野心的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;对澳大利亚通讯联系和北亚出口贸易至关重要的海底电缆和航线也穿过这些岛屿。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fukushima water release: why Japan ignoring safety concerns and going ahead with discharge plan could hit its trustworthiness]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/opinion/article/3227529/fukushima-water-release-why-japan-ignoring-safety-concerns-and-going-ahead-discharge-plan-could-hit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 10:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/13/ac97d912-8500-4933-9c81-94cd34265b9c_4a9e2a53.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;联合国核监察机构负责人对日本即将释放经处理的核武器发表的不一致评论福岛核电站的放射性水流入海洋本身就令人费解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但更令人费解的是，东京愿意放弃数十年来通过排放受污染的水而建立的负责任和积极的全球形象从世界上最严重的核灾难之一变成了全球公域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，国际原子能机构 (IAEA) 负责人拉斐尔·格罗西 (Rafael Grossi) 表示，该机构得出的结论是，日本的计划符合安全标准和全球工业。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几天后，格罗西表示，评估背后的一两个国际专家团队可能表达了担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，他很快就与该言论保持距离，并坚称表示对国际原子能机构的报告没有内部分歧，并补充说他之前在采访中“暗示”团队之间不和是“误解的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;怎么会这样？没有进一步的解释。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;关于日本计划将福岛废水排入大海的信息&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在像将核污染的水倒入海洋这样严重的情况下，可能会造成在接下来的几十年里，格罗西的相互矛盾的评论和他的专家团队的“一致”观点并不能激发信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果国际原子能机构愿意观察的话，不乏不同的声音。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;加拿大核安全委员会表示，氚会增加患癌症的风险，指的是放射性废水中的危险元素，由于缺乏现有技术而无法去除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国核安全委员会监管委员会承认，任何接触包括氚在内的辐射都可能造成一定的健康风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国家原子能机构表示，超过70%的载核水在经过检测后未能达到排放限值。过滤系统，需要进一步处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本对 2011 年因大地震和海啸而瘫痪的工厂的废水进行处理，此举颇受争议，这与其长期以来负责任的全球形象不符，甚至严重背离。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从从第二次世界大战的废墟中崛起以来，日本已经摆脱了军国主义侵略者的形象，并在帮助欠发达国家（例如通过官方发展援助计划）方面建立了可靠的声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;多年来，日本作为促进社会经济长期发展的主要援助国和全球资本和信贷的主要来源国，赢得了钦佩和尊重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;支持全球基础设施、可再生能源和教育，协助救灾，并为全球维和行动做出贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我在 20 世纪 80 年代的新加坡长大，亲眼目睹了日本在流行文化中的软实力是如何扎根并发展起来的。无数人被学习日语所吸引，并了解这个国家如何成为（当时）不仅在经济增长方面而且在技术创新方面排名第一的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从那时起，日本电影、美食、电视节目、动漫、漫画、电子游戏和音乐深受喜爱，并为东亚国家的积极全球形象做出了贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着韩国人拒绝福岛计划，尹与日本的关系可能陷入困境&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;去年，安霍尔特-益普索国家品牌指数将日本列为外国人钦佩和尊重的国家第二位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡尤索夫伊萨东南亚研究所对东南亚国家进行的年度调查，东京去年仍然是该地区最值得信赖的大国，54.5% 的人认为它将“做正确的事”，为全球和平与治理做出贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但日本是否“做正确的事”？福岛废水？无视邻国正当合理关切，超出“正确的事情”吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;绿色和平组织指责东京违反《联合国海洋法公约》，而众多团体和专家却对此表示不满。指出了其他可用且可行的废水处理替代解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;采用最简单且最具成本效益的选择并不能很好地说明日本的经济实力和良好的全球治理记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;日本以分享全球问题的解决方案而闻名，而不是成为问题的一部分，甚至助长问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本作为一个负责任、值得信赖和可靠的大国的形象，一旦释放放射性水的按钮被激活，让世界变得更美好的良好记录很可能会被削弱。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[International Criminal Court investigates killings in Sudan’s Darfur as UN reports mass grave]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3227636/international-criminal-court-investigates-killings-sudans-darfur-un-reports-mass-grave?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 10:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/ee1b7dff-caf5-489f-a7da-c98c7ef1d88b_cc114e00.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;国际刑事法院检察官表示，他正在调查涉嫌新的战争罪和反人类罪苏丹达尔富尔地区目前的冲突已造成 3,000 多人死亡，迫使超过 300 万人逃离家园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡里姆·汗 (Karim Khan) 周四向联合国安理会表示，政府军与准军事部队之间的战斗快速安全部队已进入达尔富尔，达尔富尔曾在 2003 年遭受流血和暴行的蹂躏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，世界、国家和安理会“面临着让历史重演的危险”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005 年，安理会将达尔富尔局势提交国际刑事法院，汗表示，根据该决议，该法院仍然有权调查广阔的西部地区的犯罪行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达尔富尔一直是其中之一。 4 月 15 日开始的当前冲突的中心，变成了种族暴力的舞台，准军事部队和阿拉伯民兵联盟攻击非洲少数民族群体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四早些时候，联合国人权办公室在在西达尔富尔州的一个乱葬坑中发现了至少 87 具尸体，其中一些来自非洲马萨利特部落，并援引“可靠消息”称他们是被快速支援部队战士和盟军民兵杀害的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;至少 22 名平民在苏丹喀土穆附近的空袭中丧生&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们正在调查这些指控，”汗告诉安理会。 “从任何分析来看，我们都不是处于人类灾难的悬崖边，而是正处于一场灾难之中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“妇女和儿童、男孩和女孩、老人和年轻人都在担心自己的生命安全，他们生活在冲突之中，家园被烧毁，生活充满不确定性。正如我们所说，许多人不知道今晚会发生什么，也不知道明天等待着他们的命运是什么，”检察官说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汗说，国际刑事法院还在调查西达尔富尔州的许多其他指控，包括抢劫、法外杀戮和焚烧房屋，以及北达尔富尔州的指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，苏丹境内外任何协助或教唆达尔富尔犯罪的人都将受到调查。他说，他指示他的办公室优先处理针对儿童的犯罪以及性暴力和基于性别的暴力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须采取集体紧急行动，保护最脆弱的群体，如果这个经常重复的短语‘汗说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2003 年，来自该地区中部民族和撒哈拉以南非洲社区的叛乱分子发动叛乱，指责阿拉伯人主导的达尔富尔地区，广阔的达尔富尔地区陷入流血之中。喀土穆政府的歧视和忽视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;时任总统奥马尔·巴希尔领导下的政府以空中轰炸的焦土袭击作为回应，并释放了被称为金戈威德的当地阿拉伯游牧民兵，他们被指控大规模屠杀和强奸。多达 30 万人被杀，270 万人被赶出家园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，国际刑事法院针对苏丹政府支持的部队在达尔富尔的暴行进行的首次审判在荷兰海牙开始。被告金戈威德领导人阿里·穆罕默德·阿里·阿卜杜勒·拉赫曼 (Ali Muhammad Ali Abd – Al-Rahman)，又名阿里·库沙卜 (Ali Kushayb)，对所有 31 项战争罪和反人类罪指控均表示无罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汗告诉安理会，检方已结束其调查尽管冲突仍在继续，但案件的审判预计将继续进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;苏丹战火纷飞，埋葬了 180 具身份不明的尸体&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他引用了一位不愿透露姓名的证人的话，他告诉法庭，20 年后， ：“我们想要正义。我们希望所有那些让我们的生活变得羞辱、痛苦和疲惫的人承担责任……我们想要和平。我们想回到我们的祖国”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴希尔还面临国际刑事法院对与达尔富尔冲突有关的种族灭绝和反人类罪的指控。自从 2019 年与国际刑事法院通缉的另外两名嫌疑人一起被赶下台以来，他一直在喀土穆的监狱里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汗在提交给安理会的一份报告中表示，他的办公室了解到这三名嫌疑人已从科伯释放四月份战斗爆发后，首都喀土穆的监狱里。他说，他的办公室最近向政府发出了一封信，寻求确认他们目前的位置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在苏丹七个邻国的领导人周四在开罗举行最高调的和平会议后不久，汗向安理会通报了情况自90天前这个东北部非洲国家爆发冲突以来，谈判一直在进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;12周的战斗已将苏丹首都喀土穆变成了城市战场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冲突迫使超过2.4据国际移民组织称，数百万人逃离家园前往国内更安全的地区。该机构称，还有大约 738,000 人越境进入邻国。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s central bank governor calls for economic prudence as his retirement nears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3227582/chinas-central-bank-governor-calls-economic-prudence-his-retirement-nears?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/13/2807f254-4425-4dbb-b818-e9ed4a80fa9d_4456fa6f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在全球可能面临长期经济调整的情况下，中国必须保持货币政策央行行长表示，要保持政策的稳定性和连贯性，在全球竞争中保持战略发展的快车道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外界普遍预计易纲将在央行行长任期内很快卸任。 China (PBOC) governor, flagged some concerns on hot-button issues and offered advice in a recent article for the Journal of Economic Research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He wrote about how the world&#39;s second-largest economy should maintain positive interest rates in line with its potential growth – not like the big stimulus and ultra-loose monetary policies that triggered inflation and market volatility in the West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yi would also like to see greater market-driven force and more flexibility in the yuan&#39;s exchange rate regime, which could help China absorb external shocks, such as from aggressive US interest rate hikes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Maintaining positive interest rates is beneficial to providing positive incentives for the market, in line with the Chinese tradition of saving, and conducive to long-term social development,” Yi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As central bank governor since 2018, Yi kept inflation at bay in China, coped with coronavirus shocks, and helped achieve Beijing&#39;s growth goals without turning the country&#39;s debt crisis into a catastrophe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To best support the real economy moving forward, Yi now suggests that China should keep a prudent monetary policy and avoid “helicopter money” – or printing and distributing of large sums of money to the public to spur economic growth. He also called for prioritising domestic demand, improving the marketisation of interest rates, stabilising market expectations and reducing the cost of corporate finance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The PBOC] should fulfil the role of structural monetary policy tools and increase financial support for key areas and weak links in the national economy,” Yi said in the article.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yi received a PhD from the University of Illinois and was a tenured associate professor at Indiana University-Purdue University Indianapolis.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Crisis of confidence&#39; in China&#39;s banking system must be urgently addressed&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He is widely viewed as a pro-market official and an important aide to Liu He, who stepped down as vice-premier in March but now is believed to still play an important advisory role to President Xi Jinping.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 65-year-old Yi did not get a place in the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party in October. He received a senior advisory role in the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference in a bid to reassure markets and investors as the country fights against economic headwinds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yi&#39;s removal as deputy party chief of the PBOC on July 1 signalled that he will leave the inner decision-making circle soon, and he did not show up at Premier Li Qiang&#39;s symposium with internet platform companies on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“His ideas are consistent and clear: the monetary policy tools should fit in with the country&#39;s economic performance and demand,” said Zhao Xijun, a finance professor at Renmin University in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The governor has carried out a stable and cautious monetary policy in the past, and this has reduced macro risks and uncertainties faced by the market while mitigating economic volatility, according to Zhao.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The central bank will need to consider how to make its monetary policy better aligned with Beijing&#39;s adjustments to fiscal, social and industrial policies while stabilising the recovery of the economy in the wake of pandemic shocks, Zhao added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During his five-year tenure as bank governor, Yi was tasked with defusing financial risks, including the takeover of Baoshang Bank – China&#39;s first state bank seizure in over 20 years – and the restructuring of many small and medium-sized commercial banks. The central bank also stepped up its regulation of internet finance and scrutiny of platform companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the PBOC&#39;s “three red lines” for property developers – initiated in 2020 in response to President Xi Jinping&#39;s stated principle that a house is to be lived in, not for speculation – triggered defaults of many private developers, including Evergrande. It later relaxed financing regulations to ensure property delivery, but the risks have not yet been fully addressed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Premier Li eyes &#39;combination of punches&#39; at critical economic juncture&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Last year, the embezzlement of people&#39;s banking savings in village banks in central China&#39;s Henan province triggered massive protests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pan Gongsheng, head of the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, has been named party chief of the central bank. He also met visiting US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen last week and is expected to succeed Yi at the helm of the central bank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pan, who has more than two decades of financial industry experience, with a track record of steering the foreign exchange regulator since 2016, will face challenges from the yuan&#39;s depreciation relative to the US dollar, partly driven by China&#39;s weak post-Covid recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s one-year medium-term lending facility (MLF) rate was 1.9 per cent, down from 3.3 per cent five years ago and lower than the US benchmark.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The offshore yuan weakened to 7.17 against the US dollar on Thursday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thailand’s Myanmar talks open up diplomatic track ‘parallel’ to Asean’s, deepen regional divide]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227604/thailands-myanmar-talks-open-diplomatic-track-parallel-aseans-deepen-regional-divide?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 09:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/13/10cc0698-7ede-4f8a-bf9d-0d4eabc372a0_825822b3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;This week&#39;s set of Asean meetings were seen as an opportunity for the bloc to evaluate its joint efforts in urging Myanmar&#39;s junta to adhere to a pre-established plan for restoring democracy following a 2021 coup in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, revelations of the extent of Thailand&#39;s unilateral communication with its violence-wracked neighbour&#39;s military rulers underscore a significant regional divide, according to analysts. That schism was further put on display by a delay by Asean in sending out a joint communique, which was released late Thursday, two days after the bloc held its first set of talks for the week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thailand&#39;s Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai on Wednesday said he had met jailed Myanmar leader Aung San Suu Kyi in prison on Sunday, adding that the Nobel Peace Prize laureate told him she “supported dialogue” to end her country&#39;s internal crisis following a coup in February 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Thai official – currently serving in a caretaker capacity pending a post-election power transition in his country – described his visit as a “step in the right direction” in the peace process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Observers who spoke to This Week in Asia sharply disagreed, saying the unilateral approach by Bangkok undermined the so-called Asean centrality principle, in which the bloc as a collective drives decision-making.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asean&#39;s plan to Myanmar junta chief Min Aung Hlaing to return to a path of democracy following his coup involves a Five-Point Consensus plan the military leader agreed with the bloc two months after he seized power. He has thus far been intransigent in implementing the peace plan, which has seen Asean freeze junta officials out of high-level engagements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Charles Santiago, from the Asean Parliamentarians for Human Rights Group, said Pramudwinai&#39;s move to meet Suu Kyi was a “brazen attempt” to undermine Asean&#39;s collective Myanmar strategy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moreover, Indonesia – the bloc&#39;s chair for 2023 – had also been undermined through the Thai moves, Santiago and others said. In its role as chair, Indonesia has conducted 110 contacts with various factions involved in Myanmar&#39;s internal strife, with the hope that this would lead to talks on firmer footing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apart from his latest overtures, Pramudwinai – despite being in a government that is currently operating on a caretaker basis pending a post-election power handover – has played a key role in convening ad hoc “Track 1.5” dialogues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These talks have featured the Myanmar junta&#39;s foreign policy chief Wunna Maung Lwin as well as representatives of Cambodia, China, Laos, Vietnam, Japan and Bangladesh.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singapore-based analyst Aaron Connelly said Thailand&#39;s actions created a diplomatic track “parallel to Asean&#39;s” in which not all Asean member states were consulted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The junta in Myanmar is trying to shift the venue for diplomacy dealing with the conflict there away from Asean, which has excluded it from any high-level meetings in response to its refusal to implement the Five-Point Consensus, to a Thai-led process that Pramudwinai initiated in December 2022,” said Connelly, a research fellow on Southeast Asian politics and foreign policy at the International Institute for Strategic Studies think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Thailand&#39;s informal talks with Myanmar junta expose Asean divisions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hunter Marston, a Southeast Asia-focused researcher at the Australian National University, said it was clear that Indonesia as Asean chair – and not individual countries – had the best tools to engage with all sides involved in Myanmar&#39;s civil strife, including the civilian administration-in-exile which styles itself the National Unity Government (NUG).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Indonesian foreign minister&#39;s efforts, including via remarks at this week&#39;s meetings, to characterise Thailand&#39;s overtures as a “sideshow” were important to help Asean&#39;s diplomatic efforts regain momentum, Marston said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia also has the backing of Asean&#39;s dialogue partners, such as the United States, to continue with its effort to promote inclusive dialogue in Myanmar, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the last couple of weeks, Indonesia has met representatives of various ethnic groups and youth organisations linked to the [NUG&#39;s armed wing] People&#39;s Defence Force,” he said. “It&#39;s been publicly sticking to its promises to engage all sides in dialogue, and that&#39;s good because it does show the junta that Asean will engage with other stakeholders even if the Myanmar military does not want it to.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The delay in the release of a joint document is believed to be due to disagreements on the wording of the section about Myanmar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The document published on the Asean website on Friday morning referred to the Thai overtures. It noted that that “a number” of Asean states viewed Bangkok&#39;s activities as a “positive development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We reaffirmed Asean unity and reiterated that any effort should support, in line with the Five Point Consensus and in coordination with the Chair of Asean,” the statement said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Malaysia, a vocal critic of the junta, earlier urged Asean to strongly condemn the junta&#39;s actions, including violence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I pressed for a stronger statement on this issue to be included in the joint communique of the Asean ministerial meeting,” Foreign Minister Zambry Abdul Kadir said in a statement late on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Is outgoing Thai government &#39;setting the tone&#39; for next PM with Myanmar talks?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lina Alexandra, head of the department of international relations with the Centre for Strategic and International Studies Indonesia, suggested there were divisions among countries about the Five-Point Consensus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some Asean member states are clearly raising the issue of Myanmar fatigue, about normalising [ties with] the junta,” she said. “Indonesia, Malaysia, and Singapore are really opposed to this idea, because the junta is the culprit. What&#39;s the point of having the Five-Point Consensus?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia, which will hand over the reins of Asean chairmanship to Laos at the end of the year, has faced criticism over its intense behind-the-scenes efforts to broker talks not bearing fruit. However, observers such as Marston held a contrary view, noting its engagements with previously out-of-reach groups and the setting up of a dedicated office of special envoy to Myanmar in Jakarta.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts have called for the bloc to explore other avenues, including extending the term of a special envoy to Myanmar beyond one year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[WHO says aspartame sweetener ‘possibly carcinogenic’, but safe in limited quantities]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3227631/who-says-aspartame-sweetener-possibly-carcinogenic-safe-limited-quantities?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 09:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/14/afdb41f7-8d17-4f97-a7c5-c13ad3fcdd71_1efb6245.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The WHO said on Friday it was now classifying aspartame, an artificial sweetener commonly used in soft drinks, as “possibly carcinogenic to humans” – though the acceptable daily intake level remains unchanged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re not advising companies to withdraw products, nor are we advising consumers to stop consuming altogether,” said Francesco Branca, the World Health Organization&#39;s nutrition and food safety director.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re just advising for a bit of moderation,” he told a press conference presenting the findings of two reviews of available evidence on aspartame.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The WHO&#39;s International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC) carried out its first-ever evaluation of the carcinogenicity of aspartame at a meeting in Lyon, France, from June 6 to 13.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The working group classified aspartame as possibly carcinogenic to humans,” the WHO said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was placed in category Group 2B, based on the limited evidence available, which specifically concerned hepatocellular carcinoma – a type of liver cancer.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;If aspartame is declared unsafe, we may need to retrain our taste buds&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;There was also limited-strength evidence regarding cancer in experimental animals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Group 2B category also contains extract of aloe vera and caffeic acid found in tea and coffee, said Paul Pharoah, a professor of cancer epidemiology at the Cedars-Sinai Medical Center in Los Angeles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The general public should not be worried about the risk of cancer associated with a chemical classed as Group 2B,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The IARC&#39;s Mary Schubauer-Berigan said the limited evidence for hepatocellular carcinoma came from three studies, conducted in the United States and across 10 European countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These are the only epidemiological studies that examined liver cancer,” she told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Branca added: “We have, in a sense, raised a flag here, indicating that we need to clarify much more the situation,” but nor is it “something which we can dismiss”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A second group, JECFA – the Joint Expert Committee on Food Additives formed by the WHO and its fellow UN agency the Food and Agriculture Organization – met in Geneva from June 27 to July 6 to evaluate the risks associated with aspartame.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It concluded that the data it evaluated indicated no reason to change the acceptable daily intake (ADI), established in 1981, of zero to 40 milligrammes of aspartame per kilogram of body weight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With a can of sugar-free soft drink typically containing 200 or 300mg of aspartame sweetener, an adult weighing 70kg would therefore need to consume more than nine to 14 cans per day to exceed the ADI, assuming no additional aspartame intake from other sources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The problem is for high consumers,” said Branca.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong food safety experts urge calm over &#39;possibly carcinogenic&#39; sweetener&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Somebody who drinks a soda every once in a while … shouldn&#39;t have a concern.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aspartame is an artificial chemical sweetener widely used in various food and drink products from the 1980s onwards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is found in diet drinks, chewing gum, gelatin, ice cream, dairy products such as yogurt, breakfast cereals, toothpaste, cough drops and chewable vitamins.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The International Sweeteners Association said that Group 2B classification puts aspartame in the same category as kimchi and other pickled vegetables.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“JECFA has once again reaffirmed aspartame&#39;s safety after conducting a thorough, comprehensive and scientifically rigorous review,” said ISA chief Frances Hunt-Wood.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for Camille Dorioz, campaign manager at the consumer organisation Foodwatch, Friday&#39;s update leaves a “bitter taste”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A possibly carcinogenic sweetener has no place in our food and drink,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Back in May, the WHO said artificial sweeteners, used to replace sugar in a vast range of products, do not help in losing weight and can have serious health effects.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China natural sweetener stocks gain on report aspartame is possibly carcinogenic&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The UN health agency released guidelines advising against using so-called non-sugar sweeteners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Branca was asked about what consumers should do in the light of Friday&#39;s update, when trying to choose what was best between a soft drink with added sugar, and one with added sweeteners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There should be a third option considered, which is to drink water instead – and to limit the consumption of sweetened products altogether,” he replied.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are alternatives that do not contain either free sugars or sweeteners – and those should be the products that should be preferred by consumers.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Doggone it! Pet owner in China slashes US$1.4 million reward for return of lost dog to  US$690 after it is found, sparking anger  online]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3227288/doggone-it-pet-owner-china-slashes-us14-million-reward-return-lost-dog-us690-after-it-found-sparking?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/13/3fa54c09-7b38-49a1-8afa-1567f9df39ce_94cae999.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一位狗主人承诺悬赏1000万元人民币（140万美元） ）谁找到了他丢失的宠物，但他食言，只给了几千元钱，这在社交媒体上引发了争议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;失主杨某于7月9日发布公告称，他八岁的宠物“天狼”（他说是一只退役军犬）前一天晚上在河南省省会郑州北龙湖地区附近失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了鼓励大家帮忙，杨某做出了丰厚的悬赏承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“提供重要线索的，悬赏200万元。”如果狗被找到并安全归还，将悬赏1000万元。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨说，天朗除了是亲密的家人之外，“为国家做出了贡献” ”并警告说，如果有人伤害了这只狗，“我们将不惜一切代价讨回公道。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一悬赏措施在郑州引起了广泛关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据济南日报新闻集团报道，当地微信群里一条广为流传的帖子称，很多人都前往北龙湖寻找这只动物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月9日下午3点40分，一名群友声称已经找到了这只狗，随后该消息被证实。郑州流浪动物收养中心在微博上证实了这一消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，尽管这只狗失踪不到一天就被找到，但主人却没有兑现承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道一位知情人士向河南广播电台透露，狗主人只向发现它的人提供了 5000 元人民币（690 美元）的奖励。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“狗主人用了 1000 万元人民币作为噱头，但无论是200万还是1000万，这都是不可能的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚杨关于这只狗服兵役的说法是否属实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事件导致杨某被警方行政拘留15天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有关悬赏的话题标签在微博上获得了3亿的浏览量，许多社交媒体观察人士表示愤怒&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人与人之间的信任已经完全被破坏了！”一位评论者表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种悬赏通知没有法律效力吗？去告他吧！” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这只是个玩笑”，还有人反驳道，“即使提起诉讼，法院也不会支持1000万的悬赏！”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;天津国浩律师事务所合伙人、前检察官张永泉告诉《早报》，业主的行为构成违约，但在实践中很难执行该协议。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“虽然可以要求履行合同，但业主也可以以合同明显不公平为由主张调整。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据常识和核心价值观，一只狗不可能有这么高的价值。法院很可能会接受这一辩护。”张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“毕竟，在中国，一只狗的售价高达数千万元，会产生非常负面的社会影响。 Therefore, the case is likely to end with the citizen accepting 5,000 yuan and not pursuing further legal action,” the lawyer added.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 09:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s status as international city high on agenda at Financial Secretary Paul Chan’s talks in Beijing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3227620/hong-kongs-status-international-city-high-agenda-financial-secretary-paul-chans-talks-beijing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.14 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/13/68f5c21a-67b3-4983-86a2-dbc5e6fbfb0b_1b5dc384.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港作为国际金融中心推动国家发展的作用一直受到高度重视本周，北京高级官员与财政司长陈茂波讨论了这一议程，一些分析人士表示，这是中央政府对香港事务更加亲力亲为的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些分析人士还表示他们认为，在全球政治局势依然紧张的情况下，北京方面担心该市的经济发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;成龙于周四结束的为期三天的北京之行引起了媒体的关注，财政部长夏宝龙会见了他， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈也是新一届中共中央港澳工作办公室周二召开第一次会议以来第一位会见夏的香港官员。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;北京半官方智库中华港澳研究会顾问刘兆佳教授表示，他认为夏与陈会面也是为了展示中央的全面管辖权。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该教授表示：“除了听取陈的报告外，夏可能还向陈提供了一些实际指导。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港政府在事件发生后发布的新闻声明这次会议让公众难得一睹此类高层会议的细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三的声明称，陈肇始“向[夏]详细报告了香港和香港的最新经济和民生状况。巩固和提升香港国际金融中心地位的策略和工作……以及下半年举行的大型国际会议的筹备进展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[夏】会议表示，中央将支持香港在“一国两制”原则下继续发挥独特地位和优势，维护良好的国际营商环境，为经济增长创造强劲动力，并为国家高质量发展做出贡献。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位资深中国观察家刘锐兆表示，他也有类似的观点，并补充道：“并不是说北京对香港的经济发展并不满意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但当美国可能对中国施加更大压力来打压中国时，北京可能希望香港为其经济遭受的直接或附带损害做好更好的准备。香港也有可能需要与中央协调应对。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他解释说，北京可能不希望香港经济如此严重依赖西方，应该进一步探索与中东或东盟国家等其他市场的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的 Paul Chan 在上海之行吸引科技公司后暗示“好消息”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;其地位从国家提升国务院港澳事务办公室（港澳办）是夏的新工作办公室，是在三月份批准党和国家机构改革后设立的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新办公室行使中央政府对香港和澳门的管辖权， ”香港政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘教授表示，他相信中央政府可能不想表明陈在那里向党汇报，而是向国家汇报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈周四还表示会见国家发展和改革委员会副主任丛良Chan briefed Cong on the city&#39;s situation in finance, the economy and innovation and technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They also had an in-depth conversation on a variety of topics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These included Hong Kong&#39;s progress in realising its position on the international stage in several areas as outlined in the National 14th Five-year Plan, and the promotion of deeper economic integration into the Greater Bay Area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong government statement said the city&#39;s contribution to the development of the Belt and Road Initiative, a plan to link a variety of economies, was also discussed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Mild&#39; growth for Hong Kong in first quarter amid upbeat outlook: Paul Chan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chan last visited Beijing in April, when he called on the HKMAO deputy director Yang Wanming and also discussed Hong Kong&#39;s economic development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It can be expected that Chan or other senior Hong Kong officials will need to visit Beijing more often to update the central authorities on the city&#39;s latest situation,” Professor Lau predicted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tam Yiu-chung, the city&#39;s former sole delegate to the country&#39;s top legislative body, the National People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee, said it was national policy to maintain and enhance Hong Kong&#39;s international status.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The National 14th Five-Year Plan already stated that the central authorities would support Hong Kong to enhance its status as an international financial centre and deepen and expand the connectivity between the mainland and Hong Kong&#39;s financial markets,” Tam said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also highlighted President Xi Jinping&#39;s address last July at the inaugural ceremony for John Lee&#39;s administration, where he emphasised that “Hong Kong&#39;s close connection with the world market and strong support from the motherland are its distinctive advantages”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Simon Lee Siu-po, an economist and honorary fellow at the Asia-Pacific Institute of Business at Chinese University, agreed it was important to China for Hong Kong to remain an international city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The mainland needs foreign investment and Hong Kong needs to maintain its super-connector role to attract investment to China,” he explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he added that did not mean that Hong Kong should follow too closely some mainland Chinese measures, such as the zero Covid policy and the ban on some Japanese food products amid concern about nuclear contaminated water from the ill-fated Fukushima nuclear plant, which could damage Hong Kong&#39;s status as an international city.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 14 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>