<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Indonesia President Joko Widodo reassures Singapore investors of returns on beleaguered new capital city Nusantara]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223289/indonesia-president-joko-widodo-reassures-singapore-investors-returns-beleaguered-new-capital-city?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 21:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/0eba734a-512f-498c-ae64-58dc8f95cdbb_e0980c9e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三，印度尼西亚总统佐科维多多为他的国家新的 32 美元-十亿首都城市向新加坡投资者开放，这是吸引资金进入迄今为止未能吸引大笔投资的项目的最新尝试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在新加坡淡马锡控股主办的以可持续发展为重点的会议上发言时，总统向有意在婆罗洲岛丛林中建设城市努桑塔拉的投资者提供了价值 26 亿美元的 300 个开发配套，并承诺高回报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一切都会好起来的，不用担心，你的印度尼西亚的投资将继续安全，并且 Nusantara 首都的发展 [将] 连续，”Jokowi 说道，正如他所熟知的那样，同时展示了计划中的未来城市的图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所以鉴于明年的大选和总统选举中预期的权力交接，投资者担心该项目的可行性和未来，到目前为止，还没有签署任何投资协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nusantara 将成为东南部的首府明年将成为亚洲最大的经济体，取代该国拥挤但活跃的商业和政治中心雅加达。佐科威在其两个任期内将基础设施发展作为优先事项，在执政十年后准备明年卸任时，他将这个项目视为他遗产的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他曾表示，他最期待的是由私营部门资助的城市，政府在 3 月推出了一系列激励措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nusantara 当局主席 Bambang Susantono 在同一个论坛上表示，为该项目提供资金将是有利可图的，理由是 11投资该市电力系统的潜在回报率为 % 至 13%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自韩国、日本、中国、德国和阿拉伯联合酋长国的投资者正在进行尽职调查，上周又有约 100 人访问了努桑塔拉，他说，但没有详细说明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到明年，预计将有大约 16,000 名公务员、军人和警察搬到努桑塔拉。政府大楼的建设正在进行中，但截至 3 月，现场只看到工人临时安置点。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Democrats’ disastrous US debt ceiling deal snatches defeat from jaws of victory]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3223234/democrats-disastrous-us-debt-ceiling-deal-snatches-defeat-jaws-victory?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/b0d20ac7-7734-471e-a766-8ee09b55332c_863bdab4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;有一个关于两党合作的可恶的美国政治神话，根据这个神话，痛苦的对手，伤痕累累通过战斗，找到共同点，携手并肩漫步到夕阳下。这主要是胡说八道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Appomattox 之后，尤利西斯·格兰特 (Ulysses S. Grant) 没有与罗伯特·李 (Robert E. Lee) 和解。富兰克林·罗斯福在大萧条期间没有与赫伯特·胡佛和解，约翰·肯尼迪在 1960 年大选后也没有与理查德·尼克松和解。人们确实听到了罗纳德·里根和蒂普·奥尼尔交换花言巧语的甜蜜回忆。但真正的奥尼尔在原则和政治上竭尽全力与里根抗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔拜登最近在犯下令人震惊的行为后赞扬了众议院议长凯文麦卡锡政治投降——在税收执法、社会计划、学生债务、环境等方面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最糟糕的是，拜登放弃了债务上限不应阻碍未来进步优先事项的原则。但我们被告知，一切都很好，因为拜登和麦卡锡一起解决了问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但白宫和财政部至少有三种貌似合法、完全符合宪法的方式来化解假想的危机，而无需麦卡锡参与以及他越来越精神错乱的共和党核心小组。政府本可以铸造一枚高价值的铂金硬币并将其存放在美国联邦储备委员会，诉诸永远不会到期的统一债券，或发行溢价债券。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，他们从战壕中走出来，挥舞着白旗，并以讨价还价的方式卖掉了他们要塞的钥匙——所有这些都是为了让围攻的军队消失几年。更糟糕的是，民主党人知道共和党军队内部分裂且叛变。拜登表明，当他正确地告诉他们，在他们第一次接近时迷路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但还有一个更大的事实，没有人愿意承认：共和党人的大炸弹总是哑弹。根据法律，财政部不能停止或优先支付。财政部长珍妮特·耶伦和她的前任们早就强调了这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使你超过了“限度”，支票也必须发出。债务上限只会阻止财政部发行新债券。在最坏的情况下，美联储的财政部总账户将没有足够的资金来支付支票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到那时，美联储可能会发放信贷额度——透支——以确保付款得到兑现.无担保、无利息、隔夜透支不在债务上限范围内，并且可以说是一种合法的可能性。美联储自己的记录表明，此事将由其理事会决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题最终可能会在法庭上得到检验，但那又怎样？如果美联储如此决定，或者如果法院如此下令，其中一些财政部支票可能会反弹，成为对财政部的无担保债权。如果银行拒绝兑现，美联储需要多长时间才能恳求国会解决“危机”？我怀疑这种情况会在第二天开市前发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果违反债务上限真的有“灾难”的风险，那么责任应该归咎于那些决定大肆宣传的共和党人，并且他们几乎肯定会弃牌。如果与所有逻辑相反，他们选择了政治自杀，那么对民主党人来说就更好了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论哪种方式，白宫都握有大炮，但它仍然投降了。拜登的顾问似乎并不特别在意所做的让步，而且至少有些人有充分的经济理由避免违约的后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;让我们来看看这种情况。假设麦卡锡的势力坚守，拜登不投降，美联储发放透支，政治僵局持续下去。即便如此，生活仍会正常进行，只是到期国债将以现金偿还，因为它们将不再展期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;债券持有人可能不喜欢这样，他们可能会用现金购买别的东西。正如希拉里·克林顿在《纽约时报》中警告的那样，国际美元将会贬值，这意味着以国际美元为生的极少数精英将受到更大的打击。对于美国其他地区，这将类似于罗斯福于 1933 年暂停金本位制并推出新政。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国工业将变得更具竞争力，工业和制造业工作岗位将开始回归。尽管美元贬值是有代价的，但必须权衡利弊。此外，无论如何，美元都会走软。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“灾难”情景从一开始就是荒谬的。这确实与民主党的性格有关。它会继续迎合大型金融机构，还是会被迫代表自己的选民和美国人民的利益？&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;支持美国债务上限协议的主流共和党人欢迎理智的迹象&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;如果拜登再次当选，国会民主党人将在2025年再次面临同样的选择。他们可以同意更多的让步，再次躲在“两党合作”的花言巧语背后，也可以最终拒绝屈服于勒索。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果拜登被击败呢？共和党人将在联邦计划、法规、税收和债务上限方面为所欲为。最近的不光彩事件使这种结果更有可能发生。毕竟，谁需要一个不会为自己或其选民挺身而出的民主党？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple’s AirDrop in focus as China moves to restrict Wi-fi, Bluetooth file-sharing over ‘national security’ concerns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3223303/apples-airdrop-focus-china-moves-restrict-wi-fi-bluetooth-file-sharing-over-national-security?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 20:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/c51fe8ea-8d92-4952-bcaf-53b785bd699e_841a132e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;为了“国家安全”，中国正计划规范附近移动设备之间的文件共享原因，此举预计会影响此类通信应用程序的使用，例如 Apple 的 AirDrop。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国最高互联网监管机构发布的草案，新规定旨在限制任何“文件”的使用依托 Wi-Fi、蓝牙等信息技术即时组网并与其他设备进行近距离通信的传输服务”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家互联网信息办公室 (CAC) 发布了法规草案周二在其网站上发布了针对此事的为期一个月的公众咨询。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CAC 的举措是北京“维护国家安全”的最新举措。文件共享服务 AirDrop（可在 iPhone 和其他 Apple 设备上使用）在去年冬天反对大陆严格的零 Covid 限制的公开示威期间以及在 2019 年香港的反政府抗议活动中被使用。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;近年来其他公司推出的类似近距离无线通信功能包括 Google 的 Files by Google 和 Google Android 操作系统上的 Fast Share。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国手机制造商 Vivo、小米和 Oppo 也提供此类文件传输服务&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法规规定，如果科技公司希望包含任何可用于“公开表达和社会动员”的功能，则它们必须接受安全评估。此类功能的所有用户也必须实名注册。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据上海华东政法大学法学教授高福平介绍，实名注册要求旨在尽管中国在十年前就推出了网络活动实名制，但对于 AirDrop 等网络传输服务，内容控制“填补了一个漏洞”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这主要是关于网络安全，以及核心目标是确保在发生问题时可以跟踪所有信息传输，”高说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple 的 AirDrop 功能于 2011 年推出，是一种通过 Wi 与附近用户共享文件的便捷工具-fi 或蓝牙，无需依赖互联网连接。图片可以匿名分享，AirDrop 只显示附近手机的昵称，用户无法识别发件人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;条例草案还规定，此类“近距离网状网络”服务提供商“保存相关记录”，一旦发现“违法信息”或“传播有害信息”，将及时向互联网监管部门报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但并未详细说明哪些信息属于违法或有害信息。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据科技市场追踪机构 CounterPoint Research 的最新数据，Apple 的 iPhone 占据了中国大陆移动设备市场份额的五分之一和香港市场份额的一半左右。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 11 月，抗议活动在中国多个城市爆发，抗议活动与政府严厉的零 Covid 封锁、边境关闭、大规模检测和严格隔离政策有关。西方媒体报道称，AirDrop 当时被用来分享反政府图片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当月早些时候，在更新其操作系统时，Apple 对通过所有 iPhone 交换 AirDrop 内容施加了 10 分钟的时间限制在中国大陆销售。这被视为防止中国 iPhone 用户逃避该国严格的网络审查的举措。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然苹果公司没有解释为什么做出这样的改变，但它是在一名抗议者——后来被昵称为“桥人”之后不久发生的”——在北京的一座桥上展开两条横幅，呼吁结束严厉的 Covid-19 政策并批评执政的共产党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然互联网审查员屏蔽了抗议活动的内容，但据报道照片被泄露通过 AirDrop 在中国公众中分享。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，在 2019 年香港反政府抗议活动期间，年轻的活动人士使用 AirDrop 在地铁和其他公共场所发送信息，邀请公众加入&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学法学副教授 Angela Zhang 表示，北京的最新收紧措施“共同旨在加强 CAC 对 [互联网] 内容和信息传播的控制”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她也指出，新规不太可能对整个科技行业产生重大影响，因为它们主要针对的是 AirDrop 功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple 中国大陆总部没有立即回复置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北京誓言打击“敌对势力”，但未提及抗议&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;CAC 规则草案还要求科技公司设定“接收关闭”作为此类功能的默认设置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;快照预览也必须被禁用，除非用户同意。当前的 AirDrop 设置允许向用户发送被视为敏感或明确的信息，但他们可以选择接受或拒绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，有人呼吁像 Apple 这样的大型科技公司修改 AirDrop 等功能，以避免潜在的滥用，因为罪犯可以通过共享露骨图片轻松骚扰用户，这对性侵犯幸存者来说尤其容易触发。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 21:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Europe’s No 2 chip maker STMicroelectronics to form US$3.2 billion semiconductor joint venture with China’s Sanan Optoelectronics in Chongqing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3223287/europes-no-2-chip-maker-stmicroelectronics-form-us32-billion-semiconductor-joint-venture-chinas?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/21cb40da-6961-486e-a370-e3b63ab639b9_32fa77ac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧洲第二大芯片制造商意法半导体 (STM) 和中国公司三安光电周三表示，他们已同意在西南部城市重庆成立一家价值 32 亿美元的半导体合资企业，以支持国内对电动汽车、工业电力和能源领域对碳化硅 (SiC) 器件不断增长的需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该交易涉及创建一个新的 200 毫米 SiC 设备制造业务，该业务将于 2025 年第四季度投产，预计 2028 年全面建成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国正在快速走向电气化意法半导体总裁兼首席执行官让-马克切里在周三发布的声明中表示： “与重要的本地合作伙伴一起创建专门的代工厂是满足中国客户不断增长的需求的最有效方式。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家新企业的资金将来自意法半导体和三安光电，以及当地政府的支持根据声明，以及向合资企业提供贷款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，三安光电将使用自有的 SiC 衬底工艺，单独建设和运营一个新的 200mm SiC 衬底制造工厂，以满足合资企业的要求。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SiC是当代最重要的先进陶瓷之一，是由硅和碳组成的半导体基础材料。历史上，制造商在轴承、加热机械部件、汽车制动器甚至磨刀工具等设备的高温环境中使用 SiC。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，SiC 已成为半导体行业的一股力量。应用于金属氧化物半导体场效应晶体管、电源模块等芯片。 SiC 器件现已广泛应用于电动汽车、轨道交通以及风能和太阳能应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意法半导体在中国主要制造基地重庆的新合资企业凸显了中国在保持强大实力方面的努力“传统半导体”——定义为采用 28 纳米或更早工艺技术制造的芯片——在美国贸易制裁限制大陆获得先进集成电路和芯片制造设备的情况下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三安光电首席执行官西蒙Lin 表示，与 STMicroelectronics 的合资企业有望成为“中国市场广泛采用 SiC 器件的主要推动力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的制造合资企业的完成需要获得监管部门的批准，据声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于瑞士的 STMicroelectronics 已在中国开展业务约四十年，尽管华盛顿和北京之间的技术战不断升级，但它已采取行动加深与世界第二大经济体的联系。&lt;/p>; p&lt;p>;据官方报纸《经济日报》当月报道，在中国庞大的电动汽车市场对半导体需求快速增长的情况下，公司总裁奇瑞在去年 12 月访问中国期间表达了意法半导体对中国的承诺.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国汽车工业协会的数据，去年中国新能源汽车销量几乎翻了一番，达到 690 万辆，连续八年位居世界前列。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 21:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping calls for greater efforts to fight desertification after climate change leads to spike in dust clouds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3223297/chinese-president-xi-jinping-calls-greater-efforts-fight-desertification-after-climate-change-leads?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/18143f67-051f-4140-bf0d-3f2319886e1c_b412193e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国国家主席习近平呼吁加大力度应对荒漠化，他警告说由于气候变化，袭击该国北部的尘云数量有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平在周一和周二视察内蒙古时发表了上述评论，称该国在防止气候变化方面取得了显着进展&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去两年，受气候变化影响，我国北方沙尘天气事件增多，”习近平周二表示，根据对国家通讯社新华社说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然中国的荒漠化防治工作显示出“全面和加速的改善”，但他警告说，大面积地区仍然受到影响，并敦促官员们明白，这需要“长期、艰巨的努力” ，重复性和不确定性”的努力来解决这个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着 5 月高温打破记录，亚洲气候问题加剧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2023 年前四个月，中国北方发生了 11 起沙尘事件– 国家气候中心副主任贾小龙今年早些时候表示，这是过去十年中同期数量最多的一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中三起事件被归类为沙尘暴，其中一起发生在据新华社报道，3 月 19 日至 23 日发生的风暴是本世纪有记录以来的第三强风暴，影响面积超过 485 万平方公里（190 万平方英里）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月初的另一场沙尘暴席卷了超过20 个省份，受影响面积达 460 万平方公里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月发表在同行评审期刊《大气科学进展》上的一项中国研究发现，蒙古和中国最大的沙漠——新疆的塔克拉玛干沙漠，是中国北方沙尘的两个主要来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年春天，它表示扬尘和沙尘吹过与蒙古的边界造成了 42% 的沙尘浓度，而塔克拉玛干则贡献了 26% .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究发现，增强的蒙古气旋和冷锋是沙尘事件的关键因素，将沙尘带南下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国北方已受到沙尘暴影响几十年来，但近年来由于控制工程，事件的频率和强度有所下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国面临扩大碳排放权交易的呼声&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国实施了大绿色1978 年的 Wall 项目，目标是在宽达 4,800 公里乘以 1,500 公里（3,000 乘以 900 英里）的地带种植约 8,800 万英亩的森林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划 - 正式名称为三北防护林工程——旨在将该地区的森林覆盖率从 1978 年的 5% 提高到 2050 年的 15%，到 2019 年已达到 13.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马军，北京-非营利组织公共与环境事务研究所表示，在过去的二十年中，沙尘事件的频率和强度一直在下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这不仅是因为绿色长城项目的实施，还有其他政策，例如绿色换粮计划，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;绿色换粮计划于 1999 年制定，政府出资让农民在自己的土地上植树，以对抗森林砍伐.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在访问内蒙古期间，习主席表示，这十年对于治沙工作至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[我们应该]用 10 年时间建设三北防护林工程建成功能完备、牢不可破的北方绿色长城和生态安全屏障，”习近平说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还强调了提高沙漠生态系统质量和稳定性的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中蒙荒漠化防治荒漠化 中蒙联手防治荒漠化 &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;马云说，中国从以往的荒漠化防治工作中吸取了教训，可以与其他国家分享。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“例如，应该根据当地的生态情况，将树木、灌木和草地结合起来——而不是仅仅种植树木，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国有大约 250 万平方公里的地下土地荒漠化，治沙工作难度大，不能放松。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 21:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong civil service chief appeals to staff to sign up as organ donors and give the gift of life]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3223306/hong-kong-civil-service-chief-appeals-staff-sign-organ-donors-and-give-gift-life?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 21:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/6dc9239e-71be-47d2-a069-0bb1afebf769_9a1036ee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港当局已呼吁超过 173,000 名公务员报名成为器官捐献者在从登记册中撤回的人数激增之后，市领导称这是为了“破坏”该系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公务员事务局局长杨何佩欣周三在致政府工作人员的一封信中呼吁在中央器官捐赠登记处登记并告知他们的家人他们的决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举是在卫生当局发现申请从上次登记中除名的人数“异常增加”之​​后做出的12 月，政府透露有意与中国大陆建立捐赠机制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官员表示，在过去几个月收到的 5,785 份撤回申请中，有 2,900 多份被发现无效，因为这些申请是由&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方逮捕了四名男子，他们未经同意以他人的名义提交了一些提款申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨在邮报看到的信中说： “香港每天有超过2000名病人和家属在等待器官捐献。令人遗憾的是，许多患者在得到合适的器官配型和移植之前就去世了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，获得广大社区对器官捐献的积极支持非常重要，以期为这些患者带来希望&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我诚挚地邀请同事们响应号召，在中央器官捐赠名册登记，并告诉家人您的意愿。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还告诉十多年前，当她在卫生福利及食物局任职公务员时，一位母亲在儿子车祸身亡后，虽然悲痛欲绝，但仍决定捐献器官，令她“深受感动” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然香港的器官移植成功率很高，但我们需要有这样无私和富有同情心的捐献者和家人，才能造福有需要的病人，”杨写道。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;h3>;香港器官捐献名册受撤回申请浪潮冲击&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;卫生局局长罗仲茂周三在立法会的活动中表示，许多等待移植名单的人都在生死边缘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，看到“极少数”人干预器官捐赠登记册，他感到很痛心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港 7.4 人中约有 5%百万人口 - 370,000 人 - 已登记为捐献者，卢说还有改善的空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会主席梁君源补充说，散布有关器官捐献计划的谣言是一种表现出“别有用心的行为”没有良心”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这四名年龄在 19 至 47 岁之间的人因撤回而被捕，据称他们取消了登记，其中包括政府官员、立法者、艺术家和已经去世的人的登记。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方当时表示，不排除进一步逮捕的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港卫生局局长警告称，警方将打击器官捐献谣言&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;行政长官John Lee Ka-chiu 周二表示，他“担心”似乎旨在破坏器官捐赠计划的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，这种行为让他想起了 2019 年反政府抗议活动期间发生的事件，这座城市的“颜色革命”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须谴责这些无耻行径。政府也将追究他们的法律责任，”Lee 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee 强调，自 2008 年设立登记册以来，登记为捐助者的人数稳步增加。2009 年有 45,000 人登记。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港目前有一个“选择加入”的捐赠制度，人们必须同意在他们死后才允许使用他们的器官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些国家，如新加坡和奥地利，使用“选择退出”系统，除非个人另有说明，否则假定同意。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 21:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘It’s scary’: New York has world’s worst air quality as Canada wildfires rage]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223294/its-scary-new-york-has-worlds-worst-air-quality-canada-wildfires-rage?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 20:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/abccd877-34ce-4c61-948c-e4a105eef905_4e8def6c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二晚上，纽约是世界上污染最严重的主要城市，烟雾据 IQAir 网站称，加拿大野火造成的雾霾笼罩了这座城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这座城市的污染水平被认为处于“不健康”范围内，高于新德里、印度和巴格达的污染水平, 伊朗凌晨 1:25。据瑞士空气质量公司称，纽约时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国。当局发布空气质量警报。据报道，从克利夫兰到布法罗的五大湖地区出现了雾霾和野火产生的烟雾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约市市长埃里克·亚当斯周二晚间在一份声明中表示，已向所有人发布空气质量健康警告五个行政区，虽然预计情况会在周三上午有所改善，但预计当天晚些时候会再次恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“出于谨慎考虑，我们正在采取预防措施，以保护纽约人的健康，直到我们能够更好地了解未来的空气质量报告，”亚当斯说。 “我们建议所有纽约人尽可能限制户外活动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国纽约空气质量指数在凌晨 1:05 达到 0-500 的 222，使空气处于“非常不健康”类别。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二大部分时间笼罩在纽约市上空的烟雾在下午晚些时候变浓，遮住了哈德逊河对岸新泽西州的景色，使夕阳看起来像红色的球体。在费城地区，黄昏带来了更多的薰衣草雾霾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布鲁克林的 Sal 和 Lilly Murphy 将这种燃烧的气味比作篝火。他们说，他们甚至可以在曼哈顿的一家餐厅里闻到室内的烟味，然后走到外面，看到天空看起来像是要下暴风雨——但没有下雨。 Lilly 戴着口罩进行保护。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在“前所未有的”野火情况下，加拿大西部有数千人撤离&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这有点可怕，”Sal Murphy 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数周以来，大火产生的烟雾已经飘过美国东北部各州，但直到最近才在大多数地方引起人们的注意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果燃烧速度继续保持不变，加拿大将迎来有史以来最严重的野火季节步伐。政府官员说，到目前为止，大约有 330 万公顷（820 万英亩）的土地被烧毁。目前约有 413 处火灾正在燃烧，26,000 名加拿大人被迫撤离家园。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 20:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan’s tech industry not ‘hollowing out’ as chips head to US, AmCham says, but exports offer weak support]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3223285/taiwans-tech-industry-not-hollowing-out-chips-head-us-amcham-says-exports-offer-weak-support?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 20:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/07/d2952e9d-e9d5-4fa6-a735-03d553d7bba6_b2effa0f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;担心如果投资“错位”，台湾产业将空心化台湾美国商会周三表示，因为大公司可能会将他们的研究、开发和最先进的生产留在岛上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但出口连续第九个月下降表明高科技硬件公司——自 1980 年代以来台湾经济的支柱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以全球最大的代工芯片制造商和最先进技术的保持者台积电 (TSMC) 为首的科技巨头已经在过去的五年中，一直在逐渐进入美国，以满足美国政府的要求，即供应商离客户更近，并刺激美国经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“某些方面担心科技行业在美国的投资拥有 529 家会员的美国商会在其《2023 年台湾白皮书》中表示，“将导致台湾产业‘空心化’”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台积电等肯定会保持核心研发和最技术先进的国内生产，而海外投资将有助于确保他们在全球供应链中的持续强势地位，并与客户建立更紧密的关系，”该报称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高科技占近三分之一台湾经济，并使该岛在世界个人电脑、智能手机和其他普通电子产品的制造供应链中发挥核心作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾的科技公司表示他们没有离开的计划。公司领导指出，他们在台湾的员工可以在全球范围内找到客户，并利用国内供应链来满足他们的任何需求。 Operational costs are higher in the US, and many firms already outsource to factories in mainland China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yomura, for example, has done casting, tooling and assembly of electronics near its suburban Taipei base for 32 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US and Taiwan sign first agreement under new trade initiative&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;It plans to build a new plant by 2025 to keep up with anti-pollution regulations, though business has declined over the past two years, senior sales and product manager Wu Heng-hua said, adding that clients still approach Yomura from Europe, Japan and the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Taiwan, he said, “at least this is no risk if you just obey the rules and pay the taxes”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan-based Famous Computer, a 34-year-old designer of fan-less cases, plans to expand at home rather than overseas to keep using Taiwan&#39;s “mature” supply chain, company business department representative Lai Hsueh-lee said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most Taiwanese firms will keep a base in Taiwan if they&#39;re listed on the Taipei stock exchange and mesh with government regulations, said Kent Chong, managing director of professional services firm PwC Legal in Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some companies are considering TSMC&#39;s path to pursue “more agility” and avoid exposing assets in the case of any conflict in Taiwan with mainland China, Chong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mainland sees Taiwan as a breakaway territory that must be united, by force if necessary. Tensions have worsened over the past year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The AmCham white paper urges Taiwanese officials to take advantage of international news coverage during the pandemic “to strengthen itself in every way possible” while Taiwan has the “spotlight”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of the 102 suggestions for Taiwan officials made in a 2022 white paper, AmCham says chamber members consider only eight to be fully resolved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AmCham particularly wants a “reconsideration” of work-hour rules and other labour-policy changes that would help “make Taiwan more attractive to needed foreign professional and technical talent”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US&#39; Taiwan envoy urges Beijing to keep lines open to avert conflict&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The paper – an advocacy tool for American companies – warns that old regulations designed for a “factory environment” are now squelching economic development in a “modern economy driven by innovation and professional expertise”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the factory side of Taiwan&#39;s US$820 billion-plus economy, the finance ministry reported a 14.1 per cent drop in all exports last month, versus May 2022, for a value of US$36.13 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Exports of electronic components, including semiconductors, fell by 9.9 per cent in May compared with a year ago. That export category was Taiwan&#39;s largest last month, at US$15.05 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;World demand for hi-tech hardware such as semiconductors remains weak, especially in mainland China, said Standard Chartered Bank economist Tony Phoo in Taipei. Consumers do not want new electronics, he said, while Beijing is playing up economic self-sufficiency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That could be a reason, possibly, that notebooks and smartphones have not picked up strongly despite China having relaxed its Covid policy,” Phoo said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s May shipments to mainland China and Hong Kong – together its biggest export market – lost 19.4 per cent last month over May 2022, according to ministry data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some Taiwan tech components ship to mainland China for assembly and re-export to the West. The mainland&#39;s exports fell by 7.5 per cent in May compared with a year earlier – hampered by weak demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US-bound shipments from Taiwan fell by 3.5 per cent. US economic growth will slow this year to 0.7 per cent before falling to 0.4 per cent in 2024, The Conference Board research organisation forecasts.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 20:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore PM Lee Hsien Loong ‘finally Covid free’ after testing positive again 6 days ago due to rebound]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223301/singapore-pm-lee-hsien-loong-finally-covid-free-after-testing-positive-again-6-days-ago-due-rebound?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 20:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/07/3f84ca11-31db-47ae-acb1-e8e622e10c7a_83d33345.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Singapore&#39;s Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong said on Wednesday that he is “finally Covid free”, six days after testing positive again for the disease.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee first tested positive for Covid-19 on May 22. He said on May 28 that he was Covid-19 negative and would return to work, before testing positive again on June 1 due to a “Covid rebound”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Delighted to be finally Covid free so I could catch up with Indonesian President Joko Widodo and his wife Ibu Iriana, over a chicken rice lunch today – one of the president&#39;s favourite local delights in Singapore,” said Lee in a Facebook post on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Widodo is in Singapore to speak at the Ecosperity conference, an annual event on sustainable development organised by Temasek.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Prime Minister, who is 71, said on June 1 that his doctors had advised him to isolate until he tested negative. The doctors said his positive test six days ago was due to a “Covid rebound, which happens in 5 to 10 per cent of cases”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He tested positive for the disease for the first time on May 22 following his visits to South Africa and Kenya.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was prescribed the antiviral medication Paxlovid because of his age, and his most recent vaccine booster was in November.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore&#39;s Covid cases are on the rise. Most young kids aren&#39;t fully protected&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) issued a health advisory in May last year about the potential for the recurrence of Covid-19, or Covid rebound.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said a brief return of symptoms may be part of the “natural history” of Covid-19 in some people, independent of treatment with Paxlovid and regardless of vaccination status.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Covid rebound has been reported to occur between two and eight days after initial recovery and is characterised by a recurrence of symptoms or a new positive viral test after having tested negative, added the CDC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 20:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hang Seng Bank and Qianhai joint-venture mutual fund to launch 2 fixed-income products to tap cross-border opportunities in China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3223300/hang-seng-bank-and-qianhai-joint-venture-mutual-fund-launch-two-fixed-income-products-tap-cross?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 20:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/07/5c16c73e-b8d8-439c-b17f-aafd5fc2191c_9f820e2f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hang Seng Qianhai Fund Management, a joint-venture of Hang Seng Bank and local authorities in Shenzhen Qianhai, is launching more diverse products to capture cross-border opportunities in China, particularly the Greater Bay Area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hang Seng Qianhai is 70 per cent owned by Hang Seng Bank and is the first mutual fund in mainland China to be controlled by a Hong Kong entity. It is based in Shenzhen&#39;s Qianhai special economic zone, which serves as a services pilot area for Hong Kong and Shenzhen cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fund is launching two new fixed-income-focused funds on the mainland, according to Liu Yu, its general manager. “We are increasing not only the categories of our products, but also the types of strategies, and continue to expand them,” Liu said in an interview with the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The launches come at a time when new product releases have fallen to an eight-year low in China. Only 34 new funds were rolled out in May, a year-on-year and monthly plunge of more than 60 per cent, according to brokerage Shanghai Securities which cited financial data provider Wind Information. The sales of 31.15 billion shares to retail investors last month also slumped to their lowest level in eight years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hang Seng Qianhai is, however, trying to leverage its background as a pilot initiative of Hong Kong and Shenzhen cooperation to tap record-high savings and increasing demand for wealth management products in the world&#39;s second-largest asset-management industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scale of the two funds is altogether expected to be more than 600 million yuan (US$84.3 million), according to the company. It kicked off the sales of a fund with at least 80 per cent of its allocation to bonds on May 12, and expects to wrap up sales earlier than the fund&#39;s August 11 deadline. The other is a “fixed-income plus” product, with 80 per cent of its allocation to bonds and 20 per cent to stocks and other more liquid bonds.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Bay area special zones to speed up tax, legal incentives for offshore funds&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We will focus on fixed-income this year,” Liu said, adding that bond-focused products had performed relatively better than equity funds amid the volatility of the past few years. It is a “natural choice” because this year&#39;s overall sales of equity funds have proven to be difficult, while fixed-income sales have done better, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese retail investors, who are very sensitive to market volatility, have pulled out of mutual funds in recent weeks after equity markets in the country slid amid geopolitical risks and concerns about the sustainability of China&#39;s economic recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shanghai Composite Index shed 3.6 per cent in May, after a 15.1 per cent slump last year. In Hong Kong, the Hang Seng Index fell 8.4 per cent last month, following a 15.5 per cent drop in 2022. On the bond market front, the yield of China&#39;s 10-year government bonds fell to 2.748 per cent on Wednesday, the lowest level since November 10 last year, in a bull market for the fixed-income space that started mid-April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hang Seng Qianhai&#39;s efforts also come amid fierce competition from domestic players and accelerated expansion by international fund managers. Fidelity International, Neuberger Berman and AllianceBernstein, for instance, are increasing their presence on the mainland by either acquiring full stakes in mixed-ownership entities, or by launching new enterprises.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fund also participates in Hong Kong&#39;s Wealth Management Connect scheme by providing its bond fund products to Hang Seng Bank, through which the lender&#39;s offshore clients can access mainland funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is big potential for overseas and mixed-ownership fund managers to leverage their investments and management expertise in China&#39;s 130 trillion yuan asset-management industry despite short-term difficulties, Liu said. The coming inclusion of equity funds in the Wealth Management Connect is “beneficial” for Hang Seng Qianhai and the fund industry, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong, Shenzhen offer perks to lure venture capital firms to Qianhai&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“But it also poses more challenges for market participants,” Liu said. “After all, equity funds are more volatile, [therefore] the requirements such as in compliance are higher.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 20:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Will Nepal PM’s ‘historic’ India trip, new trade deals, be enough to mend strained ties?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3223273/will-nepal-pms-historic-india-trip-new-trade-deals-be-enough-mend-strained-ties?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.07 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/07/b25f8e36-2cfd-4fd8-9ddc-73e87d37e205_229d71e6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;India and Nepal signed a series of trade deals last week, but that may not be enough to smooth bilateral ties amid a border dispute and growing anti-India sentiment within the landlocked Himalayan country, analysts have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The South Asian neighbours sealed a number of projects – built with Indian aid – during Nepali Prime Minister Pushpa Kumar Dahal&#39;s meeting with his Indian counterpart Narendra Modi, including a 17.4km cross-border railway line connecting Kurthal and Bijalpura.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New Delhi also approved a trilateral power transaction, whereby Nepal will be able to export 40 megawatts of power to Bangladesh via India.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China on their mind: why the India-Nepal border has become a flashpoint&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While Delhi&#39;s approach of providing economic aid was one way to boost ties following years of increasing anti-India sentiment, both sides sidestepped discussions on thorny issues. Analysts said Dahal&#39;s visit did not address many of Nepal&#39;s concerns, despite the prime minister having promised it would be a “historic” trip.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nepal&#39;s priorities were quick implementation of previously agreed projects and agreements, settlement of the border dispute at Kalapani and the Indian help for full operationalisation of the Bhairahawa International Airport,” said Nishchal Pandey, director of the Kathmandu-based Centre for South Asian Studies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“However, the visit has scuttled these primary concerns and dwelt on the peripheral issues more important to India.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two countries have been disputing control over a region called Kalapani, since the 1816 Treaty of Sugauli between Nepal and British India which agreed that the Kali river would form Nepal&#39;s western boundary. Neither side has been able to agree on the origin of the river, and its location – at a trijunction between China, India and Nepal – complicates the issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While both leaders mentioned the dispute during their talks, there was no sign of a resolution. After the visit, Dahal reportedly insisted in the Nepali parliament that he had told Modi “ties between Nepal and India would not return to normal” until the border dispute was resolved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another Kathmandu-based analyst, who did not want to be named, said opposition parties had slammed Dahal&#39;s visit as “underwhelming”, with former prime minister KP Sharma Oli saying Dahal had “failed to speak up to India”. The analyst noted, however, that the trade deals were a boost to Nepal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That sentiment was shared by Sangeeta Thapliyal, a professor at the School of International Studies in the Jawaharlal Nehru University&#39;s Centre for Inner Asian Studies, who said the visit managed to deliver tangible goals for both countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Both countries have emphasised on infrastructure and transport linkages that will further enhance cross border connectivity,” she said. “[The projects] will consolidate moves towards sub-regional economic development and economic interdependence.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Dahal&#39;s four-day visit came days after a controversial mural in the newly inaugurated Indian parliament building caused outrage in Kathmandu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mural, meant to depict ancient India, also includes ancient Nepali towns of historical value, such as Lumbini and Kapilvastu, triggering backlash from Nepali political parties. The row also threatened to reignite the decades-old border dispute.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spokesman from India&#39;s external affairs ministry, however, said Dahal had not raised the mural issue with Modi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mural was the latest in a string of incidents that have soured bilateral ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2015, an undeclared “blockade” backed by Delhi – ostensibly annoyed at not getting its way when the Nepalese constitution was being drafted – left Nepalis struggling for essential items for five months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, under former leader Oli, Nepal released new maps claiming contested territories – including the Kalapani area – as its own, drawing India&#39;s ire.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s belt and road projects set to gain &#39;momentum&#39; as Nepal gets leftist PM&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s move to cut down on the service years of Nepali Gurkha soldiers in its army has also raised Kathmandu&#39;s ire. Under the Agnipath scheme, introduced in June last year, Gurkhas can now only serve a four-year term in the Indian army when they had historically served for much longer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Concerns over the Gurkha soldiers&#39; livelihood had led the Nepali government to ask India to stop recruiting Nepali Gurkhas into the Indian army.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s foreign secretary, Vinay Mohan Kwatra, said the Dahal-Modi talks covered the entire spectrum of bilateral cooperation, including political, economic, trade and development partnership. The Agnipath scheme, he said, was not discussed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dahal, long perceived by India as being pro-China, himself has a chequered history of maintaining ties with Delhi. He visited China instead of India for his first foreign trip as prime minister in 2008, breaking an unspoken tradition. In his third tenure as prime minister, Dahal did make Delhi his first port of call, albeit months after assuming office in December last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Thursday, however, both Dahal and Modi talked up the close bilateral relationship at Delhi&#39;s Hyderabad House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dahal called India a “close neighbour and an important partner”, saying bilateral ties were “age-old and multifaceted”. Modi repaid the sentiment: “We will continue to strive to take our relationship to Himalayan heights.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the border dispute, Dahal said he had discussed the issue with Modi on Thursday. “I urge Prime Minister Modi to resolve the boundary matter through the established, bilateral diplomatic mechanism,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Modi, on his part, said India would work to “resolve all issues, including the boundary matter”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While China did not feature on the discussion agenda, recent events would have put Delhi on alert.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dahal&#39;s trip came as local reports in Kathmandu claimed that the Nepali army was planning to procure defence equipment, including armoured personnel carriers and rifles, from a Chinese supplier, Norinco.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the army dismissed the reports, India was certain to have taken note of it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Delhi is also concerned about a possible move by the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army to induct Nepali Gurkha soldiers into its ranks, a fallout from the Agnipath scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will US, India benefit from Nepal&#39;s latest political shifts at China&#39;s expense?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Last week, during the handover ceremony of a reconstructed hospital built with Chinese assistance in Kathmandu, Dahal hailed Nepal&#39;s ties with China, which he said “date back to time immemorial”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pandey said while Delhi had tried to win Dahal over by offering developmental aid, that might not be enough for the Nepalese back home who were watching this trip closely.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Dahal] had raised the expectation of the Nepalese public by saying this would be a &#39;historic&#39; visit before his departure,” Pandey said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The] general public and the intelligentsia over-read this statement and expected more than what has eventually come out.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 07 Jun 2023 19:50:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>