<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[X, formerly Twitter, lets users hide once-vaunted blue check]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229798/x-formerly-twitter-lets-users-hide-once-vaunted-blue-check?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 07:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/03/df67657a-9402-4641-ad93-869c84e6f8c9_b62d3e98.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;现在将允许社交媒体平台 X（以前称为 Twitter）上的用户该公司表示，这是为了隐藏他们曾经珍贵的蓝色勾号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 收购该公司之前，蓝色支票是 Twitter 上令人垂涎的地位象征，一些人嘲笑蓝色支票，认为这是用户愿意这样做的标志。支付特殊待遇费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为订阅者，您可以选择隐藏帐户上的复选标记，”X 帮助页面周三表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“复选标记将被隐藏在你的个人资料和帖子上。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Twitter 上长期免费的蓝色勾号旨在表明某些用户（例如记者、名人和政客）的身份已经过验证，以建立信任&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但马斯克谴责这是一个“领主与农民系统”，并向任何支付 Blue 订阅费用的人开放了对蜱虫的访问权限——这是一个每月 8 美元的计划，让用户可以访问还有其他特殊功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在人们购买刻度线和冒充包括大亨本人在内的知名人士出现问题后，他迅速暂停了该计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月这位古怪的亿万富翁随后采取了长期承诺的举措，取消 Twitter 用户的免费蓝色勾号。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;勾号，勾号……繁荣：Twitter Blue 注册在虚假帐户混乱后消失&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;一些人称赞此举是平等主义的，而另一些人则谴责此举是为了维护自己在平台上的地位而为了金钱而被勒索。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文字大师斯蒂芬·金（Stephen King）此前发誓他永远不会吐槽，甚至告诉马斯克马斯克在回应当时有关蜱虫的新闻报道时表示，他“付钱给了一张蓝色支票”。 ”，并回复 King 的消息说：“不客气，合十礼。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;X Blue 订阅者可以试图隐藏这一事实的消息促使一名用户发布了一篇帖子，声称马斯克“摧毁了十年前的信任象征，却把它变成了耻辱的标志”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;X 帐户 @ianvisits 的一篇帖子说，“蓝色蜱虫现在毒性如此之大，以至于你可以隐瞒自己有一只蜱虫的事实.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他付费功能（例如超过 280 个字符的帖子）仍可能允许其他用户识别蓝色订阅者，即使他们的蓝色勾号已被隐藏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ X 在其帮助页面上说：“复选标记可能仍会出现在某些地方，并且某些功能仍可能显示您有有效的订阅。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot;最佳&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s natural science fund supports new ‘chiplet’ tech research to advance semiconductor self-sufficiency amid threat of new US sanctions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3229760/chinas-natural-science-fund-supports-new-chiplet-tech-research-advance-semiconductor-self?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/02/6cf8c3e0-0370-4e53-ae26-317e5fe77a20_11e1d5ac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;国家自然科学基金委员会 (NSFC)，国内主要资助来源基础研究和前沿探索，启动了一项新计划，资助数十个专注于“chiplet”技术的项目，这被视为该国在美国制裁下实现半导体自给自足的捷径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据一份报告称，隶属于科学技术部的国家自然科学基金委员会计划为多达 30 个研究项目提供高达 4600 万元人民币（640 万美元）的资助，这些项目将在三到四年内进行。周一在其网站上发布了通知。该公司表示，申请将于 9 月 1 日至 7 日期间接受。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小芯片（Chiplet）是一种预先开发的硅芯片，可以封装成更复杂的处理器，它在大陆引起了很大兴趣，因为它们可以降低设计成本，并且可以甚至提供了延长摩尔定律的解决方案，摩尔定律是指集成电路（IC）上的晶体管数量每两年翻一番。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家自然科学基金委员会最新项目的目标是“开发一项研究基金会的通知称，“在半导体领域培养具有国际影响力的团队，提高中国的自主创新能力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划旨在通过组装的突破，为中国在半导体领域找到“新技术路径”。国家自然科学基金委员会表示，其目的是提高这些设备的性能“一个或两个水平”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它预计将资助研究项目，包括剖析、组合和重用小芯片的方法、半导体设计、三维芯片加工技术和高性能集成电路结构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家自然科学基金委员会的新举措凸显了北京在美国主导的贸易制裁、这已经破坏了大陆在全球供应链中的地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计到本月中旬，中国的半导体发展计划将再次受到打击，据​​报道，美国总统乔·拜登计划签署一项行政命令，限制半导体的发展。美国在中国的关键技术投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“扎实创新”：随着美国加大科技战力度，中国习近平重申自力更生号召&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据报道，该行政命令将重点关注半导体、人工智能和量子计算。它不会影响任何现有投资，只会禁止某些交易。其他交易必须向美国政府披露。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿对中国获取先进集成电路和半导体制造设备的能力实施广泛控制，迫使北京和大陆企业更加注重生产老一代芯片的发展越来越引起美国和欧洲官员的关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家自然科学基金委员会成立于1986年，负责指导、协调和利用国家自然科学基金支持基础研究。该基金会去年将资助资金增加至 330 亿元人民币，比 2021 年增长 6.8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 3 月份的两会期间，科技部部长王志刚表示，国家必须“致力于促进一个容忍失败并鼓励研究人员花更多时间的研究环境”。据《南华早报》报道，这是因为“基础领域的研究往往路径不明确、方法不确定、失败率较高”。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Faster than humans? Drones, crawler robot at Hong Kong’s CLP Power cut inspection times from 12 to 1 day]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3229764/faster-humans-drones-crawler-robot-hong-kongs-clp-power-cut-inspection-times-12-1-day?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/02/0a65d69e-ade3-4400-8b24-1703fc86c55a_2196f609.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港电力供应商中华电力表示，其五架无人机机队和履带式机器人已减少了发电厂的设施检查时间，并补充说该技术还有助于削减开支。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中电工程师表示，该设备在某些情况下将检查时间从 12 天缩短至一两天，并导致更多灵活安排检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们补充说，机器人能够比人类更详细地检查设施，并有助于减少在密闭区域作业的工人的安全隐患。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公司有两架笼式无人机用于内部检查，三架室外无人机用于外部检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在我们可以快速进行检查，只需在无人机发现缺陷的特定位置搭脚手架即可。”中电工程师 Grace Wong Chung-yan 周二表示。 “这使得检查和维修工作变得更加高效。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无人机帮助将80米高锅炉的检查时间从12天缩短到一两天，而以前只需要两天。最多七人使用履带式机器人检查 1.4 公里的涵洞，该机器人于 2021 年推出。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;谁需要老师？我有 ChatGPT！香港教育家担心未来&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wong表示，无人机可以创建被检查设施的三维模型，比较不同版本的模型可以帮助轻松识别差异。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“发电厂的设施非常庞大。寻找缺陷就像海上寻针。有些在隐蔽的地方或死角，很容易被人类错过。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无人机体积小，灵活。它们可以去人类无法到达的地方。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港消防部门利用人工智能帮助寻找滞留的徒步旅行者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;笼式无人机、户外无人机和履带式机器人目前正在研发中中电旗下两座发电厂（均位于屯门的青山发电厂及龙鼓滩发电厂）使用了无人机，而该公司仅在大屿山竹篙湾发电厂部署户外无人机进行外部检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司早在2016年就使用户外无人机检查其外部设施，但工程师发现它们在涡轮机大厅和锅炉等密闭空间中表现不佳，因为该技术依赖GPS系统进行位置跟踪，但信号无法穿透地面&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中电随后于2019年推出用于内部设施检查的笼式无人机。该技术使用光探测和测距（LiDAR）系统和传感器进行定位，不受GPS信号的影响。碳纤维笼包围着无人机，有助于避免碰撞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无人机可以监视设施，但清洁和维修仍然由人类完成，”黄说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中电发电工程总监吴基安表示，该公司对技术的运用最近已经成熟。他补充说，公司正在尝试开发设备来进行简单的维护工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将尝试开发一些可以进行维护工作的无人机。但这并不容易，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据该公司称，无人机有助于减少检查费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一架笼式无人机的成本高达数十万港元吴说，可以多次使用，但搭建全尺寸脚手架每次要花费2至300万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中电自2021年开始使用履带式机器人检查地下涵洞，巡检时间缩短了一半以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人工巡检人员必须携带超过10公斤的设备沿着涵洞行走。而且涵洞的某些部分只有1.8米高，一个成年男子必须弯腰才能通过，对身体的要求非常高。”中电高级工程师杨慧敏说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过机器人拍摄的镜头，我们可以制定更准确的维护策略，避免人类在危险和密闭的空间中工作，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Two airlines, two apologies: why Cathay’s worked but United’s failed]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3229599/two-airlines-two-apologies-why-cathays-worked-uniteds-failed?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/01/9055fce3-ff31-48e9-9642-6320a05b895f_213550fd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;国泰航空和联合航空近期均发表道歉声明。公众的反应表明国泰航空的效果更佳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;道歉可能有不同的含义，具体取决于他们在多大程度上承认造成了伤害以及错误。当受害者的心理需求（恢复尊严、保证共同价值观和安全、看到施暴者受苦）这两方面都得到更突出的表现时，通常会得到更大的满足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空的罪行是通过录音揭露出来的空乘人员嘲笑一名讲普通话的乘客混淆了“地毯”和“毯子”这两个词。联合航空的违规行为被一张其首席执行官斯科特·柯比 (Scott Kirby) 登上私人飞机的照片记录下来，当时超过 15 万名联合航空乘客因天气原因取消航班而滞留。这两起事件都在社交媒体上公开并受到公开谴责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高质量的道歉通常包含四个要素。首先，承认伤害，但不要含糊、轻描淡写、附加条件或使用被动语态。其次，表达悔恨和自我谴责。第三，解释（确保这不是理由）。第四，提供赔偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空确认其空乘人员的行为是错误的，并多次道歉——这是一种具有文化意义的深刻悔恨表现。该航空公司在三天内发布了四次道歉，首席执行官林中基多次亲自道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;道歉以深切关注的表情开始，这是另一种表达悔恨的姿态。最初的道歉中包含了赔偿，三名船员被停职；第二天，林表示他们已被解雇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空对赔偿的承诺包括承诺通过审查其服务流程、人员培训和语言技能来纠正根本问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空在道歉方式上遵循了中国大陆文化，满足了受害人恢复尊严的心理需求。国泰航空在微博上以简体中文发表了道歉声明，林郑月娥也以普通话进行了道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空通过让其最高级别代表公开承认其不当行为并通过严厉惩罚违法者和提供赔偿来满足公众的要求。系统地审查和纠正其政策和做法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，柯比在一份声明中发表了道歉：“乘坐私人飞机是一个错误的决定，因为它对等待回家的客户不敏感。我真诚地向我们的客户和团队成员致歉。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kirby 对美联航员工的辛勤工作表示赞赏，并承诺将更加尊重员工和客户。但他使用了“错误决定”、“麻木不仁”和“分心”等温和的负面​​语气。美联航试图向公众保证更好的行为，但只提供了模糊的尊重承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它也未能承诺采取纠正措施或具体的宽容。柯比试图通过赞扬美联航员工和乘客的辛勤工作和耐心来满足他们恢复尊严的需求。该航空公司还以航空里程的形式提供赔偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但柯比没有正确解决触发因素——他奢华的生活方式与美联航员工和乘客的困境之间的差异——因此未能消除这种不尊重毛毡。一名乘客在推特上发了一张柯比1000万美元年薪的截图来回应他的道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柯比的道歉也未能满足共同价值观的需要。他对错误行为的承认态度冷淡，给美联航员工和乘客留下了安抚的印象。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;国泰航空正走在修复受损声誉的正确道路上&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;简而言之，这似乎是一个空洞的道歉。国泰航空事件和美联航事件之间最显着的区别是，柯比似乎没有面临任何后果。他本可以通过向慈善基金捐款以纪念受影响的美联航乘客和员工来表达悔意，或者为美联航员工减薪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;诚然，普遍存在的歧视和公共关系失误之间存在区别。 。基于种族和语言能力来嘲笑乘客的道德反感几乎无法与乘坐私人包机相比，这种做法并非美联航首席执行官所独有。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;滞留的美联航乘客疲惫不堪、喋喋不休且不便，但他们并没有受到不尊重或诽谤。然而，引人注目的是，国泰航空的道歉普遍被认为更为成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从根本上来说，有效的道歉必须承认并同意已经造成了伤害。空谈是廉价的，因此这种情绪必须伴随着赔偿的提议。国泰的道歉似乎更真实，因为它避免了被动的语言，采取了放心的行动，并与受害者产生了联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS ：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesian K-pop fans accuse Ganjar Pranowo of using them as ‘political tool’ ahead of 2024 election]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3229779/indonesian-k-pop-fans-accuse-ganjar-pranowo-using-them-political-tool-ahead-2024-election?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/02/3873d4bf-c0b2-4d84-8a05-328f07661fb6_be3651ed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚的韩国流行乐爱好者对总统候选人甘贾尔·普拉诺沃 (Ganjar Pranowo) 提议举办的在中爪哇举办音乐会，似乎是为了在明年大选前吸引年轻选民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ganjar 最近表示，他的竞选者和泗水市市长 Gibran Rakabuming Raka 正在考虑邀请韩国流行歌星来到这座城市，他已经不知道该向谁求助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括印度尼西亚总统、纪伯伦的父亲佐科·维多多在内的斗争民主党 (PDI-P) 总统候选人也征求了社交媒体用户的建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;h3>;佐科威和梅加瓦蒂在印度尼西亚造王者的战斗中是否存在裂痕？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然一些推荐乐队如韩国流行音乐重量级 BTS 和新男孩组合 Xodiac，但其他人质疑 Ganjar 使用音乐背后的意图节目与选民建立联系，并表示他需要关注促进工作与生活平衡和言论自由的政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“征求韩国流行音乐粉丝的想法？还有很多工作要做。 “现在不是放松和观看娱乐节目的时候。”一位用户在 X（以前称为 Twitter）上向中爪哇省长回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国流行音乐粉丝还指责 Ganjar 利用这一流派来获取政治里程。缺乏“优质创意”，建议他给当地歌手一个展示作品的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“请谈谈印度尼西亚的未来会是什么样子，先生。遇到堵车怎么办？”一位网友问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;网友还表示，韩国的韩流偶像通常在选举期间远离政治，Ganjar 不应该将他们用作竞选中的“政治工具”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;随着对他的计划的反对越来越多，甘贾尔做出了让步，坚称该计划“与政治无关”，发起的目的是为了促进当地经济和旅游业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，如果我们的意图令一些人不高兴，那也没关系，”他在 X 上的一篇帖子中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些韩国流行音乐爱好者不相信这种解释，称他的目的是将活动转化为投票，而这正是他们不支持他的原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位用户写道：“你是一个政治人物，你正在竞选总统办公室，你无法摆脱所谓的政治议程。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《雅加达邮报》报道，纪伯伦市长曾表示，他计划于 9 月举办音乐会，以纪念印尼与韩国建交 50 周年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消息并未立即公布。明确苏拉卡塔表演是否会在强烈抗议之后举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“比万圣节更可怕”：印度尼西亚公司可能会因踩踏事件而面临音乐&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚政客过去也曾利用音乐作为吸引选民的媒介。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2014 年总统竞选期间，维多多承认自己是重金属迷，并宣称他对 Metallica 和 Napalm Death 的喜爱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“令人难以置信的是，女士们，先生们，印尼新任总统是一位金属乐迷，也是一位 Lamb of God 的粉丝。”美国乐队 Lamb of God 的歌手兰迪·布莱斯 (Randy Blythe) 在维多多赢得选举后说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年总统还赞扬了他Metallica 作为业内最优秀的乐队之一，说道：“没有人能像他们一样，据我所知，新一代乐队中没有一支乐队能够写出像他们一样好的音乐。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近的一项调查发现，国防部长普拉博沃·苏比安托 (Prabowo Subianto) 现在以 35.8% 的得票率在三路总统竞选中处于领先地位，而甘贾尔 (Ganjar) 和前雅加达省长阿尼斯·巴斯韦丹 (Anies Baswedan) 的得票率分别为 32.2% 和 21.4%。&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 07:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong residents must pay thousands of dollars more to hire domestic helpers from Indonesia as Jakarta enforces new rules]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3229787/hong-kong-residents-must-pay-thousands-dollars-more-hire-domestic-helpers-indonesia-jakarta-enforces?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/02/9f90f398-d6a7-48d4-8fff-c39b2af86780_6c736f3c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港居民必须多付数千美元才能聘请印尼家庭佣工，因为据该国机构称，雅加达计划执行修订后的招聘规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚机构周三与香港劳工官员会面，警告说，不遵守规定的雇主将不会收到他们的申请&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印尼招聘协会Aspataki秘书长Filius Yandono也指出，只有一些有经验的工人知道去年生效的更新，而该市的许多雇主和机构并不知情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我们认为实施后仍然存在混乱，”Yandono说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些变化要求帮工只需支付接受培训的费用，而雇主则必须承担全部招聘费用高达 20,000 港元，比目前高出数千美元，具体取决于机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工人早些时候必须支付安置费，但该费用已被国家当局取消，以减少工人的债务&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;收费规定已于 2020 年和去年两次修订，但据印度尼西亚同行称，遵守规定的香港机构很少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多 (Joko Widodo)当香港行政长官李家超上个月访问香港时，强调了保护香港公民的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚政府表示，两人讨论了 14 万印度尼西亚人的保护和福利问题，大部分是在香港的外来务工人员，李先生表示，香港对他们对经济的贡献表示感谢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位消息人士告诉《华盛顿邮报》，国家安置和保护印尼人委员会主席海外工人预计将于 8 月 8 日访问香港，讨论国家实施新收费制度的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港对家庭佣工的窗户清洁规则是什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚驻香港总领事馆周三表示，修订后的规则旨在更好地保护工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对此类法律法规的任何修订肯定会考虑到印尼外佣安置和保护的各个相关方面[领事馆发言人表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;劳工部表示，自修订规定实施以来，当局一直与领事馆保持频繁联系，并补充说相关变化已在其网站上公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局还告知领事馆，为了维持互惠互利的关系，任何政策变化都不应导致雇主招聘费用大幅上涨或影响雇主的就业机会。 ”工人的经济负担，因为以前他们中的大多数人都必须向中介机构支付安置费并冒着负债的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为香港家庭提供12,000张海洋公园门票以感谢帮助者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;Yandono 表示，违规行为不会受到处罚，但印度尼西亚当局有权停止向该市派遣家庭佣工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港印度尼西亚劳工代理协会副主席麦克林·吴 (Mclean Ng)澳门表示，城市机构“非常努力地阻止这些规定”，因为一些老年雇主无力承担额外费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴建议雇主可能会选择来自菲律宾的工人，因为他们的工资要便宜得多招募。他补充说，印尼家庭佣工如果被多收费用，可以向劳工部或领事馆举报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市约有338,000名外籍家庭佣工，其中菲律宾人占2022年超过190,000人，移民局部门统计显示。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/一个>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US prepares to evacuate some embassy staff and families after Niger coup]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3229797/us-prepares-evacuate-some-embassy-staff-and-families-after-niger-coup?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 06:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/03/d511c109-9798-4879-9f61-10e4fa5bdb47_2bb616f6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国准备从尼日尔大使馆撤离部分工作人员和家属一名美国官员周三表示，尽管任务将保持开放，高级领导层将继续在那里开展工作，但军官们在那里夺取了权力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日尔是打击伊斯兰叛乱分子的关键西方盟友。外国势力谴责了这次接管，担心这可能会让武装分子得逞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位不愿透露姓名的官员表示，最终决定仍在等待中，但似乎有可能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该官员表示：“这是一个谨慎之举，以防安全局势恶化，使馆核心人员将保留。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该官员补充说，美国人员将于不会使用国务院包机和军用飞机。 Politico 最先报道了这一消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国务院发言人马修·米勒没有证实工作人员将被疏散，但表示华盛顿正在监视实地事件，并将优先考虑美国公民和政府人员的安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “美国驻尼亚美大使馆已经开放，我们打算让它继续开放，”米勒在新闻发布会上说。 “我们仍然致力于维护尼日尔人民以及我们与尼日尔人民的关系，我们仍然保持最高级别的外交接触。这种情况将会持续下去。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国、美国、德国和意大利在尼日尔派驻部队执行反叛乱和训练任务，帮助军队打击与基地组织和伊斯兰国有联系的组织。法国和意大利正在从尼日尔撤离欧洲公民。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;竞相从苏丹撤离外国公民&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;到目前为止，尚未宣布撤军的消息。尼日尔约有1100名美军，美军在尼日尔设有两个基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;军方突然爆发暴力冲突后，美国在苏丹撤离美国公民的处理方式受到批评4 月 15 日，装备精良的快速支援部队准军事组织将居民区变成战区，导致数十万人逃离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿疏散了美国驻喀土穆大使馆的所有政府人员，并暂停了运作由于存在安全风险。但美国公民在暴力事件中面临出境困难，并遭遇抢劫和抢劫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登政府当时表示，美国军机不需要撤离公民，因为其他国家的飞机上有足够的空间。有航班进出该国的国家。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China exports: US, EU de-risking isn’t going away, ‘the worst is yet to come’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3229739/china-exports-us-eu-de-risking-isnt-going-away-worst-yet-come?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/02/ab5fca12-643a-4478-b859-2c4319ea662a_fb1e0080.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这是关于 2023 年上半年动荡的经济陷阱和风险的第六部分尽管全球经济放缓的广泛影响被视为中国出口大幅下降的主要原因，但经济学家和贸易专家警告称发达国家“去风险”努力的影响不可低估，因为“最坏的情况尚未到来”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月份中国出口创2020年初以来最大跌幅，大幅下滑继 5 月份出现负增长和下降 7.5% 之后，同比增长 12.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大部分贸易伙伴（包括发达经济体和新兴经济体）6 月份均出现下滑，但俄罗斯除外，中国出口同比增长91%。但俄罗斯在中国出口总额中所占的份额仅为 3.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他亚洲出口大国也感受到了此类贸易阵痛。 6月份，韩国出口同比下降6%，已连续九个月下降。台湾出口暴跌23.4%，这是连续第10个月下降，也是近14年来的最大跌幅。来自越南的出口量也连续第四个月下降，下降了 10.25%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“只有穿鞋的人才知道鞋子在哪里夹住”：中国出口商的艰难时期&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“有一个真正的经济学人智库 (EIU) 全球贸易首席分析师尼克·马罗 (Nick Marro) 表示：“全球经济活动放缓，这对大多数亚洲经济体造成了相当严重的打击。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济放缓，尤其是在电子产品方面他表示，鉴于台湾和韩国对电子产品需求的严重依赖，对台湾和韩国出口行业的打击最为严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鉴于其贸易更加多样化，中国的出口活动稍微更具弹性。”篮子，”他补充道。 “但鉴于美国和欧盟需求疲软的迹象，它也未能摆脱贸易活动的低迷。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对美国和欧盟的出口量约占中国总出口量的四分之一根据中国海关数据，出口量。但自去年底以来，西方经济放缓和通胀上升抑制了消费者对中国商品的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在疫情期间，受居家需求的推动，中国对这两个地区的出口总体强劲商品和医疗产品。 2020-21 年，更具弹性的制造业从大流行的阴影中恢复过来的速度要快得多，导致中国在出口增长方面远远超过世界其他地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着经济重新开放和消费发生转变， back towards pre-pandemic trends, that&#39;s consequently caused a correction in demand,” Marro said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to statistics from the World Trade Organization, China&#39;s share of global goods exports peaked at 15.03 per cent in 2021, then declined to 14.43 per cent in 2022. From 2015-19, the percentage hovered around 13 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The share is likely to continue declining modestly to pre-pandemic levels by 2028, according to Steven Altman, senior research scholar and director of the DHL Initiative on Globalization at the New York University Stern School of Business.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even with the modest declines in China&#39;s share implied by recent forecasts, China looks set to remain the world&#39;s largest exporter by a wide margin, and to keep intact most of the rise in its share of exports that was achieved over the last few decades,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, there is cause for concern, as both economic and geopolitical factors are contributing to China&#39;s declining competitiveness, Altman added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The evidence is mixed on China&#39;s changing competitiveness due to economic factors alone, since China has also achieved success at growing more advanced products such as electric vehicles while rising costs have naturally pushed some low-end production to other countries, Altman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Geopolitical factors are more likely to weigh even more heavily in the coming years, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Changes to supply chains take time for companies to execute, so the recent emphasis we have seen from companies and governments on diversifying China-centric supply chains suggests rising headwinds for China&#39;s exports moving forward,” Altman explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington&#39;s reshoring efforts have already materialised, as China&#39;s exports to the US fell for 11 consecutive months, compared with a rising share of US imports among countries such as Mexico and Vietnam for a wide range of products that used to be predominantly “Made in China”.&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;According to International Monetary Fund (IMF) data, the Chinese mainland&#39;s share of US imports peaked in 2017 – before the US-China trade war – at 21.58 per cent. Despite a slight rebound in 2020, it did not reverse the overall trend, with the share dropping to 16.53 per cent last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trend is particularly remarkable in textiles and apparel. In the first four months of this year, 20.9 per cent of textiles and apparel that the US imported were from China – down about 4 percentage points from 2022, and falling to almost half of the total seen 10 years ago, according to figures from the Office of Textiles and Apparel under the US Department of Commerce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sheng Lu, an associate professor with the Department of Fashion and Apparel Studies at the University of Delaware, said the impact of the “de-risk” movement on China&#39;s exports should not be underestimated, as there is a strong and growing sentiment among fashion companies in the US to “reduce China exposure” further due to concerns about the forced labour risks in the supply chain and escalating US-China tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many Companies in the EU and elsewhere in the world share the same concerns. I am afraid the worst is yet to come,” Lu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s recent trade pattern has substantiated the country&#39;s diversification efforts, as rising shipments to emerging economies have partially offset the lost momentum derived from weakening Western demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Ministry of Commerce, exports from China accounted for 14 per cent of the global total in the first quarter – a 0.3-percentage-point increase compared with a year earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first half of the year, trade with the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (Asean), Latin America and Africa increased by 5.4 per cent, 7 per cent and 10.5 per cent, respectively, compared with a 1.9 per cent increase with the EU and an 8.4 per cent decline with the US, the ministry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The shift is also a reflection of the ongoing trend of global supply-chain readjustments, as China serves as a critical intermediary supplier for countries such as Mexico and those in Asean.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China eyes Asean trade ties, but members fear falling into &#39;geopolitical trap&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Trade diversification is causing a shift in demand for Chinese goods between different markets, but it&#39;s not necessarily eliminating demand for Chinese products, given that China remains an integral part of these regional supply chains,” said the EIU&#39;s Marro.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that while many companies are realising how difficult it is to wean themselves off of the incredibly competitive Chinese production and logistics ecosystems, it has also been difficult for other Asian governments to fully replicate the scale or sophistication of Chinese industrial parks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, there&#39;s a limit to how far Chinese policymakers can position Asean or Belt and Road Initiative nations to make up for any decline in Western demand, as the US and EU remain incredibly important global destinations for final consumption, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the US or EU final demand weakens, then that has an effect on the entire value chain,” Marro said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Altman from NYU said that the strength of China&#39;s exports to countries such as Mexico and the Asean region, which have growing shares of US imports, can be helpful for China, but it is still coming at a rising cost to China&#39;s exports that will grow over the medium to long term.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Over time, just as China did, those countries will also strive to build up domestic and regional supply bases, gradually raising the pressure on their suppliers in China,” Altman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guan Tao, a former Chinese foreign-exchange official and global chief economist at the Bank of China International, said that while China cannot control external factors, it should continue pushing for trade diversification, promote high-level opening up, and further facilitate foreign trade and investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[China should] participate in the process of reshaping the global industrial and supply chains with a more active attitude, to form the country&#39;s new competitive advantage,” Guan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In India, using a public toilet is a ‘traumatic experience’ for trans people]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3229774/india-using-public-toilet-traumatic-experience-trans-people?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/02/fb4db26e-81dc-40a5-8ea7-09270c11669e_92073175.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Like many transgender Indians, 32-year-old social worker Leela thinks twice before using a public toilet. After facing insults and hostility in the past, she often opts to put up with the discomfort until she gets home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Using a public toilet is perhaps the easiest thing for a non-LGBTQ person. But for a trans woman like me, it can be … a traumatic experience,” Leela said in the capital, New Delhi, asking to use only her first name.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She recalled an incident several years ago when she was forced to leave a women&#39;s toilet after other women objected to her presence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since then, I realised I have no other option but to hold my pee,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Being transgender in South Asia: laws change, public opinion doesn&#39;t&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Repeatedly holding in urine for long periods of time can cause abdominal pain and increase the risk of urinary infections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s really inhuman,” said Fred Rogers, an LGBTQ activist from the southern state of Tamil Nadu who filed a petition to Chennai High Court earlier this year demanding at least one gender-neutral bathroom in all public spaces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His is one of several such initiatives focused on boosting trans bathroom access across the country of 1.4 billion people, where awareness of transgender rights issues is slowly growing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s Supreme Court ruled in 2014 that trans people should be recognised as the “third gender”, extending rights that allow them to self-identity as their chosen gender, but prejudice and social marginalisation persists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many are rejected by their families and denied jobs, education and healthcare, driving many trans women – also known in India as hijras – to survive through begging at busy intersections and on trains, performing at social functions such as weddings or selling sex.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the Transgender Persons (Protection of Rights) Act, trans people should have equal access to public services and not face discrimination, but the bathroom issue shows that is often not the case in practice, Rogers said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Access to public toilets has become a flashpoint as fierce debate about trans rights takes place around the world, particularly in the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following other states, Florida Governor Ron DeSantis signed into law a so-called “bathroom bill” earlier this year requiring all restrooms or locker rooms at public facilities to be used exclusively for people based on their gender assigned at birth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;LGBTQ rights campaigners say trans people should be able to access single-sex spaces according to their gender identity – from swimming pool changing rooms to hospital wards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most public hospitals in India, for example, do not have specific wards for trans people, or do not allow them to be accommodated in wards of the gender with which they identify.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the bathroom issue is compounded in India by the lack of bathroom facilities in homes, many of which do not have their own toilet – especially in poorer neighbourhoods or the slums. That means shared facilities are the only option for many.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the eastern state of Assam, local LGBTQ group Drishti has launched a campaign called #NoMoreHoldingMyPee to highlight the problems faced by trans and non-binary people, who identify as neither male nor female.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Being able to answer nature&#39;s call is basic. Though there are facilities available for men and women, a trans person can feel threatened if they try to access them,” said Rituparna, a member of the group who goes by one name.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like the Tamil Nadu campaigners, the group is calling for gender-neutral toilets that can be used by anyone regardless of their sex or gender identity.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Five years since India legalised same-sex relations, there are signs of change on the issue, LGBTQ campaigners say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, Delhi&#39;s High Court ordered the city government to build public toilets for trans people within eight weeks, following a successful petition from LGBTQ rights groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities in Delhi said in response that some 500 toilets initially meant for people with disabilities had been designated for the use of trans people, adding that the creation of separate bathrooms for the third gender was now a priority.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Literal torture&#39;: India&#39;s first openly gay prince slams conversion therapy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Other public institutions such as universities are also starting to take note.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vaivab Das, a research scholar at the Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) in New Delhi, who is non-binary, was behind the introduction of gender-inclusive restrooms at the college, which now has 12 such facilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 20 IIT campuses across the country have followed suit, Das said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Trans persons have been historically removed from public spaces and denied opportunities to access education, employment and other rights,” Das added. “Making (toilets) accessible to gender minorities is a small step towards making amends for historical and systematic exclusions.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Heaviest animal ever? Scientists discover massive ancient whale]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3229792/heaviest-animal-ever-scientists-discover-massive-ancient-whale?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 05:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/03/a625da73-c5af-4743-b5ce-e816f66e8a9e_e91c4629.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Look out, blue whale – there&#39;s a new contender for your heavyweight title.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A newly discovered whale that lived nearly 40 million years ago could be the heaviest animal to have ever lived, based on a partial skeleton found in Peru, scientists said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The modern blue whale has long been considered the largest and heaviest animal ever, beating out all the giant dinosaurs of the distant past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Perucetus colossus – the colossal whale from Peru – may have been even heavier, according to a study published in the journal Nature.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Extrapolating from some massive bones found in the Peruvian desert, an international team of researchers estimated that the animal had an average body mass of 180 tonnes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That would not take the heavyweight title by itself. The biggest blue whale ever recorded weighed 190 tonnes, according to Guinness World Records.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the researchers estimated the ancient whale&#39;s weight range was between 85 and 340 tonnes, meaning it could have been significantly larger.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The researchers were careful not to declare the ancient whale had broken the record. But there was also “no reason to think that this specimen was the largest of its kind”, study co-author Eli Amson said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese marine fossils force major rethink of rebound from the &#39;Great Dying&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“I think there&#39;s a good chance that some of the individuals broke the record – but the take-home message is that we are in the ballpark of the blue whale,” said Amson, a palaeontologist at the State Museum of Natural History Stuttgart in Germany.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first fossil of the ancient whale was discovered back in 2010 by Mario Urbina, a palaeontologist who has spent decades searching the desert on the southern coast of Peru. But what he found “looked more like a boulder” than a fossil, Amson said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 13 gigantic vertebrae – one of which weighed nearly 200kg (440 pounds) – were found at the site, as well as four ribs and a hip bone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It took years and multiple trips to collect and prepare the giant fossils, and longer for the team of Peruvian and European researchers to confirm exactly what they had been found.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, they revealed it was a new species of basilosaurid, an extinct family of cetaceans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today&#39;s cetaceans include dolphins, whales and porpoises, but their early ancestors lived on land, some resembling small deer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over time they moved into the water, and basilosaurids are believed to be the first cetaceans to have a fully aquatic lifestyle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of their adaptations at that time was gigantism – they became very big.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Dinosaur fossil found with its last meal still inside of it&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But the new discovery indicates that cetaceans reached their peak body mass roughly 30 million years earlier than previously thought, the study said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like other basilosaurids, Perucetus colossus probably had a “ridiculously small” head compared to its body, Amson said – though there were no available bones to confirm this.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lacking any teeth, it was impossible to say for sure what they ate. But Amson speculated that scavenging off the sea floor was a strong possibility, partly because the animals could not swim quickly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The researchers were confident that the animal lived in shallow waters in coastal environments, due to the strange heaviness of its bones.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its whole skeleton was estimated to weigh between five to seven tonnes – more than twice as heavy as the skeleton of a blue whale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is – for sure – the heaviest skeleton of any mammal known to date,” as well as any aquatic animal, Amson said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perucetus colossus needed heavy bones to compensate for the huge amount of buoyant blubber – and air in its lungs – which could otherwise send it bobbing to the surface.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But just the right balance of bone density and blubber allowed the giant animal to stay in the middle of around 10 metres (33 feet) of water “without moving a muscle”, Amson explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Sea monster&#39; that washed ashore in Indonesia identified&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Felix Marx, a marine mammal expert at the Museum of New Zealand Te Papa Tongarewa not involved in the study, said that Perucetus colossus “is very different from anything else we&#39;ve ever found”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He cautioned that extinct sea cows had heavier bones than would be expected for their total body weight, potentially suggesting Perucetus colossus could be on the lower end of its estimated weight range.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fossils are being displayed at the Museum of Natural History in Lima.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 05:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Baidu’s Ernie Bot to be used in Great Wall Motor’s vehicles to enhance conversation between driver and car]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3229790/baidus-ernie-bot-be-used-great-wall-motors-vehicles-enhance-conversation-between-driver-and-car?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/02/57e3535b-7b01-4018-b156-73f2c06f2d39_cf4d5c7b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Great Wall Motor, China&#39;s largest sport-utility vehicle (SUV) assembler, looks set to become the first carmaker to use Baidu&#39;s ChatGPT-like artificial intelligence (AI) technology that enables conversation between driver and car.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company, based in Baoding in northern China&#39;s Hebei province, said in a statement on Wednesday that it has partnered with Baidu, a search and AI giant, to develop vehicles fitted with the chatbot tool known as Ernie Bot, reinforcing a push to make cars more intelligent and user-friendly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Several innovative features have been tested in those vehicles that are being mass produced,” the statement said. “They will be gradually put into commercial use on a wide basis.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Great Wall did not reveal which models will be the first to feature built-in Ernie Bot, China&#39;s answer to OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT, a so-called large language model. Neither did it unveil a time frame for launching its first vehicle fitted with the conversational technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Great Wall is taking a step closer to churning out vehicles with Ernie Bot built in because it has completed the tests,” said Cao Hua, a partner at the Shanghai private-equity firm Unity Asset Management, which counts AI among its investments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A tie-up between carmakers and AI technology firm will expand the use of the chatbot tool.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing-based Baidu said in another statement that other car brands including Lynk and Smart also plan to build cars fitted with the technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February, the technology behemoth said its electric vehicle (EV) subsidiary Jidu Auto will use Ernie Bot in its cars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jidu has yet to mass produce a car and plans to launch its first production model late in 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aside from conversation, Ernie Bot also provides services such as journey planning, in-car entertainment and generating images based on text inputs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EVs featuring autonomous driving technology and digital cockpits are increasingly sought after by young motorists in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Electric car sales in the mainland will rise by 35 per cent this year to 8.8 million units, UBS analyst Paul Gong predicted in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tesla is now the runaway leader in the country&#39;s premium EV segment, trailed by three Chinese start-ups – Li Auto, Nio and Xpeng.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The premium electric car builders are competing against each other to make their products more autonomous and cutting-edge in terms of their in-car entertainment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guangzhou-based Xpeng has received approval to roll out its advanced driver assistance systems for commercial use on a trial basis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some of its cars, fitted with its X NGP (Navigation Guided Pilot) software, are now capable of autonomous driving in China&#39;s top four cities – Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou and Shenzhen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some cars built by Shanghai-based Nio, are fitted with PanoCinema, a panoramic and immersive digital cockpit boasting augmented reality (AR) and virtual reality (VR) technologies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 27, Baidu, citing a test carried out by state-run newspaper China Science Daily, said its Ernie 3.5, the company&#39;s latest large language model, had surpassed ChatGPT 3.5 in comprehensive ability tests and outperformed the more advanced ChatGPT 4 in several Chinese-language capabilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Baidu has pushed to integrate Ernie Bot into other products, such as its cloud services, and announced a 1 billion yuan (US$139.3 million) venture fund to invest in Chinese generative AI start-ups in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 05:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>