<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com<item><title><![CDATA[Trump ally Rudy Giuliani turns himself in on Georgia 2020 election charges]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3232094/trump-ally-rudy-giuliani-turns-himself-georgia-2020-election-charges?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 04:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/24/c2e15d8b-7464-419e-862c-7e18d03862e5_7bec97c5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;鲁迪·朱利安尼周三在亚特兰大的一所监狱自首，罪名是与工作相关的指控推翻当时的美国总统唐纳德·特朗普在 2020 年佐治亚州总统选举中的失败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前纽约市长上周与特朗普和其他 17 人一起被起诉。富尔顿县地方检察官法尼·威利斯表示，在2020年11月共和党总统输给民主党人乔·拜登后，他们参与了一场大范围的阴谋，旨在颠覆选民的意愿。邦德定为15万美元，仅次于特朗普的20万美元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现年 79 岁的朱利安尼被指控带头特朗普迫使佐治亚州和其他竞争激烈的州的州立法者无视选民的意愿，非法任命有利于特朗普的选举人团选举人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;乔治亚州是特朗普以微弱优势输掉的几个关键州之一，促使共和党及其盟友在没有证据的情况下宣布选举被操纵，有利于他的民主党竞争对手拜登。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朱利安尼被指控做出虚假陈述并索取虚假证词，合谋制作虚假文件，并要求州议员违反就职誓言，任命支持特朗普的候补选举人名单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三早上离开他在纽约的公寓，朱利安尼说他是在“为正义而战”，自从他第一次代表特朗普以来一直如此。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我对此感觉非常非常好，因为我觉得我正在捍卫所有美国人的权利朱利安尼告诉记者，就像我作为一名美国律师多次做过的那样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2024 年共和党总统初选的早期领跑者特朗普表示，他计划在富尔顿县自首周四入狱。他和他的盟友将此次调查定性为出于政治动机，并严厉批评了民主党地方检察官威利斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普的保证金禁止恐吓证人。他会遵守这一规定吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;朱利安尼批评了对他以外的曾为特朗普工作的律师的起诉，并表示司法系统被政治化。他还强调了这样一个事实，即一些被起诉的人并不是家喻户晓的名字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“唐纳德·特朗普告诉过你这一点：他们不仅仅是为了他或我而来，”朱利安尼说。 “现在他们已经起诉了这起案件中的人，我什至不知道他们是谁。这些只是过着正常生活的普通人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;威利斯为上周在选举颠覆案中被起诉的人设定了周五中午自首的最后期限。她的团队一直在谈判保释金额以及被告在监狱自首前与律师的条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，特朗普盟友律师西德尼·鲍威尔 (S​​idney Powell) 被支付了 10 万美元的保释金，他是被指控违反农村投票设备的几人之一咖啡县，位于佐治亚州南部。泄露事件发生时，咖啡县选举主任米斯蒂·汉普顿 (Misty Hampton) 的保释金为 10,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大卫·谢弗 (David Shafer)，乔治亚州共和党前主席，曾担任特朗普的 16 名假选举人之一，以及因咖啡县违规行为而被指控的凯茜·莱瑟姆 (Cathy Latham)，她也是一名假选民，已于周三上午自首。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;律师雷·史密斯 (Ray Smith) 和肯尼思·切斯布罗 (Kenneth Chesebro) 也在周三自首，检察官称他们帮助组织了这次活动。 2020 年 12 月在州议会大厦举行的假选举人会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推动特朗普继续执政计划的律师约翰·伊士曼 (John Eastman) 和被指控参与违反《宪法》的保释担保人斯科特·霍尔 (Scott Hall)咖啡县的选举设备已于周二自首。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普照片将加入名人面孔相册&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;富尔顿县治安官办公室表示将在每天下午 4 点发布预订照片，但谢弗似乎在周三早上 7 点刚过时在社交媒体平台 X（以前称为 Twitter）上发布了他的消息：“早上好！ #NewProfilePicture。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然佐治亚州和其他地方的共和党人呼吁威利斯因起诉特朗普而受到惩罚，但周三，一群黑人牧师和社区活动人士聚集在亚特兰大州议会大厦外祈祷并宣布他们对民主党检察官的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乔治亚州非洲卫理公会主教雷金纳德·杰克逊主教表示，威利斯“由于她的勇气和决心”而受到攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 04:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Experts say Brics expansion is likely but details will be tricky as members’ priorities differ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3232093/experts-say-brics-expansion-likely-details-will-be-tricky-members-priorities-differ?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 02:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/24/684f3361-3d5f-400e-8412-ed6f61d6f06a_cdd2d4ce.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪无视金砖国家扩张可能陷入僵局的预测几小时后专家表示，他支持将更多国家加入五国集团的计划，但专家警告称，“细节决定成败”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度完全支持金砖国家的扩张，并欢迎此举周三，当金砖国家领导人在南非约翰内斯堡举行第二天会晤时，莫迪首次就此问题发表公开评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该集团目前的成员国包括巴西、俄罗斯、印度、中国和南非。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿智库昆西负责任治国研究所全球南方项目主任萨朗·希多雷 (Sarang Shidore) 问道：“我们将建立什么样的机制？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shidore 表示，成员资格可能会经历中间阶段，并补充说，这在上海合作组织 (SCO) 等其他组织中“相当正常”拥有“对话伙伴、观察员等”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，他想知道：“这就是过程吗？标准是什么？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿智库布鲁金斯学会的坦维·马丹 (Tanvi Madan) 将莫迪对金砖国家东扩的支持描述为“印度对中国一直在推动的事情的默许，而不是选择” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她转发了新德里外交政策评论员 Indrani Bagchi 于 6 月撰写的题为“金砖国家扩张中隐藏的诡计”的评论文章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;扩张“不应成为中国劫持金砖国家身份和议程的一种方式，就像他们对上海合作组织所做的那样。中国正试图用它的‘朋友’来塞满金砖国家。”巴格奇在文章中警告道，并补充说，“印度明智地建议它变得以标准为基础。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;金砖国家都是关于中国的，这恰恰是问题&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;南非总统西里尔·拉马福萨表示，将于周四结束的峰会上宣布扩大规模。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球南方 40 多个国家已表示有兴趣加入据南非官员称，金砖国家有 20 多个国家提出了正式请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shidore 表示，他期待约翰内斯堡发布“以流程为导向”的声明，而不是任何新成员名单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;其他人说金砖国家扩张可能是一个坏主意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据日内瓦安全政策中心的艾哈迈迪·阿里的说法，“快速扩张的金砖国家不一定会更强大”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“事实上，这可能会使该组织更加不连贯，无法在任何重要的事情上达成明确的共识，”他为多哈的半岛电视台新闻写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到目前为止，中国和俄罗斯一直是欧盟扩张的最坚定支持者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于新德里的智库观察者研究基金会研究与外交政策副总裁 Harsh V Pant 表示，中国的逻辑是对扩张的支持“在多个层面上都非常明确”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，五个成员的经济实力“不如 2009 年该平台首次宣布时那么有希望”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“俄罗斯在全球经济中逐渐被边缘化，而中国则面临着西方国家反对的艰难经济环境。因此，中国引进新参与者并将其与自己的经济挂钩是有道理的。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;潘特补充说，印度和巴西越来越多的人认为，中国的利益“并不重要”。与他们合作并协调行动，为新兴参与者寻求更大的发言权，而不是让金砖四国成为一个反美的平台，并由中国的优先事项塑造”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;巴西卢拉支持贸易昆西研究所的 Shidore 表示，印度和巴西有不同的看法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，印度从来没有“完全反对”扩张，问题更在于关于“如何做”，并补充说巴西利亚“可能持保留意见最多，因为巴西是其中一个非常重要的成员”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“就印度而言，这并不那么紧迫，因为印度巴西利亚是许多其他论坛的成员，也是美国的亲密合作伙伴，这给了它一些机会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据巴西政府消息人士称，巴西利亚希望中国公开宣布支持巴西申办常任理事国席位。联合国安理会希望巴西支持金砖国家的扩张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦在周二的峰会上表示：“阿根廷加入金砖国家非常重要。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿根廷一直在应对历史性的通货膨胀、外汇储备缩水和债务偿还问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢拉批评国际货币基金组织与阿根廷的 440 亿美元贷款协议“令人窒息”，暗示金砖国家银行可能采取行动增加对具有“不同标准”的其他国家的贷款，以刺激其经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，卢拉呼吁在成员国之间的商业交易中采用共同的金砖国家货币。他说：“为金砖四国成员之间的贸易和投资交易创造一种货币，可以增加我们的支付选择，并减少我们的脆弱性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但金砖四国观察人士表示，人们对金砖四国减少对金融依赖的计划知之甚少。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“金砖国家成立的金砖国家新开发银行在很大程度上是为了促进国家贷款的去美元化，该银行在很大程度上依赖于美元，目前正在努力提高美元汇率，因为日内瓦安全政策中心的阿里表示：“俄罗斯是创始成员国。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道：“其首席财务官最近承认，你无法走出美元宇宙并在平行宇宙中运作。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊戈尔·帕特里克 (Igor Patrick) 在华盛顿的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 03:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: Wagner chief Yevgeny Prigozhin on list of passengers in deadly plane crash, Russian agencies report]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3232091/ukraine-war-wagner-chief-yevgeny-prigozhin-list-passengers-deadly-plane-crash-russian-agencies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 01:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/24/6dab80b0-4b69-4966-a1bc-3e36a492484e_674b5b62.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三，一架从莫斯科飞往圣彼得堡的公务机坠毁，机上 10 人全部遇难俄罗斯紧急事务官员称，机上人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官员称，雇佣军首领叶夫根尼·普里戈任（Yevgeny Prigozhin）在乘客名单上，但目前尚不清楚他是否在机上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;未经证实的媒体报道称，这架飞机属于瓦格纳私人军事公司创始人普里戈任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯民用航空监管机构 Rosaviatsia 表示，普里戈任在乘客名单上。不过，目前尚不清楚他是否已登机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国家通讯社塔斯社援引紧急官员的话说，这架飞机载有三名飞行员和七名乘客。当局表示，他们正在调查这起坠机事故，事故发生在莫斯科以北 100 多公里（60 英里）的特维尔地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任的私人军事部队瓦格纳曾在乌克兰与俄罗斯正规军并肩作战。六月下旬针对俄罗斯军事领导层的短暂武装叛变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里姆林宫表示，他将被流放到白俄罗斯，他的战士要么退休，追随他到那里，要么加入俄罗斯军队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里姆林宫表示，他将被流放到白俄罗斯。 >;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Europe is failing Asia-Pacific climate refugees by building bigger walls]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231845/europe-failing-asia-pacific-climate-refugees-building-bigger-walls?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.24 01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/713317aa-2baf-4fcb-8a66-178acf7dbead_1f68f001.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;未来几十年，气候变化可能会给周围地区的人口带来真正的损失世界，特别是亚太地区。然而，随着欧洲又一个移民季节到来，该地区的解决方案尚未出台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府间气候变化专门委员会警告称，大规模人口流离失所即将呈指数级增长，对亚洲造成的破坏性影响尤其严重。有证据支持这一预测。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据挪威难民理事会下属的境内流离失所监测中心的数据，2010 年至 2010 年间，亚太地区有超过 2.25 亿人因自然灾害而流离失所。 2021 年。该中心表示，“该地区 95% 的灾难性流离失所是由季风降雨和热带风暴等与天气相关的灾害造成的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界银行估计还会有 89到 2050 年，东亚、太平洋地区和东南亚将有 100 万气候难民。虽然许多人将在自己的祖国流离失所，但许多人将踏上危险的旅程，前往欧洲寻找避难所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟免签证申根区由 27 个国家组成，2022 年正式寻求庇护者人数增加了 64%。去年有超过 88 万人首次申请在欧盟寻求保护，紧接着又是第二次申请。 2021 年申请数量大幅增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟数据机构欧盟统计局表示，2022 年首次寻求庇护者中近一半（46%）拥有亚洲公民身份。这是迄今为止各地区申请者比例最高的，其中非洲位居第二，为 22%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧洲的反应是收紧边境。在二月份于布鲁塞尔举行的欧洲理事会特别峰会上，代表们选择加倍加强本已严格的措施，以阻止和抵制人道主义移民。这包括加强与原籍国的合作（也称为达成让人们留在国内的协议）以及在返回和重新接纳方面的合作，或拒绝尽可能多的寻求庇护者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟同意这一点也许并不令人意外。 “确保有效控制其外部陆地和海上边界”。这可以简单地解释为“建造更大的墙”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;具有讽刺意味的是，这种强硬态度是在具有伟大人道主义目的的时刻出现的。 2016 年，德国总理安格拉·默克尔 (Angela Merkel) 在难民问题上花费了超过 200 亿欧元（合 217 亿美元），2015 年至 2016 年间，有超过 100 万寻求庇护者进入该国。热情的德国公民欢迎从饱受战争蹂躏的国家涌入的难民。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治反应是德国另类选择党等极右翼政党的崛起。这不仅结束了默克尔的仁慈时刻，并在很大程度上导致了她政治生涯的结束，而且在整个欧洲引发了极右政治和反移民政策的类似增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些政党现在正在制定国家议程移民问题，即使他们没有掌权。当然，这种对移民的强硬态度引起了生活在亚洲和印度太平洋地区的人们的极大关注。由于气候变化已经对该地区产生了重大影响，欧盟等富裕国家不愿参与人道解决方案，这令人不安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在某种程度上，这种拒绝会适得其反。欧盟27个成员国接收了全世界不到10%的难民，并且只接收了一小部分国内流离失所者。最近这一数字显着增加，主要是因为逃离俄罗斯入侵的乌克兰难民涌入。难民仅占欧盟总人口的 1.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一个层面上，欧盟在亚太地区等地的殖民历史应该产生道德责任感。目前来看，欧洲难民制度的建立无法承受气候移民的压力，存在太多逃避国家责任的漏洞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧洲有机会引领世界人道主义反应和应对危机的方法只会变得越来越严重。然而，通过选择躲在政治高墙后面，该地区不仅实施了经济上适得其反的措施，而且还假装自己的义务不存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲和印太地区人民长期以来一直期待着欧洲是民主和自由的典范。随着气候变化在整个地区蔓延，这种信念正在迅速消失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 24 Aug 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Diverse’ Germany aims to make it simpler to legally change gender]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3232087/diverse-germany-aims-make-it-simpler-legally-change-gender?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 23:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/23/4000b388-1c34-4097-8e45-ac4fc6c4f46a_2b1b9779.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;德国正​​在采取措施，为跨性别者、双性人和非二元性别者提供顺利的流程合法地改变他们的名字和性别，总理奥拉夫·肖尔茨的执政联盟试图兑现让社会更具包容性的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肖尔茨内阁周三批准了一项自决法草案，该草案将使公民能够更新他们的性别输入和名字无需经过法庭诉讼或提供专家精神病学意见——一些人抱怨这一过程可能是有辱人格和造成创伤的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新规则将于 2024 年 11 月生效最早——在议会批准后——意味着一个人只需要向登记处做出声明，确认所请求的改变最符合他们的性别认同，并且他们了解其影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在某些条件下，14 岁以上的人就可以使用该选项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“德国是多元化的，”Scholz 在 X（该平台以前称为 Twitter）上的一篇帖子中写道。 “这就是为什么我们要调整我们的法律以适应不同的生活现实。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该倡议引起了反对党的批评，其中包括极右翼的德国另类选择党 (AfD)，该党指责执政联盟德国选择党议会核心小组领导人爱丽丝·韦德尔周三表示，该党正在考虑对这项法律提出法律挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他地方的企业和政府正在考虑对这项法律提出法律挑战。面临类似举措的强烈反对。英国首相里希·苏纳克 (Rishi Sunak) 政府于 1 月份阻止了苏格兰一项允许 16 岁以上任何人轻松更改法律文件中姓名的法律。这是伦敦议会自1999年成立以来首次否决苏格兰议会提出的立法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国各州立法者在2023年提出的反LGBTQ法案比过去五年的总和还多，因为所谓的文化战争已经占据了国家议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公司在发布反 LGBTQ 商品或与跨性别影响者合作后面临抗议和抵制威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个有争议的问题德国政府法案草案的一个方面是一项提案，该提案将授权任何 14 岁或以上的人自行向登记处做出声明，尽管这需要父母或监护人的同意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这保守派基民盟/基社盟核心小组家庭政策发言人西尔维娅·布雷赫 (Silvia Breher) 表示：“法律过度干涉了父母抚养子女的权利，而这一权利受到宪法保护。”绿党成员丽莎·鲍斯 (Lisa Paus) 部长称内阁通过该法律草案对于德国跨性别者和双性者来说是一个“伟大时刻”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“《自决法》旨在保护长期Paus 说：“这是社会政策的一个进步。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style =&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South China Sea: is arrival of Philippines’ resupply mission a sign of Beijing backing off or China’s long game?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3232064/south-china-sea-arrival-philippines-resupply-mission-sign-beijing-backing-or-chinas-long-game?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/23/7f856ed0-fc05-452c-92c1-705fbc6ff33d_867ba987.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国似乎减弱了对菲律宾在南海补给任务的反应本周，观察人士称此举是为了防止国际阻力以及与东南亚邻国的进一步孤立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他们警告说，北京可能正在与马尼拉玩一场“持久战”，他们预计中国会很快就会恢复其自信的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管中国船只试图“阻止”和“骚扰”其任务，但菲律宾周二仍向有争议的南沙群岛的仁爱礁执行了补给任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾周二向有争议的南沙群岛的仁爱礁执行了补给任务。中国海警发言人刘德军随后表示，菲律宾船只已收到严厉警告并受到“有效监管”。但由于他们没有运送“非法建筑材料”，“临时特殊安排”允许他们运送食品和其他必需品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘强调，中国对南沙群岛拥有“无可争议的主权” — —北京称南沙为“南沙”，并坚决反对菲律宾“利用补给部队的机会向争议浅滩搁浅的军舰运送非法建筑材料”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一事态发展发生在中国海警船只拦截的几周后并发射水炮警告一艘执行类似补给任务的菲律宾船只。中国声称该船无视其一再警告，并试图转移建筑材料来维护和修理该船。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然中国对周二补给任务的反应并不是重大转变，但防务分析人士表示，这是一种更加谨慎的做法，表明北京不想煽动紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉惹勒南国际研究学院高级研究员科林·科(Collin Koh)表示，“非常明显，这似乎是一种升级” “我不明白为什么中国会觉得现在有必要升级[紧张局势]，这可能会使其声誉付出巨大代价，甚至可能疏远其东盟朋友， ”他指的是东南亚地区集团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特别是，周二的事态发展正值中国与其东南亚邻国就南海行为准则进行谈判之际。本周，马尼拉将接待中国和其他地区国家的外交官，讨论旨在规范资源丰富水道行为的行为准则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Koh 表示，北京方面也可能意识到，马尼拉的马科斯政府——与之前对中国更加友好的杜特尔特政府不同——很容易在国际舞台上升级问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么一艘生锈的菲律宾旧军舰会卷入南海争端？&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;涉及水枪的事件引发了世界各国的反应，其中包括马尼拉的长期盟友美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果事件（本周）确实升级，中国将似乎是罪魁祸首。高说：“中国人将不会受到良好的关注……这将戳到国际谴责的马蜂窝。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马尼拉德拉萨大学讲师唐·麦克莱恩·吉尔(Don McLain Gill)也提出类似建议：中国过去十年的模式表明，它对在南海进行接二连三的挑衅“相当谨慎”，因为担心这可能会导致重大误判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然中国试图表明，尽管它出现在该地区，但由于几周前遭到国际社会的强烈反对，它并没有试图大力封锁菲律宾水域的补给任务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Koh，专门研究菲律宾海军事务印太地区表示，中国看似温和的回应也可能是北京宣扬其该地区国家可以自行解决冲突的说法的一种方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国一再强调美国和其他西方国家各国一直在南海煽动紧张局势，破坏该地区的稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最高外交官王毅本月出访东南亚时，也传达了同样的信息，称美国和其他人“不断在海上兴风作浪，生怕南海不再混乱”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果中国不断挑战水炮[事件]的极限，它本质上是在告诉所有人：高说：“南海需要更多的地区各方[干预]。”周三，当被问及这一事件时，中国外交部发言人汪文斌表示，中国已采取必要措施，并敦促菲律宾“立即停止任何使当地局势复杂化的行动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，尽管北京这次似乎有所后退，但吉尔表示，仍不确定这种做法是否会持续下去。他引用了中国的回应，表明它正在“允许”马尼拉进行补给，并且可以用来证明未来封锁的合理性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果北京认为，它可能会恢复自信。 “国际社会对其好战姿态的关注度有所下降。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;菲律宾对“外部参与者”的支持对南海意味着什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Koh 表示，中国可以“打持久战”并决定何时对马尼拉采取更加积极的行动，因为它有这样做的军事能力。他说，中国还认为，美国不会总是在该地区存在以帮助较弱的东南亚国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鉴于其海岸警卫队、海军和海上民兵的能力，它可以派遣他说：“在西菲律宾海任何时候都持续存在，如果需要的话，可能会……动员他们进行此类活动以发出信号。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们可能认识到，他们拥有无论如何，有足够的资金去做这件事。因此，问题在于他们是否愿意按下按钮。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pakistani children rescued from broken cable car appeal for bridge, road, school]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3232086/pakistani-children-rescued-broken-cable-car-appeal-bridge-road-school?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 23:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/23/9912983a-16d3-48ed-82ea-791928654deb_b27384aa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;从巴基斯坦山谷上方悬挂的破损缆车中获救的儿童说周三，尽管他们的父母试图通过电话安抚他们，但在这 16 小时的磨难中，他们一再担心自己即将死去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还呼吁在他们的村庄修建一所学校和一座桥梁，以便他们能够以后不必再乘坐缆车了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，在一次大胆的救援行动中，六名儿童和两名成人从缆车上被救出。其中最年轻的一名被用绳索连接到直升机上的突击队员抓住，而其他人则被用木床架和绳索搭建的临时升降椅降到地面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我听说过关于奇迹的故事。获救者之一、15 岁的奥萨马·谢里夫 (Osama Sharif) 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，奥萨马前往学校领取期末考试成绩。当其中一根电缆折断时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们突然感到一阵震动，这一切发生得太突然，我们以为我们所有人都会死，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些船上的人拥有手机并开始打电话。忧心忡忡的父母试图安抚孩子们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们告诉我们不要担心，帮助即将到来，”他说。几个小时后，乘客们看到直升机在空中飞行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本地制造的缆车是开伯尔-普赫图赫瓦省巴塔格拉姆山区广泛使用的交通工具。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;滑翔穿越陡峭的山谷，它们减少了前往学校、工作场所和企业的旅行时间。但缆车往往维护不善，每年都有人在使用缆车时死亡或受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，警方逮捕了缆车车主古尔·扎林 (Gul Zarin)，罪名是忽视安全措施。西北山区地方当局表示，他们将关闭所有被认为不安全的缆车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，数千人前来观看这一危险的操作。有一次，当一个用安全带固定的孩子被拉上来时，从直升机上降下的一根绳子剧烈摇晃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，直升机增加了危险因素。旋转的叶片搅动的气流有可能削弱唯一防止缆车坠落到河谷底部的缆索。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们哭了，眼里含着泪水，因为我们担心缆车将会坠落。”奥萨马说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;巴基斯坦峡谷上空缆车上救出的全部 7 名儿童&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;日落后，直升机无法再飞行，救援人员转移了位置策略。当地警察局长纳齐尔·艾哈迈德 (Nazir Ahmed) 说，他们使用临时升降椅接近缆车，其中一根电缆仍然完好无损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当升降椅降到地面时，爆发出“上帝伟大”的呼喊声。午夜前是手术的最后阶段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;艾哈迈德说，作为预防措施，孩子们在被交给父母之前接受了氧气，其中许多人都喜极而泣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外两名幸存者 Rizwan Ullah 和 Gul Faraz 表示，他们多年来都不会忘记这次苦难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gul 说，他在等待救援时担心缆车会坠落到地面，“我们很快就会死去”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他呼吁政府在该地区建一所学校，并用桥梁和道路将他们的村庄与附近的城镇连接起来，“这样我们的老人和年轻人就不会面临这样的事情”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度北部邦公交车坠入峡谷，造成至少 26 人死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;11 岁的 Rizwan 表示，他不想再使用缆车，但那也只能是如果附近建一所学校，这也是可能的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一名获救学生阿塔·乌拉 (Ata Ullah) 说，下次他必须骑车时，他会尽量勇敢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我感到恐惧我想乘坐缆车，但我没有其他选择。等缆车修好了，我再去学校。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Brics members give support to expanding the bloc to face ‘turbulent times’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3232083/brics-members-give-support-expanding-bloc-face-turbulent-times?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 21:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/23/5bfad1a4-6aa2-4f1c-a1b1-f58b614ed60a_54968ec0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;包括中国在内的金砖国家大力支持金砖国家集团的扩张leading emerging economies, with an announcement expected during this week&#39;s summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meeting in Johannesburg on Wednesday, Chinese President Xi Jinping and his counterparts from South Africa, Brazil, Russia and India all gave their support to the move to allow more members into the grouping, which the five countries formed in 2009.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But they were still discussing that and other issues including trading more in national currencies and support for emerging markets and developing countries. South African President Cyril Ramaphosa said an announcement on expanding Brics would be made at the summit, which ends on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese president attended the summit on Wednesday and delivered a speech after skipping a business forum on Tuesday – where he had been expected to make a speech – without explanation. Xi said the world had entered a “new period of turbulence” and Brics countries had an important role in stabilising the global economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said development should not be a privilege reserved for a few but a right for all countries, and he supported the inclusion of more nations in Brics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am glad to see growing enthusiasm of developing countries about participating in Brics cooperation. And quite a number of them have applied to join … we need to accelerate the Brics expansion process to bring more countries into the Brics family,” Xi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said expansion would help countries to “pool our strengths and wisdom to make global governance more just and equitable”. He said international rules should not be dictated by those with the strongest muscles or loudest voices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi also proposed that a China-Brics science hub be set up to support innovation as well as cooperation on global remote-sensing data to support agriculture, conservation and disaster preparedness in various countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And he said China would work with other Brics nations to develop artificial intelligence frameworks and standards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi was the only leader absent from the Brics business forum on Tuesday, with Chinese Commerce Minister Wang Wentao reading a speech in his place that had a hardline message apparently aimed at the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked why Xi had not attended the forum, foreign ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin sidestepped the question, telling reporters in Beijing on Wednesday that Xi&#39;s speech had been delivered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the speech read by Wang Wentao on Tuesday, Xi said: “Some country, obsessed with maintaining its hegemony, has gone out of its way to cripple the emerging and developing countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Whoever is developing fast becomes its target of containment;谁追上来，谁就成为其阻碍的目标。 But this is futile, as I have said more than once that blowing out others&#39; lamps will not bring light to oneself.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking about expanding the bloc on Wednesday, South African leader Ramaphosa said: “We stand on the cusp of expanding the Brics family because it is through this that we will have a much stronger Brics in these turbulent times that we live in.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other Brics leaders – including Russian President Vladimir Putin, who defended the war in Ukraine in his speech delivered by video – also gave their support to the move.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“India supports expansion of Brics in line with consensus,” Prime Minister Narendra Modi said, helping to clear doubt over New Delhi&#39;s stance on allowing more countries in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move was among issues discussed at a leaders&#39; retreat at Summer Place in Hyde Park on Tuesday evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Argentina&#39;s bid for Brics membership is up for discussion and subject to debate&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Dozens of countries in the Global South are looking to join Brics, which they see as a grouping that could challenge a world order dominated by the United States and its Western allies. More than 40 countries have expressed interest in joining the bloc, with 23 having formally asked to be admitted, according to South African officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Brics countries also want to reduce the dominance of the US dollar in the international financial markets, with some leaders suggesting domestic currencies be used for payments before the launch of a proposed Brics currency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2015, Brics established the New Development Bank, which has so far approved more than 90 projects worth US$32 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brazilian President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva defended the idea of a common trading currency among the Brics countries, saying the intention was not to reject the US dollar but to facilitate trade between emerging economies in their national currencies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have advocated the idea of greater financial integration, where we can have a new reference unit, which will not replace our national currencies,” Lula da Silva said on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that Brics was not meant to challenge the US, the Group of Seven or the Group of 20 but to “organise” countries in the Global South into growing their trade and cooperation.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore police investigate 18 bomb threats around the city state, including at government buildings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3232084/singapore-police-investigate-18-bomb-threats-around-city-state-including-government-buildings?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 21:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/e15fe8c0-9778-4aee-b60e-4039ee06bf01_73e9d566.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Singapore police have launched an investigation into bomb threats allegedly made at more than a dozen locations around the city state, including government buildings and embassies, police said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities were alerted to the threats at around 09.10am local time on Wednesday, the Singapore Police Force said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It added that the threats were reported at “18 locations around Singapore, including government buildings, embassies and other places of interest”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore jails man who helped Chinese prostitute overstay visa for sex, cash&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Officers coordinated with security guards but “no items of security concern were found”, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The force did not disclose the specific locations involved or if any evacuations had taken place after the threats were made.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the Ministry of Sustainability and the Environment said its office building – which also houses the country&#39;s environment and water agencies – had received one of the bomb threats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“No threat items were found. Since this morning, we have stepped up security and restricted access into the Environment Building,” it said in a statement on Facebook.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its own statement, the police force said it was “aware that similar reports of email bomb threats sent seemingly by the same person, had been received by the Republic of Korea recently, which had turned out to be a hoax”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Suez Canal: Singapore-flagged vessel collides with tanker, traffic set to resume&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The police take all security threats seriously and will not hesitate to take action against those who intentionally communicate false information on bomb threats,” it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The force urged members of the public to report suspicious people and items, such as parcels with stains or wires, or those that give off a strange smell.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anyone found guilty of “communicating false information of a harmful thing” can be imprisoned for up to seven years, fined up to S$50,000 (US$37,000) or both, it said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s ‘pro-innovation’ AI regulations augur well for eventual public release of Ernie Bot and other local ChatGPT alternatives, Baidu CEO says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3232071/chinas-pro-innovation-ai-regulations-augur-well-eventual-public-release-ernie-bot-and-other-local?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/3d013976-3f90-4a8e-b0f1-5ef01a562e61_743e12f7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese internet search giant Baidu, which unveiled its answer to ChatGPT in March, remains confident that the country&#39;s regulators would eventually give the green light to the commercial release of Ernie Bot and other home-grown generative artificial intelligence services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Robin Li Yanhong, Baidu&#39;s co-founder, chairman and chief executive, shared that positive view in a conference call with analysts on Tuesday after the Beijing-based company reported strong second-quarter financial results.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are still awaiting the green light for the large-scale roll-out of Ernie Bot in consumer-facing apps,” Li said. “While we don&#39;t have an exact date for everything … we&#39;re quite optimistic about the future of a better regulatory environment.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He indicated that the country&#39;s new generative AI regulations, which took effect on August 15, were “more pro-innovation than regulation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Baidu&#39;s optimism reflects the supportive tone of the new regulations, which were drawn up by seven Chinese agencies led by the Cyberspace Administration of China (CAC), as authorities pledged “to take effective measures to encourage innovative development of generative AI”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Generative AI refers to algorithms – such as those behind OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT, Google&#39;s Bard, Ernie Bot and iFlytek&#39;s Spark – that can be used to create new content, including audio, code, images, text, simulations and videos.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese state media in June started to drum up support for generative AI development in the country, extolling its potential to help drive economic growth and become a useful daily tool, while maintaining caution about its risks and asserting regulation of the technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Generative AI is pretty new, and it&#39;s understandable that people might have concerns about things like user privacy, IP [intellectual property] protection and AI ethics,” Baidu&#39;s Li said. “So there should be certain regulatory requirements in place.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Baidu&#39;s Ernie Bot joins iFlytek&#39;s Spark on Apple&#39;s China App Store&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Internet regulator CAC has yet to issue a licence for any generative AI product in the country, even as Big Tech firms like Baidu, Alibaba Group Holding and iFlytek have rolled out ChatGPT-like services on a trial basis. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, Baidu&#39;s Ernie Bot and iFlytek&#39;s Spark recently became the first ChatGPT alternatives developed by Chinese Big Tech firms to get listed on Apple&#39;s mainland App Store.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ernie Bot users, however, are required to obtain an additional permit to use any of the app&#39;s functions after downloading it, as Beijing has not allowed any generative AI service to be made available to the general public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All generative AI algorithms and products must go through security testing and review by the CAC before these can be made available to the public. US start-up OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT and Google&#39;s Bard are not available in China&#39;s closed market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CAC in June published a list of 41 generative AI algorithms that have been “registered” with the agency, part of a pre-screening process before a licence is granted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While there is currently no timeline for the public roll-out of local generative AI services in mainland China, Baidu&#39;s Li said the country&#39;s AI trend was “very promising”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The government has increasingly recognised Ernie Bot, which we believe provides a good foundation for its eventual release on a large scale,” he said. “We are working closely with the regulators and other organisations to push the development and the proper usage of generative AI.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his prepared remarks during the conference call on Tuesday, Li said Baidu has already integrated Ernie Bot its various products to “improve, rebuild and create new offerings”. That included enabling the firm&#39;s Baidu Search app to provide users with more personalised and in-depth research on a topic or project.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 22:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Free shipping, faster delivery: Chinese e-commerce giants JD.com, Alibaba lock horns in logistics]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3232049/free-shipping-faster-delivery-chinese-e-commerce-giants-jdcom-alibaba-lock-horns-logistics?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/510caa2f-0143-4a44-b0b1-8368a12d624f_bcb92cc2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Delivery has emerged as the new battleground for China&#39;s e-commerce giants, as they jostle to win local consumers with faster and cheaper shipping services, in a sign of an intensifying competition in the sector amid weak consumer spending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JD.com, the Beijing-based e-commerce company founded by Richard Liu Qiangdong, on Wednesday lowered its free-shipping minimum order to 59 yuan (US$8.2) from 99 yuan. It marked the first time in eight years that the company has updated its free-shipping policy after a hike in the minimum qualifying amount in 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Subscribers to the firm&#39;s JD Plus service, akin to Amazon Prime, are now entitled to unlimited free delivery, compared with five free deliveries a month previously.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move comes as Cainiao Network, the logistics arm of Alibaba Group Holding, has rolled out same-day and next-day door-to-door delivery in 300 Chinese cities, as well as half-day express delivery in eight major cities, including Shanghai, Hangzhou, Shenzhen, Guangzhou, Dongguan, Foshan, Huizhou and Chengdu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new Cainiao Express service, which forms part of a string of initiatives unveiled in June by incoming Alibaba chairman Joe Tsai, was launched in collaboration with Tmall Supermarket. Alibaba&#39;s Taobao Tmall Commerce Group is also setting up its own logistics department to meet its unique delivery demands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Delivery charges and service quality are key factors determining success in China&#39;s heated online-shopping competition, according to analysts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Free shipping is a very effective means to compete in a crowded market and draw users from lower-tier markets,” said Zhuang Shuai, founder and chief analyst at e-commerce consultancy Bailian.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He noted that Pinduoduo, a Chinese e-commerce platform known for its cut-to-the-bone prices, has surged in popularity thanks partly to its free shipping services, available for a vast range of goods sold on its app.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JD.com has in recent months pivoted to a low-cost strategy to tap lower-tier markets by allowing smaller merchants to open stores on its platform, signalling a departure from its traditional business model that focused on wooing established brands to its platform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We want our platform to cater to more consumers and more of their needs … and to satisfy those needs, we will have to have a bigger supply [of goods],” Wang Xiong, a JD.com executive in charge of the firm&#39;s strategy direction, told the Post in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While JD.com&#39;s new free-shipping policy may have a short-term impact on the firm&#39;s revenue, it is manageable after the company recorded robust sales and income growth for the June quarter, according to Chen Tao, analyst with Beijing-based market consultancy Analysys.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JD.com reported a 50 per cent rise in net profit to 6.6 billion yuan for the three months ended June 30, while revenue rose 7.6 per cent to 287.9 billion yuan.阿里巴巴旗下淘宝和天猫的收入同期增长 12%，达到 1150 亿元人民币。 Both JD.com and Alibaba credited solid sales at the 618 mid-year shopping festival for its earnings performance.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>