<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong and global graduates, motivated by high salaries, eye career in finance in post-Covid-19 era: CFA Institute survey]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3223946/hong-kong-and-global-graduates-motivated-high-salaries-eye-career-finance-post-covid-19-era-cfa?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/1c7ebac7-16c2-41d8-834b-cebbe47a5617_1cce09aa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;金融是包括香港在内的全球毕业生的首选职业，因为他们认为根据 CFA Institute 周三发布的一项调查，该行业在后 Covid-19 时代提供更好的薪酬和增长前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约 30% 的大学毕业生表示，他们会将金融视为他们的第一要务根据 2023 年全球毕业生展望调查，其次是信息技术和电信，占 25%，医学占 21%。 4 月，英国、美国、加拿大、印度、澳大利亚、新加坡、香港和德国等 13 个市场的 9,430 多名受访者接受了调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2021 年大流行期间的一项类似调查中，金融业排名第五教育是最重要的职业选择。当时，有 14.5% 的受访者表示他们会选择银行业和金融业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“自疫情结束以来，肯定有向金融业的转变，因为它提供了非常广泛的基础CFA Institute 亚太区常务董事 Nick Pollard 在接受采访时表示：“这些知识可以将毕业生带到许多不同的方向，而且报酬更高。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种转变反映了毕业生’对未来的信心不断增强，这驱使他们进入那些以信心、乐观和创新为基础的行业，”他说。 “随着市场继续稳定和增长，金融作为一种职业将保持其吸引力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去三年中，许多商业交易和资本市场活动因冠状病毒大流行而中断，这就是为什么金融香港证券及投资学会总监徐联安表示，“Fomo”并非 2021 年毕业生的首选。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“Fomo”，穿梭于中国 Z 世代的投资动机之中：CFA Institute&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;“由于取消了所有 Covid-19 限制，业务恢复正常，”Tsui 说。 “许多金融公司正在重新招聘。很自然，毕业生再次发现金融业是一个有吸引力的职业选择。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领先的保险公司 Manulife、AIA 和 Prudential 计划今年在香港招聘合计 10,000 名新代理人，以利用回归的业务大陆游客。保诚香港周一在澳门开设了一家新分行，并计划聘请500名代理人。汇丰银行和花旗集团等主要银行也计划增加员工人数以推动其财富管理业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港金融公司愿意支付更多费用聘请人才，以抓住大湾区带来的新商机区域发展和北京支持香港作为国际金融中心的政策，”金融服务业立法者兼本地经纪公司 Grand Capital Holdings 首席执行官李惠旺说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在 Covid- 19、很多行业都缺人才，金融行业也不例外。许多金融公司已开始提供更高的薪水和更好的工作条件以吸引人才，”Lee 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;商会调查发现，四分之三的香港公司都在为人才短缺而苦苦挣扎&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港的CFA 调查显示，毕业生总体上对自己的职业前景持积极态度，近 70% 的人对自己的未来充满信心。不过，该比例略低于 75% 的全球平均水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但雇主在留住年轻人才方面可能面临挑战，因为调查显示，半数香港毕业生计划在第一份工作中留任一段时间只需要一到两年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;薪水是香港毕业生留在雇主那里的最大动力。超过 60% 的人表示他们正在寻找一份好薪水，高于 2021 年的 25%。紧随其后的是 46% 的年假和 45% 的明显增长进步机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;猎头公司 Barons &amp; Co 的董事总经理 Jerry Chang 表示，调查结果解释了为什么香港毕业生想加入银行和金融业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“银行业雇用了大量经验丰富的银行家，他们的平均水平高级职位的薪水相对于许多其他行业要高得多，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于大流行导致灵活的工作安排，因此它成为香港毕业生的首要任务也就不足为奇了.超过一半的受访者表示他们更喜欢完全的灵活性，而 45% 的人投票支持混合工作环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们中的大多数人在 Covid-19 期间毕业，习惯于在家工作并管理他们的工作自己的时间，因此准备好迎接新常态，从雇主的角度来看，留住人才非常重要，”CFA 的 Pollard 说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 08:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[To understand the Quad’s real ambitions, ignore its empty rhetoric and look at its actions in the Indo-Pacific]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3223608/understand-quads-real-ambitions-ignore-its-empty-rhetoric-and-look-its-actions-indo-pacific?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/59db588a-fd48-46c2-a600-d38646886c40_c3f0b5ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新加坡香格里拉对话中美对峙之后, Quad 的重要性越来越大。四方安全对话是澳大利亚、印度、日本和美国之间松散但发展迅速的安全安排。由于它希望通过“Quad Plus”计划进行扩张，现在是分析其意图和方向的好时机。四方领导人上个月第五次会议的声明提供了一个起点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;用他们的话说，四方打算维护“自由和开放的印太地区”并维护“基于规则的国际秩序” ”。这是主要由美国和西方建立和主导的、优先惠及他们的国际体系的准则。四方领导人认为，它越来越受到来自崛起的中国的威胁，必须阻止这种情况。他们希望通过协调他们的战略来限制、遏制并在必要时对抗中国来做到这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Quad 的议程包括“维护印太海域的和平与稳定”等安全问题，以及“遵守国际法，特别是《联合国海洋法公约》(Unclos) 中所反映的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Quad 之前举行过军事演习，其 Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness 可以为开展针对中国军队的情报监视侦察合作奠定基础。但它也巧妙地将此与一项议程合并，该议程包括在气候变化、灾害风险、流行病、基础设施、网络和海上安全等非传统安全问题上的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是对谨慎的印度的安抚和日本，以及东南亚的敏感性。事实上，如果不是印度的不结盟政策和截然不同的世界观（从其拒绝谴责俄罗斯入侵乌克兰可见一斑）以及日本禁止部署进攻性武器的宪法限制，四方机制本可以更快地朝着核心安全安排发展。澳大利亚也注意到中国和东南亚的敏感性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然这些因素可能会减缓四方机制向全面反华防御安排的演变，但日益咄咄逼人的中国可能会迫使一个或多个人保持警惕成员改变他们的曲调。美国希望 Quad 成为一种威慑力量——中国和该地区的许多国家也这么看。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Quad 的幕僚试图隐藏其所谓的“对自由和自由的坚定承诺”开放的印太地区具有包容性和弹性”然而，美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀在香格里拉对话会上表示，美国正在“在国防规划的每个阶段”“加倍努力”建立区域联盟和伙伴关系。&lt;/p>; p>;“我们的共同目标很明确：阻止侵略并深化促进繁荣和防止冲突的规则和规范，”他说。 “因此，我们正在加强规划和协调，并与我们从东海到南海再到印度洋的朋友一起进行训练。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当四方领导人说他们“寻求一个区域没有国家主导，没有国家被支配——所有国家都不受胁迫”，这被视为针对中国。但美国在军事和经济上胁迫世界各地的国家，包括印太地区的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例子包括其所谓的航行自由行动以及对中国等国家和国防部长等高级官员实施的制裁李尚福，都是为了逼迫政策和行动的改变。令人惊讶的是，华盛顿想知道为什么李克强不会见他的美国同行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;甚至四方声称由印太国家组成的说法也值得怀疑。澳大利亚是唯一真正的印太国家，因为它毗邻两个大洋。美国毗邻太平洋，那里有许多殖民时代和二战遗留下来的财产，但什么使它成为“印度”国家？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果是它在迪戈加西亚岛的军事基地，那相当困难。许多非洲国家与印度洋接壤。这并不能使它们成为“太平洋”国家。印度不是“太平洋”国家，日本也不是“印度”国家——除非将其对石油和天然气进口的海上通道的依赖计算在内。有了这个定义，在该地区拥有安全利益，许多国家可以声称自己是“印太”——英国、德国和法国等一些国家似乎倾向于这样做。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国通过在其围绕中国的战略中将该地区最边缘的国家拼凑在一起，创造了这个模糊的印太概念和组合。这似乎是基于概念帝国主义。事实上，对美国而言，关键是它在该地区拥有安全利益和军事基地，并将其军队部署在那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四方领导人一再重申他们“支持东盟的中心地位”。但四方机制如果有效，将成为区域安全管理的核心，尤其是在南中国海。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，美国及其盟国可能希望利用东盟或其部分成员国作为堡垒和缓冲中国，但未能确保他们希望的合作程度。因此，他们四处走动，在澳大利亚、英国和美国之间形成了四国和奥库斯防御协定。这样做削弱了东盟在地区安全事务中的中心地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四方领导人还强调了遵守国际法和联合国海洋法公约的重要性。但美国并没有批准《联合国海洋法公约》，其一些做法和主张，以及澳大利亚、印度和日本的做法和主张，都违反了它的规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关键是，人们不应该仅仅依靠Quad 的华而不实的言辞，而是通过其行动来衡量其意图。对于敏锐的分析师和政策制定者来说，现实胜过谎言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mainland Chinese investors look to Southeast Asia for commercial property as political tensions, interest rates make US, Australia less appealing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3223962/mainland-chinese-investors-look-southeast-asia-commercial-property-political-tensions-interest-rates?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/15fe2337-bd0e-4e2e-80d2-a566ff66eee5_37b76fe0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;东南亚的商业地产市场越来越受到中国大陆投资者的青睐，因为政治分歧和根据 Juwai IQI 的一份报告，较高的利率削弱了澳大利亚和美国等传统热门国家的吸引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚现在是中国投资该行业的主要离岸目的地，马来西亚则是根据房地产技术公司的排名，泰国排名第三，泰国排名第五。 2022年，印度尼西亚和马来西亚分别排在第四位和第五位，而泰国甚至连前五名都没有。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，去年作为首选投资目的地的美国却未能完全跻身前五，而澳大利亚在 2022 年从第二位跌至第四位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“投资者认为东南亚是一个有吸引力的目的地，因为中国与这些国家之间的商业联系正在增长，而随着美国，”报告称。 “他们快速增长的经济为可开发土地、旅游设施、工业园区以及工业和物流设施提供了机会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际货币基金组织 (IMF) 在 4 月份预测，这三个东南亚经济体今年将实现增长增长 3.4% 至 5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;IMF 表示，美国和澳大利亚今年的增长率预计仅为 1.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国和澳大利亚目前的增长率分别为 5.25% 和 4.10%，而印度尼西亚、马来西亚和泰国的增长率介于 2% 和 5.75% 之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东南亚国家的增长前景较好Juwai IQI 表示，这让投资者更有动力将资金投入那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的对外投资受到北京严格的资本管制的阻碍，这给“东南亚国家带来了进一步的优势，因为投资者发现项目获得批准在这些目的地更容易，”该报告补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿和北京的关系在过去几年中恶化，贸易、技术甚至亚洲领土主张的争端加剧了紧张局势。堪培拉和北京之间的关系也好不到哪里去，在冠状病毒大流行的起源和贸易禁令问题上的分歧加剧了不和谐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使美国对东南亚商业地产的偏好转变可能会继续&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不仅仅是利率降低了中国对美国商业房地产的投资，”Juwai IQI 的联合创始人兼集团首席执行官 Kashif Ansari 说. “你也有自 2018 年以来一直存在的结构性下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这与中国政府对对外投资方向的偏好有关。这也与投资者非常谨慎并避开未来政治紧张局势可能使事情变得更加困难的市场有关。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最终，中国大陆投资者更倾向于在国内购买商业房地产，因为&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年前三个月，中国资本购买了约 44 亿美元的国内资产，这使他们在境外投资的 5 亿美元相形见绌。仲量联行资本市场数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国大陆投资者现在在国内市场更加内向，在出国时只考虑香港和新加坡等少数几个市场，”首席财务官 Ada Choi 表示CBRE 亚太地区租户研究。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rescue dog Wilson, who helped find lost children in Colombian Amazon, is now missing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3223996/rescue-dog-wilson-who-helped-find-lost-children-colombian-amazon-now-missing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 07:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/b803c894-0401-4833-899b-5592d7cc3278_4020ab48.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;6 岁的追踪犬 Wilson，在最终成功的过程中失踪，在哥伦比亚亚马逊地区寻找四名失踪土著儿童长达数周的时间，现在他本人也成了救援任务的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数十名士兵正在丛林中搜寻两周前因公失踪的犬类英雄，军方发誓不会“抛弃一名倒下的战友”，他们可能在救援队到达之前很久就找到了孩子们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在莱斯利 40 天的漫长旅程圆满结束后，大家松了一口气， 13; Soleiny，九岁； Tien Noriel，五岁；和一岁的克里斯汀一样，哥伦比亚人也一直在社交媒体上呼吁 Wilson 安全返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;#Let&#39;sGoForWilson、#OneIsMissing 和#WilsonNationalHero 是进行巡视的一些标签。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哥伦比亚人还开始在窗户上张贴海报，坚持说：“威尔逊失踪”，而其他人则张贴他们的猫和其他宠物的照片，上面贴着恳求狗安全归来的标语。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“搜索还没有结束，”军方在上周五找到孩子后发表的一份声明中坚称，并补充说，仍有 70 多名士兵部署在茂密的丛林中寻找比利时牧羊犬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们包括克里斯蒂安·大卫·拉腊 (Cristian David Lara)，威尔逊还是一只正在接受训练的小狗时，他就是他的饲养员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉拉的一位同事告诉《观察家报》(El Espectador)，“在找到他的狗之前，他不想离开”。负责寻找孩子的佩德罗​​·桑切斯将军补充说：“我们要去威尔逊，我们要把他带回来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“神奇的一天”：4 名儿童在哥伦比亚森林被发现还活着&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 5 月 1 日的小型飞机失事夺去了三人的生命后几天，威尔逊在距离残骸约 4 公里（2.5 英里）的茂密植被中找到了克里斯汀丢弃的婴儿奶瓶船上的成年人，包括兄弟姐妹的母亲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几个星期过去了，一支由近 200 名士兵和土著丛林专家组成的团队在几只狗的陪同下不断发现孩子们还活着的迹象：吃了一半的水果、丢弃的尿布、临时住所和脚印。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后，两周前，“由于地形、湿度和恶劣天气条件的复杂性”，威尔逊一定是“迷失了方向”并消失了，军方说在一份声明中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，在他的人类战友们看不见威尔逊之后，有证据表明他可能是第一个找到孩子的人：在救援前不久，在孩子们的脚印附近发现了一只狗的脚印团队找到了他们。两个大一点的孩子 Lesly 和 Soleiny 从那以后在河边和树丛中画了一只狗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;负责监督孩子康复的哥伦比亚家庭福利研究所所长 Astrid Caceres 说，他们一直&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lesly “告诉我们……他们失去了一只狗，他们不知道它去了哪里，它陪伴了他们一段时间”，她回忆道。 p>;&lt;p>;哥伦比亚军队在几十年的内部冲突中训练了超过 17,000 只狗，专业包括爆炸物探测、排雷和搜救。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了野生动物、昆虫和亚马逊的持续降雨, 威尔逊还冒着遇到武装团体成员的风险，他们仍然活跃在丛林中，为毒品和其他非法贸易而战。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;一只救援犬在执行地震任务时走失后，土耳其送给墨西哥一只可爱的小狗&lt;/h3>; p>;Sanchez 说 Wilson 没有配备 GPS 追踪器来防止“敌人”找到他和他的人类战友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在波哥大，55 岁的家庭主妇 Nora Villa 是密切关注事件的人之一狗的命运。 “拜托，愿他们尽一切可能找到小狗威尔逊！”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在威尔逊失踪的那天，军方在推特上发誓“永远不会抛弃战场上倒下的战友”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寻找孩子的行动被称为“行动”霍普将继续“寻找我们的威尔逊犬，它……在急于寻找孩子的过程中，与部队走散了”，它说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple taps Chinese contract manufacturer Luxshare, six other mainland suppliers in production of Vision Pro mixed-reality headset]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3223959/apple-taps-chinese-contract-manufacturer-luxshare-six-other-mainland-suppliers-production-vision-pro?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/dd58f697-e9c4-4671-945d-53cfd2d5a894_86eec935.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国电子产品代工制造商立讯精密，苹果 AirPods 的主要供应商根据当地咨询公司 Wellsenn XR 的最新物料清单 (BOM) 分析，还赢得了 iPhone 15 订单，成为美国科技巨头新款 Vision Pro 混合现实耳机的组装商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该分析显示七家大陆公司是苹果 Vision Pro 耳机的供应商，该耳机上周作为“空间计算”设备推出，改变了用户与他们喜爱的应用程序交互、捕捉图像、欣赏电视节目和电影以及通过以下方式与他人联系的方式FaceTime。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除立讯精密（Luxshare）外，Vision Pro 的其他主要大陆供应商包括摄像头模组制造商高伟电子控股和深圳德赛电池科技，后者提供锂电池和电源据跟踪中国增强现实 (AR) 和虚拟现实 (VR) 行业的 Wellsenn XR 称，立讯精密和其他中国大陆公司参与生产 Vision Pro 耳机反映了尽管地缘政治和经济发展可能会加速全球供应链重组，但苹果公司对该国庞大的电子制造供应网络投下了新的信任票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，台湾公司仍然占参与其中的大部分供应商苹果Vision Pro耳机的生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有11家台湾供应商参与Vision Pro，包括塑料非球面透镜和光学元件制造商Largan Precision Co，光学镜头产品供应商Genius Electronic Optical Co，触控显示技术台湾金融报纸《商报》援引摩根士丹利的研究数据称，GIS-KY 和代工芯片制造商台积电的报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大陆和台湾的公司占了超过参与 Vision Pro 生产的供应商总数的一半，其中还包括韩国公司三星电子和 LG 电子以及日本索尼公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很明显，Vision Pro 目前的供应商，类似于技术研究公司和咨询公司 Counterpoint 的高级分析师 Ivan Lam 说：“iPhone 背后的 [公司] 结构是世界顶级消费电子元件供应商之一。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“这是计算的未来”：我们试用 Apple 的 3,499 美元 Vision Pro 耳机&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“当 Apple 在不久的将来发布价格更低的 AR/VR 产品时，供应链结构可能与当前的产品非常相似，”Lam 说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，Wellsenn XR 的分析还发现，Vision Pro 耳机生产中使用的所有组件和材料的预估 BOM 成本总计为 1,590 美元，不到该设备 3,499 美元的一半零售价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以下公司构成 Apple 在中国大陆供应 Vision Pro 耳机的公司：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; – 立讯精密位于南部科技中心深圳，稳步攀升 Apple 供应商行列据 Counterpoint 的 Lam 称，在过去的二十年中成为第一家被美国科技巨头招募来制造“第一代”产品 Vision Pro 的中国大陆合同制造商。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;富士康最大的中国竞争对手成立了由一名前工厂工人提供&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; – 这家总部位于东莞的公司将三星、LG 和苹果视为客户，于 2020 年获得立讯精密的战略投资，以帮助扩展到智能手机相机镜头的制造领域。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>; – 这家位于山东省东部的中国音频元件制造商在被列为 Vision Pro 耳机的精选供应商之一后，从去年停产的 AirPods 2 中恢复过来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; – 这家总部位于深圳的公司成立于近 40 年前，为包括苹果和华为技术有限公司在内的多家移动设备公司供应锂电池。在这家美国科技巨头转向大陆电池供应商以降低生产成本后，它进入了苹果的供应链。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>; – 兆威成立于2001年，为Vision Pro提供面向VR的电动对焦驱动系统。该组件可自动调整耳机的镜头，以确保用户清晰的视野。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; – MacBook 机箱制造商 Everwin Precision 和 iPhone 充电器供应商 Lingyi iTech 被 Apple 聘请为其提供结构组件，例如中框和外壳， &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt; /a&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore jails teacher for taking some 170 upskirt videos of over 40 colleagues, students]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223974/singapore-jails-teacher-taking-some-170-upskirt-videos-over-40-colleagues-students?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/59f45c00-e881-4d02-8ebd-b299b16e6958_dbc123bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新加坡的一位中学老师拍摄了大约 170 部同事和同事的裙底视频该校舍的学生已被判处 10 个月零两周的监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名 50 岁的男子因保护受害者的身份而在禁言令下无法透露姓名，他承认有罪九月至三项通过拍摄裙底视频侮辱女性尊严的罪名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在量刑时考虑了其他五项类似指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子自 2008 年以来一直在中学工作并于2015年成为管教主任。被捕时，他还教普通话。根据禁言令，学校也不能透露姓名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TODAY 了解到，尽管他自 2018 年以来一直被停职，但他仍然受雇为一名教师。TODAY 已经向教育部询问了他的身份，因为他已被判刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二宣判后，该男子的律师劳伦斯·吴 (Laurence Goh) 立即表示，他的当事人打算对判决提出上诉。该男子获得 15,000 新元（11,200 美元）的保释金，等待上诉听证会。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2015 年 4 月 18 日至 2018 年 7 月 11 日期间，罪犯拍摄了 156 部掀裙视频他学校至少有 38 名不同的同事，在多个场合拍摄了多达 12 部同一受害者的视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还拍摄了学校至少 7 名不同女学生的 12 部视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;根据副检察官 Yvonne Poon 准备的法庭文件，该老师通常会先邀请女同事到他的工作站进行数据输入，然后拍摄女同事的裙底视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他会设置他的手机调到录像模式，而同事则站在他的办公桌前键入学校相关数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“令人震惊”：新加坡男子，86 岁，因黑客攻击伴侣致死而被判入狱 15 年&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;然后，该男子会在受害者不知情或不同意的情况下，将手机放在受害者的裙子下面，摄像头朝上，录制一段掀裙视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老师只会邀请穿裙子或连衣裙的女同事过来到他的工作站而不是那些穿裤子的人。他很少邀请他的男同事到工作站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罪犯在拍摄学生的裙底视频时采用了类似的方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他通常会把学生带到纪律室并让女孩将某些东西输入计算机。趁着学生走神的时候，他会用手机录下她的裙底视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;录完视频后，老师会用他的办公室将视频从他的手机转移到外接硬盘上&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有一次，一名男学生因为拍了两段女老师的裙底视频而被抓并受到了惩罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老师自己用学生的手机录制了这些视频他以“取证”为借口拿走了手机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DPP Poon 说，尽管该男子没有分享或发布他制作的许多视频，但他已经将它们用于自己的性满足。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名女教师于 2018 年 7 月 14 日报警，她怀疑该男子一直在拍摄包括她在内的女教师的裙底视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子很硬磁盘被警方没收，发现包含约 170 部掀裙视频。每个视频的标题还包括受害者的姓名或首字母缩写（如果他知道），以及模糊的描述，例如“Student1”或“Lift Girl”（如果他不认识）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查还揭示了一个单独的事件，其中被告录制了一段在他岳母举办的派对上站在他旁边的女性亲戚的裙底视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡男子因使用非自愿性爱片段勒索前女友而入狱&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;辩护律师 Goh 提到了心理健康研究所的一份精神病学报告，他说，该报告显示该老师患有两种类型的抑郁症，这导致&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goh 说这意味着他的客户应该被判处非监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，地方法官 Brenda Tan 不同意并引用了报告中一名医生的言论即使老师可能依靠“严重失调”和“非法”的应对机制来“缓解他的抑郁情绪”，他仍然有能力对自己的欲望和冲动进行自我控制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;她补充说，他犯罪的规模和持续时间足以让他入狱，因为他以纪律主管的身份有预谋地实施这些行为，滥用了同事和学生的信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于每项罪名拍摄同事和学生的裙底视频，这位老师可能会被判入狱长达一年或罚款，或两者兼施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事最初由 &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>; 发布&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China ‘anxious and regretful’ over Ukraine war, says PLA strategist]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3223980/china-anxious-and-regretful-over-ukraine-war-says-pla-strategist?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/13/9fc147f2-2158-49d0-8138-773b3c31abbf_0fbbfe52.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国对乌克兰战争感到震惊并担心局势，并试图一位中国人民解放军战略家表示，找到和平解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近在新加坡结束的香格里拉防务对话期间，何雷中将强调，北京并未预料到这场战争，这始于去年 2 月俄罗斯入侵其邻国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国非常焦虑和遗憾，因为到目前为止我们还没有看到和平的曙光，”他告诉邮报，并补充说北京认为谈判是结束战争的唯一解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他质疑美国是为了和平还是战争，并补充说华盛顿目前的行动将延长冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我想问美国真的要和平吗？如果你[美国]真的想成为幕后的‘黑手’，还是你真的想成为带来和平的朋友？” he asked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He&#39;s remarks are consistent with comments made by Li Hui, China&#39;s special envoy for Eurasian affairs, who said after wrapping up his 12-day tour of Europe last month he had felt it was “rather difficult” to get all parties to sit down at the negotiation table&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He, a former vice-president of the PLA&#39;s Academy of Military Sciences who led the Chinese delegation to the Shangri-La Dialogue in 2017 and 2018, denied media reports that Beijing wanted to persuade Ukraine to “give up territory to Moscow as price of peace”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our stance is consistent.我们坚持各方的领土安全和主权应得到尊重。 No country can violate the security of another country for its own national security,” he said and criticised Nato for using the war to pressure and isolate Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;More terrorist missiles&#39;: Russian strikes on Zelensky&#39;s hometown kill 11&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The US treated Ukraine like cannon fodder in its struggle against Russia, so it would have one less competitor and strategic rival if Moscow loses the war.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Chenming, a researcher at the Beijing-based Yuan Wang military science and technology think tank, said Beijing was surprised that Ukraine had put up a tough fight especially after it lost Crimea to Russia eight years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Indeed, China didn&#39;t expect the Ukrainians could be so bold to fight against the powerful Russian troops for so long,” said Zhou, adding that he expects the war to continue until both sides become exhausted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other Chinese defence analysts said He and Li&#39;s remarks reflected Beijing&#39;s worries over the Ukraine war, which has seen both sides deploying more troops and lethal weapons in recent months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China feels anxious because it believes that one of the ultimate goals of the US-led West is not about weakening Russia but containing China, a move to preserve Washington&#39;s global hegemony,” said Eagle Yin Shuguang, a research fellow of the China Foundation for International and Strategic Studies in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Ukraine crisis has brought the US and European countries to a level of solidarity that is unprecedented, putting great pressure on China, which now wants to play the role of a key mediator.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yin said the war was likely to continue for at least another year as Western countries send Kyiv more advanced and powerful weapons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Both Russia and Ukrainian militaries have escalated their strikes, with many civilian facilities like power plants and dams now targets,” Yin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ni Lexiong, a professor of political science at Shanghai University of Political Science and Law, said Beijing was worried about what might happen if Russian President Vladimir Putin felt he was being cornered.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine claims new gains in early phase of counteroffensive&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The worst scenario is Putin using a tactical nuclear weapon as the last resort in order to win,” Ni said. “Only the victor on the battlefield has bargaining power at the negotiation table - that&#39;s always the case in any war.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou also urged Nato to make sure Moscow had a way out. “Don&#39;t force Putin into becoming another Adolf Hitler, bearing in mind that the Ukraine war has already flamed the rise of nationalism [in Russia],” Zhou said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[To deal with Hong Kong’s mental health struggles, increasing manpower is not enough]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3223816/deal-hong-kongs-mental-health-struggles-increasing-manpower-not-enough?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/13/5c188d2e-4788-4c5f-ac83-2cc753f0014b_4bc5d4f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After the recent tragic events involving people who appeared to be struggling with mental health issues, the Hong Kong government has taken prompt action, asking the Health Bureau&#39;s Advisory Committee on Mental Health to look at issues related to the model for psychiatric, rehabilitation and support services as well as manpower needs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While addressing the manpower shortage in health services is important, it is equally critical to comprehensively review Hong Kong&#39;s mental health and related services, to address the crux of the challenge in order to improve and sustain the mental health of the population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prevention is more effective and cost-efficient than treatment after illness has developed.为了妥善解决我们社区的心理健康需求，我们需要从宏观层面审视公共服务。 The authorities should address four aspects: increasing the number of healthcare staff, improving the matching and allocation of resources, nurturing individual resilience, and creating a caring and empathetic society.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Based on a projection at the end of last year, the Hospital Authority has 293,000 psychiatric patients and just 385 psychiatrists, with a doctor-patient ratio of one to 761, which is much lower than that of nearby countries. Meanwhile, demand for outpatient psychiatric services continues to rise, from 897,777 visits in 2018-19 to 957,149 in 2021-22.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With manpower in the public sector constrained, it has been suggested that patients should be diverted to the private healthcare system, but the cost of this is prohibitive.如果我们以每年1%的精神疾病发生率计算，那么以700万人口计算，每年可能新增7万名患者。这比一年中的现有工作量增加了 20%，但该系统现在无法扩展以提供 20% 以上的人力。 It looks like Hong Kong&#39;s mental health services will always be playing catch-up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent tragic events, the deadly attacks were allegedly committed by people who had received psychiatric care (as in the Diamond Hill shopping centre stabbing), or community outreach services (in the Sham Shui Po case). We must reflect on whether these services are adequate, effective, appropriate and responsive to people&#39;s needs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Sham Shui Po case, police have arrested a woman from the local ethnic minority community after her three children were found unconscious in their subdivided home and were later certified dead in hospital. There is an NGO located in the same building that provides services to low-income households and its staff had conducted welfare checks, but, unfortunately, did not get a chance to establish contact with that family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Social Welfare Department, the woman and her daughters were an active case under an integrated family service centre. The quality of such services and allocation of resources should be reviewed and adjusted, especially for ethnic minorities. Their needs have sometimes been overlooked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To sustainably improve the mental health of the population, we need to encourage and empower people to seek help. In addition to relying on the medical system for aid and treatment, we can improve our population&#39;s “suboptimal health” through education.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suboptimal health refers to the border state between good health and disease, and people in this state include those experiencing stress, who are often depressed, anxious or worried, prone to temper tantrums and who are hypersensitive. Those in suboptimal health do not have the obvious medical symptoms that warrant services from the healthcare system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We can improve suboptimal health through community support and counselling services, online and offline.本中心一直倡导将心理健康教育纳入幼儿园、中小学课程，让学生从小就更好地学会管理自己的情绪和人际冲突。 This helps build self-esteem and hope when facing adversity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government and the people of Hong Kong should work together to create a caring community. We may not be able to achieve immediate improvements to Hong Kong&#39;s crowded living conditions, but we can pursue policies conducive to mental health, such as adjusting working hours, improving low incomes and promoting family-friendly initiatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the day of the incident in Sham Shui Po, the district officer organised a seminar on emotional support in the community.通过讲座，以往不知道如何寻求帮助的居民，更多地了解了自己的情绪和寻求帮助的方式。 There were residents who said they were reluctant to seek help because of the high cost of mental health-related services.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hongkongers&#39; ailing mental health calls for a system revamp&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Fortunately, the Sham Shui Po community has a caring district commissioner, district councillors, business owners and neighbours willing to help each other and create a humanistic community. Through integrating community and service resources, we can ensure a better flow of aid to those in need.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To sum up, the prevention and treatment of mental illnesses should be integrated, and health and social services need to be better connected, as prevention is better than cure.需要采取补救措施，但它们往往是短暂的。我们需要促进社区的健康。 It takes the whole community working together to improve and sustain collective mental health.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[North Koreans who fled to China may be sent back to a harsh fate, US panel hears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3223995/north-koreans-who-fled-china-may-be-sent-back-harsh-fate-us-panel-hears?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 05:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_coronavirus_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/ccd9beb4-90b1-480f-a955-76703d674c55_f8e176ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The abating Covid-19 pandemic could result in up to 2,000 North Koreans being sent back to their country from China to face imprisonment or worse, US lawmakers heard in testimony on Tuesday. The experts who spoke urged the international community to pressure China and the United Nations to prevent their return.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Witnesses told the Congressional-Executive Commission on China that the pandemic – along with China&#39;s increasingly sophisticated security systems – has darkened the outlook for North Koreans fleeing their country to work, escape persecution or unite with family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have good reason to believe that such repatriation is imminent, as North Korea reopens its border following extended closure in the wake of the Covid-19 pandemic,” said Representative Chris Smith, a Republican from New Jersey. “I share this with deep concern.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even as Pyongyang has refused to accept foreign vaccines, it has responded to the pandemic by shutting itself off from the world.这导致中国在其共同边界附近逮捕了大量朝鲜人。 They are languishing as Pyongyang refuses to take them back, witnesses said, fearful they will import the disease.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, which considers fleeing North Koreans to be economic migrants rather than refugees, would like to send them back but has met with a refusal from Pyongyang, witnesses said. Most are kept in six known Chinese detention camps near the border, which satellite images suggest have been expanded, said Hanna Song, a director with the Seoul-based Database Center for North Korean Human Rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The commission, created in 2000 to advise Congress on human rights and rule of law issues in China, is comprised of nine senators, nine members of the House of Representatives and five senior administration officials appointed by the president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;North Korea&#39;s lockdown and the growing difficulty of escaping through China have also affected the number of refugees able to make it to South Korea, experts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China and North Korea reopen rail link after 2-year coronavirus closure&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Over the past two decades, some 34,000 fleeing North Koreans have reached South Korea, most after crossing the border into China, testified Robert R. King, a former US State Department envoy for North Korean human rights issues. The peak year was 2011 when 2,700 North Koreans made it to China, but that figure fell to just 67 last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;King said he has met in his official and unofficial capacities with Chinese, North Korean and UN officials, urging Beijing to let North Koreans move to third countries rather than returning them to Pyongyang, which considers those who depart traitors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I was singularly unsuccessful,” he told the commission. “We need to continue the effort to press the Chinese because these people are being denied their free choice of where they want to go.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many of those fleeing North Korea are facing ever longer odds, witnesses said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cost of brokers helping North Koreans escape has risen precipitously as risks have mounted. In the early 2000s, the fee was US$1,500, Hanna said, a figure that is now nearly US$40,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s growing use of Alipay, WeChat Pay and other digital currencies, facial recognition software in railway stations and other technologies are also making it more difficult for North Koreans to elude Chinese security, witnesses said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Witnesses urged Washington, Seoul and especially the UN to step up pressure on China and North Korea. But they said things appeared to be moving in the wrong direction given that North Korea was recently elected to the executive board of the World Health Organization and in June 2022 assumed the presidency of a UN disarmament conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If we don&#39;t take real actions today, I assure you I could be invited back to a congressional hearing in 2033,” said Lee Jung-hoon, international affairs dean at Yonsei University and a former South Korean ambassador-at-large. “And we will be echoing the same old rhetoric.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 05:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Cormac McCarthy, dark genius of American literature, dead at 89]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3223994/cormac-mccarthy-dark-genius-american-literature-dead-89?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 05:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/16c9d515-73b7-4e2e-89c6-3176487dc3ee_4f4b8603.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Cormac McCarthy, whose nihilistic and violent tales of the American frontier and post-apocalyptic worlds led to awards, film adaptations and sleepless nights for his enthralled and appalled readers, died on Tuesday at the age of 89.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McCarthy – arguably the greatest American writer since Ernest Hemingway or William Faulkner, both of whom he was sometimes compared to – died of natural causes at his home in Santa Fe, New Mexico, according to a statement from publisher Penguin Random House that cited his son, John McCarthy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Little known for the first 60 years or so of his life, rapturous reviews of 1992&#39;s All the Pretty Horses – the first in The Border Trilogy – changed all that. The book was made into a film – as were 2005&#39;s No Country for Old Men and 2006&#39;s Pulitzer Prize-winning The Road.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But McCarthy was never seen on the red carpet.他是一个非常注重隐私的人，几乎从不接受采访。 2007 年，他为奥普拉·温弗瑞 (Oprah Winfrey) 授予了一个罕见的例外，告诉她：“我认为 [interviews] 对你的头脑没有好处。 If you spend a lot of time thinking about how to write a book, you probably shouldn&#39;t be thinking about it, you probably should be doing it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McCarthy wrote with a distinctive, spare style that eschewed grammatical norms but drew the reader in relentlessly to his world of blood, dust and an unforgiving universe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He stood at the window of the empty cafe and watched the activities in the square and he said that it was good that God kept the truths of life from the young as they were starting out or else they&#39;d have no heart to start at all,” he wrote in typical fashion in All the Pretty Horses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Born Charles Joseph McCarthy Jnr on July 20, 1933, in Providence, Rhode Island, McCarthy was one of six children in his Irish Catholic family, and later switched to using the old Irish name of Cormac.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His father was a lawyer and he was brought up in Tennessee in relative comfort. But middle America was not for him.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Cormac McCarthy&#39;s tale of American carnage draws on Sodom and Gomorrah&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“I felt early on I wasn&#39;t going to be a respectable citizen. I hated school from the day I set foot in it,” he told The New York Times in another rare interview in 1992.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He served in the Air Force in the 1950s and was married twice before the 1960s were out – first to Lee Holleman, who he met at college and with whom he had a son, and later to English singer Anne DeLisle, from whom he separated in 1976.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a short spell in Europe, he returned to Tennessee to settle near Knoxville, Tennessee and later moved to El Paso, Texas and then to Santa Fe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His first book The Orchard Keeper, set in rural Tennessee and published in 1965, landed with Faulkner&#39;s last editor, who recognised the young writer&#39;s potential.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But despite positive reviews – and some shocked reaction – for this and other early works like Child of God and Outer Dark, commercial success eluded McCarthy and he scraped by on writers&#39; grants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1985 Blood Meridian was published, garnering little attention at the time, although it is now considered his first truly great novel and perhaps his best. With lots of violence and no heroes, it tells the tale of a gang of scalp hunters in the mid-19th century West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All the Pretty Horses, a coming-of-age book that kicked off a trilogy centred around Texas ranch hands at the close of the frontier, finally brought him acclaim in the 1990s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trilogy was followed by No Country for Old Men, a deeply disturbing and yet riveting Western crime novel about a drug deal gone wrong, quickly adapted into a film by Joel and Ethan Coen that won the 2007 best picture Oscar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This was the time that also saw the publication of The Road – perhaps even darker than what went before. Set in a world where an unnamed disaster has ended society and food production, a father and his son walk through a devastated landscape occupied by desperate people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The full depths of human depravity are on display – but also the love that the small family is able to sustain through it all. The Road won multiple awards and was also made into a film in 2009.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then came a long period until two new companion novels were released in 2022 – interconnected books The Passenger and Stella Maris that were unmistakably McCarthy, now approaching 90 years of age, albeit somewhat gentler – and, perhaps, valedictory.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hilary Mantel, author of &#39;Wolf Hall&#39; Tudor saga, dies at 70&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Enough,” says one character for whom death is approaching. “我从来没有想过这种生活特别有益健康或温和，而且我从来没有丝毫理解我为什么会在这里。 If there is an afterlife – and I pray most fervently that there is not – I can only hope that they wont sing.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a statement, Nihar Malaviya, CEO of Penguin Random House, said: “Cormac McCarthy changed the course of literature. For 60 years, he demonstrated an unwavering dedication to his craft, and to exploring the infinite possibilities and power of the written word.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McCarthy was married three times, divorcing his third wife Jennifer Winkley in 2006. He had two children: Cullen, born in 1962, and John, born in 1998.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 05:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s human rights record unlikely to come up when Joe Biden hosts Narendra Modi: experts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3223993/indias-human-rights-record-unlikely-come-when-joe-biden-hosts-narendra-modi-experts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 04:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/74e1bdf4-6f67-441c-b1c7-ffcb34c0bddc_b0955707.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s chequered track record with Muslim minorities, political opposition and independent journalism under Narendra Modi is unlikely to feature on the agenda when US President Joe Biden hosts the Indian leader during a state visit to Washington next week, according to observers of US-India relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“By definition, a large-scale official visit like this is going to be a success. It has to be a success for both sides, and that means that there is a real reluctance to introduce difficult topics in this context,” said Donald Camp of the Centre for Strategic and International Studies, a Washington-based think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You want bonhomie, you want grand success to come out of this because the two heads of government are depending on that,” said Camp of the high-level meeting. “My guess is that human rights will not be much of a focus of the conversation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The White House has drawn criticism from human rights organisations in the US on “what is happening in India under the Modi government”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden, who has described America&#39;s great-power rivalry with China as an ideological battle between like-minded democracies versus autocracies, will receive Modi during the prime minister&#39;s three-day US visit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden and Modi will meet on June 22, and the Indian leader is due to address a joint session of Congress. The day will culminate in a state dinner at the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two last met at the Group of 7 summit in Hiroshima in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ahead of next week&#39;s visit, Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International, both global human rights advocacy organisations, have invited policymakers and journalists to a June 20 screening in Washington of a BBC documentary on communal riots that erupted in 2002 while Modi served as the chief minister of the Indian state of Gujarat.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;India&#39;s Gandhi takes a swipe at &#39;nasty&#39; Modi in US for his &#39;not Indian values&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The violence resulted in the deaths of at least 1,000 people, most of them Muslims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Titled India: the Modi Question, the film was banned by the Modi government in January. The Indian foreign ministry condemned it as a “propaganda piece, designed to push a particular discredited narrative”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Soon after the ban, BBC offices in India were raided by government authorities for alleged tax violations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Advocacy groups have been raising concerns about the persecution of minorities in the country as well as the treatment of critical voices and journalists under Modi&#39;s Hindu-nationalist government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A report this year by Freedom House, a US government-funded non-profit organisation, described India as a “partly free” for the third year in a row, adding that “democratic rights in India remain under pressure, particularly for marginalised groups”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India scored 51 out of 100 on internet freedom, according to the report, placing the South Asian country alongside Bangladesh, Libya, Iraq, Kyrgyzstan and Nicaragua.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, Twitter&#39;s former CEO, Jack Dorsey, said the Modi government had threatened to shut down the social media platform and raid its employees if it did not remove tweets and accounts linked to a 2020 anti-government farmers&#39; protest. Dorsey claimed Twitter was asked to censor journalists critical of the government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Indian government has rejected the allegations as “an outright lie … perhaps an attempt to brush out that very dubious period of Twitter&#39;s history.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;With G20 event, India seeks to project normalcy in disputed Kashmir&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Dorsey quit as Twitter&#39;s CEO in 2021, and the company was bought by billionaire Elon Musk in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some experts have noted the selective nature of the Biden administration&#39;s value-based diplomacy, which focuses on human rights and democracy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Michael Kugelman of the Wilson Centre, another Washington-based think tank, recently observed that Biden has shunned countries like Bangladesh, run by Sheikh Hasina – the country&#39;s longest-serving prime minister and long accused of autocratic practices – as an example of his values-based foreign policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet Washington has said little publicly about “democratic backsliding” in New Delhi, Kugelman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After viewing each other with suspicion for decades, Washington and New Delhi have aligned more closely as China&#39;s military might and economic influence expand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US-India ties constitute “a new kind of relationship, trying to break new ground, and in some ways … moving a little bit faster even than we do with traditional allies”, according to Richard Rossow, also of CSIS.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US had already become India&#39;s largest defence exercise partner, topping US$20 billion in total US defence sales to India, he noted, with American companies hoping to secure additional sales during Modi&#39;s visit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I suspect next week is going to be chock full of announcements big and small, related to furthering US-India security ties, and a lot of that is going to be focused on not just operational issues, but actually helping India through co-development of new defensive weapons systems,” Rossow said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Monday described Modi&#39;s visit as “historic” and poised to “solidify what President Biden has called the defining relationship of the 21st century”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Top military leaders of Quad nations meet for Indo-Pacific security&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Blinken made the remarks while addressing a meeting of the US-India Business Council in Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a veiled message to Beijing, America&#39;s top diplomat said Washington regarded the US-Indian partnership as important based on its “shared commitment to address regional and global challenges promoting health security, working with our Quad partners to build a free, open, secure, prosperous Indo-Pacific, where people, goods, ideas can travel freely, and rules are applied fairly”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the four US-led Quadrilateral Security Dialogue members, India is the only one that shares a land border with China, and it fought a war with the Asian giant in 1962.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bloc, originally formed in 2004 to coordinate humanitarian aid following the Indian Ocean tsunami, includes Japan and Australia and gained new prominence in 2017 under the Donald Trump administration to counter China&#39;s growing regional clout.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Revived by Trump as a group of democracies offering an alternative vision to an “autocratic” China, the alliance has since been embraced by Biden as part of his Indo-Pacific strategy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But analysts caution against expecting a full-fledged defence and security alliance from New Delhi, such as in the event of a conflict involving China and Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“India has never let us think that there would be any kind of alliance,” said Camp of CSIS. “Anyone who thinks that India will become a treaty ally is simply wrong.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India prizes its strategic autonomy, Camp added, noting that despite a long-running border dispute with China, New Delhi has cooperated with Beijing as a member of the China-led, regional security-focused Shanghai Cooperation Organisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India is also a founding member of the BRICS bloc, an association of five major emerging national economies that includes Brazil, Russia, China and South Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US regional strategy is an ocean short compared with China, critics say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Given New Delhi&#39;s extensive cooperation with Beijing, India “cannot afford to have China as a committed enemy”, Camp said. “That will always be high on their list of strategic priorities”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, American enthusiasm for US-Indian relations has reached a fever pitch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eric Garcetti, America&#39;s newly installed ambassador to India, declared on Monday that “it is so clear that Indians love Americans and Americans love Indians”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hours after Garcetti spoke and thousands of miles away in New Delhi, US National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan intimated that Modi&#39;s state visit would yield promising dividends. Sullivan, meeting his Indian counterpart Ajit Doval to finalise deliverables for the Indian leader&#39;s trip, said: “We are just getting started.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 04:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>