<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Ex-naval intelligence commander sees ‘dangerous trend’ in closed US-China communications]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3230321/ex-naval-intelligence-commander-sees-dangerous-trend-closed-us-china-communications?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 06:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/974f21c3-963a-48e2-bcd7-5d9fc7d6f4b5_9aa44214.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;华盛顿在理解北京的决策过程方面已经面临障碍，而且可能会发展成一位前美国军事情报领导人周一表示，自中国切断与美国的军事沟通渠道以来，这是一种“危险的趋势”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国很难真正理解......我们没有足够的东西，我们需要上个月担任海军情报办公室指挥官的海军少将迈克尔·斯图德曼在哈德逊研究所的一次活动中表示：题为“主导地位的安魂曲：美国遏制侵略的新战略”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯图德曼称习近平主席领导下的中国体系“笨拙”，他说：“没有办法潜在地保证你能够获得正确的权利。”在正确的时间提供此类信息。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于中国切断与美国军方沟通的观点而言，这是可怕的事情 - 没有热线。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;一年前，时任众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台湾后，北京切断了与华盛顿的三个主要军事沟通渠道。美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯 6 月访问北京时，提议恢复这些渠道，但习近平拒绝了这一提议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;布林肯表示，他告诉北京官员美国并不寻求“遏制”中国&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;周一，斯图德曼表示，北京方面可能会要求美国改善态度并表现出尊重，但同时也相信热线电话可能会导致潜在的危险行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人，他说，“相信如果有热线电话，我们就更容易做出危险行为”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯图德曼表示，中国对美国的看法是“不给他们提供安全网，然后也许他们的力量和行为将会更加保守”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论想法如何，斯图德曼说，“现在官方沟通很少......&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个非常就我们作为大国真正解决问题的能力而言，这是一个危险的趋势。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周一的活动中，美国前情报官员提请人们关注台湾局势，并呼吁采取更多努力来塑造台湾局势。北京高层领导人的看法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯图德曼表示，如果习近平“试图打击台湾，最终将导致主席和党委书记的垮台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我认为他低估了这一点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们需要投入时间和精力的是预防......这是主要策略，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国可能会拒绝对话作为“交换筹码”：美国指挥官&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;也在活动中，负责情报和安全的前国防部副部长埃兹拉·科恩表示，中国一直在从事“非常规战争活动”科恩表示，美国应重点应对这一转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国将非常规战争定义为“国家和非国家行为者之间为争夺合法性和合法性而进行的暴力斗争”。对相关人群的影响”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科恩同意“理解”和“塑造”中国的决策过程是一个关键目标：“你不能仅仅通过情报收集来做到这一点。您还可以通过探索和做一些事情来引发某些反应来做到这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这将帮助我们更好地理解决策过程，也有助于我们塑造决策过程，”他说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在该研究所上个月发表的一篇论文中，保守派鹰派智库哈德逊认为，五角大楼需要对抗中国，以此作为阻止侵略的手段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些努力，该研究所表示，应包括“削弱中国领导人对破坏性情景的信心”和“利用评估和部队设计技术，通过了解和塑造中国领导人的情景偏好和风险认知来支持竞选活动”。&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Guandan in, Texas Hold ’em out: How China’s hottest poker game ‘throwing eggs’ reveals changing attitudes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230187/guandan-texas-hold-em-out-how-chinas-hottest-poker-game-throwing-eggs-reveals-changing-attitudes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/0a59e277-7a17-48ed-8d68-22684eb55f19_e16c742c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一种名为“扔鸡蛋”的扑克游戏正在变得火爆在中国，它在那些将其作为一种放松和社交方式玩的人中越来越受欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很少有人能解释这种由两队四名玩家使用两副牌玩的游戏是如何以及为何在中国流行起来的。从江苏省沿海地区的一项区域性消遣到全国范围内的业余爱好，仅用了十年时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论如何，随着新的锦标赛在全国各地涌现，关丹正在成为一项真正的全国性运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;关丹的一个不寻常之处在于它得到了中国官僚的充分拥护。例如，据湖北省体育局称，湖北省中部地区今年 5 月举办了为期两天的政府官员关丹比赛，吸引了来自 34 支球队的 174 名选手参加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参赛者来自湖北省烟草局和经济规划局和武汉铁路局分别获得金、银、铜牌，省水利局获得团体冠军。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国加强对干部生活方式的审查，关丹为他们提供了一条政治正确的道路。公务员在举办豪华宴会或参观卡拉 OK 俱乐部、按摩院和高尔夫球场时，可以招待他们，而不会引起不必要的注意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在会议室或附近的办公室与同事打牌只需要四个人关蛋比其他纸牌游戏有更多优势。桥牌是已故最高领导人邓小平最喜欢的消遣，但它需要太多的思考，而且对很多人来说太无聊了。斗地主也很流行，很容易沦为赌博游戏，对干部来说是禁忌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，关蛋简单易学，不是为赌博而设计的。更好的是，玩这个游戏需要队友之间不断沟通，这使其成为官僚们增进信任和友情的完美方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，关蛋不仅得到了上级的宽容，而且得到了积极的鼓励。由国家体育总局棋牌中心主办的为期四个月的全国关丹锦标赛正在火热进行中。该中心正试图将关蛋变成与桥牌和围棋一样的中国官方“运动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对关蛋受欢迎程度的深入考察也揭示了中国社会有趣的变化。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在某种程度上，由于许多政府官员“躺着”以避免冒险，这种游戏已经激增。这暗示了中国统治机构的内向心态。毕竟，当您可以轻松地与亲密的同事一起玩熟悉的纸牌游戏一整天时，结识新朋友或尝试最新的流行时尚有何意义？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很难估计有多少时间已经在官丹上花了很多钱，但有传闻表明该游戏相当容易上瘾。南京市原市长季建业2011年告诉记者，很多官员在关丹上花费的时间太长，已经开始影响政府工作。具有讽刺意味的是，2015年，吉因腐败被判处15年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这款游戏的影响力正在蔓延到私营部门，特别是在与政府官员互动频繁的领域。在中国金融业，关蛋已经取代了据说在华尔街专业人士中流行的德州扑克，成为首选游戏，因为人们认为关蛋与地方官员的交往比与西方资本家的交往更重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;私营部门员工必须学习政府的规范和文化，才能被视为“我们自己的人”并把事情做好。就像所谓的官僚装扮一样，玩关蛋有一种文化亲和感。在这方面，关丹在协调公私部门的利益方面发挥着积极的作用。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Crypto firms are making false claims about Hong Kong licence applications and investors should beware, says SFC]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3230298/crypto-firms-are-making-false-claims-about-hong-kong-licence-applications-and-investors-should?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/a9cd3390-63d4-4c0a-a9ab-35bd0141eccc_c4c200fb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一些加密货币交易平台虚假声称其遵守香港新监管制度据香港证监会称，该市证券监管机构敦促投资者注意风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些无牌虚拟资产交易平台声称已向证监会提交申请，要求投资者注意风险。证监会在周一发布的一份声明中表示，允许他们在香港合法经营，但实际上并未这样做。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种欺诈性说法，旨在“给公众一种虚假的保证感”，并且监管机构称，旨在“诱导他人进行虚拟资产交易”的行为属于《反洗钱和反恐融资条例》规定的犯罪行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 10 月，香港宣布大力推动拥抱虚拟资产交易虚拟资产行业的目标是成为全球加密货币中心，并在接下来的几个月中制定了规则，允许集中式加密货币交易所接纳零售客户，前提是他们获得证监会批准的牌照。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;HashKey和 OSL 获准为香港散户投资者提供加密货币交易所&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;许可要求涵盖广泛的领域，包括用户入门、资产托管、网络安全和公司治理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一从今年 6 月 1 日开始的一年宽限期，允许已经在香港拥有大量业务的交易所继续运营，同时对其平台进行更改以遵守证监会的规则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但有些平台，据证监会称，目前在过渡期间为零售用户提供服务的公司正在提供违反新制度下规则的服务和产品，例如加密货币衍生品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;监管机构还指出，它可能会“采取谨慎态度”在评估牌照申请时，“看待”此类不合规行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市的投资者应注意，已公开宣布有意向证监会申请牌照的加密货币交易平台“可能或可能”监管机构警告说，不要，毕竟要提交许可证申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果平台“停止运营”，在不受监管的虚拟资产交易所进行交易的投资者可能会面临“损失全部投资”的风险它还提醒投资者，“崩盘、被黑客攻击”或“遭受任何资产挪用”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多加密货币交易所已公开承诺在香港申请牌照，其中包括 OKX 和火币网等其中是世界上最大的加密货币交易所之一，并且均在中国大陆成立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;证监会迄今为止尚未根据其新的虚拟资产制度颁发任何许可证，但已批准两家本地公司本地加密货币公司 HashKey 和 OSL 是香港证监会许可向专业投资者提供某些数字资产交易服务的唯一两家交易所，上周表示其牌照已升级允许他们向散户用户提供服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两个平台都被批准立即合法接纳散户投资者，并表示他们一开始只会提供比特币和以太坊。 HashKey 和 OSL 还表示，他们正在为零售用户开发新的移动应用程序。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korean lesbian couple beat same-sex barriers to parenthood: ‘happy mothers’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3230295/south-korean-lesbian-couple-beat-same-sex-barriers-parenthood-happy-mothers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/e21f8cc5-c1ff-42ac-8ddc-2e766b8e7cad_26c96a15.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国在提高出生率的政策上花费了数十亿美元。但当金奎珍和她的妻子想要生孩子时，他们不得不飞往比利时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从法律上讲，韩国认为金单身，尽管她于 2019 年在首尔举行了婚礼，并在新州合法登记。约克市——因为该国不承认同性结合。首尔市当局拒绝登记她的婚姻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，当这对幸福的夫妇决定准备生孩子时，他们的家庭选择很有限：单身人士通常被认为没有资格收养，精子库是为存在生育问题的异性已婚夫妇。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国修改“鬼婴”法，但外国儿童被排除在外&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但金奎珍和她的妻子金世妍 - 他们分享巧合的是，Kyu-jin 的姓氏相同 - 无论如何还是决定尝试一下，多亏了在比利时使用捐献精子进行体外受精，Kyu-jin 现在已经怀孕八个月了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇计划在自己的祖国生孩子，在 Sae-yeon 担任医生的医院，并决定公开讲话，以提高韩国对同性父母身份的认识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多韩国人认为，他们应该“通过不孩子”，Kyu-jin 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她不认为自己会生孩子，特别是因为在社会保守的韩国成长为同性恋“并不容易”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是现在，Kyu-jin 和她的妻子觉得他们可以做好父母的工作，尽管在韩国没有合法途径让他们一起成为母亲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个孩子将在幸福的母亲中成长。我们相信孩子也很可能会幸福。”Sae-yeon 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国的出生率（每位女性的出生率为 0.78%）是世界上最低的国家之一。首尔投入了数十亿美元鼓励公民生育更多孩子，但收效甚微。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政策包括补贴生育治疗、现金奖金和免费儿童保育，但政府只针对异性恋、已婚夫妇。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;这意味着许多未婚或同性关系的准父母被忽视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，官方的做法反映了对单亲身份根深蒂固的耻辱，并指出事实上，到 2020 年，韩国所有婴儿中只有 2.5% 是非婚生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经合组织的平均比例约为 40%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在韩国，人们试图Sae-yeon 说，“传统体系之外”的父母受到了很多伤害性的批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们在批评并说有些人不应该生孩子，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们在批评并说有些人不应该生孩子。” >;&lt;p>;还有重大的实际障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sae-yeon 对她的孩子没有合法的父母权利，她没有资格享受育儿假，也无法担任孩子的法定监护人。改变这种情况的唯一方法是她合法收养自己的孩子，由于官方不愿允许未婚人士收养，这本身就很棘手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奎珍在法国工作了一段时间后，才产生了自己可以生孩子的想法。她的法国老板在得知她是一名女同性恋并已婚后，询问她是否打算组建家庭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我很惊讶，因为这是一个私人问题。我想（女同性恋生孩子）在这里一定很常见，如果人们在第一次见到某人时会问这个问题的话。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国范围内的精子短缺意味着法国的体外受精治疗会长期延迟，因此夫妇前往比利时，在那里他们收到了一笔匿名捐款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对夫妇被称为“自私”，因为他们的孩子可能会因父母的性取向而受到歧视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kyu -jin 和 Sae-yeon 表示，如果事实证明在韩国抚养孩子太难，他们甚至可能会考虑移民。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国立法者领导消除国家“禁养儿童区”的斗争&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;“有很多热心人担心我们的孩子，他们担心孩子会受到多大的（情感）伤害，”Kyu-jin 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是如果这些善意——心地善良的人可以帮助我们的社会对我们的孩子更加包容，最终将不需要这样的担忧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使是婴儿的祖父母一开始也可能不会见到新来的人 - Sae-yeon 就是这样目前与她的父母没有建立完整的关系，她的父母没有参加这对夫妇 2019 年的婚礼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们都非常努力，但（最终）没有成功，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她希望他们最终能接受她与奎珍的关系，并见到他们的孙子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不知道那时会过去多少时间。但我想我们会为错过了这么多有趣和幸福的时刻而感到遗憾。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden signs into law bill approving US-Taiwan trade agreement to boost bilateral economic ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3230322/joe-biden-signs-law-bill-approving-us-taiwan-trade-agreement-boost-bilateral-economic-ties?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 06:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/67bafd69-10f6-40d4-a0d0-63ff74eee553_b9a3ddce.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登周一签署了一项法案，批准第一份谈判协议成为法律该协议于 6 月 1 日签署，涵盖简化海关程序、打击腐败和帮助小企业等内容。熟悉两个市场的监管程序。它的总体目标是加强美台贸易和经济关系，但不包括任何市场准入条款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是 21 世纪贸易倡议（双边贸易框架）下预计达成的几项协议中的第一项。双方于去年6月共同发起会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案名为《美国与台湾倡议21世纪贸易第一协议实施法案》，于6月由参议院财政领导人首次宣布委员会和众议院筹款委员会。该法案于同月在众议院获得通过，并于 7 月在参议院获得通过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院版本的发起人、筹款委员会主席、密苏里州共和党众议员贾森·史密斯 (Jason Smith) 上周在该法案即将通过时表示总统办公桌：“随着中国继续威胁美国的利益，台湾与美国保持着密切的贸易关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这项立法加强了与这个重要盟友的关系，并确保美国人民拥有强有力的声音史密斯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;观察人士指出，该法案既是为了维护国会对贸易政策的权威，也是为了表明对加强与台湾的经济接触的支持。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;新法律要求美国贸易代表办公室在与台湾分享之前，向国会展示并允许国会审查该倡议下的任何未来谈判文本；三天内分享台湾起草的任何文本；并在谈判期间向国会提供每日简报。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着美国国会制定五角大楼的预算，中国仍然是人们关注的焦点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;它还要求，除非美国总统做出决定，否则未来的协议不会生效该文本在达成协议前 60 天公开发布，批准该文本的法案已成为法律。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周一的一份声明中，拜登表达了对该法律部分内容的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“如果该法案第 7 条的要求不允许地侵犯我与外国伙伴进行谈判的宪法权力，我的政府将视这些要求不具有约束力，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国会近几个月来，美国越来越多地表达出希望美国加强与台湾经济接触的愿望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参众两院目前正在考虑一项法案，授权政府与台北谈判一项税收协议，该协议将为美国居民和台湾居民提供税收优惠。台湾免双重征税。该法案上个月通过了参议院一个重要委员会的批准。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong property ‘price war’ imminent as Li Ka-shing’s CK Asset slashes flats to lowest seen in city in seven years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3230283/hong-kong-property-price-war-imminent-li-ka-shings-ck-asset-slashes-flats-lowest-seen-city-seven?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/de105780-cfa7-405d-99b0-9e58b654faf9_ea3c7899.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港购房者争相以全市最低价格抢购新楼七年来，押注香港首富的旗舰房地产公司对低迷的市场有正确的解读。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;超过 8,000 名潜在买家已存入支票，竞购 2019 年海岸线 II 的 254 个单位。尚未推出的油塘。该项目由香港亿万富翁李嘉诚的房地产旗舰长实集团控股，距离九龙东南角的地铁站约10分钟路程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该项目首批132个单位是折扣后平均售价为每平方英尺 14,997 港元（1,921 美元），比会德丰地产最近在邻近蓝田推出的 Koko Mare 和 Koko Rosso 便宜 16%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ Coast Line II 的推出只是价格战的开始。”香港仲量联行董事长曾舜晞表示，他称长实集团激进的定价是为了引起关注，并改善不愿购房的购房者的情绪。现在，因为他们预计价格会继续下跌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾表示，对其他项目的 16% 折扣并不是低得惊人，而是符合当前的市场形势，因为政府指数显示市场正在调整2022 年，该价格已上涨约 14%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“长实集团所做的实际上是引用了更实际、更现实、更更新的市场价格，”曾表示。 “如果新项目以正常市场价格推出，反应会非常缓慢和冷淡。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，项目二期并没有像一期那样保证海景。有228个单位但尚未宣布出售。曾表示，长江实业可能会“一路”提高价格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;银河联昌证券物业管理董事总经理郑中正也认为，长江实业可能会逐步提高该项目的价格。他预计整个项目的平均价格最终将至少达到每平方英尺16,000港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑先生表示，整个项目的毛利率约为25%至30%，即尽管低于多年来项目 30% 至 40% 的收益率，但对公司来说仍然是一个合理的利润。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;不要指望香港房地产价格会很快回升&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >; 由于利率上升打压买家情绪，香港一级市场已经降温。两个新推出的项目——黄竹坑的La Montague和元朗的High Park I——最近反应冷淡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，根据仲量联行的数据，已竣工项目中的未售出单位数量是自2007年以来最高的。香港共有83,000个住房单位，其中18,000个已竣工，其余正在建设中。预计 2023 年将有约 25,000 套单位投放市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了消化库存，开发商明白他们需要提供一些折扣，”程说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;供应过剩在外部经济环境充满挑战、利率高企、中国内地经济复苏缓慢的情况下，下半年的新增供应将进一步给本已陷入困境的住宅市场带来压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“房地产市场将会有仲量联行的 Tsang 表示：“未来几年会很艰难。”该公司预计下半年房价将下跌 5% 至 10%，到 2023 年总跌幅将达到 5% 至 8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;价格新房市场的压力也蔓延到了二级市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;银河-联昌的郑先生表示，二级市场“周末成交量已经冻结”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 据利嘉阁地产 (Ricacorp Properties) 称，周末全市二级市场仅录得四宗销售，比上周末好。美联物业也录得四宗成交，而中原地产则只有三宗成交。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海岸线二期的低价也会影响附近的二级市场，本地购房者可额外讨价还价5%至10%的折扣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;美联物业香港及澳门住宅部门行政总裁布兆明表示，二手交易将继续徘徊在低位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“买家的购买力严重不足整体楼市出现两极分化，一级市场热闹，二级市场安静。”Po 表示。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can China’s second-gen factory owners give ‘made in China’ a second chance in crisis?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3230287/can-chinas-second-gen-factory-owners-give-made-china-second-chance-crisis?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/94ad456b-0817-487a-9d3b-07ada98a53fa_6aba0b8d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在从家具销售到电子商务等多种工作之间跳来跳去之后，十年何蕾决定在2021年回国，接管父亲创办的一家有30年历史的工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她回国的主要原因是父母已经六十多岁了，身体日渐衰弱。不再允许他们全身心投入到拥有大约 50 名工人的工厂的日常运营中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我是他们唯一的孩子。如果我不回去，工厂真的要倒闭吗？” 34岁的他说道。 “那那些跟着我爸爸十几二十年的员工呢？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;何的工厂位于广东佛山，是当地以镀铝为主的产业集群的一部分，是不可或缺的建筑。办公楼天花板和商场自动扶梯所用的材料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在她正式成为新老板之前，她对这个行业知之甚少，不知道如何经营一家工厂或处理其一连串的优先事项，从税收到招聘。现在，工作两年后，他面临着经济大幅放缓带来的挑战，她正试图通过频繁去医院看望父亲来平衡这一挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“加剧、减速” “，冷却”：中国 7 月活动数据的 4 个要点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“有时我会感到很累、很困惑，而且我不知道该怎么办，”她说。 “然后我就发消息到群里问问，怎么招新人，怎么管理，甚至工厂实在开不下去了，怎么安全撤离。”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;他所依赖的聊天群由数百名像她一样的“厂二代”（第二代工厂主）组成。自从今年早些时候“嫦二代”开始流行以来，这些千禧一代甚至 Z 世代的成员遍布全国各地并跨越所有可以想象的制造业领域，他们一直通过在线帖子相互联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的父母已经雕刻了走出类似的成功之路。他们出身卑微，经历了中国空前经济增长的黄金时代，从蓬勃发展的房地产业、快速城市化和中国加入世界贸易组织中获利。与此同时，他们的设施（通常规模较小）也是该国崛起为“世界工厂”和第二大经济体的支柱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三十年后，当谈到代际时有了传承，他们的孩子——精通网络且往往有海外教育背景——能够站在更高的起点上。但优惠的宏观环境早已不复存在，取而代之的是房地产业低迷、国内经济放缓、全球供应链重新布局、来自其他发展中国家的激烈竞争以及地缘政治紧张局势加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，随着工厂的重担落到了第二代的肩上，这也让他们对“中国制造”的未来负责。能否继续繁荣甚至生存取决于他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国主要城市写字楼空置率持续上升，以及疫情以来新基建项目持续受到抑制，他并不乐观。她说，现在在广东，当一个新的建设项目出现时，数百家像何这样的工厂都会竞争，而不管它是否有利可图。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“正如我爸爸常说的，在这个行业能发大财的时代早已过去了”，她感叹道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前途黯淡难免让她产生了退出的念头，但这并不是一个好办法。当她考虑到工人（其中许多人看着她长大）以及工厂的重要性时，这是真正可行的选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在很难为他们这个年纪的人找到另一份工作，”他说。 “我不能就这么抛弃他们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;房地产市场的低迷对郑世杰的打击同样严重。 2019年，他正式从叔叔手中接手了湖北省武汉市的一家制造工厂。该工厂生产用于所有需要电力的场景的配电设备，年工业产值接近2000万元人民币（278万美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但现在，工厂余额上的应收账款总计近1000万元——自2021年全国大范围房地产危机爆发以来，多家房地产公司积累的资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们是夕阳产业。整个市场都在下滑。”这位 30 岁的人说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的业务的另一个主要收入来源来自市政项目，但随着地方政府的大力投入，来自这些项目的资金也在萎缩。由于现金流压力越来越大，郑的几位同行最近退出了这个行业，这与前几代人争相进入这个行业形成了鲜明的对比。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这感觉就像[中国]所说的那样，‘攻城易，守地难’，”郑说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的工厂活动回落至7月收缩：财新PMI&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对于出口型制造商来说，今年的市场并不比房地产上游的制造商好，因为全球经济放缓抑制了海外对中国产品的需求，西方国家（尤其是美国）加速以中国为中心的供应链多元化趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一趋势对于服装行业尤其明显，因为美国时装公司正在严重减少“中国风险敞口” ” and moving sourcing orders to China&#39;s competitors in Asia, according to Sheng Lu, an associate professor with the Department of Fashion &amp; Apparel Studies at the University of Delaware.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first five months of 2023, measured in value, the share of US apparel imports from China fell to 18.3 per cent, compared with nearly 30 per cent in 2019, according to figures from the Office of Textiles and Apparel under the US Department of Commerce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile , the share of total imports from Vietnam, Bangladesh, Indonesia, India, and Cambodia reached a new high of 44.3 per cent, up from 37.1 per cent in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For 27-year-old Jenny Jiao, the figures reflect an urgency for her to grow up quickly to share her family&#39;s burden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After obtaining a master&#39;s degree from Johns Hopkins University and briefly working in finance, Jiao decided to go back to her father&#39;s casual-suits factory based in Liaoning province late last year, shortly before a trade company sourcing for the US market broke the contract to buy around 200,000 suits a year – for which her father had specifically built a new facility and hired 200 more workers.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The trade company said that if they don&#39;t shift the sourcing to Cambodia, their clients in the US would terminate the collaboration with them,” Jiao said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With lost orders and heavy loans for the new facility, Jiao felt the pressure on her shoulders quickly piling up – if the loan can&#39;t be repaid, it means the painstaking efforts of her dad in the past two decades would end in vain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ Honestly, in the next five or six years, it will be a success as long as we can survive.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, Jiao and his father have settled on a clear division of labour: the father continues to focus on the daily management of the two apparel plants, so that the daughter can be given the luxury to try something new.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So far, the trials include reaching out to foreign brands directly – skipping the trade companies in between , and expanding domestic market exposure by promoting on Xiaohongshu – a lifestyle app popular with Chinese youth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, through taking costume design courses, she is working on bringing in independent design – from pattern making to material procurement – as opposed to the old mode of contract manufacturing in which the factories simply follow the demand of downstream clients and process using the materials provided.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Every direction has its own hurdles,” Jiao said. “Ultimately, I just want to sell more clothes and bring back more orders. I don&#39;t want the factories to end up closing their doors on my watch.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aside from bringing their business out of an economic dilemma amid rising external uncertainties, most second-generation factory owners are also desperate to prove themselves, especially to their parents and more experienced long-time employees who may still regard them as children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In small companies like ours, whomever gets the new orders is qualified as the boss,” said He from Foshan. “Before you bring back real orders, no one respects you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s a tricky time&#39;: firms adjust to new reality as China pull-out intensifies&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Even though she has officially taken over the factory, old resources and clients established by the older generation cannot simply be inherited. She needs to strive to secure her own new clients.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In fact, I don&#39;t think we are Changerdai, but first-generation entrepreneurs,” He said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For many traditional manufacturing sectors with scarce technological innovation involved, keeping the price down is always the silver bullet in gaining market share, but many are also looking to reform and upgrade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Such a decision, however, is never easy to make. For smaller manufacturers, with their weaker ability to resist risks, the cost of trial and error is much higher.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zheng, the power-distribution equipment producer in Wuhan, had thought of riding the wave of green energy and shifting to products like electric-vehicle charging piles, but in the end decided to maintain the status quo while continuing to assess a possible shift.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Transformation means more risks and challenges. The overall economic condition is not good now, and we have a very tight cash flow,” he said. “Shifting to a new product means much more fixed expenses such as for new equipment in the very early stages. The pressure can be very high.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before Kitty Pan went back in 2019, her father&#39;s factory producing spa-pedicure chairs and shampoo stations for salons were on the cusp of collapse: it was bleeding cash after rounds of price wars with peers in the domestic market and could barely afford to pay its employees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I felt that if [low-price competition] continued, there was not going to be any way out,” said the 29-year-old Foshan native. “So, I thought, why not go in the opposite direction – by focusing more on quality rather than price.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The real turning point came when she attended a beauty trade show in South Korea that year, where she managed to settle a long-term contract with a client who was also searching for a stable supply of shampoo stations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thanks to the order, the factory&#39;s operations have stabilised despite the three-year pandemic. As more new overseas clients were developed, exports now account for 80 per cent of the factory&#39;s overall business, and the firm was recognised late last year as a “hi-tech enterprise” by the local government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I felt like there are always more solutions than problems,” Pan said. “Times have changed. How can we just spin our wheels?”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Skilled manpower and hi-tech: what&#39;s the outlook when China is short of both?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Unlike Pan, who took over a teetering factory, 27-year-old Gloria Liang was luckier when she joined her father&#39;s metal-plate-processing factory last year, as it has a stable customer base with an annual turnover in the tens of millions of yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Liang was not satisfied with the status quo, and believed she must bring new blood to the company that had inevitably been impacted by the property slump.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Right now, regardless of products, the whole manufacturing sector can&#39;t escape the rat race, as the information gap is closing,” Liang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With a master&#39;s degree in innovation and entrepreneurship from the University of Bristol, she started out by promoting the factory and its products on social media. Within months, she has become one of the most popular influencers on Xiaohongshu representing the young factory community, thanks to which she has also expanded the company&#39;s custom stainless-steel-furniture business by attracting customers online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compared with her father&#39;s generation, which was more fixated on sales figures, Liang believed the future competitiveness of a factory relies on innovation – that is, hi-tech products and refined services that can&#39;t be easily duplicated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We don&#39;t want to do just manufacturing, but smart manufacturing,” Liang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also having studied overseas, and at the age of 27, Sun Chuanzhen has been looking to promote his father&#39;s chemical-adhesive products online to attract foreign buyers instead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unlike other traditional manufacturing sectors, China&#39;s fast-growing chemical industry, which has been the largest in the world by revenue since 2011, has largely stayed intact from the ongoing global industrial chain relocation, as cost pressures for chemicals are significant and the country is the world&#39;s biggest chemical consumer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, Sun has made plans to dedicate more efforts to developing more advanced and environmentally friendly adhesive formulations since returning to the Shandong-based factory in January, as both China and the rest of the world are tightening up environmental requirements for the industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By copying advanced experiences and undertaking the transfer of production capacity from the West, China&#39;s chemical industry has accumulated around three decades of technical, capital and talent reserves, but that does not mean its status is unshakeable, Sun added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What is the problem now? That is, some emerging countries, like those in Southeast Asia, Latin America and even Africa, also want to build their own chemical industries. So, they are like China 20 years ago,” he said. “If we don&#39;t take a step forward, we will surely be replaced by them. And this is the crisis of China&#39;s manufacturing sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So, we should continue to develop better products based on existing advantages, making them unable to catch up.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Coco Lee’s death highlights need to battle enduring stigma surrounding mental health issues]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230205/coco-lees-death-highlights-need-battle-enduring-stigma-surrounding-mental-health-issues?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/da5cc8de-db84-4d01-ac1b-d643dfe8917e_0299abf6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong and Macau have been saddened by the recent deaths of pop star Coco Lee and online influencer Jane Lao, the former manager of a popular Macau-based YouTube channel. These tragedies involving women dealing with depression have sparked discussion on how to identify and treat mental health issues, as well as what friends and relatives can do to help.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This might be the only positive outcome of the two deaths. However, we should not forget that there is a large group of people who have long been stigmatised, and that mental health is not just an individual issue but a societal one.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many studies show the severity of Hongkongers&#39; mental health struggles. A 2013 study by the Hong Kong Mental Morbidity Survey Team found that 13.3 per cent of local Chinese adults had common mental health disorders. The Hospital Authority reported this year that the number of psychiatric patients diagnosed with depression rose from 56,100 to 66,000 between 2018 and the end of 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A recent report by a University of Hong Kong research team found that 16 per cent of respondents, aged 15 to 24, had a probable psychiatric disorder and 1.5 per cent had attempted suicide. A 2017 review of mental health by the Food and Health Bureau estimated that between 1.1 million and 1.8 million people in the city had a mental disorder and between 70,000 and 220,000 people had severe mental illness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the large number of people potentially struggling with mental health issues, open discussion of the subject is rare in Hong Kong. It is considered a private matter, unlike illnesses such as the flu. Symptoms of depression are mistaken as choosing to isolate from others or being in a “bad mood”, harming social interactions with friends and family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this sense, suppressing mental health concerns becomes a matter of managing one&#39;s image in front of others. Hiding how they feel only puts more pressure on those grappling with their mental health.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Society has long stigmatised people with mental illness. Popular culture portrays mental health facilities in a negative light, with people receiving treatment written off as “crazy”. While society has changed and awareness has improved, those with mental health issues still face heavy stigma.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 2014 study found that respondents in Hong Kong held strongly negative views about the potential violent and annoying behaviour of people with serious mental disorders. A 2021 study found that stigma related to mental health was higher among women, older people and the less educated.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hongkongers&#39; happiness falls to 3-year low, poll finds, as experts warn of anxiety&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;This continuing stigma prevents people from openly discussing their mental health or seeking help for fear of facing judgment from or discrimination by family, friends and colleagues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong has a reputation for efficiency. The city&#39;s high-pressure environment leaves people little room to unwind after the workday. Hongkongers are under constant pressure to keep working to pay their mortgage, rent, education expenses and more.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deaths of Lee and Lao are a reminder that while those in the limelight might maintain an upbeat public persona, but they too could be battling mental health problems. Calling for people to have greater awareness of mental health issues and learning how to help those dealing with them is only the first step.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Promoting mental health should involve more than telling those struggling to seek help. The goal should be to build an environment where mental health issues can be discussed like any other health concern and people dealing with them can be accepted by those around them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, the government must do more to recruit the mental health professionals Hong Kong needs. Secretary for Health Lo Chung-mau&#39;s response to a question in the Legislative Council last month showed that the number of psychiatrists, psychologists, nurses and social workers employed by government agencies is still less than ideal. Everyone in the city must come together to create a better environment and prevent other tragic, needless deaths in the future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you have suicidal thoughts or know someone who is experiencing them, help is available. In Hong Kong, dial +852 2896 0000 for The Samaritans or +852 2382 0000 for Suicide Prevention Services.在美国，请拨打 988 自杀和危机生命热线：988 或 +1 800 273 8255。有关其他国家/地区的帮助热线列表，请访问。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[HSBC exec slams ‘weak’ UK for siding with US against China, drawing backlash from MPs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230320/hsbc-exec-slams-weak-uk-siding-us-against-china-drawing-backlash-mps?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 05:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/08/a42baf0a-48ac-4777-82d6-5bbb10507ad9_91849751.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;HSBC Holdings drew criticism from British lawmakers after its head of public affairs accused the UK government of being “weak” by following US policy on China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sherard Cowper-Coles told a private event in London in June that the UK would often bow to the demands of Washington and had been strong-armed into cutting back business dealings with China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He apologised for “any offence caused” in a statement that said his were “personal comments”. The bank reiterated in its own statement that the comments were his personal views.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nevertheless, two China critics in the UK&#39;s governing Conservative Party – who have both been sanctioned by the Asian nation – slammed the London-listed bank, Europe&#39;s largest. Former Tory Party leader Iain Duncan Smith said HSBC “have an awful lot to answer for”, while fellow backbencher Tim Loughton branded the lender an “apologist” for the Chinese government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Perhaps HSBC should get on with putting their own house in order before criticising others, not least when their actions over the last two years suggest their willingness to act first in the interests of an autocratic communist state,” said Alicia Kearns, chair of the UK Parliament&#39;s foreign affairs select committee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The remarks expose a growing rift in the Tory Party between Prime Minister Rishi Sunak, who has sought to preserve and grow trading links with the world&#39;s second-largest economy, and those in his party who are suspicious President Xi Jinping&#39;s government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They want Britain to reduce ties with China over disputes ranging from the Covid-19 pandemic to its treatment of Uygur Muslims and its stance on Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Increasingly HSBC has become an apologist for the totalitarian Chinese Communist Government,” Loughton said. Cowper-Coles&#39;s comments suggested a “kind of arrogant complacency where principles and regard for human suffering kowtow to business opportunity”. That, he warned could encourage an “emboldened China to bulldoze aside international rule of law and to buy international influence”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China targets British institutions as government fails to recognise threat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Cowper-Coles told attendants at a closed-door event in London in June that the UK should not blindly follow the US but rather look after its own interests, according to the people familiar with the matter, who asked not to be identified because the event was private.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The HSBC employee, a former diplomat, is acting like “the worst sort of apologist, blind to the outrages that the Chinese government commits against its people”, Duncan Smith said. “He cannot separate his personal views from HSBC because he is an adviser to HSBC. Now we know what he is advising them,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luke de Pulford, executive director of the Inter-Parliamentary Alliance on China, which counts several China hawk British lawmakers as members, also criticised the comments by Cowper-Coles, saying such “diplomatic pragmatism” belonged in the past and reflected an obsession with trade over everything else.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, Vince Cable, the former leader of the Liberal Democrat party and business minister, said in a Bloomberg Radio interview that “deferring excessively to pressure from the United States is unhelpful to the UK and not in our interests”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is not the first time British politicians have taken aim at HSBC. In June, the bank was criticised by the UK parliament&#39;s Foreign Affairs Select Committee and the US Congress Select Committee on China after the bank denied some Hong Kong expatriates access to their retirement funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;British politicians also spoke out after a report that a Chinese Communist Party committee was set up at HSBC&#39;s local investment banking arm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sunak and Foreign Secretary James Cleverly have described China as an “epoch-defining challenge” to UK security, accusing Beijing of running secret police stations in Britain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nevertheless, in an illustration of the premier&#39;s outreach to China, the British and Chinese governments are reviewing dates for a visit by Cleverly to the country, after a planned July trip was postponed.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 05:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine says it foiled Volodymyr Zelensky assassination plot, detained woman informant]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3230317/ukraine-says-it-foiled-volodymyr-zelensky-assassination-plot-detained-woman-informant?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 05:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/08/48e07823-dac7-46d4-88b2-8200bd46ef0f_3d2dbb76.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukraine&#39;s security service said it foiled an effort to assassinate President Volodymyr Zelensky with an air strike, and that it had detained a collaborator that tried to reveal his location.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The SBU said on Monday that Russia planned to use information gathered by the alleged informant to launch a massive air strike on the southern Mykolaiv region while Zelensky was visiting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spokeswoman for Ukraine&#39;s armed forces said that the SBU was able to “foil the attack on the president during a recent trip to Mykolaiv”, describing it as an “aborted assassination attempt”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman had tried to figure out the timings and the route for Zelensky&#39;s visit, but the SBU learned about her efforts in advance and put extra security in place during his trip, the SBU said. “Zelensky is safe, the plot was foiled in advance,” the spokeswoman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By tracking the woman they also found that she was trying to locate where Ukraine&#39;s electronic warfare systems and ammunition warehouses were placed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The SBU published screenshots of text messages consistent with an exchange between an informant and handler, but with few specifics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman was arrested on Monday after Ukraine learned the extent of her “treason,” the armed forces spokeswoman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She now faces up to 12 years in prison, the SBU said, identifying her as a resident of the city of Ochakov, in Mykolaiv, and a former saleswoman in a military store.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine&#39;s Zelensky likely to visit New York for UN General Assembly&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The armed forces spokeswoman said she was “turned collaborator by FSB agents and continued to work for them”. The FSB is Russia&#39;s main security and spy agency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is not clear when the attack on Zelensky was planned. He was last recorded visiting Mykolaiv at the end of July, though he also made trips there earlier in the war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other Russian attempts to assassinate Zelensky have been reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky survived at least three assassination attempts from Russia-backed agents in the first few weeks of the invasion, The Times of London reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky himself said he carries a pistol and would have fought to the death if Russian forces had got into his headquarters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zelensky has repeatedly visited the front lines since Russia launched its full-fledged invasion, with his office typically announcing his visits after he has already left, to reduce the risks on his life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian officials and lawmakers told Politico this month that Ukraine has a plan in place if Zelensky is killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[War of words over China breaks out on London wall in Brick Lane]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230316/war-words-over-china-breaks-out-london-wall-brick-lane?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 03:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/08/4a383ebf-4154-450c-8edc-2adca011a8ec_1d516db5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A wall on London&#39;s famous Brick Lane became the canvas for supporters and opponents of China&#39;s authorities, with graffiti echoing Chinese government propaganda immediately covered by anti-Beijing slogans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Residents on the East London street, well known for its street art, woke up on Sunday to find a whitewashed wall overlaid with red Chinese characters outlining the 12 “core socialist values” at the heart of Chinese Communist Party (CCP) propaganda.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These values, defined by the CCP, include “prosperity”, “patriotism” and “harmony”, “democracy”, “equality”, “freedom” and “the rule of law”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The graffiti drew widespread criticism on social networks, and was quickly covered with slogans hostile to the Chinese authorities and Xi Jinping.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I utterly condemn the #CCP thugs who defaced London&#39;s Brick Lane with their regime&#39;s vile hate-filled propaganda,” tweeted Benedict Rogers, head of rights group Hong Kong Watch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the slogans daubed on top of the graffiti included “some are more equal than others”, and “no freedom in China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The local council removed both the pro- and anti-China graffiti on Monday morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing envoy protests against British criticism of Hong Kong security law raid&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“I think it did get covered up too quickly,” local artist Russell Shaw Higgs said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Yesterday was very interesting because many people came and responded with counter graffiti and it became a literal conversation on the walls, which is what it should be,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Instagram, an art student said he was the author of the original graffiti, but denied any political message and denounced the threats he had received in recent days.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>