<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Apple’s new US$3,499 AR headset may face trademark issue in China as ‘Vision Pro’ name already belongs to Huawei]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3223812/apples-new-us3499-ar-headset-may-face-trademark-issue-china-vision-pro-name-already-belongs-huawei?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/fe057c97-3825-477c-9714-3dad13aa6e1b_b6a9aeeb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Apple Vision Pro，备受期待的 3,499 美元增强现实 (AR) 耳机刚刚亮相这家美国科技巨头的品牌可能在中国面临商标问题，该名称两年前已由华为技术有限公司注册。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家总部位于深圳的智能手机和电信设备制造商于 2021 年注册了“Vision Pro”商标，涵盖根据中国国家知识产权局 (CNIPA) 商标局的记录，包括虚拟现实 (VR) 耳机和可穿戴视频显示器在内的广泛商品和服务类别。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为于 2019 年提交了申请，并根据 CNIPA 数据库中的信息，在两年后获得了“Vision Pro”的独家权利，为期十年，直至 2031 年 11 月 27 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这对 Apple 来说可能是一个棘手的问题在上周推出 Apple Vision Pro 之后，它在中国推出，预计将于明年上市，首先在美国推出，然后再推广到其他市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“这是计算的未来”：我们尝试 Apple 的3,499 美元的 Vision Pro 耳机&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Apple Vision Pro 是该公司十年来的首款主要新产品，它允许用户体验叠加在任何物理空间上的数字内容，例如游戏和 3D 视频。据首席执行官蒂姆库克称，这有望标志着“计算新时代的开始”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苹果和华为没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“华为上海德邦律师事务所高级合伙人游云亭表示，苹果公司有权就其出售Apple Vision Pro的行为提起法律诉讼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从法律角度来看，苹果公司正在推动尤说，根据中国的知识产权法和之前的法院判决，华为将产品推向包括中国在内的全球市场，这可能构成商标侵权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;您补充说，华为目前可能不会选择采取行动，作为处于中美科技紧张局势中心的公司，它可能希望保持低调，或者在产品正式上市后寻求赔偿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为，曾经是主要的智能手机在美国实施制裁切断其先进芯片供应之前，作为苹果公司的竞争对手，该公司以“Vision”的产品名称推出了几款消费电子产品，包括去年 12 月的 Huawei Vision Glass，以及一系列以“Vision”命名的智能电视屏幕。 Vision 系列。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两家公司之前曾进行过商标战，当时 Apple 在 2021 年阻止华为使用“MatePod”名称的法律尝试失败，此前这家总部位于加利福尼亚州库比蒂诺的公司辩称该名称熟悉自己的 iPod、EarPods 和 AirPods 商标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你说在 Apple Vision Pro 的案例中，该公司可能会效仿之前的案例，在瑞士钟表制造商 Swatch 提出异议后将“Apple Watch”作为商标并于 2016 年在英国禁止使用“iWatch”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple 可能有很好的机会在中国简单地注册“Apple Vision”商标，因为“Apple”在科技界是一个知名度很高的名字而“愿景”二字并没有什么显着性，据游说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“产品发布后发现商标风险的情况并不少见；商标存在冲突的可能性，特别是对于像 Apple 这样在全球范围内推出产品的大公司，”你说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping says Beijing will support Honduras’ economy while stressing ‘one-China principle’ as foundation for ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223841/xi-jinping-says-beijing-will-support-honduras-economy-while-stressing-one-china-principle-foundation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/01e96000-bac4-45aa-ac54-4ab713cf1413_ca035eab.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国国家主席习近平告诉洪都拉斯，中国决心支持洪都拉斯的经济增长这是中美洲国家从台湾转向北京后的首次会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国周一在北京为卡斯特罗铺开红地毯，习近平在人民大会堂亲自接见她&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据官方通讯社新华社发布的一份声明，习近平称赞卡斯特罗在履行与中国建立关系的竞选承诺时表现出的“历史性果断”和“强烈政治意愿”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国将坚定不移地发展与洪都拉斯的友谊，并决心支持该国的经济和社会发展，”他说，呼应了洪都拉斯代表团旨在加强与世界第二大经济体的商业联系的目标。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中国国家电视台中央电视台报道，习近平强调“一个中国原则”将是双边关系的前提和基础，并表示他相信洪都拉斯可以“全面落实”这一原则。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中央电视台报道，卡斯特罗对中国的“一带一路”倡议和其他全球项目表示“高度赞赏”，并承诺积极参与。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们相信，与中国发展良好的关系可以让我们获得更好、更多的发展机会……并愿意积极推动中国与拉美和加勒比国家共同体的关系，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国领导人见证了17项双边协议的签署根据中国外交部发言人华春莹的一条推文，在贸易、一带一路项目建设、农业、科技、文化和教育等领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在会见习近平之前，卡斯特罗参观了纪念碑天安门广场上的人民英雄，向在建立中华人民共和国的斗争中牺牲的人们致敬——这是该国爱国主义的象征。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;身着红色西装的卡斯特罗被受到中国领导人和包括高级外交官王毅在内的高级官员以及中国人民解放军各分队、一支军乐队和一群挥舞着旗帜和鲜花的儿童的欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议是在洪都拉斯结束三个月后举行的它与台北建立了 82 年的关系，并与北京建立了正式关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡斯特罗在访问上海后于周六晚上在高级代表团的陪同下抵达北京，在那里她会见了金融中心的陈吉宁共产党总书记。当天早些时候，她会见了金砖国家领导的新开发银行行长迪尔玛·罗塞夫 (Dilma Rousseff)，并提交了加入该银行的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金砖国家是由五个大型新兴经济体组成的联盟：巴西、俄罗斯、印度、中国和南非。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据当地媒体报道，洪都拉斯代表团还表达了对与中国经济合作的承诺，并在北京会见了中国贸易、工程、电信等行业的商界领袖。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;贸易初期将主要集中在向中国出口咖啡豆、白虾和瓜类等农产品，然后扩大到投资、能源、电信和基础设施等领域，洪都拉斯贸易部长弗雷迪斯·塞拉托 (Fredis Cerrato)经济发展，告诉中国小报《环球时报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪都拉斯负责经济发展的副部长梅尔文雷东多在会后接受中国在线媒体澎湃新闻的另一次采访时表示，该国将开始就经济发展问题进行谈判。下个月与中国达成自由贸易协定，目标是在一年内完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪都拉斯和中国自然资源部长 Lucky Medina Estrada 和王光华周一会面，讨论包括合理利用自然资源在内的话题资源和可再生能源主权，根据卡斯特罗办公室的一条推文。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，洪都拉斯外交部长爱德华多·恩里克·雷纳在北京举行的洪都拉斯大使馆落成典礼后会见了中国外长秦刚。外交部的推文。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在仪式上的讲话中，秦表示，根据外交部的一份声明，两国关系的发展有一个“良好的开端”，卡斯特罗的访问是两国关系的“里程碑” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“前两个月洪都拉斯与中国正式关系的快速发展证明了卡斯特罗总统的战略决策是正确的，”雷纳在活动中说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese universities ranked ahead of Oxbridge, Caltech in quality research output by Nature Index]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3223810/nature-index-rates-chinese-universities-ahead-oxbridge-caltech-quality-research-output?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/1f68a8a0-d228-4b0a-ba5b-dab2228aa9ae_a18c34b2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一些在中国以外鲜为人知的大学正在迅速超越其在中国更知名的同行根据最新的自然指数，包括牛津大学、剑桥大学、普林斯顿大学和加州理工学院在内的西方大学在高质量的科学研究中占据重要地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最新的名单中，排名前 10 位的大学贡献者中有七位来自中国——由学术期刊《自然》——追踪在世界上最有影响力的 82 种自然科学期刊上发表的研究文章的贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该指数基于 2022 年 2 月 1 日至 1 月 31 日期间的科学研究成果，使用“简单的，透明和最新的指标，证明高质量的研究和合作”，据《自然》杂志称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前五名由中国科学院 (CAS)、德国马克斯普朗克协会和法国国家科学研究中心，哈佛大学排名第二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除大型机构外，紧随其后的是中国科学技术大学（USTC）。与 CAS 关系密切的中国科学院大学 (UCAS) 在大学贡献者中排名第三。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的主导地位继续下降，南京大学是历史最悠久的大学之一和中国最负盛名的大学——与北京著名的北京大学和清华大学联手，分别位列第四、第五和第六。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯坦福排名第七，而浙江大学则以工程、计算机科学和技术方案，排名第八。其次是麻省理工学院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;排名第 10 的是位于南部广东省广州市的中山大学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国的牛津大学和剑桥大学仅进入尽管在今年由高等教育分析师 Quacquarelli Symonds 编制的 QS 世界大学排名中排名第二和第四，但分别排名第 16 和第 19 位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中山大学在 QS 榜单中排名第 267 位，根据自然指数，它对世界已发表的高质量研究的贡献高出 22%，超过了牛津大学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与它们相比，一些北美大学在自然指数中的得分也较低QS排名。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国想要更高质量的外国学生，但五倍的学费是否有帮助？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;世界排名第六的加州理工学院（Caltech）通过 QS，在自然列表中排名第 47 位。芝加哥大学在 QS 排名中位列第 10 位，在研究产出方面排名第 51 位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 QS 排名中排名最高的中国大学是第 12 位的北京大学和第 14 位的清华大学地方。 QS榜单中南京大学位列第133位，中国科学技术大学位列第94位。 UCAS 未包含在 QS 排名中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看看 2015 年至 2023 年的自然指数，就可以看出中国在高质量研究成果方面正在迅速缩小与美国的差距。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;2015 年，中国在已发表研究质量（该指数的标志性指标）中的份额占美国产出的 37%。到 2020 年，这一比例上升至 69%。在今年的榜单中，中国的份额超过美国 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在该指数追踪的四大学科中——化学、地球与环境、生命科学和物理科学——中国大学在化学领域遥遥领先。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继 2018 年在化学领域的贡献超过美国之后，中国机构今年贡献的研究是名单上美国同行的两倍多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;物理学方面，中科大、清华大学和国科大分列Nature Index排行榜前三名。相应地，美国在生命科学领域保持领先地位，其研究成果是中国的三倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国研究的增长在一定程度上与许多知名科学家的回国有关，这一转变包括将他们的学术关系转移到该国的机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;谢晓亮是最新一位放弃美国公民身份的中国科学家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;此外，8 月发表的一篇文章同行评议期刊《科学》指出，中国科学家的高被引论文发表数量已跃居前列。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国大学的科研水平显着提升。厦门大学教授彭力说：“节奏快了，研究成果自然就多了。”但该索引的范围有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该索引主要由来自各个领域的少数代表性期刊的结果组成。它更多的是基础科学研究领域的衡量指标，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国现在拥有世界上最强大的高超音速风洞&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;刘说，自然指数反映了研究的一个方面，只跟踪一小部分已发表的文章，仅涵盖自然科学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多科研机构不发表论文或撰写专利，而是选择对技术保密。因此，这份名单反映的信息是有限的，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;QS 和 US News 的排名——通常将中国大学排在较低的位置——也考虑了学校的财富和荣誉等因素，作为其排名的指标“软实力”。自然指数未考虑这些因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平在呼吁全球科技合作时与顶尖科学家接触&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京一家留学机构的代表该机构表示，在推荐海外院校时，主要参考更广泛的QS排名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“除了研究能力，学生还考虑师资质量和毕业率等因素。最终，他们选择了一所与他们的专业能力相匹配的排名靠前的学校，”该代表说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出国留学仍然被视为学生学术培训的重要组成部分，刘将国际交流描述为“至关重要”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“比如，博士毕业后，最好去国外做博士后研究，这样可以开阔视野。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese nanoplatform “航母”给癌症患者送药&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;彭还把出国留学的机会作为大学经历的重要组成部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因为很多大学在招生时都强调海外经历，当学生继续学习时，他们应该首先考虑更好的海外大学。” p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘We will be worse off’: Singapore’s DPM Wong says change in mindset needed over materialism, career ‘arms race’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3223848/we-will-be-worse-singapores-dpm-wong-says-change-mindset-needed-over-materialism-career-arms-race?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 22:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/92f9f3ce-a49e-44b5-b564-e701a287fdea_8a1b8921.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新加坡下一任领导人黄循财向新加坡最富有的国家之一的居民提出挑战接受更广泛的成功定义，超越物质主义的关注和工作场所的声望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从去年巩固了他作为总理李显龙继承人的地位以来，50 岁的黄，一直在领导一项名为 Forward Singapore 的全国性反馈收集活动，他说该活动旨在在人们对住房、移民和生活成本的不满情绪不断上升的情况下重塑社会契约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在研究所组织的会议上发言Policy Studies 智库的 Wong 表示，与新加坡人的互动实际上表明，许多人希望成功“少看路尽头的金罐，多看我们一路走来的使命感和成就感”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果我们一直朝那个方向努力，我的房子一定比你的房子大，我的薪水一定比你的薪水大，我的生活地位一定比你的生活地位高，我们会不会更快乐？我对此深表怀疑，”他在小组讨论中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;副总理兼财政部长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这并不是说无法提供住房和所有其他好东西……而是让我们超越某个特定点来反思——我们想要什么，为了我们的孩子？”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong 还要求新加坡人改变以目标为导向或专注于银行等传统“声望”工作的心态，转而考虑“旅程”作为更广泛的成功衡量标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“更广泛的成功感不仅仅是针对特定的职业或工作，而是将成功视为一段旅程……会有起伏，会有挫折，就会有障碍，”他说，并补充说拥有多个职业也可能是一种成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天的许多心态也很注重地位，等级森严。即使在银行内部，有些工作也比其他工作更有声望。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong 说，这种对成功的新定义还包括能够考虑各种“非传统”工作，例如厨师或开办机械车间，但由于工资较低而在文化上被回避。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非金钱方面的满足感，例如良好的人际关系和家庭、社区参与同样重要，即使它们没有“体现在我们的 GDP 中” ”，王补充道。他鼓励商界和社区领袖帮助实现这一改变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为全球贸易和金融中心以及超级富豪的奢侈低税基地而享有盛誉的岛国，已经近几十年来财富大幅增长——但与此同时，人们对收入差距的担忧也在加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，该国的收入不平等一直在下降，尽管中产阶级受到不断上升的打击&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议的其他小组讨论了这些问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着中产阶级居民感到压力，“两个新加坡”的情景是否会出现？&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;教育部长陈振声强调了黄之锋在关于任人唯贤的演讲中所说的，他说新加坡人必须考虑成功和幸福，而不是个人的胜利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，这包括对社会做出更广泛的贡献。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;“让我们认识到，我们个人的成功不仅仅是因为我们自己的能力和努力，而是因为系统给我们的机会和我们周围人的支持，”陈说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们都能做到这一点，那么新加坡的贤能政治品牌将团结我们而不是分裂我们……这不仅仅是让我们领先于人群，而是让我们团结在一起。” &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Saudi minister calls for people-to-people exchanges with China for businesses to ‘kick the tires, do due diligence’ to enhance trade]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3223849/saudi-minister-calls-people-people-exchanges-china-businesses-kick-tires-do-due-diligence-enhance?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 22:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/ff55df00-be74-4a8b-9408-7bc252b0a646_d473af92.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;沙特阿拉伯投资部长 Khalid A. Al-Falih 呼吁中国大陆增加投资和香港在利雅得与由恒隆地产董事长陈启宗率领的商业代表团举行闭门会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;部长在第一天的晚宴后会见了代表团在周日举行的第十届阿中商业会议（ACBC）上，他表示希望看到沙特阿拉伯与中国之间经济和人际关系的发展。他还表示愿意在方便的时候尽早访问香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加强交流的目的是让企业家“踢轮胎，双勤，前进”，达成交易，他在包括邮报在内的约 40 名代表参加的闭门会议上说。 “我们想要更多的品牌、技术以及进入全球和中国市场的机会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;部长的评论是在第 10 届为期两天的会议的第一天发表的，有 3,500 多名代表参加了会议来自 23 个不同国家的人，包括中国人民政治协商会议 (CPPCC) 副主席胡春华。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从 Al-Falih 到外交、环境和政策制定者的沙特部长游行农业方面也表达了改善与中国关系的希望，涵盖从文化交流到直接项目和投资的方方面面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我希望这些访问之后会有一些公司进行投资，”Al-Falih 说，用英语发表他的讲话。 “如果我们选择合资，我们很乐意为您介绍多个值得信赖的合作伙伴。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Al-Falih表示，他希望尽快前往香港和大陆，他的这是自 2019 年以来的首次访问，因为在 Covid-19 大流行期间发生了“很多变化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据他的计划，沙特政府正在敲定派遣高级代表团前往北京的计划据知情人士透露，将于 10 月参加第 10 届“一带一路”倡议 (BRI) 论坛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港政府热衷于将香港定位为“一带一路”倡议的“超级连接器” ，还计划派出一个由“数百名”企业高管和官员组成的代表团参加论坛，人们说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 是香港推广和品牌工作组的成员，他说他仍然看到沙特阿拉伯和中国之间文化交流的“短缺”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须建立一个长期的人与人之间的关系 [programme for] 以真正发展经济关系或其他关系，”他说. “如果没有那种友谊，恐怕根基就不会那么牢固。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港行政长官李家超率领 30 名企业高管代表团前往沙特阿拉伯和阿拉伯联合酋长国阿联酋航空 (UAE) 于 2 月研究金融服务、技术和物流领域的投资机会。为期一周的访问是在北京加大力度促进与该地区的商业联系之后进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;私营部门也可以建立人与人之间的联系，因为企业在形成“经济”方面发挥着重要作用Al-Falih 说，阿拉伯消费者的“软实力”，最终有助于形成经济合作的势头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“普通人对其他国家的印象不是由 [数量] 资本流动造成的，或贸易量，但取决于消费量，”这位部长说，并补充说中国品牌在沙特的家用电器、手持数字设备、时尚和旅游领域越来越受欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有时我们关注在更具体的事情上。我们希望中国来建设铁路、港口……我们想要这些，是的，但正如你们中的许多人所意识到的那样，私营部门参与者可以更有力量在国家之间架起桥梁，”这位部长说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Al-法力赫说，建立人文关系的挑战之一是教育。他说，虽然利雅得的目标是将中文提升为该国最常学习的第二语言，但在招聘教师方面仍需要“努力工作”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;沙特阿拉伯和中国无视西方的愤怒，承诺更紧密地联系关系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Al-Falih 和 Chan 都表示，促进关系的有效方式是在彼此的国家提供教育机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据沙特阿拉伯教育部的数据，共有截至去年12月，共有174名沙特学生在中国大学就读，其中包括131名奖学金获得者和43名自费学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，该部表示，沙特阿拉伯每年为沙特大学的中国学生提供477名奖学金，2018年至2022年共有688名中国学生在沙特高校就读。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba’s Taobao to host Lionel Messi in live-streaming e-commerce show with Chinese liquor influencer Li Xuanzhuo]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3223833/alibabas-taobao-host-lionel-messi-live-streaming-e-commerce-show-chinese-liquor-influencer-li?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/27733e65-6b20-4d73-95d6-aa51a0040eb6_9e2b5826.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;足球巨星莱昂内尔·梅西计划出现在阿里巴巴的直播节目中集团控股的淘宝直播平台将于周三晚在北京举办去年世界杯冠军阿根廷队和澳大利亚队之间的友谊赛前一天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位传奇足球运动员将与中国网红李娜一起现场直播根据《南华早报》母公司阿里巴巴发布的海报，炫着时间为晚上 6 点至晚上 9 点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴没有透露与梅西亮相相关的商业条款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅西，他于周六抵达中国首都，将为阿里巴巴的电子商务直播平台带来急需的流量，该平台与 PDD Holdings 的拼多多和字节跳动的抖音等本地竞争对手展开了激烈的战斗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位七届金球奖得主将加入 Li 的行列，后者曾经在三个月内售出超过 600,000 瓶酒，收入超过 5000 万元人民币（700 万美元），一举成名。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;李在 2019 年首次亮相直播，由佛山优旺科技代理，这是一家所谓的多渠道网络公司，专注于开发有影响力的内容。成立于 2010 年，2018 年进入直播行业，同年在深圳上市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然周三节目的细节尚未公布，但社交媒体上流传的一则通知截图显示，归因于 Yowant 的消息显示，该活动将在梅西下榻的北京四季酒店举行。据报道，现场约有 120 名安保人员驻守。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正在第七次访问中国的梅西周六受到了中国球迷的摇滚明星欢迎，首先是在他乘坐私人飞机降落后在北京机场据中国媒体报道，他和他的队友被“异常热情”的粉丝暂时“困住了”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几项计划中的活动，包括在北京的粉丝见面会三里屯地区，由于安全原因被取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 35 岁的足球运动员最后一次访问该国是在 2017 年，他将于周四在北京新装修的拥有 68,000 个座位的工人体育场带领阿根廷队对阵澳大利亚队.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China, India visa dispute threatens to sideline last journalists in each country]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223835/china-india-visa-dispute-threatens-sideline-last-journalists-each-country?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 20:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/12/841bcf3b-d4f5-4331-8f0d-d351418167d7_8c7c9b3c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国呼吁印度恢复签证审查并取消对中国人的“不合理”限制驻印度记者，此前中国记者因中国所说的“歧视性待遇”而被拒绝居留许可和银行卡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，北京拒绝为最后一名在中国工作的印度记者续签签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国和印度正处于地缘政治分裂之中&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据报道，四名常驻中国的印度记者中的最后一名被拒绝签证，并被中国当局要求在本月底前离开该国。此前，印度对两名驻当地的中国记者采取了同样的行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及最后一名印度记者的命运时，中国外交部发言人汪文斌说：“其中一名仍在中国工作和生活。”中国记者。他没有评论记者的签证状况，也没有续签签证的前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国一直像对待朋友和家人一样对待在中国的印度记者。中方一直保持克制，秉持善意，与印方多次沟通。然而，令人遗憾的是，印度没有采取任何行动来解决这个问题，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王猛烈抨击了他所谓的印度对中国驻印记者的“歧视性”和“不公平”待遇，并援引国家通讯社新华社前新德里分社社长胡晓明撰写的一篇文章中的帐户，他说他今年早些时候被要求离开印度，因为他在那里“待得太久”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一些中国记者在印度等待签证已经三年了。一些记者在印度驻扎5年，连续7次拿到的签证有效期不到1个月，甚至只有15天。”无法申请居留证、手机卡和银行卡以及驾驶执照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京早些时候表示，目前只有一名中国记者永久驻扎在印度，当局仍未续签其签证。北京表示，新德里一再拒绝批准中国记者的新签证申请，并且只签发了最长三个月的短期签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一度，中国有 14 名记者常驻印度。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;中国和印度领导人继续保持距离&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;印度外交部本月早些时候否认它利用对中国记者的签证限制来阻碍两国之间的媒体联系。 Instead, it accused China of creating obstacles for Indian journalists to hire locals to help with their reporting there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relations between the two Asian powers have deteriorated since a deadly clash in 2020 in the Galwan Valley – a disputed section of their shared border in the Himalayan region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few rounds of military talks have been held since to ease the border tensions, and both sides agreed to disengage from the disputed region last September.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese President Xi Jinping has not yet held a bilateral meeting with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi since he resumed in-person diplomacy following three years of Covid-19 restrictions. The two leaders greeted each other briefly during a Group of 20 summit in Indonesia last year.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Coincidence or deliberate interception? PLA cuts into Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen’s radio call with air force officer]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3223832/coincidence-or-deliberate-interception-pla-cuts-taiwanese-president-tsai-ing-wens-radio-call-air?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/12/7b79efa9-d593-42bc-ab06-4a942dc292e9_c58a5ed6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The People&#39;s Liberation Army disrupted a radio call between Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen and the island&#39;s air force, sparking a discussion about secure communications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsai was visiting southern Taiwan on Friday to boost morale among service personnel ahead of next week&#39;s Dragon Boat Festival and spoke to two female officers stationed at an air defence and missile command centre in Kaohsiung.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a video clip broadcast by local media, Tsai was seen radioing an air force captain, saying “Hotel Delta, this is the president”, before a PLA warning was heard in the background.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is the Chinese air force, you have already intruded into our airspace and seriously violated our sovereignty,” the message said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsai broke into a smile when she heard the warning and an officer came forward to shut down the radio broadcast by the PLA. The conversation continued with Tsai asking the air force captain if she had spotted anything unusual on patrol, and urging her to remain vigilant when she was told nothing had been spotted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The episode was later remade into a funny clip by the mainland-based nationalistic news outlet Huanqiu.com, showing Tsai making a weird smile.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Most Europeans would want to stay neutral in a US-China war over Taiwan: study&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On Monday, the Taiwanese air force explained that the PLA had not cut into Tsai&#39;s radio channel and the PLA warning came from another radio channel monitored by the control centre of the island&#39;s air force defence and missile command.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Tsai was using a combat readiness exclusive radio line for communication and the PLA was using the aircraft emergency frequency in its radio broadcast,” the Taiwanese air force said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They were two different systems and the president was not affected at all,” it said, adding that the air force was able to effectively control different situations around Taiwan and respond to all kinds of actions taken by the PLA.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwanese Premier Chen Chien-jen also said on Monday that the PLA had not intercepted Tsai&#39;s radio system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This reflects the kind of challenges our air force has to tackle every day in defending our air territory,” he said, referring to the missile command&#39;s role in monitoring what the PLA Air Force says and does.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Military experts in Taiwan said while the apparent disruption could be a coincidence, there was a strong need for the island&#39;s authorities to understand if plans for senior officials to visit important military facilities were being leaked to the PLA.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The PLA warning appeared to have been directed to some other foreign aircraft and not ours,” said Chieh Chung, a security analyst at National Policy Foundation, a Taipei think tank affiliated with the main opposition party the Kuomintang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was possible that the warning which was monitored by the control centre came as Tsai was starting her radio call, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But the question is about the timing – why it came right as Tsai addressed the captain. The security authorities here should carefully review the issue as it would be a serious problem for our military if the PLA Air Force knew the timing of Tsai&#39;s call and was able to issue its warning at the same time,” Chieh said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the island&#39;s security authorities must study the incident closely to see if mainland China had a full grasp of Tsai&#39;s important itineraries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chang Yen-ting, a retired air force general, also said if it was a coincidence it was a very unusual one.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing voices support for Taiwan&#39;s pro-unification forces in latest exchange&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“There might not be a communication security lapse in the radio communication networks, but the security authorities here should try to figure out if the PLA had obtained intelligence about the president&#39;s plan to make the radio calls,” Chang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the PLA is able to easily get hold of what the president, the defence minister and the chief of general staff are going to do, it means the Chinese communists&#39; infiltration into Taiwan is very serious.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rudeness tops list for complaints about Hong Kong taxi trade, survey finds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3223839/rudeness-tops-list-complaints-about-hong-kong-taxi-trade-survey-finds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 21:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/12/99af7193-6536-4103-b908-683d0a4f14d5_bda7231b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Passengers were less satisfied with taxi services in Hong Kong this year compared to pre-pandemic times, but tourists tended to give higher scores than residents, a survey has found.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reaction to the statement “drivers treat passengers politely” was the worst-rated part of the survey, released on Monday. Only 35 per cent of respondents agreed and it mustered a score of 3.21 out of 5.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The poll found 55.3 per cent of passengers were satisfied with the taxi trade, but 36.6 per cent labelled the service average and a little over 8 per cent rated the service as “unsatisfactory” or “extremely unsatisfactory”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last survey, carried out in the second quarter of 2019, found about 70 per cent of passengers thought the taxi service was satisfactory. The poll was suspended for three years because of Covid-19.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong Taxi Council, which released the results of the service quality survey, blamed the falling ratings on an ageing workforce and fleet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ryan Wong Cheuk-pong, the council chairman, appealed to the government to ban online car-hailing services, such as Uber, to help tackle the problem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Online car-hailing services are more flexible in terms of service time and fares, so it has attracted many young drivers,” Wong explained. “But such services are not regulated by the government and customers may find it difficult to defend their rights.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The government should outlaw such services, or else the ageing problem in the taxi industry cannot be solved,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong also said that some owners were reluctant to replace old cabs with newer ones because they might want to obtain a government subsidy under the Green Energy Transport Fund, which refunds up to HK$3 million (US$382,973) of the cost of a new electric cab.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it was not all bad news for the taxi trade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 46.8 per cent of respondents agreed that “the vehicles are neat and tidy”, which notched up the highest average score at 3.45.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong targets greater uptake of electric taxis by introducing more models&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The survey ran from April to early May and polled 1,211 passengers, 90 per cent of them from the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The poll used a questionnaire made up of 13 metrics, covering areas such as vehicle conditions, drivers&#39; attitudes, and convenience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ride-hailing services are not legal in Hong Kong without a hire-car permit and Uber has come under attack by the taxi industry, which has 18,163 licensed cabs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Passengers like the online hailing service because drivers turn up fast and the cashless fare payment system was convenient.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong added the industry would not consider the importation of labour from outside Hong Kong unless the problems intensified.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Taxi drivers have to be very familiar with Hong Kong and should communicate well in Cantonese. It is inappropriate to have imported drivers at this stage,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The survey also found tourists gave a higher average score on taxi service quality, at 80.58 per cent, than residents, with an average of 57.59 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Shake-up of licensing regime needed for Hong Kong&#39;s ageing taxi drivers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The gap between scores from tourists and Hongkongers widened compared to 2019, when tourists rated service quality at 69.72, just seven points higher than residents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That might be due to drivers&#39; strengthening cleaning of the cabs during the pandemic and their efforts to treat tourists politely to leave them a good impression of Hong Kong,” Danny Ho Chik-kuen, an assistant professor at Hang Seng University of Hong Kong, who was commissioned to carry out the survey, suggested.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He Wenbo, a tourist from mainland China&#39;s Hunan province, said: “I think taxis in Hong Kong are quite good as Hongkongers behave in a good manner and I think the prices are reasonable.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 35-year-old said he had spotted some social media posts about how mainland tourists were ripped off by Hong Kong taxi drivers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he said he had never had a bad experience with the city&#39;s taxi trade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nicolas Conpoyan, a 60-year-old office worker who has lived in Hong Kong for 30 years, agreed the city&#39;s cabbies provided a good service.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Conpoyan added he would rate the service provided at 70 out of 100 – but had one major complaint.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think the drivers are not very polite,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore teen pleads guilty to telling friend to pour boiling water on abuse victim]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223840/singapore-teen-pleads-guilty-telling-friend-pour-boiling-water-abuse-victim?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 21:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/12/6731c28e-f0ce-4e48-a8c2-f9f297332b9f_f64d7654.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A 16-year-old girl turned on a kettle, then directed her friend to pour boiling water on a 19-year-old man with special needs, causing first- and second-degree burns. The assault was part of repeated physical abuse of the victim spanning nine days that was inflicted by a group of four in a hotel room.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The girl, now aged 18, pleaded guilty on Monday to a charge of forming a common intent to cause hurt with the use of boiling water, and one unrelated charge of consuming the drug methamphetamine, also known as “ice”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She will be sentenced on July 19.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore teen admits trying to rape 8-year-old sister&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Muhammad Shahfakhry Mohamad Faizal, the man who poured the boiling water on the victim, was sentenced to five-and-a-half years&#39; jail in February. The 22-year-old assaulted the victim multiple times.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two other members of the group – Putri Nuramira Aishah Rosli, 20, and a girl aged 17 – were both sentenced last year to one year of reformative training.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the Children and Young Persons Act, the names of individuals who commit their offences when they were aged under 18 cannot be published.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What happened&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The court heard that before being assaulted by the group, the victim – who has a low intelligence quotient (IQ) – was friends with two members of the group and did not know the other two.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On January 15, 2022, the offenders were staying at the Arton Boutique Hotel in the Jalan Besar area where three of them were consuming illicit drugs, though not the teenager who pleaded guilty on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That day, the victim asked the other teenage girl where she was, and he then met her and the others at the hotel. Two days later on January 17, the victim started staying at the hotel with them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From January 17 to 25 last year, the victim was subjected to various types of physical abuse by the group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On January 17, for example, both Shahfakhry and the other young woman who cannot be named attacked the victim by slapping, punching and kicking him, Deputy Public Prosecutor (DPP) Selene Yap said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The offender who pleaded guilty on Monday had filmed one of those assaults.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the evening of January 19, the then 16-year-old girl set a kettle to boil and gestured to Shahfakhry to pour the boiling water on the victim, which he did on the victim&#39;s back.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore teen arrested after being caught humping cat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;By January 25, after observing that the victim was in a “bad state”, Shahfakhry, Putri and the other girl stopped hitting him and bought medication and bandages to tend to his wounds, DPP Yap said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The physical assaults of the victim came to light when the victim&#39;s sister saw a post on social media with a photo that showed a badly injured person who looked like her brother.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She made a police report on January 25, stating that her brother had left home on January 14 and had not returned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police investigations eventually traced the victim to the hotel where he was found on January 26. He taken to Singapore General Hospital with critical injuries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three members of the group were arrested on the same day while the 18-year-old who pleaded guilty on Monday was arrested the next day.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore teen admits carrying drunk colleague into toilet to be raped by another&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A medical report found that the victim had sustained numerous injuries, including chemical burns to his scalp, face and back. He also had cigarette butt burns, slash wounds and amnesia from a possible traumatic brain injury.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He had to be given alternative nutritional support because he was unable to take food orally due to limitations in opening his mouth and an acute stress reaction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 18-year-old will return to court on July 19 for sentencing after the judge receives reports on her suitability for probation and reformative training.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For forming a common intent to cause hurt with the use of a heated substance, the offender could be jailed for up to seven years, fined or caned, or be given any combination of these punishments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Arab-China Business Conference: Chinese EV maker Human Horizons’ US$5.6 billion deal among agreements worth US$10 billion signed during two-day summit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3223842/arab-china-business-conference-chinese-ev-maker-human-horizons-us56-billion-deal-among-agreements?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.12 21:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/12/b243fb80-ed30-4490-aa0d-3b6367ca2b0a_a48c80cd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A two-day business conference between China and the Arab world has ended in Riyadh with investment deals worth US$10 billion, more than half of which came in a partnership signed by Chinese electric car maker Human Horizons and Saudi Arabia&#39;s investment ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The joint-venture will conduct “automotive research, development, manufacturing and sales” as part of a US$5.6 billion deal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The conference, which followed a high-profile visit to Saudi Arabia by Chinese President Xi Jinping last December, saw deals being signed by Chinese firms from sectors such as technology, renewable energy, agriculture, real estate, metals, tourism and healthcare. The conference, which has been hosted by Riyadh for the first time, is now in its 10th year. This year&#39;s edition drew more than 3,500 attendees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Chinese companies now have a better chance of building infrastructure, assembling electric vehicles [EVs], running new-energy projects and developing technology businesses in Saudi Arabia now that the Middle Eastern country embarks on its Vision 2030 strategy,” said Yan Jinglan, a professor of foreign studies at the East China University of Science and Technology in Shanghai. “Investment and production in the Kingdom will benefit some Chinese firms, particularly manufacturers who face heated competition at home.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Saudi Arabia, China ignore Western ire to pledge closer ties&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Saudi&#39;s Vision 2030 strategy is a development plan aimed at reducing the country&#39;s reliance on oil and transforming its economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has vowed to support Saudi Arabia&#39;s vision to diversify its economy, despite oil dominating current economic ties between the two countries. Beijing&#39;s growing interest in the region was underlined by Xi&#39;s visit in December, when he attended the China-Arab Countries summit and the China-Gulf Cooperation Council summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His co-hosting of the China-Arab Countries Summit and first visit to the region since 2016 were widely seen as attempts to increase Beijing&#39;s influence in a region that, in common with China, has an increasingly frayed relationship with the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vast majority of deals signed during the summit are for projects in Saudi Arabia or by Saudi firms and government entities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai-based Human Horizons&#39; deal comes amid a push by Riyadh, which has been seeking growth in its technology and green-energy sectors, including the development of a domestic EV manufacturing industry, as part of its Saudi Vision 2030 plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;No doubt&#39; over China&#39;s Middle East economic inroads, but politics &#39;more complex&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The carmaker develops autonomous driving technology and produces EVs under its high-end HiPhi brand, which also aims to enter the European market this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Premium or luxury EV models might sit well with the Saudi market,” said David Zhang, a visiting professor at Huanghe Science and Technology College. “Human Horizons is the right pioneer to test the market with its expensive models before other Chinese EVs foray into Saudi Arabia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The carmaker currently assembles two luxury EV models, with the cheapest version of the cars sporting a price tag of US$80,000. HiPhi, however, does not feature in lists of China&#39;s top 15 EV makers in terms of monthly sales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among other deals signed during the summit, AMR ALuwlaa Company and Zhonghuan International Group signed a US$533 million deal to establish an iron factory in Saudi Arabia, and Saudi ASK Group and China National Geological and Mining Corporation signed a US$500 million cooperation agreement on copper mining.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese state-owned rolling stock manufacturer CRRC Corporation, building materials company Sunda International Group, home appliances group Haier and Atlas Renewable Energy were among other companies that signed deals with the Saudi ministry. The details of these deals have not yet been made public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai-based Octopus Online Tour Development signed an agreement with the ministry to explore tourism opportunities between the two countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The aim is to establish mutual interest and we will follow up by exploring how to boost tourism both ways,” Yuan Dong, Octopus Online&#39;s vice-managing director, told the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Arab countries will work with China to seize the opportunities for broader economic integration of the two sides,” Khalid al-Falih, the Saudi investment minister, said during the opening of the conference on Sunday. He noted that China&#39;s outward foreign direct investment had grown by 20 per cent annually over the past decade, but said that “there is still potential to increase investment flows in the other direction to take advantage of China&#39;s large and prosperous market”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While China&#39;s outbound investments grew only 0.9 per cent last year, outbound mergers and acquisitions activity continued to slow and recorded a value drop of 52 per cent year on year, according to a report by accounting firm EY in February this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s ministry of commerce, however, said the country recorded a 35.7 per cent year-on-year growth in overseas direct investment in the first two months of this year, after Beijing abandoned its strict Covid-19 control policies after three years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing is the Arab countries&#39; largest trading partner with a volume of commerce worth a record US$430 billion last year, Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Faisal Bin Farhan said when he kicked off the conference on Sunday. Saudi Arabia alone made up a quarter of the volume, with bilateral trade rising 30 per cent in 2022 to US$106.1 billion.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 12 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>