<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Rich young Asians urged to build culture of giving ‘boldly’ to tackle climate change, inequality]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3225050/rich-young-asians-urged-build-culture-giving-boldly-tackle-climate-change-inequality?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 19:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/250a720b-5d69-45a8-87cc-d666643ab2c8_c97e3c27.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;亚洲超级富豪被敦促投身慈善事业，以帮助解决亚洲面临的重叠危机从气候变化到难以获得教育和医疗保健，大量的家庭资金被转移到愿意奉献的年轻、更具社会意识的一代人手中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周在吉隆坡，1,300 名代表加入了亚洲最大的会议此次慈善聚会由总部位于新加坡的亚洲公益创投网络 (AVPN) 和马来西亚主权财富基金的社会影响力部门 Yayasan Hasanah 主办。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在整个财富创造的黄金时代，社会影响力受到关注。亚洲——疫情大流行加剧了不平等现象的加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“极端天气事件”：厄尔尼诺现象迫在眉睫，亚洲将迎来高温&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美元百万富翁的数量根据汇丰银行 2022 年的一份报告，随着全球增长极东移，亚洲人口预计在本世纪末翻一番，达到近 8000 万，超过美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而世界银行表示，数百人亚洲仍有数百万人陷入极端贫困，非洲大陆的大片地区还严重受到气候危机、大流行的持续影响以及人工智能对劳动力市场造成破坏的风险的影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;慈善事业有潜力填补一些空白。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在见证人类历史上最大规模的财富转移，”AVPN 首席项目官 Tristan Ace 说道。通往亚洲各地捐赠者和社会企业的门户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从印度和印度尼西亚到中国，过去 20 到 30 年来创造了大量财富，”Ace 说。 “下一代人希望做与祖父母不同的事情。这提供了一个巨大的机会，可以大胆思考并投资于未来问题的解决方案，例如摆脱煤炭的转型。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自亚洲各地的主权基金、家族办公室、基金会、个人捐助者和社会企业参加了三场会议日会议名为“全球挑战：亚洲解决方案”，探讨慈善捐赠在解决绿色转型、性别差异、青年技能差距以及公平获得教育和医疗保健方面的潜力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是专家警告说，从现在到2030年，亚太地区每年需要额外投入1.5万亿美元才能实现联合国可持续发展目标，还有很长的路要走，而应对气候变化也需要高达23万亿美元的投资缺口马来西亚妇女、家庭和社区部长南希·舒克里 (Nancy Shukri) 表示：“重要的是，慈善事业应超越慈善事业，成为通过解决根本原因支持社会正义的关键机制。”周四代表安瓦尔·易卜拉欣总理发表讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“真正为人类服务的经济是拥抱社会正义、保护环境和培育人民福祉的经济。这是一个重视人而非利润的经济体。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在整个亚洲，富人的队伍越来越深。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的胡润富豪榜称，中国仍然是超级富豪的最大来源国-富有的国家有 969 名亿万富翁，领先于美国（691 名）和印度，位居第三。汇丰银行 2022 年的研究表明，预计到 2030 年，13.4% 的新加坡人口将成为百万富翁，这一比例高于亚太地区任何地方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但自 2008 年金融危机以来，财富已慢慢向东倾斜面向未来的社会和经济的机会正在出现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“亚洲的财富大幅增长，导致财富持有者除了慈善事业外还参与社会投资，”首席执行官 Naina Subberwal Batra 说道。 AVPN。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“家族办公室越来越多地推动其投资顾问提出一系列能够产生积极社会净影响的投资。我们的目标是激励和赋权新一代的捐赠者。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲的愿景是创造一种文化，在这种文化中“捐赠不仅仅是一种选择，而是为了更大的利益而共同承担的责任” ”，她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;捐赠是由商业帝国的年轻继承者推动的，这些商业帝国已经乘上了高速增长的浪潮。专家表示，这些后代中的许多人在海外接受过教育，与他们的父母和祖父母相比，他们对自己所在地区的贫富差距、气候危机和根深蒂固的贫困有不同的了解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们有潜力向整个亚洲释放大量慈善资金，但对超级富豪捐赠的批评者警告说，这可能会转移人们对金钱来源方式以及他们影响力所支撑的不平等经济和政治体系的注意力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“确实存在一些怀疑，”AVPN 的 Ace 说。 “但这些人希望成为解决方案的一部分，并且已经拥有现有的基础设施。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了推动真正的变革，公司应该将捐赠纳入其“核心业务”，董事总经理 Shahira Ahmed Bazari 表示&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们的后全球化世界中，我们面临着前所未有的挑战，需要创新的解决方案和集体行动，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论是影响深远的气候变化的影响或大流行病加剧的经济差距，我们经常听到将更可持续的做法融入我们开展业务和日常生活的方式的呼声。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 20:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China protests over Joe Biden’s ‘disparaging’ comments likening Xi Jinping to ‘dictator’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3225052/china-protests-over-joe-bidens-disparaging-comments-likening-xi-jinping-dictator?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 20:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/dcca179c-3243-4ac8-a9b3-dc6a89e673e6_13f24f22.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京正式向白宫抗议美国总统拜登将其中文比作中文的言论美国国务卿安东尼将中国国家主席习近平称为“独裁者”，其驻美国使团警告称，对中国政治制度和最高领导人的挑衅将带来“后果”。布林肯的中国修复关系之行包括周一与习近平的会面，北京加大了对华盛顿的赌注，质疑其稳定两国紧张关系的诚意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据周四发表的声明，中国驻华盛顿大使馆、北京驻华盛顿高级特使谢锋周三向白宫和国务院未透露姓名的高级官员“提出严正交涉和强烈抗议”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明援引未透露姓名的大使馆发言人的话说：称拜登的“贬低”言论“错误、荒唐、不负责任，构成公然的政治挑衅”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;布林肯访华可能让美国一些盟友陷入“岌岌可危的境地”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;外国外交部发言人毛宁也谴责拜登的言论“极其荒谬和不负责任”，并表示这些言论“严重违反基本事实、外交礼节和中国的政治尊严”。不过，她周三在北京举行的例行吹风会上发表的言论并未出现在外交部网站上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;使馆在声明中进一步阐述了北京的立场，称“对中国最高领导人的抹黑”此举损害了双方互信，“性质和影响十分消极”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国政府和人民对此深感侮辱，坚决反对。拜登总统此前曾明确表示，美国尊重中国的制度，不寻求改变中国的制度，无意搞新冷战。但最近针对中国政治制度和最高领导人的不负责任言论，让人不禁质疑美方的诚意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明称，将“坚决回应”“针对中国的政治挑衅”。 ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们敦促美方立即采取切实行动，消除负面影响，恪守自身承诺。否则，它将承担一切后果。”大使馆在声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登周二在加州举行的筹款活动上发表了针对中国领导人的异常尖锐的言论，这是他明年竞选活动的一部分总统选举。他说，当美国二月份击落一个所谓的中国间谍气球时，习近平“非常不安”，这促使布林肯推迟了当月对中国的访问计划，因为“他不知道气球在那里”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“这对独裁者来说是一个巨大的尴尬，因为他们不知道发生了什么，”他告诉捐助者，并补充说习近平“希望再次建立关系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三被问及拜登的评论时，美国国务院发言人韦丹特·帕特尔表示，没有必要劝他们回去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“总统认为，外交手段，包括国务卿最近的这次访问，是管理紧张局势的负责任方式，”帕特尔说。 “我认为总统的言论不需要进一步澄清或进一步解释。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫周三试图淡化拜登的言论，称其“充满期待”布林肯本周早些时候期待已久的中国之行取得了进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“总统坦诚地谈论中国和我们之间的分歧，这并不奇怪——我们当然是据法新社报道，一位不愿透露姓名的高级政府官员表示，这并不孤单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“总统认为，外交手段，包括国务卿布林肯采取的外交手段，是负责任的管理方式。”这位官员补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯和习近平周一对北京进行了为期两天的访问，这是美国最高外交官五年来的首次访问，他同意稳定两国之间的竞争，从而避免紧张局势的发生。陷入冲突。虽然此次访问没有取得突破，但双方同意继续进行高层外交交往，其中包括中国外交部长秦刚访问华盛顿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但布林肯结束会议数小时后，紧张局势又开始重新出现。周一，中国外交部北美大洋洲司司长杨涛猛烈抨击华盛顿对台湾的“一个中国”政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在媒体上发表讲话在周一晚间的新闻发布会上，杨指责美国背弃了之前对台湾的承诺，北京认为台湾是一个失控的省份，必须在必要时使用武力与大陆统一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨说美国最初承认“世界上只有一个中国，台湾是中国的一部分”。但他随后又声称，多年来华盛顿决定将《与台湾关系法》和所谓的对台六项保证纳入其一个中国政策，这违背了北京和华盛顿双方的共识。他补充说：“中国坚决反对他们，也不承认他们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;分析人士称，中国猛烈抨击拜登对习近平的“荒谬”言论，不要抱任何幻想&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周一，习近平的高级外交政策助理王毅也将美中关系恶化的责任直接归咎于拜登政府，敦促华盛顿对“美国对华误解”和“错误的对华政策”进行“反省” 。然而，美国负责东亚和太平洋事务的助理国务卿丹尼尔·克里滕布林克(Daniel Kritenbrink)后来回击称，只有“双向”，才有可能建立富有成效的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，新西兰预计下周访问北京并会见习近平的总理克里斯·希普金斯周四表示，他不同意拜登将中国领导人比作“独裁者”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;七国集团工​​业化国家也七国集团代表与布林肯在伦敦举行会议后，周三表示团结并支持在与中国打交道时进行更密切的协调。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 20:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: Kyiv hits bridge linking Crimea to mainland in blow to Russian supply route]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225046/ukraine-war-kyiv-hits-bridge-linking-crimea-mainland-blow-russian-supply-route?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 20:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/68f70cf2-27f5-4870-9a58-a6606190c1dd_103aea37.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;乌克兰导弹早些时候击中了连接克里米亚半岛与乌克兰大陆的少数桥梁之一周四，在基辅努力将俄罗斯占领军驱逐出乌克兰南部地区时，切断了俄罗斯占领军的主要补给路线之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗拉基米尔·萨尔多，俄罗斯在乌克兰赫尔松省被占领地区设立的政府首脑发布了有关 Chonhar 公路桥的视频，那里的沥青被炸出弹坑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“基辅政权奉伦敦之命实施的又一毫无意义的行为。就特别军事行动而言，它解决不了任何问题。”他说，并发誓要修复桥梁并恢复交通。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;无人机战争在乌克兰是如何演变的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他威胁说以一座连接邻国摩尔多瓦和北约成员国罗马尼亚的桥梁为目标进行报复：“很快就会做出非常严肃的反应。”夜间遭到袭击的琼哈尔大桥是通往克里米亚的少数通道之一，通过狭窄的地峡与乌克兰大陆相连。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;替代路线需要在路况较差的道路上绕行数小时。俄罗斯新闻通讯社援引俄罗斯在克里米亚部署的运输官员的话称，修复桥梁可能需要数周时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这座桥超出了乌克兰使用一年的战场火箭的射程，但在新部署的武器的射程范围内例如英国和法国的空射巡航导弹，使基辅能够袭击俄罗斯几周前还认为安全的后勤路线。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这次袭击“是对基辅军事后勤的打击”乌克兰赫尔松地区管理机构官员尤里·索博列夫斯基 (Yuriy Sobolevsky) 表示，“对占领者和占领国的心理影响更为重要。他说：“赫尔松地区没有任何地方能让他们感到安全。” 据俄新社报道，俄罗斯调查人员称，乌克兰军队向大桥发射了四枚导弹。报道援引军事调查人员发言人的话说，其中一枚导弹残骸上发现的标记表明它是在法国制造的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰正在攻击俄罗斯补给线，以破坏莫斯科对被占领土的防御。南部，基辅正处于战争中最雄心勃勃的反攻的早期阶段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基辅表示，迄今为止已夺回八个村庄，但尚未投入大部分部队参加战斗和其前进部队尚未到达俄罗斯的主要防线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最新的战斗情况中，乌克兰军方报告称在东南部和东部取得了“部分成功”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;部队总参谋部发言人安德烈·科瓦廖夫（Andriy Kovaliov）表示，他们在攻击里夫诺波尔（Rivnopil）和斯塔罗马约尔斯克（Staromayorske）村庄后，加强了他们所达到的阵地，指的是俄罗斯控制地区的定居点，向南推进的乌克兰军队迄今已占领了四个村庄。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还描述了东部地区的激烈战斗，乌克兰称其一直在阻止俄罗斯的袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯称已击退乌克兰的反击并造成重大人员伤亡，但乌克兰对此予以否认。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰总统弗拉基米尔·泽连斯基承认，迄今为止进展缓慢，但表示他的部队正在谨慎地进入布满地雷和防守严密的地区，以尽量减少损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泽连斯基周四指责俄罗斯策划了这一计划欧洲最大的扎波罗热核电站发生恐怖袭击，该核电站位于前线附近俄罗斯控制的领土上。莫斯科否认有任何此类计划。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan suffers another diplomatic blow as Fiji pulls the plug on representative office’s name change]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3225029/taiwan-suffers-another-diplomatic-blow-fiji-pulls-plug-representative-offices-name-change?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/f0a09471-06a9-4b0c-9149-e54739a1b98a_947305cd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;正当台湾通过恢复其代表的官方头衔来庆祝小小的外交收获时斐济这个太平洋小岛国在北京的压力下终止了更名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾驻苏瓦办事处被称为中华民国（台湾）驻共和国贸易代表团斐济虽然没有正式关系，但享有外交特权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后在2018年，亲大陆的总理白尼马拉马政府单方面将名称改为台北驻斐济贸易办事处，并剥夺了其外交职务。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年三月，对台北友好的新斐济联合政府允许台湾恢复使团的前身名称和外交特权，这一举动引起了与台湾建立官方关系的北京的强烈抗议。 1975年与这个太平洋岛国建立了外交关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但周四，台湾外交部表示，由于来自斐济的巨大压力，斐济三党联合政府决定暂停恢复代表团的官方头衔和外交特权。北京。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国高级外交官将在习近平与阿尔巴尼亚会谈之前访问澳大利亚&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“斐济政府决定恢复我使团的正式名称后，中国驻当地大使馆不仅提出抗议台湾外交部在一份声明中表示，“反对此举，但也威胁要采取报复行动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大陆外交部副部长马朝旭在四月访问斐济时，对苏瓦施加了更大的压力，台湾外交部表示，经过一系列内阁讨论，促使联合政府撤销该办公室恢复名称的许可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾外交部对斐济未能“坚持其立场”表示遗憾，并谴责北京的行为“屡次在国际舞台上打压台湾，贬低我们的主权”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾外交部表示，自1971年台北在苏瓦设立代表处以来，双方在农业、农业、农业等领域合作交流密切。渔业、医疗、教育、人才培养，极大造福斐济人民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;表示将继续与太平洋岛国分享台湾经济发展的成功经验，致力于维护和平与稳定&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三在苏瓦举行的新闻发布会上，北京驻斐济大使周健称联合政府的决定是“正确”举措，将有助于巩固双边关系并加强经济合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“中方愿本着一个中国原则，务实加强同斐济各界合作，提升两国关系水平，增进斐济民众福祉， ”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周表示，自 1 月份以来，北京已向斐济捐赠了价值 700 万斐济元（315 万美元）的太阳能产品，与斐济签署了价值 1700 万斐济元的经济技术合作协议，并提供了价值25万美元的医疗援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在与美国的竞争日益激烈之际，中国任命太平洋岛国特使&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;斐济是前英国殖民地，是第一个建交的太平洋岛国1970 年宣布脱离英国独立五年后，它与北京建立了联系。尽管它与台湾没有保持正式关系，但它继续允许台北在苏瓦代表处使用其官方名称，直到 2018 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为自己的领土，必须将其收复，必要时可以使用武力，随着美国加强在该地区的存在，北京一直在努力确保其在斐济和其他太平洋岛国的影响力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于多方面的争端，美中关系处于数十年来的最低点。美国与斐济和大多数其他国家一样，不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对以武力改变现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter’s Elon Musk wants cage match with Meta boss Mark Zuckerberg]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3225038/twitters-elon-musk-wants-cage-match-meta-boss-mark-zuckerberg?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 19:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/335b7d34-c808-4b8f-9d4d-07a2f7f6ea09_e221589e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;科技巨头马克·扎克伯格和埃隆·马斯克正在进行激烈的商业竞争，而且这种竞争已经蔓延开来陷入操场上的口角，两人主动提出在笼子里打架。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克接管 Twitter 几个月后，扎克伯格的 Meta 暗示它计划推出自己的基于文本的社交媒体平台 - 本质上是直接竞争对手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从那时起，马斯克就在 Twitter 上发消息攻击扎克伯格，并于本周告诉他的粉丝：“如果他笑的话，我就准备参加一场笼式比赛。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扎克伯格追随了科技大佬们变强并发布武术视频的趋势，周三他在 Instagram Stories 上回应了这条消息的屏幕截图，并回应道：“给我发送位置。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta 证实向法新社表示，扎克伯格的信息是真实的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次交流在社交媒体上引发了欢乐，并出现了大量的战斗预测——扎克伯格明显成为最受欢迎的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“请上帝让科技记者泰勒·洛伦茨 (Taylor Lorenz) 在 Twitter 上写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;播客贝内特·汤姆林 (Bennett Tomlin) 写道，“最好的马斯克与扎克伯格的笼式比赛是两个人进入，没有人离开的比赛。”&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;马克·扎克伯格称埃隆·马斯克的人工智能预测“不负责任”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;多年来，这两个人在从政治到人工智能的各个方面都持有相反的观点，互相引诱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他们的新业务竞争加剧了敌意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克对 Meta 官员最近声称人们对“稳健运行”的 Twitter 替代品有兴趣的说法做出了愤怒的回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位特斯拉和 SpaceX 的老板收购了马斯克斥资 440 亿美元斥资 440 亿美元收购了这家社交媒体公司，然后解雇了大部分员工，并允许被禁止的右翼阴谋论者重返该平台，从而导致广告商纷纷逃离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马斯克去年在巴黎的一次活动中为自己对 Twitter 的处理方式进行了辩护。周，说广告商已经回来，他已经消灭了几乎所有机器人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候接受美国播客莱克斯·弗里德曼 (Lex Fridman) 采访时，扎克伯格被要求对马斯克处理 Twitter 的方式发表一些积极的看法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;停顿八秒后，他表示马斯克“很早就带头推动 Twitter 变得更加精简”，他表示此举对整个行业有利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扎克伯格宣布在马斯克在 Twitter 上裁员几个月后，他的公司裁员了数千人。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; 风格=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russian court rejects Wall Street Journal reporter Gershkovich’s appeal against pre-trial detention]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225041/russian-court-rejects-wall-street-journal-reporter-gershkovichs-appeal-against-pre-trial-detention?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 18:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/d657c1a1-520e-41e0-918a-edfedff43b29_43313fc9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周四，美国记者埃文·格什科维奇 (Evan Gershkovich) 对其提出的新上诉被莫斯科法院驳回。法庭上的路透社记者称，他因间谍罪被审前拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华尔街日报》记者否认间谍指控，如果罪名成立，他可能会被判处最高 20 年监禁.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的父母米哈伊尔·格什科维奇 (Mikhail Gershkovich) 和埃拉·米尔曼 (Ella Milman) 于 1979 年离开苏联前往美国，在法庭上支持他们的儿子。美国大使林恩·特雷西 (Lynne Tracy) 不得进入房间。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯以间谍罪逮捕《华尔街日报》记者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;格什科维奇 (Gershkovich) 穿着蓝色牛仔裤和黑色 T 恤，站在玻璃盒子里并对在诉讼开始前短暂获准拍摄他的记者微笑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名 31 岁的男子于 3 月份被捕，并被俄罗斯联邦安全局安全部门指控在乌拉尔市收集军事机密叶卡捷琳堡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的报纸强烈否认对格什科维奇的指控，格什科维奇得到了俄罗斯外交部的认可。美国称他被错误拘留，并要求释放他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格什科维奇正在对他在审判前继续被关押在莫斯科莱福尔托沃监狱提出上诉，审判日期尚未确定。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;《华尔街日报》主编艾玛·塔克 (Emma Tucker) 在听证会前告诉 BBC，她对上诉的期望不高，但走完法律程序很重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，一家法院拒绝了格什科维奇的律师提出的将他转移到软禁、同意限制其行动或获得保释的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格什科维奇被关押时正值华盛顿和莫斯科之间的关系处于最低点去年，俄罗斯向乌克兰派遣了数万名士兵，进行所谓的“特别军事行动”，这是自冷战以来的这一点。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Rich women’s dragon boat team’ from wealthy Chinese village rows against male tide in unique ‘phoenix boat’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3224732/rich-womens-dragon-boat-team-wealthy-chinese-village-rows-against-male-tide-unique-phoenix-boat?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/3ec6061f-170e-4457-bd4c-aaedaa03b003_aba004b5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一群中国富裕妇女组成了龙舟赛在这项长期以来属于男性专属的运动中，龙舟队已成为内地女权主义的励志象征。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自广州的这支被称为“富家女子龙舟队”的赛艇队，在据当地媒体《羊城晚报》周六报道，中国南部广东省有 50 名女性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她们都来自珠江新城中央商务区附近的城中村猎德。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;这支队伍的起源可以追溯到2007年，当时珠江新城开始拆除旧房，为新房让路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为补偿，据报道每户都获得了一份新房产面积达 600 平方米（6,458 平方英尺）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据房地产经纪服务公司链家称，该地区的平均房价目前高达 20 万元（28,000 美元）每平方米。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在本月一年一度的端午节来临之际，女子赛艇队开始变得兴奋起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不久之后，有关该队的谣言和笑话就开始流传开来。网上流传：“只有有钱的女人才能加入队”、“人们应该为赛艇运动员加油，如果他们赢了，租金就会减少”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位负责人村里宣传的陈姓负责人承认，队员们现在都拥有价值数千万元的房产，但强调“会游泳”是加入队伍的唯一要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈说，村里的妇女报名加入这个团队，是为了通过团队合作增进睦邻友好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名姓梁的团队成员告诉九拍新闻，她是在团队成立时加入的。 1998年成立了全省第一支女子龙舟队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梁说，她这样做是为了实现儿时参加龙舟比赛的梦想，而直到最近，龙舟比赛只允许男子参赛。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;然而，他们的船的设计并不像传统的男性使用的龙舟，而是专为女性设计的所谓“凤船”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国文化中，龙被视为男性象征和女性凤凰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年6月，佛山附近的一名看似游客的女子因登上男子龙舟而被一名男子辱骂后遭到网络欺凌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;一些人，包括几位民俗文化专家，坚持长期以来禁止女性使用龙舟的观念——广东女子龙舟队教练赵婷强烈反对这种态度。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“我们不再生活在一个重男轻女的时代。为什么女性不能参加赛龙舟？”她问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项运动在中国南方有着悠久的历史，可以追溯到大约 2,500 年前。这些木船形状像龙，可以由几十到一百多名划船者提供动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该活动被认为起源于崇拜主宰地球水域的龙神的习俗&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一种信仰认为，人们赛龙舟象征性地营救公元前 278 年在河中溺水身亡的爱国诗人屈原。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;龙据华侨大学体育学院副教授隋文杰介绍，赛艇运动现已风靡60多个国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自1995年起，每隔一年举办一次世界龙舟锦标赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Long overdue’: South Korea revises law to make it easier to punish stalkers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3225039/long-overdue-south-korea-revises-law-make-it-easier-punish-stalkers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 18:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/22/c8b71e1d-1f7f-47ae-9feb-b3583c9c57f8_cf0b37dd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在韩国，无论受害者是否同意，跟踪者现在都将面临刑事处罚。对本周在国民议会全体会议上通过的所谓反跟踪法的修改。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案于周三获得全体出席会议的 246 名议员一致通过，这是罕见的&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国国会通过旨在加强对跟踪犯罪的惩罚力度的修订法案，决定废除一项有争议的条款，该条款规定，如果受害者不同意惩罚，跟踪者就不能被追究刑事责任.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国因首尔站报复性谋杀女性被判40年监禁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2021年立法的初步法律规定，缠扰者只有在获得受害者许可后才能受到惩罚。它因未能解决跟踪犯罪的核心性质而受到民间团体的强烈批评。由于担心遭到报复，跟踪的受害者往往会放弃寻求对肇事者的惩罚。因此，许多肇事者在与受害者达成和解后，避免了刑事处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妇女权利组织表示，修订“早就该”了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是应该的几年前就完成了。 We had expressed grave concerns on the matter since the legislation of the initial anti-stalking law and repeatedly called on the government to eliminate the unreasonable clause,” said Song Ran-hee, head of the Korea Women&#39;s Hotline. “It&#39;s hard to welcome their belated move.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She lamented that many stalking crimes – including the murders of victims – could have been prevented if the government had introduced proper laws and preventive measures in the first place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eliminating the controversial clause of the anti-stalking law was a campaign pledge made by President Yoon Suk-yeol, who vowed to get tough on crimes against women. But after taking office in May last year, his administration had not swiftly taken steps to carry out the promise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Discussions on strengthening the anti-stalking law finally gained momentum in September last year following the brutal murder of a female subway employee by a former co-worker in a restroom at Sindang subway station in Seoul.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The offender, Jeon Joo-hwan, who had been stalking and threatening the victim for more than two years, committed the murder just one day before he was to be sentenced on stalking charges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Public anger mounted against law enforcement officials and the legal system for failing to prevent the crime despite the fact the Jeon had shown typical signs of a violent stalker, sparking calls for legal reforms and stronger punishments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Against this backdrop, the Ministry of Justice announced in October plans to revise the anti-stalking law, which was eventually put to vote at Wednesday&#39;s plenary session.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I believe that the revision encompasses most of what can be considered in order to protect victims [of stalking],” Justice Minister Han Dong-hoon said during an Assembly session on Tuesday, vowing to swiftly enforce the measures once the revision received the green light.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This article was first published on .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[With 89 new video game licenses in June, and one for NetEase, China’s approved titles this year surpass 2022’s total]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/article/3225001/89-new-video-game-licenses-june-and-one-netease-chinas-approved-titles-year-surpass-2022s-total?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 17:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/22/a129f155-c652-4edf-8bd1-fdaf6879ab13_508fd89d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese regulators have approved 89 new video games for sale in China for June, covering titles from major players – including Youzu Interactive and NetEase – as the world&#39;s largest gaming market maintains momentum with new licenses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The National Press and Publication Administration (NPPA), the agency responsible for licensing video games in China, published its latest list of approvals on Wednesday. It was the largest batch this year, by a single title. The numbers have been closely watched since an eight-month licensing freeze ended in April 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tencent Holdings, operator of the world&#39;s largest video gaming business by revenue, was absent from the list this month. The company received one new license last month after a string of approvals earlier this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, China&#39;s second-largest video gaming company made the cut again this month, with NetEase&#39;s Yanyun Sixteen Sounds getting a license for mobile and personal computers. The Hangzhou-based company had a strong start to the year, with first-quarter net profits surging 53.7 per cent year on year to 6.8 billion yuan (US$983.6 million).&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Tencent unveils over 30 video game updates, new titles amid market turnaround&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Another title in the latest batch was Crimson Echo, a mobile game by Shanghai-based Youzu Interactive, also known as Yoozoo. A computer game called Island and Factory, from Shenzhen Zhongqingbao Interactive Network, was the only game approved that was not accessible on mobile.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest batch of games is in line with the steady pace of approvals this year. More than 85 games have been approved each month in 2023, rising from just a few dozen right after the NPPA resumed the monthly publication of the license list last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The crackdown in 2021 that froze approvals and limited minors to playing for just one hour a day, three days a week, caused widespread concern about the state of China&#39;s gaming industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The NPPA has approved over 500 domestic games so far in 2023, compared with 466 domestic approvals for all of 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In December, it approved 87 domestic titles and 44 that were imported. By comparison, the NPPA has approved just 27 imported games this year so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Beijing has tightened its grip on online content in recent years, it has become more difficult for foreign games to get approval for monetisation in the mainland. All imported games must be “localised” with the help of a Chinese company and vetted by censors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mobile platforms have long been the dominant form of gaming in China, where titles like Tencent&#39;s Honour of Kings and Peacekeeper Elite, the local version of PUBG Mobile, dominate the market in terms of revenue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese developers now account for 47 per cent of global mobile game revenue, according to a report this month from market intelligence firm Niko Partners.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Regulator approves 86 video games in China in May, including Ace Force 2&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While Tencent and NetEase remained the dominant players in 2022, accounting for more than 60 per cent of PC and mobile game revenue, their combined market share decreased from 2021 owing to weak performance from legacy titles and a lack of new launches, leaving smaller competitors to gain ground, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of last year, China had just over 700 million gamers across all platforms, which is expected to increase to 730 million by 2027, Niko Partners said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Xinmei Shen&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[With China in mind, Biden and Modi to seal deals from space to chips, 5G to critical minerals]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3225033/china-mind-biden-and-modi-seal-deals-space-chips-5g-critical-minerals?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 17:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/22/3a4a6d67-1ca1-479b-a791-cc9489676715_cbd45fef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden and Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Thursday will announce a slew of cooperation agreements spanning from space to semiconductors, critical minerals to core technologies, telecommunications and defence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden is hosting Modi at the White House for a state visit, only the third such visit for his administration since taking office in January 2021. They will hold bilateral talks on Thursday afternoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Known for avoiding impromptu media interactions, Modi will hold a joint press briefing with Biden to share the outcomes of the meeting. It will be followed by Modi&#39;s address to a joint session of US Congress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to senior Biden administration officials, the two leaders will announce key collaborations under the umbrella of the US-India Critical and Emerging Technology (iCET) initiative, which was launched in May last year to deepen cooperation in artificial intelligence, quantum computing, semiconductors and wireless telecommunication.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;American chip maker Micron Technology will set up a US$2.75 billion semiconductor assembly and test facility in India. On Wednesday, Micron&#39;s Indian-American CEO Sanjay Mehrotra also met Modi to discuss the plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, Applied Materials, an American manufacturing company that offers equipment, services and software to chip makers, will open a commercialisation and innovation centre in India. Lam Research, another US-based semiconductor company, will train 60,000 Indian engineers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The developments come against the backdrop of a fierce competition between Beijing and Washington for supremacy in advanced semiconductor technology. Last month, Micron was blocked from key infrastructure projects by Beijing in an apparent retaliation to Biden&#39;s ban on the export of cutting-edge semiconductor technology to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But diversification of semiconductor supply chains is not the only area of concern for the Biden administration as it is also looking to reduce reliance on China for critical minerals used in batteries that power electric vehicles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this regard, Washington will support New Delhi&#39;s membership to the US-led mineral security partnership aimed at strengthening critical minerals supply chains. Other members of the grouping are Australia, Canada, Finland, France, Germany, Japan, South Korea, Sweden, the United Kingdom and the European Commission.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Partnerships on advanced telecommunications are also on the cards when Biden and Modi talk business. According to senior Biden administration officials, both sides have agreed to work together on 5G and 6G technologies. India will also participate in the US “rip and replace” programme that removes telecoms equipment made by untrusted vendors&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November, the US banned the sale and import of new communications equipment from five Chinese companies, including telecoms giant Huawei Technologies, on national security concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A senior Biden administration official on Wednesday said there was “no partner more consequential now and into the future than India” when thinking about the future of AI, computing, building resilient supply chains for clean energy technologies, semiconductors and other critical and emerging technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lifting the new-found bilateral trust to cosmic levels, US and Indian space agencies will be developing the strategic framework for human space flight cooperation this year. Both sides have also agreed to a joint mission to the International Space Station in 2024. New Delhi will also join the Artemis Accords, a US-led effort to return humans to the moon by 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Biden-Modi bilateral talks will also herald the two countries&#39; entry into what a Biden administration official described as the “next generation of defence partnership”, including a proposal by the US&#39; General Electric to jointly produce F414 jet engines with India&#39;s Hindustan Aeronautics. This marks a greater transfer of American jet engine technology to a non-treaty ally than ever before. India will also be buying 31 MQ-9B drones worth US$3 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, the India-US Defence Acceleration Ecosystem, also called Indus X, was launched to facilitate joint innovation on defence technologies, and accelerate the integration of India&#39;s fledgling private sector defence industry with the US industrial complex.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A senior Biden administration official said that India&#39;s emergence as a great power would be “central to ensuring US interests and the interests of our partners in the coming decades”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another key agreement is expected in allowing US Navy ships operating across theatres to service and undergo major repairs in Indian shipyards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India, along with Australia and Japan, is a member of the US-led Quadrilateral Security Dialogue aimed at countering China in the Indo-Pacific region. The grouping is largely seen by Beijing as anti-China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday, just hours before Modi landed in Washington, Biden claimed he had told Chinese President Xi Jinping that the Quad was aimed at ensuring that “international air and sea lines remain open”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So now we have India, Australia, Japan and the United States working hand in glove in the South China Sea,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;No fantasies&#39; as China slams &#39;ridiculous&#39; Biden comments on Xi: analysts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing claims large swathes of the South China Sea in a dispute with the Philippines, a mutual defence treaty ally of the US. While Washington does not have any territorial claims in the region, it asserts the right to innocent passage under the freedom of navigation. Beijing says US actions violate international law due to the use of military ships and aircraft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India after long maintaining a neutral stance has made a tilt towards Washington on the issue. Locked in a historical dispute over a land border with Beijing, New Delhi in 2020 called the South China Sea a “part of global commons”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A senior Biden administration official on Wednesday said India&#39;s “growing commitment to playing a more engaged international role, including in the Indo-Pacific Quad, demonstrates a new and growing willingness” to join Washington in “protecting and advancing a shared vision of a free, open and rule-based global order as a strong maritime democracy”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, some in Washington have accused Biden of becoming blinded by the great power rivalry and rolling out a red carpet for Modi – a man who was once denied a US visa for violent riots that largely targeted India&#39;s Muslim minority under his watch in 2002.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Human rights groups have also raised concerns regarding democratic backsliding and suppression of political opposition and a free press under Modi in India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Biden administration official on Wednesday said Biden shared a close relationship with Modi and would not shy away from holding conversations on religious discrimination, treatment of minorities and press freedoms.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Finland’s Ulko-Tammio wants to become a ‘phone-free island’, asks travellers to switch off smart devices]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225026/finlands-ulko-tammio-wants-become-phone-free-island-asks-travellers-switch-smart-devices?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.22 17:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/22/539b9d7f-fb87-42e5-9092-0f2952659901_d4ceb4a3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Administrators at most destinations yearn to have them go viral on TikTok, or dream of attracting droves of Netflix Inc. viewers, despite the risk of overwhelming communities. A small island off the southeastern coast of Finland is taking the opposite approach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tourism officials for Ulko-Tammio, one of several islands inside Eastern Gulf of Finland National Park, say they want it to be a “phone-free island” and are urging visitors to “switch off their smart devices and to stop and genuinely enjoy the islands,” said Mats Selin, an expert with Visit Kotka-Hamina, in a release.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sentiment is echoed by Parks &amp; Wildlife Finland, which manages the island&#39;s pristine environment and wildlife. “We encourage visitors to put their phones away voluntarily and to focus their senses on nature rather than on their phones,” said outdoor recreation and visitor manager Joel Heino, in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;From status symbol to disrupter: charting China&#39;s mobile phone boom&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On the travel side, booking a digital-free holiday in a tropical locale is a growing trend that even corporate executives are resorting to, and digital detox retreat options have long existed for those choosing to pull their noses out of phones on trips. But it&#39;s not the norm for an industry that relies on influencers and breathtaking visuals on social media to attract visitors or convey a sense of place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some 63 per cent of millennials and younger travellers say they&#39;ve used at least one social media platform to plan trips in the past 12 months, according to the June 2023 sentiment survey of American travellers from Destination Analysts. Besides, does your holiday really happen if you don&#39;t post about all the fun you&#39;re having there?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Attempts to get consumers to ditch their phones have increased over the years, particularly in the entertainment business.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Electronic dance music artist Lane 8 is famous for his phone-free concerts, and it&#39;s brought bigger crowds for his live shows. Dave Chappelle and Alicia Keys were among the earliest adopters to ban phones at performances through use of the Yondr pouch, dating back to 2015: Pop your iPhone in a grey and lime-green pouch that seals as soon as you close it; you can carry it around, but you won&#39;t be able to snap it open until you reach an unlocking station as you exit the event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;San Francisco-based Yondr&#39;s locking phone cases are now used in select courthouses, theatres, restaurants and schools in the US that are looking to limit the use of devices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January 2023, Thermae Bath Spa, located in historic Bath, England, announced it was becoming a mobile-free zone and would partner with Yondr. The public thermal day spa noted in a release that phones were “a regular source of annoyance” to guests, as well as “a problem for our staff who have to recover dropped phones from the bottom of pools.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yondr&#39;s last public data release cited an estimated 1 million customers using its pouches in March 2022; the company said it was unable to share more recent data with Bloomberg. Questions as to whether the pouch&#39;s effectiveness arose after it was used for the Broadway show Take Me out, and leaked footage and images of a naked Jesse Williams on stage nonetheless appeared on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There will be no Yondr pouches on Finland&#39;s Ulko-Tammio island. But amid growing proof that social media is addictive and can impair mental health, perhaps more travellers are ready to ditch their phones in the great outdoors. It&#39;s nice to think that a nudge will suffice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If not, you can use a digital camera to get great photos, though you won&#39;t be able to post them while on the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Man in China makes US$1,500 a day retrieving phones lost in lake as tourism booms&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“There is no need to ban art,” said Annika Ruohonen, Visit Kotka-Hamina&#39;s content creation manager, via email.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ulko-Tammio can be reached by private boat year-round, weather permitting, and by boat taxi or small ship cruise during the summer months from Kotka, an hour and a half&#39;s drive east from Helsinki. Boat taxis are also available from Hamina, which lies an additional 20 minutes east of Kotka.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You would then simply stay off your phone while experiencing Ulko-Tammio&#39;s isolated scenic water views – with rugged cliffs and arctic bird species – from the observation tower. Then you could tour the island&#39;s historic fortress and caves, used in two battles with the Soviet Union during World War II, and rock carvings that date back to the 19th century.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Posting any shots or video of you standing just 6 miles (10 kilometres) from the Russian border would have to wait till you get back to your hotel.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 22 Jun 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>