<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Guizhou offers Hong Kong lessons in building bridges and tackling poverty]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230296/guizhou-offers-hong-kong-lessons-building-bridges-and-tackling-poverty?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/68ea4cca-bf91-489c-965c-1062972369b1_a09a310d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在香港，贫困人口的数量和贫富差距的大小似乎近年来有所恶化。在这座城市应对贫困挑战的过程中，也许我们可以向贵州学习，这个曾经的贫困省份如今已经变成了一个充满希望和信心的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;归根结底，就是利用该地区独特的优势&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在我们最近到贵州推广心理健康教育期间，我们对一个地区的转变感到震惊曾经以“三尺无平地”而闻名的中国西南重要的交通和地理枢纽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关键组成部分？桥梁。中国悠久的桥梁建设历史证明了此类建筑如何能够改善城市化、经济发展、生产力甚至社会关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贵州坐落在西南部山区，是中国变革力量的象征。桥梁。曾经看似不可能的地形已被掌握，桥梁成为连接整个地区的脉络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1979年至2020年，贵州的公路网快速发展，培育了许多新桥梁。特别值得一提的是2009年建成的巴陵河大桥。这座悬索桥不仅在尺寸和复杂性上取得了突破，而且还促进了贵州的交通、贸易乃至体育活动——桥上提供蹦极、跳伞、滑翔伞和其他极限活动.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，贵州已成为被誉为世界“桥梁博物馆”的贵州。贵州拥有28,000多座公路桥梁，被认为拥有世界最高100座桥梁中的近一半，其中包括前10名中的四座。贵州共有15座桥梁获得了25项国家和国际奖项。这些工程壮举获得国际赞誉，标志着贵州在世界地图上的地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有趣的是，这些桥梁的功能也发生了演变。它们从仅仅作为交通便利设施，现在也是经济发展的催化剂，带来了贸易和旅游业，同时也鼓励了环境保护和生态欣赏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;重要的是，这些桥梁使贵州成为陆路交通枢纽，凸显其在连接“一带一路”倡议中中国西部陆海走廊的独特区位作用，并有可能与成渝地区双城经济圈形成更大的经济区域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些改善的交通联系减少了贵州省的经济发展，国内生产总值已跃居地区前列。贵州今年上半年的 GDP 已超过 1 万亿元人民币（1,400 亿美元），使西藏或甘肃等同样贫困的地区相形见绌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些桥梁同时也是旅游胜地，提供了独特的机会打造“桥梁”旅游。例如，巴岭河大桥自2019年以来已吸引了约5万名游客，极大地促进了当地经济的发展。桥梁旅游、体育旅游和文化旅游的融合也带动了当地民宿、露营和当地农产品销售的业务，产生了可观的收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贵州在实现经济多元化的同时，还涉足高科技领域，贵州致力于包容性增长，推出了茅台酒，展现出强大的市场竞争力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去十年，贵州923万人摆脱了贫困。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果贵州继续深化改革，创造良好的发展环境，它可以利用自身的优势改善交通，吸引更多资源、人力和资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贵州生活成本低廉，风景优美，夏季气候宜人，为香港和其他地区提供了如何在推动经济发展的同时不忽视的经验教训。弱势群体，与联合国“不让任何人掉队”的可持续发展目标相呼应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在是香港搭建桥梁，成为通往世界的超级联系人的时候了。我们需要努力保持和加强我们对中国内地和国际社会的独特贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港如何发挥超级联系人的作用&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;我们的大学一直在在研究和知识交流方面做得很好。我们还需要重新联系社区中的人们，甚至是那些持不同观点的人们，让人们有机会并对未来充满信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于年轻人，我们需要对他们进行投资，以提高他们的社会流动性。我们需要投资基础设施以改善工人的流动性。政府与社会之间的“桥梁”需要重建，以增进信任和理解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府执行这些政策的能力对于我们的成功至关重要。贵州提供了通过建设桥梁实现转型的绝佳范例。同样，在香港，我们可以通过搭建桥梁来重建自己。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Afghan women, ‘gradually dying’ as Taliban shuts off more jobs, retrain as nurses]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3230409/afghan-women-gradually-dying-taliban-shuts-more-jobs-retrain-nurses?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/965880bf-1a21-4ad3-8aaa-08960bfd2db8_6d1dae85.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在阿富汗大学任教十年后，前经济学家 Shabana Sediqian 即将接受再培训作为一名护士——这不是她设想的职业转变，但至少可以让她再次走出家门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越来越多的职业女性正在报名参加护理和助产课程，自从两年前塔利班夺取政权以来，她们已经厌倦了被困在家里，而且在失业后急需钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sediqian 表示，护理几乎是生活在“贫困线”下的女性唯一仍然可以从事的职业。 “软禁”，因为该国的强硬伊斯兰领导人对他们的自由施加了越来越严厉的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是我可以在经济上帮助我的家人，并帮助自己找到工作并走出家门的唯一方法几个小时，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;30 岁的 Nilab Azizi 是三个孩子的母亲，曾为一个国际援助项目工作，她迫切希望重新回到以前的职业生活，并期待着9 月份开始为期三年的护理课程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一年多以来，我一直试图重返工作岗位，但塔利班对女性关闭了所有大门，”她说。 “呆在家里无所事事就像逐渐死去。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塔利班政府禁止女孩进入高中、大学和大多数工作，包括为联合国和非政府组织 (NGO) 工作。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;但是，该禁令并不适用于医疗专业人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汤森路透基金会采访了全国各地的 10 名护士和实习生，他们表示，他们要么已经转行，要么有朋友和同事已经这样做了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北部城市马扎里沙里夫一家与卫生部合作的私人医疗机构首席执行官 Khaled Ferdous 表示，参加该机构课程的护理和助产专业学生人数超过了自 2021 年中期以来，这一数字增加了一倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，几乎 90% 的人来自不相关的专业背景。他们包括前公务员、教师、记者和大学本科生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，由于女孩被禁止接受中等教育，援助机构担心，学习助产和护理的申请将在未来几年枯竭，这会对她们产生可​​怕的影响。阿富汗未来的医疗保健。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卫生部没有回复置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管做出了承诺，阿富汗妇女和女孩仍然被困&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;塔利班于 2021 年 8 月 15 日掌权时，36 岁的塞迪琴是西部城市赫拉特一所私立大学的经济系主任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二天，她的照片出现在教职员板上被白了。几周后，她的职位由一名男子填补。从那时起，她就成了一名家庭主妇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济拮据和困在家里的挫败感促使她从九月份开始参加护理课程。她的一个姐妹在不得不放弃大学文学学位后，已经开始接受助产士培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每天都在经济上和情感上挣扎，”过去每月收入 400 美元的 Sediqian 说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位三个孩子的母亲作为一名护士预计每月收入约 150 美元，并希望攒钱送女儿们出国留学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sediqian 说她对此感到愤怒她所有的知识和专业知识都被抛弃了，但计划在新的职业中利用她的领导技能来赋予其他护士权力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于阿齐兹来说，护理更适合她之前在马扎尔教育家庭的工作-与 i-Sharif 和周边村庄讨论医疗保健问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿富汗是世界上孕产妇和婴儿死亡率最高的国家之一，在怀孕或分娩期间每两小时就有一名妇女死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿齐兹希望护理职业将帮助她继续提高人们对母乳喂养、儿童营养和童婚危险的认识——童婚在阿富汗呈上升趋势，并增加了出生并发症和孕产妇死亡的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;塔利班的对妇女的镇压升级，而世界却视而不见：报告&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;阿富汗的经济危机和塔利班接管后国际发展援助的撤回使负担过重的卫生部门难以维持生计。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;国际捐助者继续为基本卫生服务提供资金，但仍存在重大缺口 — — 特别是在农村地区 — — 并且许多卫生专业人员因更广泛的人才外流而离开该国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿富汗根据官方数据，约有 4,400 个医疗机构，大部分由国家或国际非政府组织运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但许多诊所缺乏熟练的工作人员、设备和药品。农村地区的一些机构几乎无法运转。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，随着贫困加剧，营养不良加剧，需要治疗的人数有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shaqayque Barakzai，19 岁，赫拉特的一名老学生护士说，她的工作让她感到“在这个女性的黑暗时代，她被赋予了权力和价值”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她曾想成为一名室内设计师，但在塔利班禁止女孩进入高等院校后，她选择了护理工作教育。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，她担心找工作。当她 2021 年开始课程时，有 50 名学生，但她说最新的入学人数是这个数字的两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我最担心的是，当我们明年毕业时，将没有足够的工作机会一切，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴拉克扎伊说，虽然非常基本的农村诊所有空缺，但塔利班不允许妇女单独出行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;援助机构称，女性卫生工作者面临着特殊的挑战，包括在检查站对他们的着装、工作或缺乏监护人（监护人的男性亲属）进行严厉审问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有些人甚至因为没有监护人而被从工作场所送回家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;一位人道主义专家描述了一位带着年幼婴儿的卫生工作者如何被一名公交车司机留在路边，距离她位于农村地区的家有几英里远，因为她没有亲属。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;之后搬到新工作后，她的丈夫不得不辞掉工作，因为除非他和她在一起，否则她不可以上夜班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;监护人的要求也增加了农村地区流动医疗队的成本。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个非政府组织表示，最初每个团队派出一名陪同人员，但当局越来越多地要求每位女性配备一名监护人，这使得每次旅行的费用每天增加约 40 美元，并可能使总费用增加约 7,000 美元&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管面临挑战，联合国儿童基金会与当地非政府组织一起帮助管理该国约 60% 的卫生服务，表示在其支付工资的 27,000 名员工中，女性占到了 10,000 人，略高于 18 名。几个月前。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;塔利班让所有阿富汗人的生活变得更糟。现在，外国援助正在枯竭&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;支持全国其他医院和诊所的全球医疗慈善机构无国界医生组织 (MSF) 表示，其 900 名医务人员（即一半以上）是女性。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该慈善机构为全国各地的其他医院和诊所提供支持。 p>;&lt;p>;但是无国界医生驻阿富汗代表菲利佩·里贝罗 (Filipe Ribeiro) 对未来的人员配置表示严重担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塔利班接管时即将获得资格的女实习医生被禁止参加期末考试，女医生被禁止参加专业研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管护理和助产学校仍然开放，但里贝罗表示，禁止女子高中教育意味着她们很快将很难找到学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“谁将成为明天的助产士？”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很高兴知道一些女性现在正在尝试接受护士培训，但从中长期来看，这将是一场灾难。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore jails man 2 years for using Instagram to ask primary school pupils for sexual favours]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3230419/singapore-jails-man-2-years-using-instagram-ask-primary-school-pupils-sexual-favours?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/7890b057-eeb4-49d6-9439-b775d3192cd2_f9a273ff.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二，一名 33 岁的男子因接近而被判处两年监禁苏莱曼·侯赛因 (Sulaiman Hussain) 早些时候承认了两项对 16 岁以下未成年人进行性诱骗的指控。年龄，以及一项导致儿童或青少年犯罪的指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;量刑时还考虑了其​​他三项指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年或之前的某个时候，Sulaiman 开始与他在社交媒体平台上偶然遇到的女性资料聊天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭文件称，他会专门接近青少年，希望他们更加“友好”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;知道他们不会招待如果他透露自己的真实年龄，苏莱曼告诉他们他20多岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为了儿子的教育而在新加坡逾期居留的中国妈妈：“这是值得的”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;10月30日， 2021年，苏莱曼在Instagram上添加了第一位受害者——一名11岁的女孩为好友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他开始与她进行性对话，询问她“kkj”是什么意思”，是否喜欢，是否想对他进行口交。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对此，受害者说这意味着“阴茎”，而她只有11岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，苏莱曼表示他并不在意，“只是为了体验”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谈话中，女孩提到了她的两个朋友，当苏莱曼给他看了一张他们的照片后，他叫了其中一个朋友。她的朋友们“又热又性感”，并说他想与对方发生性关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他在 Instagram 上将他们俩添加为好友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 11 月 1 日，苏莱曼要求受害者在她的小学附近与他见面，并对他进行口交。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭文件称，他也打算发生性行为，因为他感到“饥渴”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，由于女孩放学晚了，会议没有举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苏莱曼毫不留情地在晚上晚些时候再次给她发消息，安排会面，并发送了一张自己的露骨照片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当她拒绝与他进行视频通话的请求时，苏莱曼称她“无聊”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在女孩的一位朋友告诉女孩的老师苏莱曼发送的消息后，他后来被捕.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 8 月 31 日，Sulaiman 在 Instagram 上添加了他的第二个受害者——一名 10 岁的女孩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 9 月的某个时候，他开始了一个不适当的行为与她交谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Instagram 上看到女孩手上沾有胶水的视频后，他告诉她应该触摸他的“叮咚”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当她问时他明白他的意思，他说他想和她发生性关系。随后，他继续向她提出性要求，例如发送自己的露骨照片，但她没有答应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，她最终在一个月后发送了一张自己的裸照，以便他停止发送信息。法庭文件称，同月，苏莱曼试图给她视频通话，她接受了，因为她“很好奇他长什么样”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他们手淫了应苏莱曼的要求，他们在视频通话中进行了大约五分钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 11 月 1 日，苏莱曼安排第二天在女孩所在的小学附近与她见面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，她没有出现。然后，他要求女孩发送一张自己的裸照，作为让他等待的道歉，女孩答应了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭文件没有说明第二名受害者何时报告此事。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;世界前7名最强大的海军中有5个在亚洲。新加坡排名第24位&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;副检察官谭志浩寻求判处24至30个月监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，苏莱曼是一名性掠夺者，利用了两个人的性好奇心年轻的小学生，以满足自己不正常的性欲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DPP Tan 补充说，苏莱曼在调查过程中被发现患有恋童癖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对 14 岁以下的受害者进行性诱骗，苏莱曼可能会被判处最高四年监禁、罚款，或两者并罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些因儿童犯罪而被判有罪的人，最高可被罚款 2,000 新元（1,500 美元），最高可被监禁一年，或两者兼而有之。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tory Lanez gets 10 years in prison for shooting Megan Thee Stallion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230446/tory-lanez-gets-10-years-prison-shooting-megan-thee-stallion?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 07:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/09/8546c7ea-3fa2-47be-8842-dceb034038e8_01aa31d5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国法官周二因枪击案判处说唱歌手 Tory Lanez 10 年监禁洛杉矶高等法院法官大卫·赫里福德 (David Herriford) 对 31 岁的拉内兹 (Lanez) 作出了判决，他于 12 月被判犯有三项重罪： -自动枪械；车内持有已上膛、未注册的枪支，并因严重疏忽而开枪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一判决结束了一场戏剧性的审判，这场审判在嘻哈界掀起了一场文化风暴，引发了包括黑人受害者不愿与警察交谈、嘻哈中的性别政治、网络毒性、保护黑人女性以及厌女症的后果，厌女症是厌女症黑人女性的一种特殊经历。赫里福德表示，这“很困难”许多人形容拉内兹在量刑听证会上与向梅根开枪的人“和解”，“善良、慈善的人和好父亲”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有时好人也会做坏事，”赫里福德说。 “行动是有后果的，在这起案件中没有赢家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅根作证说，拉内兹向她的脚后开枪，并在她走下一辆SUV时大喊让她跳舞。他们于 2020 年 7 月在凯莉·詹纳 (Kylie Jenner) 位于好莱坞山的家中参加泳池派对后骑行。她必须接受手术以取出子弹碎片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“自从我被被告恶意开枪以来，我没有经历过一天的平静，”梅根在检察官周一宣读的一份声明中说。 “慢慢地，但可以肯定的是，我正在康复并康复，但我永远不会像以前一样了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在法官宣判之前，拉内兹向赫里福德求饶。 Lanez 请求缓刑或判处最低刑期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;BTS 和 Megan Thee Stallion 合作制作新的 Butter remix&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“如果我能扭转那天晚上发生的一系列事件并改变它们，”我会的，拉内兹继续说道。 “受害者是我的朋友。受害者是我至今仍然关心的人。”他补充道：“那天晚上我做错的一切，我承担全部责任。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉内兹在宣读判决时显得很震惊，但没有任何反应。宣判后，他的家人和法庭上的粉丝也保持安静。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宣判前，拉内兹的父亲桑斯塔尔·彼得森 (Sonstar Peterson) 强忍着泪水，谈到这位说唱歌手的母亲在他 11 岁时去世的事，当时他才出生几天。在她第一次表现出可能导致她死亡的罕见血液疾病的症状后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为没有人能克服这一点，”他谈到他们最小的孩子，他的法定名字是Daystar Peterson 。 “但他的音乐成为了他的出路。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lanez 于 2009 年开始发行混音带，人气稳步上升，并转向各大唱片公司的专辑。他的最后两张专辑都进入了 Billboard 排行榜前 10 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅根·西·斯塔林 (Megan Thee Stallion) 现年 28 岁，在枪击事件发生时已经是一颗冉冉升起的新星，此后她的声望不断飙升。原名梅根·皮特 (Megan Pete)，她赢得了 2021 年格莱美最佳新人奖，并凭借与碧昂丝 (Beyoncé) 合作的《Savage》获得单曲第一名，并作为嘉宾出演了卡迪·B (Cardi B) 的《WAP》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老彼得森作为一名基督教牧师，他是对拉内兹的品格和慈善捐赠发表声明的几位人士之一，拉内兹小儿子的母亲也是如此，她在法庭上谈到了拉内兹作为父亲的品质。还有数十人写信给赫里福德，其中包括说唱歌手伊基·阿塞莉亚 (Iggy Azalea)，她请求法官做出“具有变革性的判决，而不是毁灭性的判决”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赫里福德说，拉内兹大约六岁的儿子，还送来了一封手写信，但法官没有进一步描述。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;谁杀了图帕克·沙库尔？拉斯维加斯警方发出搜查令&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;拉内兹的家人和支持者挤满了法庭；在审判期间，他们声称对他的起诉是由梅根和音乐界有权势的人物发起的。 12月宣读判决后，拉内兹的父亲谴责了导致他儿子被定罪的“邪恶制度”；周一，桑斯塔尔·彼得森 (Sonstar Peterson) 就自己的言论向赫里福德 (Herriford) 道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉内兹 (Lanez) 被定罪后已入狱。洛杉矶县监狱的一名牧师周一在法庭上表示，拉内兹领导了每日祈祷小组，这缓解了他被关押的保护性拘留所的紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赫里福德拒绝了拉内兹辩护律师提出的请求5 月 9 日进行新的审判。定罪后立即提出此类动议很常见，但很少成功。拉内兹的律师辩称，没有足够的证据对他定罪，而且向陪审员提交的一些证据不应该被允许。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;律师们对梅根的证词进行了辩解，即拉内兹敦促她不要去警察局，因为他正在假释，将会陷入严重的麻烦，这既是不真实的，也是对之前不良行为的不适当的宽容。他们表示，检察官用来证明拉内兹可能是枪手的 DNA 证据远远低于行业标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉内兹的律师计划对定罪提出上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赫里福德早些时候发现周一，梅根被枪杀时是一个特别脆弱的受害者，但拉内兹向她开枪时并没有特别残忍或冷酷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她的身体上有永久性的伤疤，”副地区检察官亚历山大·博特 (Alexander Bott) 表示。法庭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她的余生肯定会受到情感创伤。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China has a 31-point plan for private sector to kick-start economy. But are bruised business owners buying it?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3229706/china-has-31-point-plan-private-sector-kick-start-economy-are-bruised-business-owners-buying-it?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/52c727dc-e1b5-4f03-837a-7c125a8be130_f2cc1a7e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京发布“促进民营经济发展31条意见” ” 上个月，几位顶级企业家（大多是中国最高政治机构的现任或前任成员）通过官方媒体纷纷对此举表示赞赏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项内容广泛的计划表明最高领导层“关心”私营企业他们异口同声地说，他们对经济充满信心，并声称他们对私营部门的未来充满“信心”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前还不清楚他们是否发自内心地说。作为中国政治体系的成员，他们必须遵守官方路线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论如何，他们确实传达了北京方面的明确信息。随着经济失去动力，在中国与以美国为首的西方国家之间的紧张关系日益加剧之际，政府依靠私营部门来引领疫情后的复苏，并支撑就业和技术创新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我们将全力以赴，遵循指导意见的方向，”亿万富翁、移动出行平台滴滴出行创始人兼首席执行官程维对中共喉舌《人民日报》表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将在创造就业、扩大消费、增强国际竞争优势等方面发挥积极作用，把企业做大、做优、做强。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新的行动计划是否会给中国经济的脊梁插上翅膀？飞得更高？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;然而，股市似乎并不相信北京的言论。 7 月 19 日晚指导意见发布后，沪深指数连续三天下跌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《南华早报》联系到的企业家表示，他们对北京方面在指导意见中的承诺不太信服，并会等待地方层面采取具体措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，分析师呼吁结束官方对私营企业的“歧视”，尽管一位观察家担心“束缚”可能会继续存在。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东部省份安徽省的一家水泥公司老板Jason Liu对该行动计划并没有抱太大希望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该指导方针触及了市场准入等长期问题。障碍和融资困难，”刘说。 “这些是当局数十年来发誓要解决的问题。但这些问题仍然悬而未决。我不确定这次会有什么不同。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新的指导方针是自习近平主席三月份开始其历史性的第三个国家主席任期以来北京发布的最全面的指导方针。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;该计划承诺通过“市场化、法治化、国际化”打造“一流营商环境”，涉及私营部门面临的一系列挑战，例如市场准入壁垒、确保公平竞争、融资支持、付款违约、知识产权和法律保护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这可能是[当局]善意的表达。 [但是]经过这些年的镇压、网上诽谤以及政府支持的公司在经济中日益占据主导地位，我对党[对私营部门]支持的信心已经破灭了，”刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“真正发生重大变化之前，我就得过且过。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的私营经济占国内生产总值的60%以上，技术进步的70%以上据官方数据，该行业占城镇劳动力的80%以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但该行业在资源配置和市场准入方面受到歧视，排名始终低于国有企业由于执政党依靠国有部门在政治、经济和社会方面发挥影响力，因此私营经济在过去三年中也遭受了一系列打击。正如习近平所呼吁的“遏制资本盲目扩张”，监管打压主要针对互联网科技公司、房地产开发商和民办教育公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些打击行动导致数万亿美元的资金蒸发市场价值的下降，恰逢中国“零新冠”方针下的严格抗疫限制，导致大规模企业倒闭和失业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主要社交媒体影响者煽风点火，进一步打击了商业信心。网上对私营企业的对抗，是对北京旨在缩小贫富差距的“共同富裕”举措的反应。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;民族主义博主司马南被禁止使用中国社交媒体&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“[甚至]中国的互联网世界受到严格审查，针对私营经济的敌对声音并未平息。这表明北京对[这种情绪]的容忍，”刘说。 “虽然习主席在三月份[在年度立法会议上]称私营企业家是‘我们这边的人’，但我们需要时间来恢复信心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家政策变化的迹象去年年底，随着中国加倍努力重振受新冠疫情打击的经济，“以人为主导”的模式变得明显。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平在 12 月召开的党的年度经济工作会议上表示，中国将修改规章制度，减少市场准入刘说，在三月份的全国人大和最高政协年会期间，习近平再次试图安抚私营部门。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“私营部门是我们党长期执政的重要力量，”习近平对代表私营企业的北京顾问表示。 “我们始终把私营企业、私营企业家视为自己这边的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此之际，由于长期的新冠疫情限制和房地产市场的影响，中国经济出现了近半个世纪以来最糟糕的表现之一。市场低迷，去年自 2021 年以来仅扩大了 3%。今年预期的大流行后复苏也一直难以起飞，青年失业率创历史新高，零售销售疲软。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;John Wang，中部湖南省的一位农业综合企业老板表示，私营部门面临的最大风险是政策制定的不可预测性和不一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我很高兴《指导意见》规定，私营企业的财产和合法权利以及企业家的利益将得到更好的保护，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但它没有解决政府政策与法律之间的关系。在现实的商业世界中，很多情况下政策凌驾于法律之上。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说，去年当地政府强迫他关闭了他的化肥厂，因为该厂靠近河流，据称存在环境风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;六年前，同一地方政府推动他建造该设施，因为他们渴望实现投资目标。 But when environmental protection became a key aspect for their performance evaluations, Wang found himself slapped with an administrative order to shut his factory.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This happened despite his making all the equipment upgrades needed to meet the government&#39;s environmental standards, according to Wang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Under such circumstances, legal protection sounds like empty talk,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang is a deputy to the local city-level legislative body, but said his political identity had brought him very limited influence in policymaking or implementation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is always a &#39;correct&#39; official stance. Everyone just follows suit,” Wang said. “No one dares to be an outlier who disagrees with the mainstream opinion … the minority obeys the majority.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s economic backbone, private firms decry lack of parity in policy support&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The new 31-point action plan, jointly released by the party and the State Council, China&#39;s cabinet, promises to “trust, unite, serve, guide and educate” private business owners as before, and “actively and prudently” develop party members from the sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also includes a pledge to streamline the industry distribution of entrepreneur representatives in China&#39;s legislative and political consulting bodies, and to encourage them to “play a bigger role” in international economic activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think it means that the party wants to absorb more members from emerging hi-tech sectors and phase out those from sunset industries,” Wang said. “It&#39;s not about generally elevating the political status of private entrepreneurs.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fred Zhang, a factory owner in eastern Jiangsu province, welcomed the plan&#39;s emphasis on cultivating “a cordial and clean relationship between government and business”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Local government has been a big headache to me,” Zhang said. “I think the best they can do is just leave us alone.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang said his local government, which he would not identify for fear of retaliation, had introduced a slew of policies in recent years requiring companies to go through various costly and time-consuming licensing procedures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Local officials told me the third-party licensing requirements were aimed at better quality assurance. However, officials would not be held accountable if anything bad happened.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They had also been keen to set up government-controlled business groups in sectors ranging from grain and oil trade, to water treatment and tourism, Zhang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These business groups were set up to make the state sector bigger and stronger, in response to the party&#39;s repeated calls, Zhang was told.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They have turned out to be strong competitors to private companies in the sense that they get our people. Many young people prefer stable and easy jobs in government-affiliated companies,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Outstanding people&#39;: China to give private sector more say as economy falters&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In its latest action plan, Beijing has vowed to change the status quo, with all regions and departments prohibited from setting up market entry barriers such as authentication or licensing. Administrative approvals will be streamlined and better regulated, and a level playing field created so that all companies are treated equally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Zhang remained sceptical. “When governments have their own companies, I can&#39;t see how private companies will ever be treated equally,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After all, the constitution stipulates the SOEs&#39; dominance in China&#39;s economic system, while the private economy is just a complement.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Shijin, former vice-president and research fellow at the State Council&#39;s Development Research Centre, said China should stop distinguishing between companies based on their ownership.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China needs entrepreneurship [now] more than at any other time,” Liu – a former member of China&#39;s top political advisory body – told a forum in Beijing late last month. “There is no need to categorise companies based on their ownership. We should make breakthroughs in eliminating ownership discrimination.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However Chen Daoyin, an independent political scientist and former Shanghai-based professor, said it was unlikely such categorisation would be dropped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The party made it clear during the 15th national congress in 1997 that the public sector controls the lifelines of the national economy and plays a leading role in economic development, setting the tone for the positions of the two sectors, Chen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The congress of September 1997 came a few months after the death of paramount leader Deng Xiaoping – the leader of China&#39;s reform and opening up drive since the late 1970s – and set the tone for the relationship between private and public ownership in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s up to the party to define which industries are &#39;lifelines&#39;. Traditionally they include petroleum, electricity, roads and railways, and so on. In recent years, digital financial services, culture and other industries concerning ideology have been added to the list,” Chen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The new guideline responds to the urgent needs of reviving the economy and helping the country survive the rivalry with the West. However, the tone is consistent with the past – the party will encourage, support and guide the development of the private sector, among which &#39;guiding&#39; is the dominating theme,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It means China&#39;s private companies will continue to dance with shackles on.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 06:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can humble fly solve China’s protein problem as food stocks dwindle?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3230242/can-humble-fly-solve-chinas-protein-problem-food-stocks-dwindle?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/f01366c3-b96f-4983-8199-9634f7b9065f_02f0f2b5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Insects nourished by kitchen and other organic waste could be a more sustainable way to provide protein for China&#39;s population, as conventional sources become increasingly scarce, according to Chinese scientists and international industry experts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The insect-based proteins make a highly nutritious animal feed which is better for livestock health and addresses dwindling fish stocks and the substantial environmental concerns around intensive livestock farming.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Urban residents produce large amounts of biodegradable kitchen scraps and other matter every day which is literally going to waste, according to the Shanghai Observer, a news agency owned by the city&#39;s party committee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In Shanghai alone, the average daily output of wet waste was 9,329 tonnes from March to July 2022. Yet the city could only process 8,200 tonnes a day, leaving a deficit of about 1,100 tonnes each day,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Insect farming technology offers a potential solution to both problems. Worms fed with pre-processed wet waste convert the organic matter into a rich source of nutrients – a process that is efficient, harmless and sustainable.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;These insects are helping Singapore save the planet&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;An insect farm established by the The Shanghai Urban Construction Investment Corporation is testing the process, converting 50 tonnes of pre-processed wet waste into 11 tonnes of protein-rich larvae and 12.8 tonnes of organic fertiliser daily.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a peer-reviewed paper published by the Guangdong Chemical Industry journal, the farm uses the black soldier fly (BSF), from the tropical grasslands of South America.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The insect was chosen for its short life cycle – around 35 days – and strong resilience, making it ideal for cultivation, according to lead author Ma Cong, manager of the project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“By crushing the waste and adjusting its water content, scientists create a suitable environment for BSF larvae. Larvae in the third-stage can grow into high-protein, high-fat fifth-stage BSF larvae in one week,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The droppings from these larvae are high in organic matter, nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium, and also contain a wealth of beneficial bacteria, making it an excellent new type of organic fertiliser,” Ma added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The harvested larvae can be used to make animal feed, pet food, bio-oil and other products, according to the paper. The process is sustainable, with some of the larvae selected to lay eggs after pupation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While insect farming is in its early stages in China, the process has been proven in the Netherlands, where leading company Protix converts 65,000 tonnes of waste into 14,000 tonnes of insect larvae.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The resulting insect-based products for pets, fish and livestock had a retail value of more than 70 million euros (US$77 million) in 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Protix CEO Kees Aarts, the nutritional and environmental advantages of insect-based proteins underscore their potential as a vital resource for the future, starting with their use as an animal feed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Insect-based proteins bring about improvements in the liver quality and skin health of salmon, [as well as] the fur, breath, and digestive health of dogs, and reduce diarrhoea and mortality rates in piglets and chickens,” Aarts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“BSF has high feed efficiency, short life cycles, ability to eat low grade organics – and they keep eating before the adult phase. It consumes much less land and water to create an equal quantity of proteins [compared with] poultry meat or beef offal.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What is the state of China&#39;s food-security drive, and is it succeeding?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In addition to providing a more sustainable alternative to traditional animal farming, the insects&#39; diet can be tailored to include things other than daily household waste.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Protix, its years of experience mean it can match waste streams to a suitable diet for the insects, expanding the potential to recycle most of a region&#39;s safe and legal organic material into a valuable protein source.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In China, where insect farming&#39;s potential growth is enormous, the treatment of wet waste to make sure impurities are screened out, will be essential.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s seeds, in an agricultural choke hold, must see breeding advancements&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to Ma&#39;s paper, securing the raw materials for insect breeding is the cornerstone of the technology, with impurities such as plastic bags affecting the growth efficiency of BSF.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Only by properly treating wet waste, through steps like sorting, collecting, transporting, screening, and crushing, can we ensure a smooth BSF breeding,” Ma said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another key focus is to increase the economic and environmental benefits of the process. “Our products currently include feed, bio-oil and organic fertiliser. However, the public&#39;s understanding and acceptance of these products need to improve,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Aarts, the future of insect-based proteins is promising.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As traditional protein sources continue to deplete and climate change concerns increase, insect-based proteins offer a sustainable, nutritious, and efficient alternative,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 06:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In India’s brutal ethnic war, women are participants as well as victims]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3230415/indias-brutal-ethnic-war-women-are-participants-well-victims?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/08/30df2f15-6844-41c5-a78d-4961b663db0f_8096fd7f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;In the sectarian violence that has ravaged India&#39;s Manipur state, women have been victims of brutal attacks. Residents and security officials say they are also at the forefront of the conflict, picking up arms, blocking troops and, according to police complaints, instigating sexual assaults.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s northeastern states have been historically prone to insurgencies and ethnic violence, but the vicious conflict between majority Meiteis and minority tribal Kukis in Manipur hit world headlines last month when a video surfaced of two Kuki women being paraded naked through a jeering mob.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a police complaint reviewed by Reuters, one of the women said she was raped and her father and brother killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kukis say a loosely formed group of Meitei women, known as Meira Paibis, or Women Torch-bearers, is responsible for instigating some of the rapes of women of the minority community. The Meiteis deny the accusation, but the incidents underline the bitterness between communities in the small state on the border with Myanmar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Women&#39;s participation in it [the rapes] underscores the absolute breakdown of all social ties,” said Praveen Donthi, a senior analyst at the International Crisis Group who has written a report on the Manipur conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It has made the physical and emotional divide between the communities complete and reconciliation now looks unattainable.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s Supreme Court announced this week that it will monitor investigations into cases of sexual violence in the state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Manipur police chief Rajiv Singh and other senior police officials did not respond to multiple requests for comment on the cases of sexual violence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the fighting began in early May, at least 180 people, including 21 women, have been killed and tens of thousands made homeless, according to government data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Security forces say women also block peacekeeping operations, taking advantage of laws that prevent male troops from any physical confrontation with women. They also occupy bunkers on the front lines, rifles in hand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In one case of sexual assault, a 19-year-old Kuki tribal woman told Reuters she was raped near the state capital Imphal on May 15 by three men after she was taken to a group of Meira Paibis and beaten in their presence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One of the women from the mob gave clear instructions to four men to kill me,” she said in a police complaint filed on July 21, which Reuters has reviewed. She escaped and said she had been too scared to file the report earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police did not answer questions about the case and there is no record of any arrests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moirangthen Thoibi Devi, a Meira Paibis member in Moirang town near Imphal, said suggestions that any Meitei woman could instigate or even support acts of sexual violence were completely “untrue”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Meira Paibis does not differentiate between Kuki or Meitei,” she said, speaking alongside a group of other Meitei women. “Kuki mothers are also in pain, Meitei mothers are also in pain.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The women said they had heard of nine Meitei women being raped, but they had no evidence and were not directly aware of any incidents. Reuters was unable to locate any victim, and police and Meitei civil society bodies did not share information of any known cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ngainekim, the president of the Kuki Women Organisation for Human Rights, said she had sent a letter to Prime Minister Narendra Modi in July saying that “sexual violence and rape as a method or tactic of warfare is being widely perpetrated” by the Meiteis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ngainekim, who uses one name, said in the letter that she knew of 13 cases of Kuki women being raped or murdered, including two women who “the Meira Paibis dragged out … from their hostel and handed over to the Meitei menfolk”. They were “later gang-raped and killed in a car wash shed” in East Imphal, she said in the letter, which was reviewed by Reuters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a police complaint reviewed by Reuters, the mother of one of the victims blames unnamed Meitei youth but does not mention Meira Paibis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The reports of women urging their menfolk on to rape Kuki women … should terrify us,” wrote historian and author Mukul Kesavan in a newspaper column. “A state where women abet the public rape and murder of other women is slouching towards a nightmare worse than mere anarchy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;India&#39;s Modi faces no-confidence vote over deadly violence in Manipur&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Security officials accuse women on both sides, but largely Meiteis, of blocking troops from conducting operations, and regulating entry points to their villages. With few women soldiers, the army does not have the authority to act against women.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Meira Paibis “have weaponised it very well, it&#39;s a major chink in our system,” said a senior officer from the Assam Rifles paramilitary organisation assigned to peacekeeping duties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is a reason we block the army … because they have directly supported the Kukis,” said Thoibi Devi, the woman from Meira Paibis, standing with other women at a checkpoint where they stop all vehicles, including military ones.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vak Vaiphei, a Kuki leader in the tribal-controlled Kangvai village, said when military personnel try to take over their bunkers, women surround them and push them out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearby, a Kuki woman, wearing a black T-shirt, camouflage trousers and holding a double-barrelled gun, said she felt safer taking up arms against the Meiteis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I will be scared if I sit at home,” Lamnu Haokip, 23, said. “But now I&#39;m here, so I can shoot them.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 06:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Jailed ex-premier Imran Khan barred from Pakistan politics for five years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3230441/jailed-ex-premier-imran-khan-barred-pakistan-politics-five-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/09/585ed371-6e7c-43c3-ae21-71bb22fbc294_c2d54e77.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Former Pakistani prime minister Imran Khan, who has been convicted and jailed on corruption charges, was barred from politics for five years on Tuesday, an official order said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The order by the Election Commission of Pakistan (ECP), seen by Reuters and confirmed by a senior officer, said Khan was disqualified in line with his conviction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Imran Ahmad Khan Niazi is disqualified for a period of five years,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khan&#39;s constituency would now stand vacant, the order added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Pakistan&#39;s ex-PM Khan jailed for 3 years over illegal selling of state gifts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Under Pakistani law, a convicted person cannot run for any public office for a period defined by the ECP, which could be up to a maximum of five years staring from the conviction date.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We knew this was inevitable,” Khan&#39;s aide Zulfikar Bukhari said, saying the party will challenge the disqualification in high court.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re highly confident it will be reversed,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khan, who has denied any wrongdoing, was sentenced to three years imprisonment on Saturday on charges of unlawfully selling state gifts he and his family acquired during his tenure from 2018 to 2022. He was arrested at his Lahore house and taken to a prison near Islamabad.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khan&#39;s legal team has filed an appeal seeking to set aside the guilty verdict, which Islamabad High Court will take up on Wednesday, his lawyer Naeem Panjutha said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The petition seen by Reuters described the conviction as “without lawful authority, tainted with bias”, and said Khan, 70, had not received an adequate hearing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said the court had rejected a list of witnesses for the defence a day before reaching its verdict, calling this a “gross travesty of justice, and a slap in the face of due process and fair trial”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court had expedited the trial after Khan refused to attend hearings despite repeated summonses and arrest warrants.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;New arrest warrant issued for ex-Pakistan PM Imran Khan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Khan has been at the heart of political turmoil since he was ousted as prime minister in a vote of no-confidence last year, raising concern about Pakistan&#39;s stability as it grapples with an economic crisis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With Khan out of the political picture for now, all eyes should be turning to a coming election, said South Asia Institute director at the Washington-based Wilson Centre, Michael Kugelman.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Any delay in the election – due by November – would fuel more public anger and inject more uncertainty into the political environment, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That volatility and uncertainty could have implications for political stability but also the economy, if foreign investors and donors become reluctant to deploy more capital in such an environment,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June Pakistan secured a last-gasp US$3 billion deal with the IMF, which has sought a consensus on policy objectives among all political parties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khan&#39;s legal team says he is being kept in abject conditions in a small, so-called C-class cell in a prison in Attock, near the capital Islamabad, with an open toilet, when he should qualify for a B-class cell with facilities including an attached washroom, newspapers, books and television.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A request had been filed on his behalf for an A-class cell with all the facilities he was entitled to.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Interior Minister Rana Sanaullah, who spent several months in jail on drug trafficking charges he says were fabricated during Khan&#39;s tenure, said that Khan himself had been a proponent of uniformity in prisons.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 06:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US warned Japan that China was hacking its defence networks, officials say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230445/us-warned-japan-china-was-hacking-its-defence-networks-officials-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 06:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/09/568d0e14-a620-4477-a627-447c402a153f_a544153e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The US warned Japan over the course of a year that Chinese state hackers had infiltrated its defence networks before Tokyo took sufficient action to try to secure them, according to current and former US officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Senior US national security officials grew increasingly concerned that sensitive information that the US shares with some allies could be at risk as a result of the breach, which was discovered several years ago. That prompted multiple US delegations since 2020 to fly to Tokyo to warn Japan, according to the officials, who asked not to be identified discussing the sensitive matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, the US saw insufficient evidence Japan was taking action to secure its networks despite warning of a problem, said a former intelligence official. General Paul Nakasone, director of the National Security Agency and commander of US Cyber Command, was among US officials who visited Tokyo to flag the issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Japan wanted proof of the infiltration, said the former official, who added that intelligence is sometimes too sensitive to share specifics. Japan also was reluctant to let the US into its networks, the former official said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only after Anne Neuberger, deputy national security adviser for cyber and emerging technology, visited Japan in mid-November 2021 did the US and Japan chart a successful way forward, according to the officials. Japan has since set about boosting its cybersecurity defences, although the US is eager to see it do still more, according to statements from both countries this year, in addition to national security experts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The breach and the US warnings were reported earlier by The Washington Post, which cited multiple current and former US and Japanese officials it didn&#39;t identify.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yasukazu Hamada, Japan&#39;s defence minister, declined to comment on the Washington Post report, telling reporters in Tokyo on Tuesday that it does not comment on individual cyberattacks and how they are handled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I won&#39;t comment on the details due to the nature of the matter,” Hamada said. “We have not confirmed that classified information held by the defence ministry has been leaked due to a cyberattack.” The Japanese embassy in Washington didn&#39;t immediately respond to messages requesting comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese hackers breached US government email accounts, Microsoft says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tensions between the US and China are increasing due in part to concerns of a potential Chinese attack on Taiwan, which would likely be accompanied by cyberattacks, particularly in the early stages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing regards the island as a breakaway province to be brought under mainland control – by force, if necessary. Many countries, including the US, do not officially recognise Taiwan as an independent state but oppose the use of force to change the status quo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, the US and Japan agreed that a cyberattack against either country in Japan could, in certain circumstances, constitute an armed attack. The US has about 56,000 troops based in Japan, according to the US Defence Department.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In August 2021, Yasuhide Nakayama, who was then Japan&#39;s state minister of defence, said he and Nakasone were “opening a new chapter in our joint efforts in cyberspace” as part of a visit to US Cyber Command to discuss security challenges in cyberspace and bilateral cooperation, according to US Cyber Command.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan established a Cyber Defence Group in 2014, as part of its Self-Defence Forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But amid a growing spate of cyberattacks, it reorganised and launched a full cyber defence command in March 2022, along with a commitment to engage in offensive cyber operations and plans to expand to 4,000 people by the end of 2027, according to Japan&#39;s Ministry of Defence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to visits to Japan by both Nakasone and Neuberger, then National Cyber Director Chris Inglis also visited Japan in December 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US Navy hit by Chinese hacking campaign, report says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In a statement, the US Defence Department described the US-Japan Alliance as the cornerstone of peace and security in the Indo-Pacific and said it was strengthening cyber cooperation as part of “alliance modernisation efforts”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, the US and Japan agreed to “intensify collaboration to counter increasingly sophisticated and persistent cyber threats” following security talks to strengthen the alliance in Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The United States welcomed Japan&#39;s initiatives to bolster its national cybersecurity posture,” said a joint statement, citing the creation of a new organisation to coordinate whole-of-government cybersecurity policies and a new framework set to “provide a foundation for a wider range of US-Japan cooperation.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 06:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia’s bid to become a ‘multilateral player’ in Indo-Pacific at risk over lack of funding]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3230428/australias-bid-become-multilateral-player-indo-pacific-risk-over-lack-funding?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/034f08b5-8928-4ef0-9573-041526f05ab3_88d312f6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚更新了其国际发展计划，重点关注气候变化和消除贫困项目，但专家表示，缺乏新的资金可能会危及其成功及其在该地区发挥更大影响力的功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各国越来越多地利用提供此类援助来在该地区赢得更多朋友对于澳大利亚来说，这种紧张局势随着中国与所罗门群岛等太平洋国家的往来增多而加剧，所罗门群岛过去曾受益于堪培拉的大量援助捐款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但无论澳大利亚的最新举措是否有效，援助部门最高机构澳大利亚国际发展委员会 (ACFID) 首席执行官马克·珀塞尔 (Marc Purcell) 表示，该项目旨在对抗中国的影响力，要正确执行该计划，需要更多资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国对太平洋地区的援助随着澳大利亚支出飙升，各国经济暴跌：报告“预算足够吗？”不，事实并非如此，我们需要做得更多。”他说，考虑到澳大利亚希望将援助范围与太平洋国家一起扩展到东南亚和南亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2023-24 财年，澳大利亚分配了14亿澳元（9亿美元）的海外发展资金流向太平洋地区，7亿多澳元流向东南亚。自 5 月份预算以来，这一直是官方的，周二宣布的计划概述了该预算的蓝图，而不是新资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;珀塞尔表示，澳大利亚“[援助支出]远低于经合组织的平均水平”，并且要恢复到平均水平，“还有很多工作要做，可以说，中国和美国等正在进入该地区的其他参与者是更大的捐助者”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管已经获得了额外的资金珀塞尔补充道，现任安东尼·阿尔巴内斯政府在过去两份预算中分配了更多资金，用于提供援助和促进劳工移民等事务，以及可能在三年内与太平洋国家举行气候变化会议，因此需要更多资金。 Purcell 补充道，澳大利亚需要提高水平，以达到发达国家平均贡献国民总收入 0.3% 的水平。目前，澳大利亚提供了国民总收入的 0.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 5 月份的预算中，阿尔巴尼亚政府在前莫里森联合政府提供的拨款基础上进行了改进，承诺在五年内再拨款 17 亿澳元.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现实是，如果不投入新资金，就无法主办联合国会议；如果不成为更强大的多边参与者，就无法竞标 [联合国] 安理会席位。”珀塞尔说道。 “因此，[资金]是否足以完成这项工作还有待观察。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ACFID 还希望看到向印太地区以外的地区提供援助，以及更多“关于如何实现这一目标的切实承诺”。澳大利亚国立大学发展政策中心高级研究官员卡梅伦·希尔 (Cameron Hill) 表示，该战略也没有解决承诺的 2.5% 的增长资金问题一年意味着至少在 2036-37 年之前，实际资金将保持不变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果资金没有实际增长，澳大利亚政府将很难兑现包括性别平等在内的新承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;h3>;所罗门群岛告诉批评者，中国警方的交易不是对太平洋的“威胁”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;希尔还表示，上届莫里森政府表现出“对援助的明显矛盾心理”。 It was accused of having “the worst Australian foreign policy failure” in the Pacific after the Solomon Islands struck a new security pact with China last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For that reason, development aid needed to be adequately funded to serve Australia&#39;s national interests, said Melissa Conley Tyler, executive director at development, diplomacy and defence group AP4D.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While she agreed there were funding challenges, Conley Tyler said the policy set out to “make the case for more effective development spending”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Australia&#39;s Minister for International Development and the Pacific Pat Conroy was confident the new programme would “advance Australia&#39;s national interest and add another tool to Australia&#39;s armoury of statecraft”, although he would not be drawn into saying the programme was targeted at China during local media interviews on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has been a big aid provider in the Indo-Pacific, and in Southeast Asia for example, it is the region&#39;s largest development partner and its biggest source of official development finance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Conroy said, against geostrategic competition in the region, the new programme had an edge in that Canberra would stipulate that local workers and materials must be used in development projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s a key differentiator between how Australia will do development in the region versus other countries, and it&#39;s to our advantage,” he said in one of his local media interviews.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US beats China in soft power and popularity in Southeast Asia, giving it regional edge: analysis]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3230442/us-beats-china-soft-power-and-popularity-southeast-asia-giving-it-regional-edge-analysis?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 04:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/09/f4670aa9-46f3-49fe-b7b2-6b8c526f7dc3_a7aa58aa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国在东南亚比中国拥有更大的软实力和知名度，展现华盛顿周二发布的综合民意调查分析发现，这两个大国在这个具有重要战略意义的地区对峙时具有明显的优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数公民，特别是该地区人口最多的国家——印度尼西亚、菲律宾和越南– 根据华盛顿智库战略与国际研究中心的白皮书，中国比中国更信任美国的政策和意图。这使美国在一系列问题上巩固联盟或至少防止地区国家与北京结盟而损害华盛顿方面占据上风。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“华盛顿需要更加适应各个国家如何看待彼此之间的关系这份长达 24 页的报告称，对北京行为和意图的日益担忧为该地区创造了外交和经济开放。 “华盛顿应该推进积极的政治、安全和经济议程来应对当前形势。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这份题为“评估美国和中国在东南亚的影响力”的报告也指出，软实力并不重要。唯一起作用的因素。它认为，硬实力和提供具体利益的能力也很重要，尽管它并没有影响它们的相对有效性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，中国被广泛视为每个国家的主要经济大国。除菲律宾外，有足够的数据进行分析。报告称：“现实情况是，从大多数指标来看，中国正在扩大经济影响力差距。”虽然美国在东南亚总体上享有盛誉，但华盛顿方面却没有做到这一点也令人沮丧咨询公司 Bower Group Asia 的研究主管、《北京阴影下：东南亚的中国挑战》一书的作者 Murray Hiebert 表示，更多的是参与制定贸易规则和投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“大多数大国的普遍态度像印度尼西亚、马来西亚、泰国一样，美国是比中国更好的安全伙伴，更值得信赖。”希伯特说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;前海军情报领导人认为美中封闭渠道存在“危险趋势” &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“但在经济方面，美国对退出跨太平洋伙伴关系协定感到非常失望，”他补充道，他指的是一项连接亚太地区 11 个国家的贸易倡议。美国于 2017 年在时任总统唐纳德·特朗普的领导下退出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CSIS 调查中对中国战略和经济影响力的一些最高评估是在柬埔寨和老挝发表的。中国还是所分析的所有 10 个国家中最大的贸易伙伴，也是大多数国家中最大的投资者，而美国被认为提供了大量的传统发展援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去的调查直接对受访者进行了民意调查。 But CSIS took a different approach, opting instead to collate and weight already available regional and individual-country survey data to piece together a comprehensive picture from the granular data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Policymakers in Washington and regional capitals alike tend to make assumptions about Southeast Asian opinion using anecdotes or tiny elite samples, often from just a couple of countries,” the report explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US should drop pursuit of &#39;American primacy&#39; in Southeast Asia, report urges&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But the white paper also noted gaps in individual country polls given weaknesses in methodology, such as an outright lack of surveys in places like Myanmar and inconsistent polling on the views of politicians, academics and other elites.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It recommended that the US expand surveys of the general public as well as politicians and other elites in Southeast Asia to better understand how it is perceived.它还敦促华盛顿针对影响最大的举措，并评估其随着时间的推移取得的进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国可以提高其地区地位，并利用对中国动机和不断扩大的足迹的怀疑，通过更多的外交、经济和影响力参与来提高其地区地位。欧亚集团 (Eurasia Group) 中国和东北亚顾问杰里米·陈 (Jeremy Chan) 表示，在安全问题上，华盛顿的战略很大一部分应该基于简单地出现在地区论坛上，并为中国提供替代方案。陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国关注东盟贸易关系，但成员国担心陷入“地缘政治陷阱”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;至于他补充说，对于北京来说，它“可以通过淡化一些言论以及海事主张和活动来改善其在该地区的形象”，并指出：“但这可能不会很快发生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，包括软实力在内的权力动态会随着条件的变化而变化，包括中国更加“孤立的民族主义”、冠状病毒大流行持续的经济影响、俄罗斯乌克兰战争的影响以及美中之间不断升级的战略竞争.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查结果来自皮尤研究中心、洛伊研究所、独立中心、亚洲脉搏和欧亚集团以及其他智库和咨询机构之前的调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洛伊研究所4月份发布的调查发现，中国在东南亚的外交和经济联系比美国更强，而美国在国防网络和文化影响力方面得分更高。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 04:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>