<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Baby dies after landslide buries home as torrential rain pounds South Korea]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3226082/baby-dies-after-landslide-buries-home-torrential-rain-pounds-south-korea?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 15:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/8a6cca38-5697-4c27-b5e7-2ab55797bb66_d7fc4460.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国暴雨引发山体滑坡，导致一名一岁婴儿死亡当局周五表示，洪水淹没了道路和桥梁，迫使数百个家庭撤离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是自周二夏季雨季开始以来的第二起死亡事件，此前一场山体滑坡掩埋了婴儿位于东南部的家。荣州市一夜之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据媒体报道，10 吨重的山体滑坡发生时，救援人员将家中 9 人救出，消防部门出动了 40 多辆车辆和 110 名消防员。但婴儿在被送往医院后不久就去世了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国会兑现禁止“寄生虫式”地下室公寓的誓言吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;荣州是受此次疫情影响最严重的地区之一灾害官员表示，季风影响，自周四午夜以来降雨量超过 284 毫米（11.2 英寸），他们还向包括济州岛在内的南部其他地区发布了大雨警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;气象官员表示，他们预计直到周六早上，南部地区都会有更多降雨，而救灾当局的数据显示，有 350 人被疏散，其中大多数在西南部的全罗省。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数十处设施遭到破坏，多条道路和高速公路被封锁&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在西南部的咸平县，周四，一名公共工作人员在外出检查河上的泄洪闸后被发现死亡。她于周二失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年八月，创纪录的暴雨导致首都首尔断电、地铁和房屋被淹没，造成至少八人死亡。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia calling: red carpet rolled out for Chinese tourists as Western sanctions bite]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3225993/russia-calling-chinese-tourists-find-red-carpet-laid-down-western-sanctions-bite?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/1629def5-09bd-42ad-9a22-3349b4b950b6_a2c0ca05.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;六月的一个星期五下午，北京在创纪录的夏季高温下烘烤，俄罗斯酒店和航空公司代表热情地展示了他们为中国客户量身定制的最新旅游项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你可以在圣彼得堡度过一个凉爽的夏天，”其中一位代表告诉聚集在北京市中心会议厅的中国旅行社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“圣彼得堡是一个凉爽的夏天”。 >;&lt;p>;另一个人说道：“我们有非常著名的总统套房，习近平主席访问莫斯科期间就住在这里。”观众席上响起一片窃窃私语。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的信息很简单——俄罗斯欢迎中国游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;16个月前入侵乌克兰后，俄罗斯受到美国主导的制裁的挤压，现在正在寻求世界第二大经济体来帮助抵消对其旅游和文化部门的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;据俄罗斯国家通讯社塔斯社报道，去年只有约 19 万来自前苏联国家以外的外国游客访问了俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，中国引领旅游业重启的计划面临着以下障碍：聚集在北京的业内人士表示，缺乏有利的签证政策或便捷的支付方式，以及对最近瓦格纳叛乱等事件的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果没有豁免计划，中国游客需要支付费用俄罗斯旅游签证需额外支付 1,500 元至 2,000 元人民币（207 美元至 275 美元），”圣彼得堡的中国旅行社谢尔盖·张 (Sergey Zhang) 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张说，付款方式是另一个大障碍。 。俄罗斯在 2022 年 2 月入侵乌克兰后受到制裁，已被切断与全球支付系统的联系，这使得使用外国信用卡支付变得非常复杂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，中国银联的业务已受到限制与受到制裁的俄罗斯银行。 “外国游客可能必须携带大量卢布现金，这是一个大问题，”张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周的瓦格纳叛乱 - 来自私人雇佣军组织的战士短暂占领了南部地区的军事设施北京一家旅行社的经理王亮表示，俄罗斯城市向莫斯科游行——也可能会阻止中国游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着俄罗斯摇摇欲坠，精英阶​​层颤抖，一些私人飞机离开&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们会等到明年才重新开始俄罗斯之旅，因为存在一些安全问题，特别是在靠近欧洲的地区，”王说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外展活动继俄罗斯总理米哈伊尔·米舒斯京五月下旬高调访问中国之后，圣彼得堡和莫斯科旅游部门牵头做出了努力，重点是贸易和经济支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推动旅游业发展似乎很顺利尽管两国“无限制”的战略伙伴关系和蓬勃发展的贸易关系（主要是由中国进口俄罗斯能源推动的）在乌克兰战争后面临西方越来越严格的审查，但它们已被提上议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国习近平主席于三月前往莫斯科会见俄罗斯总统普京，随后发表联合声明，承诺“深化新时代全面战略伙伴关系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会晤后，双方同意“据中国外交部称，“扩大旅游合作与交流，鼓励营造舒适的旅游环境”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据俄罗斯当局称，电子签证计划将于 7 月启动，俄罗斯官员和旅游运营商表示他们正在准备接待中国游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科预计将于 12 月推出 7 天支付卡，作为外国游客的 Visa 和万事达卡的替代品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首都莫斯科旅游委员会主席叶夫根尼·科兹洛夫 (Evgeny Kozlov) 表示，莫斯科旅游委员会主席叶夫根尼·科兹洛夫 (Evgeny Kozlov) 表示，他们已经投入巨资，为来自中国的游客提供更便捷的旅行，设置了更多中文标识，并培训了更多中文导游。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京旅游路演上，科兹洛夫表示，这项投资将帮助中国游客“更好地了解”这座城市的历史和文化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“莫斯科是一座非常美丽的城市。我们真诚地希望更多的中国游客来到莫斯科并度过愉快的时光。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着西方制裁的影响，中国商人在俄罗斯“做得很好”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在冠状病毒大流行之前，俄罗斯是中国游客的首选目的地之一，莫斯科红场和圣彼得堡冬宫博物馆等地标建筑都挤满了中国游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯还于2019年对中国旅游团免除了签证要求三到五十人。根据俄罗斯央行的数据，当年估计有 170 万中国人访问俄罗斯，消费总额达 10 亿美元，比任何其他国家的游客都多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一度，中国大佬太多了旅行团到俄罗斯旅游，一些当地人开始抱怨无法享受自己的文化遗产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张说，虽然没有迹象表明休闲旅游会很快恢复往日的辉煌，但商务旅行涉及中国投资者恢复得很快，已经达到新冠疫情前水平的80%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于西方的制裁，中国企业现在在俄罗斯市场有机会。”&lt;/p>; >;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As US-China rivalry spikes, New Zealand avoiding getting pulled from ‘pillar to post’: minister]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3226062/us-china-rivalry-spikes-new-zealand-avoiding-getting-pulled-pillar-post-minister?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 13:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/88955f60-792f-442b-ad2f-6df86e50b3e5_16e651ca.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新西兰正在谨慎处理与中国的关系，必须避免被从“支柱”中拉出来这个太平洋国家外交部长周五表示，“在北京和美国之间的战略竞争中”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳纳亚·马胡塔 (Nanaia Mahuta) 发表上述言论之际，总理克里斯·希普金斯 (Chris Hipkins) 即将结束对中国为期六天的访问。率领一个贸易代表团，其中包括与中国国家主席习近平和总理李强会面，重点讨论经济伙伴关系和贸易问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;希普金斯因在访问期间没有花更多时间引起新西兰对人类的担忧而面临国内批评。新疆的侵犯人权行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国是一种复杂的关系，我们需要非常谨慎地处理，”马胡塔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说希普金斯对贸易的关注并没有改变新西兰的外交政策，但表明新西兰与中国有着广泛的利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新西兰总理不同意拜登的观点，称习近平不是“独裁者”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在希普金斯与习近平会面后的一份声明中，有没有提及人权问题或台湾海峡。前总理杰辛达·阿德恩 (Jacinda Ardern) 与习近平 2022 年 11 月会面的宣读中提到了这两点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我毫不怀疑，双方会讨论贸易和经济问题、人权问题马胡塔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部没有立即回应置评请求。中国驻新西兰大使馆发言人上周表示，过去五十年来，“通过共同努力，在相互尊重、求同存异的基础上”，两国关系取得了长足发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期以来，新西兰在五眼情报共享联盟中一直被视为对中国持温和甚至缺席的态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国在安全问题上的基调以及中国在南太平洋日益增强的影响力去年变得强硬起来在中国与所罗门群岛达成安全协议之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mahuta 表示，希普金斯在三月份访问中国后对中国进行了访问，这强化了两国关系的微妙性质。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mahuta 的此行受到了密切关注本周，《澳大利亚人报》称她遭到了对方长达一小时的训斥。她形容这次会议“非常有力”。她说，在会议上，她注意到“对新疆人权状况以及香港权利和自由受到侵蚀的深切关注。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她表示，中国和新西兰可能就问题进行艰难的对话他们对此意见不一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在一些相当困难的时期，我们一直与中国保持外交对话，”她说，但没有详细说明。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;反核新西兰是在“玩火”吗？ ”，因为它正在考虑在奥库斯扮演的角色？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她更广泛地说，外交政策和地缘政治挑战变得越来越复杂，包括气候变化对各国的影响、乌克兰战争以及大量难民需要重新安置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在太平洋地区面临着两个大国之间的战略竞争的挑战，”她说。 “新西兰处于这样的位置，我们希望确保我们不会被从一个支柱拉到另一个职位，我们以能够维护我们利益的方式管理重要关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我们是一个民主国家。我们信奉开放、透明、民主的原则。我们将继续与持有相同价值观的人保持一致。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taylor Swift fans in Indonesia, Philippines, Malaysia blame poor infrastructure, conservative laws for concert snubs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3226052/taylor-swift-fans-indonesia-philippines-malaysia-blame-poor-infrastructure-conservative-laws-concert?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/0d610a3f-d3b2-4ff2-a94f-c60c49c35bb8_c2d287d7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;数以百万计的东南亚泰勒·斯威夫特粉丝痛惜错过了观看的机会这位明星决定只在新加坡演出后，开始举办演唱会，一些人将她赶走的原因归咎于其国家糟糕的娱乐基础设施和宗教保守主义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位美国乡村流行歌手将在新加坡举办六场演唱会。明年三月，作为她全球 Eras 巡演的一部分，几周前英国摇滚乐队 Coldplay 也在新加坡进行了六场演出——这是他们在 Music of the Spheres 世界巡演中在任何国家度过的最长时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“她只能在新加坡打球，这真的很遗憾。宿务市的“斯威夫特”大学生基娜·特里西亚·利加斯 (Kheena Thrisia Ligas) 说：“泰勒在菲律宾拥有庞大的粉丝群，但她没有钱飞到新加坡去看她的偶像。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯威夫特的歌曲在菲律宾非常受欢迎。菲律宾，在 Spotify 排行榜上连续 610 天位居榜首，并成为全国卡拉 OK 机上人群的最爱。粉丝们通过变装秀和从吕宋岛到米沙鄢群岛和棉兰老岛的其他活动来庆祝她的 Eras 巡演，以说服她到菲律宾演出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ligas 推测斯威夫特跳过菲律宾的原因之一是因为它“没有可以容纳时代巡回赛的体育场”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我相信这整个惨败也是因为我们的政府只真正支持篮球，这解释了为什么我们的国家只有[体育]竞技场，”这位22岁的年轻人说道。 “我认为，如果我们希望像泰勒这样的大艺术家来菲律宾举办演出，物流和场馆的机制或法规也应该到位。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在邻国印度尼西亚和马来西亚，基础设施建设很完善。这不是问题，因为雅加达的格罗拉蓬卡诺主体育场可容纳约 77,000 人，而吉隆坡的武吉加里尔国家体育场则有 85,000 个座位。新加坡国家体育场可容纳 55,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但粉丝们指出繁文缛节和政治保守主义是阻碍国际表演者的因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Iqhram，马来西亚的 Swiftie，以 1 号为名这位歌手宣布新加坡演唱会日期后，他说，他申请了一张信用卡，以便注册以获得预售门票的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位来自砂拉越的 24 岁歌迷表示，他斯威夫特曾预计斯威夫特会跳过马来西亚，因为“在马来西亚申请音乐会许可证时存在不必要的官僚主义”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，艺术家还必须应对官员的宗教敏感性。 “在吉隆坡举办音乐会意味着组织者或音乐家需要承担政府因政治压力而在最后一刻取消音乐会的风险，”Iqhram 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊斯兰政党马来西亚伊斯兰党 ( PAS）上个月呼吁取消酷玩乐队在吉隆坡的演唱会，因为他们认为乐队对 LGBTQ 权利的支持将促进“享乐主义和变态文化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;PAS 是谁，马来西亚最大的单一政党马来西亚的新议会？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据 Iqhram 的说法，国际音乐家应该在砂拉越举办活动，那里受到干扰的风险比吉隆坡低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他认为他的家乡是更加自由，因为“它是马来西亚唯一一个基督徒人数超过穆斯林人口的地区”，并且它拥有一定的自治权，这意味着它不一定要“遵循联邦政府制定的政策或协调一致的指导方针”。&lt;/p>;&lt;与此同时，马来西亚前青年和体育部长、现任国会议员赛沙迪 (Syed Saddiq) 对仅举办一晚酷玩乐队的经济成本表示遗憾。 “当我们在这里争论马来西亚举办音乐会的问题时，其他国家正在抓住黄金机会，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在印度尼西亚，斯威夫特的缺席被她的粉丝视为该国缺乏的进一步迹象尽管它是该地区最大的经济体和人口最多的国家，但在吸引知名人士和全球活动方面具有吸引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚 Swifties 推测，猖獗的倒卖文化也可能意味着举办演出可能会遇到更多麻烦&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在酷玩乐队的[门票销售]期间，有几起黄牛使用多台电脑和设备购买门票的案例被疯传，因此粉丝们不是与其他粉丝竞争，而是与其他粉丝竞争。”自称为“强硬派斯威夫特”的奥基·苏坦托 (Okky Sutanto) 告诉《亚洲周刊》。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“比万圣节更可怕”：印度尼西亚公司可能会因踩踏事件而受到惩罚&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;Okky 还指责国际艺术家选择新加坡而不是雅加达缺乏像样的公共交通，以及印度尼西亚在人群管理方面的缺陷记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，强硬派团体的威胁无济于事。上个月，212 集团的宗教原教旨主义者威胁要在 11 月围攻雅加达机场，试图取消酷玩乐队的演出，因为他们支持 LGBTQ 平等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，莱昂内尔·梅西 (Lionel Messi) 决定不加入阿根廷国家足球队6 月 19 日，他们在雅加达对阵印度尼西亚对手。由于以色列参加世界杯的棘手问题，印度尼西亚还被剥夺了国际足联 20 岁以下世界杯的主办权。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度尼西亚人愤怒了，国际足联因其以色列立场而取消 U20 世界杯，令人悲伤&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2012 年，Lady Gaga 取消了在雅加达的演唱会，原因是宗教团体认为她的演唱会过于粗俗，提出抗议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雅加达也意识到错失了机会，并誓言将更加积极主动地寻求与全球艺术家和活动组织者的合作。该国旅游和创意经济部长桑迪亚加·乌诺(Sandiaga Uno)表示，他正在游说酷玩乐队的音乐会主办方Live Nation，为该乐队在雅加达的演出增加一个额外的日期。但到目前为止，这种努力仍然徒劳无功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅游部创意产品和活动组织者副官 Vinsensius Jemadu 周一表示，印度尼西亚将尽力满足世界音乐家在举办巡演之前提出的几个条件&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须确保印度尼西亚在每项活动中都采用可持续原则。我们必须确保在这里举办活动能够为社区，特别是扶贫，带来最大的利益。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s Cathay Pacific hits back at union for claiming company cannot plug pilot shortfall, says 250 cockpit ex-staff to return]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3226063/hong-kongs-cathay-pacific-hits-back-union-claiming-company-cannot-plug-pilot-shortfall-says-250?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 14:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/ebbe730a-cfec-49e3-990d-2d8abffed06d_263daa70.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港旗舰航空公司国泰航空已反击工会声称其飞行员疯狂招聘并不能解决人力短缺问题，据透露，大约 250 名之前离开的机长和副驾驶将重新加入该航空公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰集团在周五的一份声明中表示，欢迎这些已申请加入该公司的员工回来。回国，承诺为所有员工提供有竞争力的薪酬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》了解到，部分回国的机长和副驾驶曾在现已解散的子公司国泰港龙航空工作过。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;飞行风险：揭开香港国泰航空飞行员的不满&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国泰航空的言论是针对香港空勤人员协会，该协会当天早些时候表示，该航空公司需要700名机长才能恢复疫情前的客运能力.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工会还表示，该公司计划在未来两年内雇用 800 名见习飞行员，但这并不能解决其所谓的将香港重建为航空枢纽的“当务之急”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“香港有很多飞行员可供选择，但国泰航空不准备按照市场价格支付经验费用，”工会主席 Paul Weatherilt 声称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司在回应中表示：“我们有足够的飞行员、机组人员和运营员工来支持我们当前的航班时刻表。我们相信，我们正在进行的培训、晋升和招聘计划将确保我们在重建过程中保持这种情况。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，该航空公司宣布今年将招募 800 名学员飞行员参加其培训计划， 2024年来自香港和中国大陆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Weatherilt指出，过去35年通过国泰计划培训的1,000名学员中，有135人晋升为机长。据工会称，学员通常需要 12 至 15 年才能成为合格机长。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国泰航空承诺今明两年聘用 800 名学员飞行员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他表示：“香港驾驶舱内缺乏经验丰富的飞行员，无法培养新一代飞行员，也无法恢复成为可与新加坡、广州和深圳等地竞争的航空枢纽。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空早前曾表示该公司表示，其合同除了削减住房和退休津贴外，还将飞行员的工资削减了约 40%，使薪酬待遇与新加坡航空等海外竞争对手的薪酬水平保持一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司已还表示，今年有望聘用 3,000 名员工，其中包括 700 名飞行员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空在 2020 年 10 月疫情期间不再认可空乘人员和飞行员工会，当时作为成本控制的一部分引入了新合同。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;国泰航空要求学员飞行员在香港机场与乘客合作&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;此前，该航空公司会与两个团体就加薪以及更改条款和条件进行谈判前线员工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空表示将通过内部渠道直接与员工沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空周五表示，其航班运力仅占疫情前的 50%。 3月底，目标是到年底达到70%，到2024年底达到100%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，人员短缺仍然是国泰航空和香港国际机场的主要障碍&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;工会表示，香港国泰航空已失去一半以上高级飞行员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该航空公司计划下个月从内地招聘 200 至 300 名空乘人员，目标是未来预计还会增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府计划为航空业引进约 6,300 名人员，这是为人员短缺行业引进 20,000 名工人的更广泛计划的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空最近推出了一系列措施来提振士气，例如调整飞行员和机组人员的薪酬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空的初级飞行员有机会申请在该航空公司的廉价航空香港飞行国泰航空担任副机长两年，成功的候选人即可加入该级别的主要航空公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，国泰集团表示预计将在 2023 年上半年实现盈利，因为该航空公司受益于强劲的旅行需求，而机票价格比大流行之前更高。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[France riots: how teen Nahel’s killing is focusing anger on police tactics]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226056/france-riots-how-teen-nahels-killing-focusing-anger-police-tactics?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 13:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_analysis/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/6321446a-6db8-4f53-bdd4-e98c520bc894_93096a9a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;本周巴黎郊外一名 17 岁青少年被警察枪杀的事件已经确定法国郊区发生了大范围的骚乱，抗议者焚烧汽车、垃圾和建筑物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这起杀戮事件还引发了人们的疑问：法国自 2005 年遭受数周城市骚乱以来是否未能继续前进。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;这名名叫纳赫尔（Nahel）的青少年被枪击事件被录像记录下来，震惊了全国。它激起了警察和贫困社区年轻人之间长期存在的紧张关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还促使人们呼吁彻底改革警察使用武器的条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;13据警方称，去年有人因在交通堵塞期间不遵守命令而在警察枪击事件中丧生。今年，包括纳赫尔（Nahel）在内的三人在类似情况下死亡，纳赫尔在接到命令时没有停下来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更普遍的是，因拒绝遵守命令而被警察杀害的人数为在增加。据警方统计，2021 年有四人在这种情况下被杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;抗议活动愈演愈烈，杀害法国青少年的警察向家人表示歉意&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在接下来的几个小时内纳赫尔去世后，法国下议院议长雅埃尔·布劳恩-皮维 (Yael Braun-Pivet) 表示，她准备重新评估一项管理警察使用枪支的法律的执行情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法律于 2017 年通过法国发生一系列极端主义袭击事件后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后，当司机不遵守命令且可能危及生命时，执法人员可以向车辆开枪&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就纳赫尔的案件而言，在初步调查得出“不符合合法使用武器的条件”后，开枪致死的警官将因故意杀人罪受到调查”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在法律出台之前，警察必须证明自卫才能证明使用枪支的合理性。自该法案生效以来，他们被授权向“其乘员可能在飞行中对其生命或人身安全或他人实施攻击”的车辆开火。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内部安全代码然而，规定只有在“绝对必要且严格相称的情况下”才允许使用武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员 Sebastian Roché、Paul le Derff 和 Simon Varaine 进行了一项统计分析将死亡人数的增加与法律联系起来，称邻国并没有出现类似的枪击死亡人数增加的情况。他们还质疑警察缺乏适当的培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2017 年法律的这一变化与警察致命枪击事件的增加之间存在非常明显的相关性，”罗奇告诉 Le Nouvel Obs 媒体。 “平均而言，枪击事件增加了 25%，致命枪击事件增加了五倍。自2017年以来，警察的做法发生了明显的转变，警察枪击事件有所增加。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了致命枪击事件外，法国警察的暴力策略也经常受到批评。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;联合国成员国谴责法国种族主义和警察暴力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 2018 年开始的黄背心抗议活动中，一位欧洲高级官员批评法国当局对反政府抗议活动的处理方式，这些抗议活动震动了该国几个月来，敦促他们“更加尊重人权”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国警方还因其对在法兰西体育场举行的 2022 年欧洲冠军联赛决赛的处理而受到严厉批评。圣但尼郊区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比赛前几个小时，警方对在拥挤、缓慢移动的队伍中被困的球迷使用了催泪瓦斯，比赛最终推迟了约 40 分钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，在反对提高退休年龄的示威浪潮中，法国警方因对抗议者过于严厉的说法而受到打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际特赦组织、国际人权联合会和欧洲委员会 –欧洲大陆主要人权机构 - 等组织都指出法国警察过度使用武力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳赫尔死后开始的法国郊区骚乱并非史无前例。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;炊具在法国反马克龙抗议活动中被禁止，招致嘲笑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;早在 2005 年，17 岁的齐德·本纳 (Zyed Benna) 和 15 岁的布纳·特拉奥雷 (Bouna Traore) 在巴黎郊区的一个变电站躲避警察后触电身亡。克利希苏布瓦在法国各地引发了三周的骚乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国范围内的骚乱在拥有大量少数民族人口的陷入困境的社区的住房项目中肆虐。尽管这些问题源于青少年的死亡，但更深层次的歧视、失业和与法国社会的疏离感等问题加剧了这些问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近二十年后，这些问题和不公正感仍然根深蒂固。在法国社会。不过，对骚乱的反应可能会有所不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2005 年没有视频，骚乱也没有这次蔓延得那么快。社交媒体也放大了最新的杀戮事件。但是，尽管 2005 年法国政府根据紧急状态法采取了残酷的应对措施，加剧了人们的愤怒，但法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙一直小心翼翼地不与任何人对抗，以避免暴力爆发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;马克龙的第一反应是说纳赫尔的死“不可原谅”。这段视频让他和他的部长们无法辩称枪击事件是正当的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，在骚乱的前两个晚上，警察在使用武力方面表现出了克制。此外，司法决定对主要嫌疑人提出故意杀人的初步指控，并继续拘留他，这可能有助于缓解紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被拘留警官的律师在法国电视频道 BFMTV 上发表讲话，该官员表示抱歉并“感到震惊”。律师洛朗-弗兰克·利纳德 (Laurent-Franck Lienard) 告诉新闻媒体，这名警官当时做了他认为必要的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他早上起床不会去杀人，”利纳德谈到这名警官时说道，其姓名尚未公布。 “他真的不想杀人。但现在他必须为自己辩护，因为他是被拘留并睡在监狱里的人。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Canada’s Alberta province calls off partnership with Chinese private equity fund that sought to invest US$10 billion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3226055/canadas-alberta-province-calls-partnership-chinese-private-equity-fund-sought-invest-us10-billion?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 13:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/6706cd62-549f-46c7-8260-2cec0e566d2e_2154f523.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;艾伯塔省政府终止了与一家中国私募股权基金的合作关系，目标金额为 10 美元投资自然资源行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拿大阿尔伯塔省的非营利组织阿尔伯塔工业中心和香港私募股权公司Can-China Global Resource Fund ( CCGRF）于 2016 年宣布建立合作伙伴关系，以鼓励整个北美地区的投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种合作关系已不复存在，”该非营利组织的传播总监卡莉·康威 (Karlee Conway) 在给路透社的电子邮件回复中表示。该发言人没有回答有关合作关系为何以及何时被取消的询问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该基金的主要投资者是中国进出口银行、总部位于温哥华的矿业公司 Hunter Dickinson 和瑞士大宗商品交易商摩科瑞 (Mercuria)。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此前未报道的事态发展正值近年来中国和加拿大之间的紧张局势升级之际，尽管路透社采访的消息人士无法证实该基金的解散是否是其直接结果。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;负责管理投资的香港 MEC Advisory、CCGRF、摩科瑞、Hunter Dickinson 和进出口银行均未回复路透的电子邮件置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我无法确认这是多伦多大学政治学教授 Lynette Ong 表示：“这与双边关系直接相关，但这确实可能是两国之间紧张局势加剧的结果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，各省政府可能会觉得被迫遵守渥太华的官方立场，或者不要过多偏离公众舆论，因为这可能会带来风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该基金唯一已知的投资是以 7.22 亿加元（5.454 亿美元）收购CQ Energy 成立于 2017 年，总部位于卡尔加里，是一家私营天然气生产服务公司。 The status of this investment is unknown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Diplomatic ties between Beijing and Ottawa started to worsen after Canada arrested Huawei Technologies CFO Meng Wanzhou in 2018 at the request of the United States. Following Meng&#39;s arrest, China detained two Canadian citizens accusing them of spying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While all three were released in 2021, the relationship between China and Canada has not returned to normal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The oil-rich province of Alberta exported C$4.5 billion worth of goods to China in 2020, making it the Canadian province&#39;s second-biggest export market. Some of China&#39;s large state oil companies expanded into Alberta before the collapse of oil prices in 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A person aware of the fund told Reuters that the US$10 billion target was for marketing purposes and the first stage of the investment was no more than US$1 billion. A person added that Exim Bank started looking into the structure of the fund “after it suffered big losses” and they sent a representative from Beijing to divest on certain projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CCGRF was set up in 2013 as part of a bilateral discussion between the governments of Canada and China to encourage investments of public and private capital into Canada&#39;s natural resources sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rift between the two countries widened since Meng&#39;s arrest. Last year, Canada forced three Chinese state investors to sell out of Canadian critical mining companies, as it tries to wean off its dependency on China in its critical mining sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This month, Canada froze ties with the China-led Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank as it launched an investigation into allegations that the institution was dominated by the Chinese Communist Party.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong out of ‘political quagmire’ and should not go down wrong path again, Beijing’s top man in city says in lead-up to July 1 celebrations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3226057/hong-kong-out-political-quagmire-and-should-not-go-down-wrong-path-again-beijings-top-man-city-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 13:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/059d2bec-8db1-42cb-ae48-c348983d6a08_591311ac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong has gradually “walked out of a political quagmire” and should not head in the wrong direction again, Beijing&#39;s top man in the city has said while calling for the financial hub to seize opportunities amid geopolitical tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zheng Yanxiong, director of the central government&#39;s liaison office, on Friday also hailed the return of a “lovely Hong Kong” at an event to launch a series of celebrations marking the July 1 anniversary of the city&#39;s return to Chinese rule.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Over the past year, the country&#39;s sovereignty, security and development interests have been effectively safeguarded. Hong Kong has gradually walked out of the quagmire of political spirals. The familiar and lovely Hong Kong we have seen in the past is back,” he told the audience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must all be aware that Hong Kong can no longer go in the wrong direction and create chaos. It cannot be used or deceived by others.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing imposed the national security law on Hong Kong in 2020 as its response to the months-long anti-government protests a year before, which rewrote the city&#39;s political landscape. The sweeping law marked its third anniversary on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zheng also praised the accomplishments of the “pragmatic and hardworking” government under Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu, saying that geopolitical changes, as well as the “global technology and industrial revolutions”, had provided immense opportunities for Hong Kong “to rise again”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Senior Beijing official urges Hong Kong to seize advantage of &#39;superconnector&#39; role&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong must steer the changes, dare to compete, take part in the restructuring of the world&#39;s interest pattern, actively integrate into national development, and shine through Chinese-style modernisation,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that the city could only go far “by maintaining the advantages of internationalisation” and the practice of “one country, two systems”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing&#39;s new top official in Hong Kong promotes city&#39;s special role&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Speaking at the same event, Lee said the city had become more attractive as it was “safeguarded” by the security law and the principle of “patriots ruling Hong Kong”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong is our common home and everyone is responsible for safeguarding the city,” Lee said, highlighting that “national security had been prioritised” in the past year under his watch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He told pro-establishment figures in the audience to “unite social forces” and contribute to the country&#39;s high-quality development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Past July 1 anniversaries of the handover had been marked by a massive annual march for greater democracy, held by the now-defunct Civil Human Rights Front, until the Covid-19 pandemic hit in 2020. Protests had also become rare after the security law took effect in the same year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year&#39;s anniversary will be marked by celebrative events organised by the government and pro-Beijing groups, with many coordinated by the Hong Kong Celebrations Association, headed by Tam Kam-kau, a deputy of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Exhibitions showcasing cultures of three mainland Chinese provinces, Shaanxi, Shandong and Liaoning will be held from Friday through July 2 in Victoria Park in Causeway Bay, where pro-democratic groups used to organise July 1 rallies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Accompanying the exhibitions will be an expo on technological achievements of firms based in Hong Kong&#39;s neighbouring mainland cities and Macau, and another on local culture.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will a 2-month shopping festival boost Hong Kong&#39;s retail, catering sectors?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, 26 fisherman boats flying the national and city flags will sail in Victoria Harbour as a part of the celebrations on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier, Lee had already announced citywide festivities to mark the anniversary, including free rides and entry to museums, alongside shopping discounts.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong catering sector banking on 2-month shopping festival to bring 20 per cent business surge as part of July 1 celebrations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3226046/hong-kong-catering-sector-banking-2-month-shopping-festival-bring-20-cent-business-surge-part-july-1?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 12:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/862999e6-5c22-4d7e-aca4-8f66597f824e_c38ee576.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s catering sector is banking on a two-month shopping festival to bring a 20 per cent surge in business, with the event part of July 1 celebrations to mark the 26th anniversary of the city&#39;s return to Chinese rule.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 1,500 restaurants will offer reduced prices on selected menu items on Saturday, with some eateries observing a 29 per cent discount – meaning “paying 71 per cent of the price” – a play on the “7/1” date.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The promotions, together with free rides and museum visits, were announced by the city&#39;s leader earlier this month. Sources said the drive would provide a boost for the recovering economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Leung Chun-wah, chairman of the Association for Hong Kong Catering Services Management Ltd, on Friday said it was difficult for the sector to offer discounts of nearly 30 per cent, as the profits on individual orders could only be 5 to 8 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some eateries do not mind having no profits at all as they want residents to dine happily,” he told a radio programme, stressing it was voluntary for outlets to offer discounts.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong retailers to offer HK$150 million in discounts, deals to get people smiling&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said sales in the catering sector had only hit 80 or 90 per cent of pre-pandemic levels, voicing hope the latest promotions and a second instalment of consumption vouchers on July 16 could boost the ailing industry by up to 20 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have so few customers after 8.30pm as their lifestyles have changed after the pandemic … Residents are sleeping earlier than before,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung added that another challenge was the 15 to 20 per cent rise in wages after the pandemic due to hiring difficulties, attributing this to an emigration wave that had seen hundreds of thousands of residents leave the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong fans snap up 14,000 free tickets in minutes for Harbour Chill Carnival&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Annie Tse Yau On-yee, chairwoman of the Hong Kong Retail Management Association, told the same radio show she hoped the “Happy Hong Kong Shopping Festival”, which kicks off on Saturday and will ride on the second phase of the consumption voucher scheme, would boost the weak retail market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tse said the buying power of tourists had dropped nearly 20 per cent compared with pre-pandemic levels, although visitor arrivals were picking up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sector had also been hit by reduced local spending, she noted. “After the border reopened, more Hong Kong residents are travelling. Compared with before when Hongkongers stayed in the city to spend, the local consumption market is quite weak now,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Happy go ducky Hong Kong prepares for rubber ducks&#39; voyage to harbour on June 10&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;More than 150 brands and 6,000 retail stores will join the shopping festival, with free cups of coffee and prizes up for grabs, as well as a chance for a one-minute shopping spree at supermarkets. The promotions are part of the two-month event by the retail sector, which is offering HK$150 million in discounts, bonuses and other goodies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The festival, which ends on August 31, will divide promotional activities into four categories that each span two weeks. They are: department stores and home goods;超市、便利店和餐馆；电子产品和珠宝； and cosmetics, health foods and fashion.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China pumps out half of world’s energy storage research as US share declines]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3226010/china-pumps-out-half-worlds-energy-storage-research-us-share-declines?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 12:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/5b683bf9-9e8b-4d17-ba2a-dc8579289a6d_dcac37d2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China accounted for 50 per cent of the world&#39;s research papers into energy storage technology published last year, an increase of five per cent on 2021, according to a report by a team of researchers from a number of Chinese universities and institutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In contrast, contributions by US scientists made up 10.5 per cent of papers on the subject in 2022, a two per cent fall on the previous year&#39;s figures, the researchers said, in a paper published by the journal Energy Storage Science and Technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has become the “most active country in the world in energy storage fields on all three aspects of fundamental study, technical research, integration and application”, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The researchers searched the Web of Science index using the keywords “energy storage” as part of the study, which provides an overview of China&#39;s research advancements in the field.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is already the world&#39;s leader in renewable energy installations and is also leading in energy storage, with a capacity of 59.8 gigawatts at the end of 2022, according to the China Energy Storage Alliance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most of China&#39;s electricity is derived from coal and energy storage is key to the country meeting its net zero goals. But a lack of large-scale methods of increasing capacity is hampering the total generation potential of existing renewable projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s new energy storage capacity to surpass 50GW by 2025&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For example, solar energy accounts for 16.6 per cent of China&#39;s installed power generation capacity but is delivering just 2.73 per cent of usable electricity to the grid, as of the first quarter of 2o23, according to the National Energy Administration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China remains reliant on pumped hydropower for its energy storage and leads the world in continuing to build facilities based on the technology. In 2022, the highest proportion of new storage capacity was derived from hydropower, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While China has the largest pumped hydropower storage capacity in the world, its primary research focus has been on other methods, such as a variety of battery-based tools as well as thermal and flywheel technologies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most of the research papers released in 2021 focused on alternatives to pumped hydropower, according to last year&#39;s report, a situation that continued in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US – which continues to rank among the top spots for energy storage – launched an initiative in 2020 to maintain its global position. The Energy Storage Grand Challenge goal is for all of the United States&#39; storage technologies to be produced domestically by 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has greater access to the materials and means of production than the US, but is still grappling with the issue of scalability if it is to meet the storage demands of existing renewable installations and their energy output, the researchers found.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Development of new renewable facilities has continued in China, despite the fact that the current energy output of solar and wind projects is not being fully harnessed, according to the National Energy Administration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the increase in research and a rise in patents relating to energy storage highlighted in the report suggests that the scientific community is prioritising innovation to help China expand its large-scale capacity.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why safe and sustainable energy storage is key to China&#39;s climate goals&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to the report, 100 megawatt projects are becoming the norm in China, where many developments are under way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese Academy of Sciences was responsible for one of a number of innovative advancements in 2022, with its research into a 300MW compressed air storage system, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The researchers said China will remain dominant in global rankings for published research, patent applications and the installation of energy storage capacity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Next year will continue to be an important one for the development of energy storage and China&#39;s technology in the field is expected to be the world&#39;s best in the coming five to 10 years, they said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Koran burning in Sweden angers Muslim world. The man who did it plans to do it again]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226031/koran-burning-sweden-angers-muslim-world-man-who-did-it-plans-do-it-again?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/c431d133-c093-4b56-bb2a-1a648f6b4817_5a2e6e59.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Several Muslim-majority countries condemned the burning of a Koran outside a mosque in Stockholm and castigated Swedish diplomats, saying the act incites hatred and should not count as free speech.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The protests came after an Iraqi citizen living in Sweden, Salwan Momika, 37, stomped on the Islamic holy book and set several pages alight in front of the Swedish capital&#39;s largest mosque on Wednesday, the first day of Muslims&#39; Eid al-Adha holiday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Within 10 days I will burn the Iraqi flag and the Koran in front of Iraq&#39;s embassy in Stockholm,” Momika told a Swedish newspaper late Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Swedish police had granted him a permit in line with free-speech protections, but authorities later said they had opened an investigation over “agitation” against an ethnic or national group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prime Minister Ulf Kristersson called the burning “legal but not appropriate”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident could pose a serious problem for Sweden&#39;s Nato membership application, which they submitted more than a year ago and has been held up partly because of similar incidents in the past.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Malaysian Muslims take to streets to protest Koran burning in Sweden&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Saudi Arabia, Islam&#39;s birthplace, said it strongly condemned the burning of the Koran.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These hateful and repeated acts cannot be accepted under any justifications. They explicitly incite hatred, exclusion and racism,” the monarchy&#39;s foreign ministry added in a statement on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Iran summoned the Swedish chargé d&#39;affaires to express its outrage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The burning of Islam&#39;s holy book was particularly offensive because it came at the time of the haj pilgrimage, the foreign ministry added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Muslim world categorically condemns insult to holy scriptures &amp; Quran,” the Islamic Republic&#39;s Foreign Minister Hussein Amirabdollahian tweeted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Allowing sacrilege &amp; insult to Quran under any justification by Sweden is unacceptable,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Misusing democracy &amp; freedom for such behaviour would just only incite terrorism &amp; extremism. The West only burns its fingers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lebanon&#39;s pro-Iran Hezbollah movement, in a statement, called on Islamic governments to take all steps to prompt other countries to “prevent the recurrence of these follies on their soil and to stop spreading the culture of hatred and rancour”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Arab League, a regional organisation, said its chief Ahmed Aboul Gheit strongly condemned Swedish authorities&#39; permission for the act.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Egypt called the Koran burning “a disgraceful act provoking Muslims&#39; feelings around the world”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Sweden links recent riots to criminal gangs that target police&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Iraq, protesters gathered outside the Swedish embassy in Baghdad on Thursday, the official Iraqi news agency INA reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the rally, some protesters raised copies of the holy Muslim book in a show of reverence, the agency added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Influential Shiite Muslim cleric Muqtada al-Sadr is said to have called for the protest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local media reported that the demonstrators demanded the expulsion of the Swedish ambassador.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Iraq&#39;s independent website Alsumaria News reported that the protesters briefly stormed the embassy before retreating. They are said to have managed to break through the gate to the premises.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Swedish foreign ministry said the embassy employees reported that they are safe. The ministry is in constant contact with them, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jordan&#39;s foreign ministry said it had summoned the Swedish ambassador in Amman in a protest against the “Swedish government&#39;s permission for extremists” to burn the Koran.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ministry condemned it as an act of “racism and hate”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Similarly, the United Arab Emirates said it had summoned the Swedish ambassador in the Gulf country and handed her a protest note.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Moroccan foreign ministry also summoned Sweden&#39;s charge d&#39;affaires in Rabat and told the diplomat how appalled Morocco was at “this unacceptable deed”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sweden&#39;s Nato bid, spurred by Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine despite long-held Swedish neutrality, is still being blocked by Turkey, a largely Muslim country, and Hungary. New members must be approved unanimously by all existing Nato members.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Anti-Nato protest sweeps Stockholm despite Ankara&#39;s warning&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan condemned Sweden for allowing someone to burn a Koran.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Those who allow these under the pretext of freedom of expression and turn a blind eye to this viciousness, as well as those who have committed this crime, will not reach their goals,” Erdogan said in video message marking the Muslim Eid holiday, without specifying which goals he meant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However on Wednesday Erdogan stressed in a phone call with German Chancellor Olaf Scholz that Sweden should not expect a green light from Turkey for its Nato accession any time soon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a statement from the Turkish communications office, Erdogan said to Scholz that although Stockholm had been taking steps in the right direction, there were still “unacceptable” circumstances.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These, he said, included the authorisation of demonstrations at which “terror propaganda” was being spread.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anti-Islam protests in Sweden have caused considerable tensions between Stockholm and Ankara in recent months. Swedish police authorised the latest protest at the mosque after similar actions had been banned in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;dpa, Agence France-Presse, Reuters and Bloomberg&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>