<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[UK braces for new waves of Channel asylum seekers with barge and barracks plan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225652/uk-braces-new-waves-channel-asylum-seekers-barge-and-barracks-plan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 10:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/c4cdb8f1-1e4d-4aa9-86b7-4f97aa3a08fe_898fe52b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英国预计将有数千名寻求庇护者乘小船抵达，并已宣布了多项计划，将无证移民转移到未使用的军事基地和大型住宿驳船。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国内政部数据显示，2023 年迄今已有超过 11,000 人穿越英吉利海峡，其中本月约有 3,300 人在温暖的天气下穿越英吉利海峡天气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月 11 日星期日是今年单日穿越人数最多的一天，有 549 人乘坐小艇和旧渔船冒险穿越英吉利海峡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寻求庇护者英国保守党政府承诺“截停船只”并将一些非法入境者送往卢旺达，但他们似乎并没有被吓倒。去年，据记录从法国穿越英吉利海峡的人数达到了前所未有的 45,755 人。这比 2021 年的 28,000 人和 2020 年的 8,500 人有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寻求来英国的人中约有一半来自冲突地区，其中阿富汗位居榜首。据内政部称，虽然去年阿尔巴尼亚人的激增有所下降，但印度人是最近抵达的人之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟是穿越地中海这一最危险的移民海域的寻求庇护者的另一个首选目的地&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;抗议者谴责英国阻止移民穿越英吉利海峡的计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在英国，数以万计的寻求庇护者住在临时住所，等待移民决定。索赔，这可能需要数年时间。住宿包括酒店，英国纳税人每天花费近 600 万英镑（750 万美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以阻止小船为旗舰政策，首相里希·苏纳克 (Rishi Sunak) 的政府希望结束对酒店的依赖以节省金钱并阻止更多寻求庇护者前来。如果 2023 年的数字与去年持平，那么到今年年底，自 2020 年以来到达海峡的游客总数将超过 125,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这些计划面临人权组织和地方当局的抵制。由于地方当局的反对，在利物浦附近为寻求庇护者停靠一艘游轮的提议被取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在伦敦皇家码头停泊一艘游轮的提议遭到皇家码头管理当局的反对后被取消和伦敦市长办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伦敦工党市长萨迪克·汗本月表示：“逃离可怕环境的弱势群体将无法获得他们所需的支持”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宣布了一项计划Bibby Stockholm 驳船将于 4 月份在英格兰南海岸的多塞特港停靠至少 18 个月，但由于该船正在进行改装，因此比原计划晚了几周。反恐警察在该船停靠的地方进行了不明原因的演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这艘驳船有 222 间卧室，可容纳 500 名单身男性寻求庇护者。该计划遭到了保守党管理的多塞特郡议会和当地保守党议员理查德·德拉克斯的反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当他们离开港口时——如果他们确实能出去的话，因为这艘驳船只不过是一个准监狱——当他们进入韦茅斯（最近的城镇）时，他们会做什么？谁来监视他们？”德拉克斯本月在 LBC 电台谈到寻求庇护者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寻求庇护者不得在英国工作或选择居住地。人权组织表示，驳船不适合逃离冲突或苦难的人们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将数千名移民转移到旧皇家空军 (RAF) 基地军营的计划也遭到了反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;h3>;英国旨在通过“明确危险”广告活动来阻止阿尔巴尼亚难民&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“很明显，政府使用废弃的军营和空军基地是为了迎合最低限度的普通民众英国难民慈善机构 Care4Calais 的首席执行官史蒂夫·史密斯 (Steve Smith) 表示：办公室的提议是在巨大的帐篷里安置寻求庇护者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自由民主党领导的委员会正在试图阻止在林肯郡的皇家空军斯坎普顿建立设施的提议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些寻求庇护者已经住在埃塞克斯韦瑟斯菲尔德的英国皇家空军基地，在那里，愤怒的当地人在极右翼团体的支持下举行了示威活动。该地区的保守党议员、英国移民部长罗伯特·詹里克 (Robert Jenrick) 发现自己与威胁要起诉政府的当地党员意见不合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然这些废弃的军事设施曾经驻扎着英国军队，但它们长期以来一直被废弃。空置且年久失修，濒临废弃，”史密斯说。 “明显的安全措施、共享的居住区以及与更广泛社区的隔离相结合，导致住宿完全不适合战争、冲突、酷刑、贩运和迫害的幸存者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;庇护申请人的数量根据政府数据，截至今年 3 月 31 日，这一数字从 2020 年的 40,830 人增加到 133,607 人。反对党工党将庇护申请积压的主要原因归咎于内政部的裁员和招聘问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一个没有得到充分解决的根本问题是庇护申请积压，我们面临的情况是，庇护申请的数量牛津大学移民观察站副主任 Robert McNeil 表示：“等待批准或拒绝庇护的人数呈螺旋式上升。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;移民是导致 2016 年英国脱欧的一个主要问题，导致英国结束了来自欧盟的人员的自由流动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英国计划在移民风潮中限制外国学生&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，随着学生人数激增和英国的发展，2022 年净移民人数达到创纪录的 606,000 人为逃离乌克兰战争的人和来自香港的英国国民（海外）护照持有者发放签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两年前推出的伦敦快速居留计划已帮助至少 105,200 名香港人抵达英国据英国政府称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了阻止非法移民的流动，苏纳克的保守党政府提议将一些乘小船抵达英国的移民送往卢旺达，他们的庇护申请将在那里进行处理。获得庇护的人将留在非洲国家，而不是返回英国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非法移民法案目前正在上议院审议。它被难民委员会贴上“残酷和肮脏”的标签，并陷入法律挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国政府辩称，其驱逐政策将阻止偷运移民跨越英吉利海峡的犯罪团伙。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政策制定者承诺解决这些问题有点不诚实，因为他们没有解决这些问题的工具。这些都是棘手的情况，仅靠国家政策无法解决。”麦克尼尔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前往英国的航程往往是漫长而危险的旅程的最后一站，一艘移民船在英国海域沉没的悲剧凸显了这一点。 6 月 14 日，希腊海岸。这艘船离开利比亚后沉没，据信船上有数百人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;八天后，一艘从突尼斯出发的移民船在意大利岛屿附近倾覆。兰佩杜萨岛，造成 40 多人失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2014 年以来，联合国已记录地中海中部地区有超过 21,000 人死亡和失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布鲁塞尔将责任归咎于人口走私但许多非政府组织和人权组织指责“欧洲堡垒”政策，这些政策凸显了难民在欧洲寻求保护时缺乏合法途径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在英国，“小船”问题已成为最重要的问题。保守党右翼的心头大患。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 2022 年，欧洲有 21 个国家接收的寻求庇护者数量超过英国。英国（74,751 人）落后于德国（296,555 人）、法国（根据内政部的数据，英国（170,705）和西班牙（128,015）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“英国政府不能继续利用该国的岛屿地位来逃避保护难民的国际责任，”史密斯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“英国政府不能继续利用该国的岛屿地位来逃避保护难民的国际责任。” >;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net NET&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/分区>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[First US M&A reforms in 45 years will crack down on illegal mergers but also delay deals by months]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3225650/first-us-ma-reforms-45-years-will-crack-down-illegal-mergers-also-delay-deals-months?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 10:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/967d8934-dc86-4325-810f-484bbffb3af7_13aff7b2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国反垄断机构要求企业上交的交易信息比之前对合并规则进行了彻底改革，这可能会使交易延迟数月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所谓的哈特-斯科特-罗迪诺备案程序的改革，是司法部和联邦贸易委员会打击的举措据一项估计，有关非法合并的调查可能会使交易时间表增加两到三个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些机构表示，这是 45 年来的第一次全面改革，将使他们能够“更有效地周二发布的拟议变更将于本周晚些时候在《联邦公报》上公布，其中要求提供有关过去 10 年收购的详细信息以及有关公司高管、董事和高管的信息。董事会观察员，以及公司员工的数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各机构将在 60 天内就拟议的变更征求公众意见。新规则要等到联邦贸易委员会和司法部发布最终版本后才会生效，预计需要几个月的时间才能完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新文件还要求披露赠款和贷款等补贴某些外国政府，包括朝鲜、中国、俄罗斯和伊朗。国会于 12 月通过了一项法律，要求各机构开始收集有关外国政府补贴的信息，因为担心中国等国家可能通过向某些公司提供财务支持来扭曲竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联邦贸易委员会估计了这份 126 页的文件将使公司准备备案所需的时间增加 100 多个小时，他们表示目前需要大约 37 个小时才能完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，彭博资讯高级分析师 Jennifer Rie 表示公司可能需要比这更长的时间来汇编各机构现在寻求的所有信息和分析。 Rie 表示，如今，一家律师事务所可以在 7 到 10 天内完成寻求反垄断批准的公司合并的文书工作。她表示，拟议的变更可能会延长该流程数月的时间，从而使美国的合并申报制度更加符合欧洲的规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在考虑将流程从 10 天改为 2-在加入 Bloomberg Intelligence 之前，Rie 从事了 10 年的反垄断法工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;长江和记、沃达丰将合并各部门，组建英国最大的移动提供商&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;反垄断支持者称赞这些变化是急需的更新，将帮助执法者更好地调查交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去 45 年中，并购格局发生了巨大变化，HSR 备案流程是反垄断组织美国经济自由项目的克里斯塔·布朗 (Krista Brown) 表示：“合并审查——应该反映出这一点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据美国法律，价值超过 1.114 亿美元的交易必须通知联邦贸易委员会和司法部，并等待 30 天。关闭。绝大多数合并不会引起任何担忧，并在初始等待期结束后完成。但这些机构可以要求提供更多信息，从而引发对交易的深入调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2021 财年（各机构公布数据的最后一年）报告的 3,520 笔交易中，联邦贸易委员会和司法部要求提供其中 65 家（约 1.9%）的更多信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在阻止平安瓜分香港顶级银行后，汇丰银行下一步将何去何从？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;今天的文件大多需要一份- 以及两个词的回应，彭博社的 Rie 表示，而新提案将要求公司提供交易的叙述性摘要，并概述公司竞争的业务领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这增加了交易的可能性不会在雷达下飞行，”她说。 “你正在为他们安排竞争重叠。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 FTC 官员表示，此次改革旨在帮助保护机构资源，并减少在前 30 天内要求提供更多文件或信息的需要。这位未获授权公开发言的人士表示，美国机构与包括欧盟、英国和加拿大在内的其他司法管辖区进行了磋商，以了解他们预先需要哪些有关交易的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位官员表示，美国机构认为新表格不会改变引发深入调查的交易数量。但该人士表示，他们预计强化后的表格可能会减少所谓的“撤回和重新提交”，指的是一种常用的技术，即公司撤回其文件并再次提交，以便向联邦贸易委员会或司法部提供额外的 30 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，各机构转向分级收费制度，最小的交易需支付 3 万美元进行合并审查，而最大的交易则必须支付 225 万美元。 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan’s surprise state-backed buyout of chip materials maker JSR hints at further ‘protection’-minded acquisitions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3225586/japans-surprise-state-backed-buyout-chip-materials-maker-jsr-hints-further-protection-minded?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/aadef3f0-25dd-4e65-b7f8-85e55cb194a9_f0ff9896.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;本周突然宣布大型半导体材料制造商 JSR Corp 将被收购日本投资公司 (JIC) 是一家强大的政府支持基金，令行业观察人士措手不及。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但观察人士表示，在全球半导体行业紧张局势日益加剧之际，周一的发展是有道理的 - 而且很可能是许多类似交易中的第一个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JSR 在召开董事会会议讨论 JIC 的报价后确认了该交易，JIC 由贸易部监管。该基金的大股东是政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;媒体报道称，JSR 最初与该公司接洽时提出了该提案的概要，该提案周二对该公司的估值为 9,090 亿日元（63 亿美元），较之前的估值有了显着提高。截至周五晚间东京交易收盘，市场对其价值的估计约为 47 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JSR 在日本和海外开展业务，占据全球光刻胶市场 30% 的份额光刻胶是一种对半导体制造至关重要的化学试剂，日本在这一领域处于世界领先地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;光刻胶应用于硅片，硅片用于集成电路并提高半导体的性能。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在周一晚间的新闻发布会上，JSR 首席执行官埃里克·约翰逊 (Eric Johnson) 表示，随着研发成本的增加和竞争对手的进步，公司一段时间以来已经认识到重组的必要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道作为一家政府支持的实体，半个多世纪前开始生产合成橡胶的 JSR 将能够进行必要的改革，同时也有助于更广泛地推动该行业的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;芯片在英特尔 500 亿美元行动的带动下，这场竞赛引发了消费热潮&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;从日本政府的角度来看，此次收购完全符合保护国家现有先进技术和开发下一代能力的积极政策。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;随着美国和中国在半导体领域的对峙以及芯片日益成为对日本经济安全至关重要的战略商品，政府干预的必要性变得更加迫切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本首相岸田文雄6 月 21 日在东京举行的新闻发布会上表示，“确保日本半导体技术的工业基础至关重要，不仅是为了增强产业竞争力，而且从脱碳和经济安全的角度来看也是如此”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东京大学科技政策教授铃木一人表示，他认为这笔交易“让所有人感到惊讶，但是，当你仔细观察时，就会发现政府采取这一步骤的原因是可以理解的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“政府希望保护重要技术免遭潜在的外国收购，特别是来自中国的技术，并保护这些公司免遭商业投资者的潜在拆散，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道，JSR Corp 在全球光刻胶市场上占据如此主导地位，显然属于国家战略利益的范畴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府显然也希望保护和维持这种市场优势。” ，因此这不仅仅是保护技术的问题，也是保留市场份额的问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东京麦格理集团日本股票研究主管达米安·通 (Damian Thong) 表示，世界各国政府正在介入保护他们的半导体产业。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;不断上升的产业政策如何赋予亚利桑那州经济实力来获得台积电交易&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这一消息让我们感到惊讶，但我绝对认为将会有更多地关注这一领域的发展，特别是在某些瓶颈能力领域，”他说。 “想要加强这些行业的不仅是政府，还有投资者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道，在关键技术领域，没有人能够承受落后的后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本政府于 6 月初更新了涵盖半导体和电子行业的战略，设定了将半导体产品国内年销售额增加三倍至超过 15 万亿日元（1,044 亿美元）的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东京还向国内外公司提供慷慨的财政支持，以建立制造工厂，台积电于 6 月初宣布将开始在日本南部的熊本建设第二家工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;政府正在为该公司在该县的第一家工厂提供 4,760 亿日元（33 亿美元）的资金援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多其他开发项目也在进行中，包括去年建立的工厂半导体制造商 Rapidus Corp 的年度投资项目，并获得八家日本科技公司的额外资金，用于在北海道建设最先进的生产工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据本周协议的条款，JIC 将推出一位政府消息人士向《朝日新闻》透露，12 月将进行每股 4,350 日元（30 美元）的要约收购，JSR 将在下一财年从东京证券交易所退市。日本政府已采取行动确保一个组织能够履行重要的国家政策角色，这表明未来可能会发生更多类似的收购。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“下一轮很可能会看到政府采取行动保护那些生产先进半导体所需的材料，因为它需要保持其在市场上的优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore jails Indonesian who filmed himself having sex with 76 women without their consent]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225647/singapore-jails-indonesian-who-filmed-himself-having-sex-76-women-without-their-consent?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/a78e5253-0da4-4ec8-8a88-2cef32db6eb8_0b52cf45.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在使用约会应用程序认识新加坡的各种女性后，Johan Wijaya 拍摄了她们与&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在调查过程中，警方在约翰的设备上发现了 76 名女性受害者的录音，这些录音在五年内被拍摄。并非所有指控都针对印度尼西亚人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，32 岁的约翰是该城邦的永久居民，在承认五项偷窥罪后，被判处八个月监禁。量刑期间还考虑了其​​他十一项类似指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约翰在 Tinder 和 OkCupid 等应用程序上与这些女性见面后，他会在亲自与她们见面之前询问她们是否愿意建立随意的关系。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在与他在家里或经济型酒店遇到的女性发生性行为之前，约翰会打开隐藏在便携式充电器内的摄像机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女人洗澡或者上厕所的时候，他会把充电宝的充电器对着床。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于录音时充电宝没有发光，所以女人不会注意到。全程录制视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约翰会将视频保存在他的笔记本电脑或硬盘上，并注明受害者的姓名以及拍摄日期，以便他稍后观看。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;h3>;电视节目临时演员拍摄了在新加坡入狱的演员的小便池照片&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据法院命令，受害者的姓名不得公开，以保护他们的身份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约翰，他的法庭文件中没有说明职业，也没有向第三方传播视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;副检察官秦金成准备的法庭文件称，2021年1月6日，Johan结识了一个25年的——通过约会应用程序与老妇联系后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两人决定几天后见面发生性关系，然后同意每周见面一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这些会议期间， Johan 会在未经该女子同意的情况下使用移动电源充电器中的摄像头记录他们的亲密行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这导致总共 16 个视频显示该女子全裸，脸部和生殖器可见。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;该女子最初并不知道这些录音，并就约翰使用手机录制的另一段录音向警方提交了报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭文件没有详细说明导致这一情况的原因。 ”房东因 Wi-Fi 速度慢&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;共提取了 391 个视频，其中 336 个包含偷窥内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些视频还涉及 76 名受害者，其中包括 25-岁的受害者和其他四名受害者，他们的待遇是对约翰提出的指控的主题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约翰最终承认这些视频是他与不同性伴侣的性活动的录音，而这些性伴侣并不同意这些录音，并且&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还承认，带摄像头的移动电源充电器是在2017年购买的，用于秘密录制此类视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于每项偷窥罪，约翰可能会被判处最高两年监禁、罚款或鞭刑，或三者并用的处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文最初由 &lt;/p>; 发表</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Catching insects instead of fish’: video of man fishing next to bed in flooded home after heavy rain goes viral delighting Chinese social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3225448/catching-insects-instead-fish-video-man-fishing-next-bed-flooded-home-after-heavy-rain-goes-viral?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/592741d3-0d4c-4a49-969c-a43853db354f_9f3b0b3b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一段中国男子回家后在床边钓鱼的视频近日，湖北省武汉市的一位不愿透露姓名的男子，在最近的大雨导致他的家被淹后，开始在床边钓鱼，但他没有钓到鱼，只钓到了昆虫据澎湃新闻报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子的妻子董某拍摄了这段视频，并在网上分享了细节，称本月早些时候发生倾盆大雨时，他们正在家里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“哎呀”瞬间，我们家就被水淹没了。”董告诉澎湃新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;山洪爆发后，董说她的丈夫想到了钓鱼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他是一名钓鱼人。” ”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名男子将一根鱼线扔进洪水里想看看发生了什么，但经过半个多小时的多次尝试，他没有钓到任何鱼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们没有看到任何鱼，但确实看到了很多昆虫。”董补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事逗乐了中国的网上观察者，他们称赞这对夫妇的积极态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个人说：“拥有如此阳光态度的人，懂得如何生活。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个人写道：“男人很可爱，他的妻子也很可爱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br >;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/ a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan to get tactical boost with Nato’s Link 22 and US SeaGuardian drones: analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3225627/taiwan-get-tactical-boost-natos-link-22-and-us-seaguardian-drones-analysts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/5b683d59-6c7a-4254-8845-d7646d57e54e_cf5fbe4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾获得北约 Link 22 战术通信系统将增强该岛的防御能力，特别是在军事专家表示，计划增加四架美国先进监视和侦察无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾一名高级国防官员上个月证实，美国将帮助这个自治岛屿获得先进的数据链&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三年前美国国务院批准了价值 6 亿美元的交易后，台湾还预计在 2025 年接收强大的 MQ-9B SeaGuardian 无人机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，在与大陆发生冲突时，Link 22 对于台湾来说将是一项非常有价值的国防通信资产，因为台湾没有自己的卫星系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台湾获得北约的 Link 22 将使其能够运营MQ-9B SeaGuardian 无人机将由美国提供，”台北军事评论员池乐毅表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[美国]向台湾出售四架 MQ-9B 并收购 Link 22鉴于台湾与大陆之间军事冲突的风险日益增加，寻求支持可以被视为美国综合威慑战略的一部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Link 22是超视距通信平台北约成员国在联合行动中使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SeaGuardian 无人机的航程可达 6,000 公里（3,730 英里），飞行时间为 40 小时，预计将推动反潜行动&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五角大楼的综合威慑战略强调综合运用外交、经济治国手段和军事力量来威慑敌军的侵略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周晨鸣，北京研究院研究员远望军事科技智库表示，Link 22将帮助台北提高对抗冲突中通信干扰的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Link 22用于安全的空中和海上数据传输，主要是用于冗余增强，以发送联合作战图像等更大的数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾军方已经使用美国制造的 Link 16 系统来连接其美制武器系统，但它与其从法国购买的拉斐特级护卫舰和幻影 2000-5 战斗机等非美国武器系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但高雄台湾海军学院前教官卢立士表示台湾获得Link 22并不意味着北约会像一些台湾分析人士预期的那样自动允许台湾加入其通信系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据北约创始条约，集体防御原则将亚洲排除在外” ......作为核心成员的法国已表示反对将[联盟]扩展到亚洲，”陆说，并补充说，他认为法国和其他北约成员国不会与台湾分享他们的军事行动代码。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“美国希望台湾拥有Link 22，因为这是操作MQ-9B最方便、成本最低的措施，MQ-9B需要与卫星连接，而台湾没有自己的卫星系统。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陆说，虽然台湾可以升级其 Link 16 系统以连接 SeaGuardian 无人机，但这将要求该岛与美国共享其军事操作代码 - 台北不愿意这样做。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 上个月访问台湾时，曾于2017年至2020年担任太平洋地区海军陆战队司令的美国退役将军史蒂文·拉德表示，美国的最终目标是将台湾纳入其C4ISR系统，这是一种指挥机制，控制、通信、计算机、情报、监视和侦察。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong leader John Lee has hit nearly every goal for his first year in office, but what do residents think of his performance?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3225646/hong-kong-leader-john-lee-has-hit-nearly-every-goal-his-first-year-office-what-do-residents-think?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/1abbba0b-4369-4f8e-b06d-972b1936ce8b_a3cb5c1a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港领导人已实现了他在任期内承诺的几乎全部 68 个目标《华盛顿邮报》发现，他上任第一年，但观察人士警告说，居民的生活可能仍不会因此而变得更好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官李家超在竞选时承诺一种能够接受公众监督的“以结果为导向”的治理方法。他在10月份的施政报告中提出了近200个关键绩效指标（KPI），涵盖土地和住房、经济、医疗保健、福利、青年发展和公务员制度改革。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在194个关键绩效指标中，68个是到年中实现 55 个目标，年底实现 55 个目标，其余的在 2 到 10 年内实现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》的一项检查发现，李明博政府已经实现了所有 KPI 的三分之一，而实现了 68 项短期目标中的 66 项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他尚未向政府工作人员发布更新后的《公务员守则》以供咨询。他的政府提出了取消公务员遵守“政治中立”要求的想法，以防止该规则被用来逃避任务，并一度暗示将在今年第一季度公布征求意见稿。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;但公务员工会联合会主席梁朝廷表示，放弃这项规定可能会拖延咨询。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这非常敏感，涉及很多细节， “ 他说。 “如果有的话，我们还在等待咨询文件。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有待实现的另一个目标是政府金融科技证明中超过 50% 的项目商业化2022-23 年概念补贴计划。 In a reply to the Legislative Council on June 5, the government said it had approved 56 projects out of the 166 applications.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s John Lee gears up for Asean trade trip as exports remain in slump&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Lee has been particularly successful in achieving goals related to attracting talent and business, as well as land and housing supply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since December, the government has launched the Top Talent Pass Scheme, lowered some requirements under existing admission schemes and set up teams at its overseas offices to lure talent, as required by nine KPIs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official figures showed that various talent schemes had received about 84,000 applications, 49,000 of which had been approved, by the end of May. Lee earlier said the city was well on its way to attracting nearly double the 35,000 workers targeted annually.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 95 per cent of the visas granted through the talent schemes were to applicants from mainland China, according to the Immigration Department. The prevalence has sparked concerns over the city&#39;s ability to attract international candidates. It also remains unknown whether newcomers would stay in the city for a year as the government wants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for luring business, the government has established the Office for Attracting Strategic Enterprises and allocated HK$30 billion (US$3.8 billion) from the Future Fund to set up the “Co‑Investment Fund” – two KPIs considered the foundation for attracting companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The office told the Post it had met over 150 top-notch enterprises working in cutting-edge technologies such as artificial intelligence and life sciences since its launch in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong John Lee&#39;s first year in office: what did he achieve?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Most of these enterprises have shown interest in setting up business in Hong Kong, the office added. One KPI set for 2027 requires the government to attract at least 100 innovation and technology enterprises with high potential.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Commerce and Economic Development Bureau, 186 mainland and overseas companies had decided to set up or expand their operations in Hong Kong since January, which is nearly 20 per cent of the goal to attract 1,130 businesses between 2023 and 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But lawmaker Duncan Chiu, who represents the technology sector, doubted many companies would come to the city because the state of the global economy made it difficult for businesses to expand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have seen new policies coming out every month since last October,” he said. “But without policy continuity, development won&#39;t be fostered with just the numbers of the delivered KPIs.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While almost all of Hong Kong&#39;s ministers have visited mainland or overseas cities to promote the city&#39;s strengths since Lee took office, Allen Shi Lop-tak, president of the Chinese Manufacturers&#39; Association, said it was too early to assess the impact of such trips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Going out is better than staying home,” Shi said. “But I don&#39;t think it would yield fruits in the short term, and it still depends on whether such activities could be held regularly instead of just meeting a certain target, then nothing comes after.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even though most KPIs under land and housing are mid- and long-term, Lee&#39;s administration managed to meet all nine short-term ones. These include tabling bills to cut time for development procedures, launching schemes to boost cooperation with private developers in building subsidised flats and setting up a dedicated office to coordinate the development of the Northern Metropolis – a government flagship project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government also told the public it had secured enough land to build 360,000 public housing flats in the next decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The missing part of this rosy picture is how will all these development projects be financed,” said legislator Doreen Kong Yuk-foon who sits on the Legislative Council&#39;s panel on housing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regina Ip Lau Suk-yee, the government&#39;s top adviser in the Executive Council, earlier urged the administration to prioritise the Northern Metropolis plan over the Lantau Tomorrow Vision, a controversial project to create three artificial islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The debate over the government&#39;s plan to build public flats on a Fanling golf course – reignited by the Hong Kong Golf Club&#39;s extensive lobbying efforts to block it – also drew scepticism on Lee&#39;s ability to achieve his goals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kong added that solving the housing problem would take more than just constructing flats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It should also come with building infrastructure and supporting facilities,” she said. “Will you live in a flat without any supporting infrastructure nearby?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;John Burns, an honorary professor at the department of politics and public administration at the University of Hong Kong, said people cared about more than meeting the KPIs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But now it may be too early to evaluate the outcomes of all these activities associated with the KPIs,” Burns said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong firms move to cut major deals in Middle East after John Lee&#39;s visit&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The political scientist also noted that with trust in the government still low, Lee&#39;s administration had to understand “results were co-produced” and needed people&#39;s cooperation and respect.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Engaging citizens is the key, not marginalising them,” he said. “Public consultation can build trust and legitimacy and lay the foundation for more stable state-society collaboration in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The government appears to believe that it doesn&#39;t have time for that, which is a dangerous position.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Natalie Wong&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rocky US-China relationship could benefit from couples therapy strategies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3225473/rocky-us-china-relationship-could-benefit-couples-therapy-strategies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/1af16e30-bc17-4a2b-86ab-7471b2d4c375_4732fe69.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Conflict is inevitable in any long-term relationship. What really matters is whether partners can manage, resolve and move on from their disagreements and build a healthier bond over time. This insight applies to international diplomacy as much as to romantic relationships.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is fair to say the aftermath of the balloon incident in February was not a shining example of conflict resolution. Rather than communicate calmly and effectively, China and the United States got caught in a cycle of blame and recrimination, sending the relationship to its lowest ebb in decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thankfully, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken&#39;s successful visit to Beijing has opened a window of opportunity to establish a more constructive and harmonious US-China relationship. Both sides have a responsibility to seize this chance – as two of the world&#39;s foremost powers, their dynamic not only influences their own nations but the entire global landscape.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken&#39;s visit, the first to China by a US secretary of state in five years, saw constructive meetings with Foreign Minister Qin Gang, top diplomat Wang Yi and President Xi Jinping, the last of which was by no means guaranteed. These positive interactions send a strong signal that, having veered dangerously close to the edge, both sides recognise they cannot risk a complete break and are committed to putting the relationship on a more steady footing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is now crucial for China and the US to work together to build a solid foundation for their relationship so future incidents cannot derail ties in the manner we have seen in the last few months. To achieve this, there are four principles from relationship therapy that can be adapted to help guide the development of stronger, more stable US-China relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, open and regular communication is the cornerstone of any strong partnership. China and the US must get back to having frequent and transparent dialogue about their intentions, concerns and expectations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first priority is to step up high-level interactions to clear the way for a meeting between Xi and US President Joe Biden at the Group of 20 or Apec summits later this year. Hopefully Blinken&#39;s trip will be followed by visits by US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen, Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo and Biden&#39;s climate envoy John Kerry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regular contacts at lower levels of government should also be restored, as well as the bilateral dialogue that withered during the Trump administration. Collectively, these meetings can provide platforms to explore avenues for cooperation and address any brewing issues and defuse tensions before they snowball into larger conflicts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Second, any relationship needs robust mechanisms to manage and resolve conflict when it does occur. China and the US must establish channels for swift and effective communication during crises, as well as pre-established protocols to manage such events, to help de-escalate such situations before they become unmanageable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even at the height of the Cold War, the US and Soviet Union maintained channels for communication and crisis management, including a hotline between Washington and Moscow. China and the US lack those kinds of mechanisms.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Would a Cold War-style agreement help prevent China-US tensions from escalating?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Looking to the longer term, the third point a relationship therapist might emphasise is the need to develop mutual respect, empathy and shared interests. Couples going through a rough patch are often advised to try to understand the other person and engage in joint activities or hobbies to strengthen their bond.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a similar vein, nations can foster empathy through cultural exchange in areas such as education, research and tourism, helping to enhance mutual understanding and reduce the “us versus them” mentality. Cultural ties between China and the US have waned in recent years because of politics and the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is now open again, but the lack of enough flights to and from the US remains a bottleneck. Fewer than 6 per cent of flights between China and the US that existed in 2019 have resumed, according to a recent Nomura report, and flights that remain are expensive. Part of the issue is that restrictions on flying over Russian airspace add a significant cost to operating these routes. Both sides need to explore ways to increase the number of flights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More broadly, both sides should strive to promote bilateral exchange across society. The number of US students in China dwindled to just around 350 last semester. Hopefully this number will begin to rise as students make new applications for next term. It would also be beneficial to promote academic exchange, including by reducing the red tape involved in having foreign guests participate in academic conferences in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the Fulbright China programme sent US scholars to China for more than four decades and sent their Chinese counterparts the other way. It was cancelled in 2020 but should be revived, as should the Peace Corps programme, which withdrew from China the same year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finally, shared goals and collaborative projects play a pivotal role in helping couples deepen their connection. Similarly, China and the US must identify areas of common ground and pursue joint initiatives that benefit both nations. This should extend beyond addressing immediate concerns and conflicts to encompass broader, more constructive themes such as climate change and global financial stability. Long-term collaboration and incremental achievements on such issues can help unite both nations under a common cause.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like successful couples, both nations must invest time and effort in nurturing their partnership. After Blinken&#39;s visit, there is a chance for China and the US to build a more solid foundation for their relationship so it is not derailed when the next surprise comes. As with any relationship, there will be bumps in the road, but these can be overcome with careful management.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rivalry between Trump and DeSantis deepens with duelling New Hampshire campaign events]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225645/rivalry-between-trump-and-desantis-deepens-duelling-new-hampshire-campaign-events?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/b61555f2-9589-469d-ad17-2d920e4676fc_207ce332.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The rivalry between Florida Governor Ron DeSantis and former US president Donald Trump deepened on Tuesday as the two leading Republican White House candidates mocked each other during duelling events in the critical early voting state of New Hampshire.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Addressing a town hall in Hollis, DeSantis vowed to “actually” build the US-Mexico border wall that Trump tried but failed to complete as president. He also pledged to tear down Washington&#39;s traditional power centres in ways that Trump fell short.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking later at a Republican women&#39;s lunch in Concord, Trump countered that DeSantis was being forced to settle for second place in the primary and accused the governor of supporting cuts to Social Security, Medicare and other entitlement programmes as a way to tame federal spending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beyond the rhetoric, the conflicting events showed each candidate&#39;s evolving strategy. DeSantis took extensive audience questions – a trademark in New Hampshire politics that he eschewed during his previous visit to the state, drawing criticisms that he was stilted and overly scripted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump, meanwhile, offered a freewheeling speech for more than hour. He did not take questions in Concord, and reporters covering the event were confined to a pen, chaperoned to the bathroom and told they could not speak to attendees in the conference centre ballroom or even in the hallways. But the former president answered questions at a subsequent stop in Manchester, where he opened his New Hampshire campaign office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DeSantis, asked about people who had twice voted for Trump because of his promises to “drain the swamp” in Washington, used his answer to draw some of his sharpest contrasts yet with the former president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He didn&#39;t drain it. It&#39;s worse today than it&#39;s ever been,” DeSantis said. He added that such promises don&#39;t go far enough because a subsequent president “can just refill it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I want to break the swamp,” DeSantis said, pledging to take power out of Washington by instructing Cabinet agencies to halve the number of employees there.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Court says Trump must face New York civil fraud claims; Ivanka case tossed&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;DeSantis has tried to gain ground on Trump by questioning the former president&#39;s continued hold on the national Republican Party. At his town hall, the governor slammed the Republicans&#39; “culture of losing” under Trump and mentioned the “massive red wave” that many in the Republican Party predicted but that never materialised nationally in last year&#39;s midterm elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We had a red wave in Florida,” DeSantis said, noting he easily won re-election last fall. “But that&#39;s because we delivered results in Florida.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many leading Republicans remain fiercely loyal to Trump, but there is some evidence that the attacks against the former president are resonating. Speaking about Trump on Tuesday, House Speaker Kevin McCarthy, a California Republican, said, “Can he win that election? Yeah, he can win that election.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The question is, is he the strongest to win the election?” McCarthy continued on CNBC&#39;s Squawk Box. “I don&#39;t know that answer.” He clarified later in the day to the conservative news outlet Breitbart that Trump “is stronger today than he was in 2016.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his own speech, Trump noted that polls show him with large primary leads. He seized on DeSantis saying that, while Social Security and other programmes need to be guaranteed for older adults, there may be work “in a bipartisan way to figure out how do you strengthen this” when it comes to younger people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You can bet he&#39;ll be doing it later,” Trump said of cuts to the programmes. “And he&#39;ll be doing it to you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump also vowed to “drain the swamp once and for all” but used the slogan more to criticise US President Joe Biden than the Florida governor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You can&#39;t drain the swamp if you&#39;re part of the swamp, and Joe Biden and other opponents, many of them, are all owned, controlled, bought and paid for, 100 per cent,” Trump said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The former president also largely echoed DeSantis&#39; sentiments in promising that “this election will be the end of the world for the corrupt political class in our nation&#39;s capital.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US presidential candidate Nikki Haley seeks major changes in China policy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;DeSantis was also asked about the pro-Trump mob that overran the US Capitol in January 2021, and responded, “If it&#39;s about relitigating things that happened two or three years ago, we&#39;re going to lose.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I had nothing to do with what happened that day. Obviously, I didn&#39;t enjoy seeing it,” DeSantis said. “But we&#39;ve got to go forward on this stuff. We cannot be looking backwards.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That, too, clashed with Trump, who repeated baseless claims on Tuesday that he was denied a second term by election fraud. Numerous federal and local officials, a long list of courts, top former campaign staff and even Trump&#39;s own attorney general have all said there is no evidence of the fraud he alleges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The candidates&#39; simultaneous visits highlighted the role that New Hampshire, the first-in-the-nation Republican primary state, will play in deciding the next Republican presidential nominee. Much of the focus of the early primary has been on Iowa and South Carolina, where evangelical Christians are dominant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Spending time in New Hampshire, by contrast, gives the candidates were testing their messages in front of a more libertarian-leaning electorate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s first-place finish in New Hampshire&#39;s 2016 Republican primary, after losing Iowa to Texas Senator Ted Cruz, helped propel him to party dominance. But his Democratic rivals won the state in the 2016 and 2020 general elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before his speech on Tuesday, Trump announced that his New Hampshire team features 150-plus dedicated activists and organisers throughout the state&#39;s 10 counties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sabrina Antle, from the town of Henniker, said she could not afford to attend the Concord lunch. She and her nine-year-old daughter tried to see the former president later in Manchester, but that event reached capacity before they got in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m a Trumper but I wouldn&#39;t be upset with Ron DeSantis because I think he&#39;d do a stand up job,” Antle said. “I just don&#39;t know if he has the attitude Trump has, just the assertiveness.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump heard discussing &#39;highly confidential&#39; documents in new recording&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;DeSantis&#39; campaign angered some members of the New Hampshire Federation of Republican Women by scheduling his town hall around the same time Trump was addressing the group&#39;s lunch. It called DeSantis&#39; event “an attempt to steal focus from” its lunch, noting that other presidential candidates scheduled around it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That did not stop DeSantis, who at the town hall talked up the new immigration policy proposal he released on Monday in South Texas – betting that the issue can energise Republican voters, even those who are 2,000 miles north of the US-Mexico border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re actually going to build the wall,” DeSantis said of Trump&#39;s failed pledges to do so. “A lot of politicians chirp.他们做出宏伟的承诺，却未能兑现实际成果。找借口的时间已经结束了。 Now is the time to deliver results and finally get the job done.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the Florida governor also tailored his Tuesday message to New Hampshire, noting how tougher border security could eventually help limit the ravages of opioid addiction, which have hit the state particularly hard, even as deaths from overdoses have climbed all over the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He promised the “most assertive” policy against drug cartels “any administration has ever had.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have to do it,” DeSantis said “because it will save lives.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Carbon Finance: How the launch of a new voluntary carbon markets claims code can help reclaim lost credibility]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3225626/carbon-finance-how-launch-new-voluntary-carbon-markets-claims-code-can-help-reclaim-lost-credibility?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/2f647e1d-3e59-4a0a-bbe7-a238dcddddd0_de5983ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Voluntary Carbon Markets Integrity Initiative (VCMI) has launched a set of global guidelines to enable companies to make more credible climate statements on the carbon credits they purchase to offset their greenhouse gas emissions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The non-profit international body on Wednesday published its “claims code of practice”, a rule book for companies to follow when making climate benefit claims. Compliance with the code is voluntary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The claims code fills a critical gap, bringing integrity to the demand-side of voluntary carbon markets,” it said in a statement. The code is the result of over 12 months of road testing by around 70 mostly multinational companies, a series of public consultations and multi-stakeholder collaboration, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While voluntary carbon markets have the potential to help fill the financing gap for climate mitigation, especially in developing nations, it can only be realised if they operate with high integrity, the organisation said in the claims code document.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This means that carbon credits must be generated by activities that truly go beyond business-as-usual and benefit host communities – the supply side – and that their use increases overall greenhouse gas mitigation rather than substituting for existing actions – the demand side,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without clear high integrity rules for both aspects, voluntary carbon markets will rightly continue to be viewed with suspicion, companies will be afraid to invest, and their potential will be lost.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the code, before companies buy any carbon offsets, they must have disclosed their annual greenhouse gas emissions and their near-term reduction targets, validated by the Science Based Targets initiative, besides having publicly committed to reaching net zero emissions no later than 2050.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They must also demonstrate that they are on track to reach their near-term reduction goals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Companies can then select one out of three tiers of claims to make, based on the percentage of their own residual emissions that will be offset by buying carbon credits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The release of the VCMI claims code follows public concern about the credibility of credits from one key category – deforestation prevention projects – flagged earlier this year by several media reports in Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Clearly [they are] a very important part of the market,” VCMI&#39;s executive director Mark Kenber told the Post in an interview ahead of the code&#39;s launch. “At the moment, forest protection is getting less than 3 per cent of the financing it needs to protect standing tropical forests, so we need to find an answer.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VCMI was launched two years ago with backing from funders including the UK government, the philanthropic arm of hedge fund Children&#39;s Investment Fund Management, Bezos Earth Fund and technology giant Google.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The VCMI code&#39;s launch will have implications for Hong Kong, where blue chip companies are seeking to buy high quality voluntary carbon credits to offset carbon footprints they cannot reduce by their own efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong has also indicated an ambition to become a regional market for carbon credits trading, bridging global demand for carbon offsets and China&#39;s potential credits supply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Voluntary credits are issued by carbon offset registries on climate mitigation projects, for each unit of emission reduction or removal that is verified. The robustness of the registries&#39; standards and methodologies are key to the quality of the credits issued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Voluntary credits traded globally jumped nearly fourfold to US$2 billion in 2021 from 2020, according to data compiler Ecosystem Marketplace. The most popular categories include renewable energy and forestry projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VCMI is considering providing compliance relief for some companies, Kenbar said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For companies that are just starting or are halfway on the net zero journey, how we incentivise them [to do more on decarbonisation] is part of the work we are doing in the next few months on introducing flexibility,” he said. “We hope to have a package by the end of the year that will be attractive both to multinationals and domestic mid-market companies.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese tourists in Thailand face jail, fine after touching ‘cute’ starfish, stepping on coral reefs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3225614/chinese-tourists-thailand-face-jail-fine-after-touching-cute-starfish-stepping-coral-reefs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/f9a312b7-0c8a-4c9e-a28c-d40118691476_7f5a1bef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Three Chinese tourists accused of touching a starfish and stepping on coral reefs during their diving expedition in Phuket could face two years in jail after they were charged for violating a marine protection law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident, which happened last week on the Thai island of Koh Racha, came to light following photos shared by a group that tracks environmental transgressions in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Environment minister Varawut Silpa-archa said in a Facebook post that two visitors admitted to the offence after turning themselves into police, while the third suspect was still at large.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Smog drives away Thailand&#39;s tourists as farmers next door slash and burn land&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Varawut added officials coordinated with the provincial tourism police, marine office and the company that organised the trip to track down the lawbreakers. He did not elaborate if the missing tourist was still being pursued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If found guilty, the visitors face two years in prison and a 200,000 baht (US$5,667) fine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two-month-old travel firm apologised for the tourists&#39; behaviour who were part of a diving group, saying it was the establishment&#39;s first junket and it “learned a lesson”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The operator also promised to raise awareness about not meddling with marine wildlife among its clients, especially Chinese who have previously been involved in similar incidents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some of them find the animals cute and want to have the pictures taken with them to show to their friends,” The Phuket News quoted a company executive as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On behalf of the company, we are very sorry that this has happened.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thai social media users directed their ire at “wild Chinese tour groups”, while others blamed the diving instructors for not sensitising the guests about the regulations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some lamented such incidents keep occurring despite law enforcement actions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two Chinese tourists were arrested in 2020 for catching protected ornamental fish using a spear gun while snorkelling in central Thailand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, South Korean actress Lee Yeol-eum was charged with catching endangered giant clams in a Thai national marine park while taking part in a reality TV show.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marine experts say more than three quarters of Thailand&#39;s coral reefs have been damaged by rising sea temperatures and unchecked tourism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tourism-dependent country&#39;s sandy beaches helped draw 6.15 million foreign visitors, including more than 700,000 Chinese, in the first quarter of the year.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>