<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Three Arrows Capital’s 37 NFTs sold for US$4.6 million loss at Sotheby’s amid crypto winter that has seen sales plummet]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3224262/three-arrows-capitals-37-nfts-sold-us46-million-loss-sothebys-amid-crypto-winter-has-seen-sales?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 10:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/42d66351-c0fc-4890-b8e5-78420a0f1f88_89826c74.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;破产的加密货币对冲基金三箭资本之前购买的一组不可替代代币该拍卖行表示，周四在纽约苏富比拍卖行以 1090 万美元的价格售出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一年前申请美国破产保护的三箭资本斥资 1550 万美元购买了 37 种 NFT。区块链跟踪器 DappRadar 的数据显示，2021 年 7 月和 2021 年 8 月的一系列购买。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不可替代代币 (NFT) 是一种基于区块链的资产，代表图像、视频等数字项目的所有权&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于监管风险，中国的 NFT 投诉在 2022 年激增 300 倍&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最昂贵的项目“Ringers #879 (The Goose)”是该系列的一部分由加拿大艺术家德米特里·切尔尼亚克 (Dmitri Cherniak) 创作的 1,000 幅计算机生成的抽象图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据 DappRadar 称，苏富比拍卖行表示，它于周四以 620 万美元的价格售出，并于 2021 年 8 月被三箭资本以约 590 万美元的价格收购&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们看到越来越多的非加密货币、非 NFT 收藏家开始真正了解质量及其有趣的原因，”苏富比数字艺术和 NFT 主管迈克尔布汉纳说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bouhanna 补充说，NFT 仅以数字形式存在，任何人都可以在线免费查看它们，但拍卖中的许多物品都附有实物印刷品，买家可以展示这些印刷品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在加密货币 Luna 和 TerraUSD 崩溃之后，总部位于新加坡的三箭资本是一系列主要加密货币公司中第一家在 2022 年破产的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着加密货币价格的上涨，NFT 市场在 2021 年爆炸式增长激增，技术爱好者押注数字资产将在在线虚拟环境中变得非常有价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但投机狂潮已经降温，到 2023 年 5 月，NFT 销售额约为 6.75 亿美元，低于峰值根据 DappRadar 的数据，2022 年 1 月的 NFT 价值为 57 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three Arrows Capital 的另外七个 NFT 已在 5 月的苏富比拍卖会上以 250 万美元的价格售出。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea sets sights on boosting Nato ties with new strategy to tackle growing China clout]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3224173/south-korea-sets-sights-boosting-nato-ties-new-strategy-tackle-growing-china-clout?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/9ef0fa15-a920-42df-a7b8-4721667cb7e6_78196548.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;韩国周四正式透露，它和印太地区的其他三个盟友正在同时制定战略，在中国日益主导的地区加强与北大西洋公约组织（北约）的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交部表示，首尔、日本、澳大利亚和新西兰已经启动了这一进程详细介绍了名为“量身定制的伙伴关系计划”(ITPP) 的倡议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在与北约一起制定 ITPP 的措辞以达成协议，”该部在本周获得的一份新闻公告中说。亚洲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，它拒绝详细说明正在进行的谈判中正在讨论的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“傲慢”：韩国就美中竞争言论召集北京特使&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北约正在寻求扩大与这四个国家的关系，这四个国家统称为亚太伙伴 (AP4)，目前被多边军事联盟描述为“全球伙伴”，以对抗强硬的中国和侵略乌克兰的侵略性俄罗斯令这个拥有 31 个成员国的集团感到不安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《日经亚洲》报道，合作伙伴将探讨在网络安全、太空以及打击新兴和破坏性虚假信息等问题上的合作。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;在北约去年公布的新战略构想中，它指责北京对欧洲-大西洋安全构成“系统性挑战”，并将莫斯科列为联盟和平与安全的“最重大和直接威胁”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北约补充说，它将“加强与印太地区新老伙伴的对话与合作，以应对跨区域挑战和共同的安全利益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国回击北约，称北约应该停止“停止划定意识形态界限来挑起对抗”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部上周表示，该地区大多数国家“不欢迎北约将触角伸向亚洲”，“不接受复制韩国外交部还证实，北约秘书长延斯·斯托尔滕贝格提议在亚洲设立联络处。东京。但该计划遭到法国的反对，法国担心它可能向中国发出错误信息，并引起东南亚国家联盟（东盟）成员国的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙反对这一预期前哨，警告扩大北约的地理范围将是一个“大错误”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北约[代表]北大西洋，第五条和第六条（在其章程中）明确将范围限制在北大西洋”一位不愿透露姓名的法国官员表示，并补充说此举将使该联盟远离其主要关注区域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该地区的任何国家都没有北约联络处。如果北约需要了解该地区的态势，它可以使用指定的大使馆作为联络点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北约与日本的关系得到发展，因为它在中国的威胁下开设了第一个亚洲办事处&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;斯托尔滕贝格将于 10 月离任的特朗普上周表示，“亚洲发生的事情对欧洲很重要，欧洲发生的事情对亚洲也很重要，因此北约盟国加强与印太伙伴的伙伴关系更为重要。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北约很可能将联络处作为与这四个国家合作的枢纽，而首相岸田文雄上个月表示日本没有成为该军事集团成员的计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;斯托尔滕贝格表示，预计 AP4 的所有领导人都将出席北约 7 月在立陶宛举行的峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Park Won-gon 教授表示，北约实施其集体军事联盟将“非常困难”，因为它&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在联合国无法进一步制裁的情况下，韩国希望加强与包括北约在内的志同道合的国家和团体的合作。”由于中国和俄罗斯的抵制，朝鲜 [因其导弹和核威胁]，”Park 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，韩国参与国际军事遏制中国的可能性几乎为零”，他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社和路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Manulife relocates senior executive to Hong Kong, as Canada’s biggest insurer joins peers using city as base for Asia expansion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3224226/manulife-relocates-senior-executive-hong-kong-canadas-biggest-insurer-joins-peers-using-city-base?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/f288792b-49ef-42fc-9b59-55b0a88ba94c_a9e27e93.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;加拿大最大的保险公司将其一名高级管理人员调往香港，加入许多同行计划将这座城市作为在亚洲扩张的基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宏利金融周五表示，已任命首席财务官 Phil Witherington 为宏利亚洲总裁兼首席执行官，自起生效7 月 1 日。他将接替 Damien Green，后者将在担任宏利金融亚洲区主席的新职位上帮助推动保险公司的区域战略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举是在香港政府呼吁更多国际公司使用将香港作为扩展其区域业务的枢纽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宏利最近与英国保诚和美国保险公司 Cigna 等竞争对手一道扩大了在香港的业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港行政总裁约翰李家超在去年 12 月表示，政府将推出更多政策，以吸引希望以香港为枢纽在亚洲扩张的国际保险公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们已阐明目标，让亚洲成为 50 Manulife 总裁兼首席执行官 Roy Gori 在接受在线采访时表示：“中期来看，我们公司的收益将从目前的 40% 左右增加到 20%。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在亚洲的时间超过125 年来，我们为 14 个市场的超过 1300 万客户提供服务。亚洲是我们特许经营权中非常重要的一部分，我们确实有一个雄心壮志，希望亚洲成为我们业务中更大的一部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港已经是宏利的亚洲总部，Witherington 计划利用将其作为进一步拓展大湾区和其他区域市场的基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在移居加拿大之前，他在香港工作了 13 年，先后在友邦保险、汇丰银行和宏利亚洲担任高级职位五年前担任全球首席财务官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我在香港度过的 13 年中，我非常清楚这座城市具有战略优势，”威瑟林顿在同一次采访中说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港是通往中国的大门。它拥有真正世界一流的基础设施和人才库，不仅由世界一流的教育体系提供支持，而且还有培养这些人才的国际和国内公司。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prudential 调动了其新任首席执行官， Anil Wadhwani 于 2 月前往香港，打破了其首席执行官常驻伦敦的传统。这家英国保险公司的香港子公司周一在澳门开设了一家分公司。&lt;​​/p>;&lt;p>;美国健康保险公司 Cigna Group 的国际市场总裁 Jason 也计划将香港作为区域枢纽，以利用大湾区不断增长的机遇萨德勒本月早些时候告诉邮报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;连接香港、澳门和广东省九个城市的湾区被北京在 2019 年的蓝图中设想为经济强国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大湾区对更广泛的中国经济的重要性的显现进一步巩固了香港的重要性和这座城市的未来前景，”Witherington 说。 “香港不仅本身是一个非常重要的市场，也是我们在区域上非常重要的一个枢纽。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nodding head, blinking and opening mouth cost Chinese boy and grandfather US$2,800 in online ‘free gaming skins’ scam]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3223958/nodding-head-blinking-and-opening-mouth-cost-chinese-boy-and-grandfather-us2800-online-free-gaming?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/6e218019-f460-4198-9683-0105aadf220f_cf9370ab.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个试图从直播中收集“免费游戏皮肤”的中国男孩结束了20,000 元（2,800 美元）被网络诈骗者损失，再次引发了对中国游戏欺诈和儿童手机成瘾的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名 10 岁的孩子住在中国中部河南省的农村，据河南电视台 6 月 8 日报道，5 月 23 日，小宇被骗从他祖父的银行账户转账。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小宇说他正在看快手直播-一名玩家在网易游戏开发的游戏蛋蛋派对上直播。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;男孩被告知，通过使用微信应用程序扫描二维码，他可以免费获得游戏皮肤或角色外观，花费100多元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扫码后，小鱼收到错误提示，微信账号连同微信钱包里的钱全部冻结，除非他在期限内采取措施一个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他被要求在消息平台QQ上添加一个人以获取有关“措施”的说明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小宇说那个人让他下载腾讯会议，中国版的 VooV 会议应用程序，以便他可以与该人分享他的手机屏幕以获得“更好的指示”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;骗子随后指示小宇下载银联应用程序，这是中国统一的移动支付应用程序银行业，让他爷爷登录，查看他名下哪张卡有钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他们让小鱼扫描一系列二维码“解冻微信账号”，通过扫描&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的两万块钱，点点头、眨眼、张嘴就没了。”小宇的爷爷刘某在描述人脸识别流程时说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，他用了10年的时间才攒够了这笔钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大陆社交媒体上，此案再次引发了对儿童沉迷手机和游戏诈骗的担忧。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国互联网络信息中心和互联网信息中心联合发布的一份报告，2021 年中国 6 至 18 岁的互联网用户估计有 1.91 亿，占该年龄段全国人口的 96.8%中国共青团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约有19.5%的受访未成年手机用户表示，他们在心理上对互联网有高度或适度依赖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京市青少年协会调查法律援助研究中心2021年调查显示，未成年人游戏成瘾倾向主要是由于游戏精心设计的激励机制、易受诱惑、来自同学的同伴压力和家长的疏忽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蛋蛋派对游戏2023年第一季度左右，在多个手机应用商店的游戏类应用排行榜上名列前茅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《每日电讯报》报道，该游戏以简单的玩法和可爱的设计深受中国未成年人欢迎中国财经媒体《深燃》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然从游戏皮肤中获利在游戏开发商中很普遍，但免费和廉价的皮肤也成为诈骗者最常用的骗取玩家钱财的工具之一。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;处理账户问题经验较少的未成年人很容易被诈骗者错误信息的严厉措辞吓到，成为他们敲诈勒索的受害者。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Antony Blinken’s trip to China shows desire to re-engage, ‘avoid worst-case scenario’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224189/antony-blinkens-trip-china-shows-desire-re-engage-avoid-worst-case-scenario?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/ec8b45f6-f3b3-4d80-a549-b85e02baba95_0b08533a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯(Antony Blinken) 将就他的高风险会见高级官员本周末访问中国，但观察人士对两国关系取得重大突破的期望不大，尽管期待已久的访问表明两个大国希望重新接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿和北京周三均证实布林肯将于周日抵达中国进行为期两天的访问，这是五年来第一位进行此类访问的美国高级外交官。此行也是在布林肯因中国间谍气球进入美国领空发生争执而在最后一刻推迟计划访问四个月后进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据美国国务院称，布林肯将讨论维护的重要性开放沟通渠道以“负责任地管理”关系，同时提出双边关切的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“激烈的竞争需要激烈而强硬的外交，以确保竞争不会演变成对抗或冲突，这就是我们的目标发言人马修·米勒 (Matthew Miller) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;‘微妙的时机’：为什么布林肯的沙特阿拉伯之行是‘给中国的信息’&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;阿尔弗雷德·吴 (Alfred Wu)，副教授新加坡国立大学李光耀公共政策学院表示，周三早些时候布林肯与中国外长秦刚的通话将为美国官员的访问定下基调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国外交部的一份声明，秦就其核心关切告诉布林肯，美国应该“表现出尊重”，停止损害中国的主权、安全和发展利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴说，这次通话可能旨在让秦传达了北京在台湾问题上的立场：“秦需要确保布林肯了解此次访问的重要性，并了解中国的底线，即台湾。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国关系陷入新的困境8 月份时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西 (Nancy Pelosi) 访问了自治的台湾，尽管北京一再警告不要进行此类访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月份，两国关系进一步受到考验，当时美国击落了一个据称是中国间谍的气球，越境进入其领土，促使布林肯推迟了他的中国之行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国社会科学院美中关系专家卢翔表示，周三的交流很重要，并指出双方的语气双方似乎“相对克制”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特别是，他说美国的宣读没有提到任何具体问题——例如台湾——只是笼统地说讨论了双边和全球问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我个人的感觉是，美国现在已经充分认识到，美中关系不仅处于最低点，而且处于高度敏感阶段——因此美国在此期间更加谨慎，”他说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;卢说，人们还认识到，如果“紧张趋势”继续下去，美国总统乔·拜登可能成为自四十多年前关系正常化以来第一位不访问中国的美国领导人。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;本周末的出访也将使布林肯成为拜登政府首位访华的内阁级官员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果拜登足够清醒，就会有一些鼓励校准美中关系。美中关系不仅仅是一个双边问题，而是一个全球问题，”卢补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着美中关系跌至新低，外交渠道是否仍然有效？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对于庞四川大学国际事务教授钟颖表示，布林肯与秦的交流对美中关系来说是一个好消息，但仍存在不确定性和挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“双方都有强烈的愿望重新接触，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，华盛顿已经试图淡化取得突破的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们去北京的目的不是负责东亚和太平洋事务的助理国务卿丹尼尔·克里滕布林克 (Daniel Kritenbrink) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现实、自信的方法和真诚的愿望，以尽可能最负责任的方式管理我们的竞争。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kritenbrink 还期望布林肯“重申美国对维护台湾海峡和平与稳定的持久利益”， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢表示，布林肯的访问将使华盛顿更好地了解北京在台湾问题上的立场和“明确战略”，而新加坡的吴表示，主要目的是尽量减少冲突风险和&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴说：“这是为了避免最坏的情况发生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;清华大学国际安全与战略研究中心高级研究员周波经常说两个主要全球大国之间的接触通常看起来很正常，但考虑到最近美中关系的低谷，这种接触变得更加重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他警告说，虽然布林肯与中国高级官员的计划会晤等双边交流将Zhou 警告说，虽然有利，但两国关系的解冻效果不太可能显着。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几乎没有妥协的余地。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Class dismissed: worse to come for Hong Kong schools as closures loom amid falling births, migration]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3224217/class-dismissed-worse-come-hong-kong-schools-closures-loom-amid-falling-births-migration?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/f8be4f95-cfe1-47d7-9393-2d72c8b6c527_693c5f0b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;家庭主妇郑思丽带着孩子与其他十几位父母和他们的孩子一起上个月就一所面临关闭威胁的学校向香港教育部长请愿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这群人举着白色的大床单，上面写着“我爱宝欣”和“宝欣是我的家”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;新学年入读小一的学生不足 16 名，黄大仙宝仁献主小学的命运岌岌可危。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;低于最低人数意味着学校不再有资格获得政府补贴，这是一个信号，表明它必须关闭、与另一所学校合并或筹集大量资金以继续自己经营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现年 36 岁的 Cheng 是 Po Yan 的前学生，她自己有三个孩子，是侄子和侄女的法定监护人。其中三个孩子已经在学校上学，她希望她六岁的老二也能去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说学校也欢迎有特殊教育需要的孩子和少数民族孩子。它对她患有轻度自闭症的 11 岁侄子照顾得很好，男孩的成绩在小一和小四之间稳步提高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是我唯一喜欢的学校，”她说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 20 日当天，教育局局长蔡玉莲拒绝与在场的媒体见面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宝欣是五所被告知不会见面的小学之一在只有 15 名儿童入学，比政府的最低要求还差一个之后，从下一学年开始获得政府拨款开办小一班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是在 2017 年出生的 56,500 名儿童中只有 42,000 名报名参加小学之后今年在公立学校。近年来，随着移民潮的涌入，一些人已经不在这座城市了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着 2018 年以来出生的婴儿数量去年降至创纪录的 32,500 人，教育工作者预计情况会更糟。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上一次入学率下降袭击香港学校是在 2004 年至 2010 年间，当时有 90 多所小学关闭。公立学校数量从2000年初的600多所减少到今年的456所。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;学校选择“死胡同”？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港小一报名结果公布分两轮 - 在学年开始前一年的 9 月，然后在 6 月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每年 9 月左右，想要将孩子送到公立学校的家长会在他们选择的学校注册。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一所学校必须有至少 16 名学生才有资格获得政府补贴以支付所有费用，包括教师的工资，并可以继续开办小一班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些少于超过16名学生仍可获得小二及以上的资助，但必须在三年后关闭，届时所有剩余学生将转往其他学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校也可以选择自筹资金，即指集资开设小一班、与另一所学校合并或申请对学校进行检讨。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;学生人数下降的香港学校被促考虑合并以求生存&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 9 月轮次中没有找到名额的孩子会在 6 月通过中央分配及时分配到新学年的学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些家长对孩子的分配学校不满意，然后转向他们更喜欢的其他学校，希望能在那里找到一席之地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种最后一刻抢椅子的过程，通常被称为“敲门”，是可能的，因为所有学校都可以自行决定录取两个或小学一年级每班三个孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着今年入学人数的急剧下降，政府于 5 月 30 日宣布将每班削减一个可自由支配名额，削减 1000 多个自由名额.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果家长把孩子搬出去，这将帮助不太受欢迎的学校面临失去学生和资源的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但代表教育界的立法会小学校长朱国强，说面临停课威胁的学校真的别无选择，因为所有的选择都是“死胡同”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，它一直在严厉打击学校，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港当局否决了 2 所入学人数不足的中学的生存计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;那些申请自办学校的人他说，获得资助的小一班必须证明他们在银行有至少 300 万港元（383,100 美元），以证明他们有能力支付教师工资和其他费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;选择他说，审查成功的希望很小。这个过程意味着要接受一组教育局官员在几天内的检查，并在各项绩效指标上获得“良好”评级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朱说官员告诉他，很少有学校有过去在此类审查中幸存下来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位代表学校理事会的校长在不愿透露姓名的情况下表示，教育当局推动合并的选择，作为应对入学率下降的一种方式，只是另一种选择&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“合并就是裁员，这只是让学校有序关闭的一种方式，”校长说。 “最终只有一个校园被使用，另一个必须关闭。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Po Yan 考虑关闭&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;本月，Po Yan 向该局申请批准其申请失败了一项审查，这意味着它是面临裁员的五所学校中唯一一所考虑到 2026 年关闭的学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长洲基督教会长洲堂金刚小学和黄孔儒大盛小学大新在证明资金充足后，成功申请开办自费小一班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;救世军中原慈善基金学校正与救世军安伟利纪念学校商讨合并事宜。两者都在柴湾，属于同一个教会团体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后一所位于坚尼地城的圣查理斯学校，由于位于一个集水区，仍然有&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港中学表示，随着学生人数下降，班级规模应该缩减&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;宝欣是一所由宗教团体经营的拥有 58 年历史的天主教学校, 香港无玷圣母会, 位于黄大仙公共屋村的老年区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有44名教师, 多年来入学人数不断下降, 小一的人数班级从三班减少到一班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这所学校以招收特殊教育需要 (SEN) 儿童而闻名，但这给一些家长留下了这不是一所好学校的印象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;校长余思伟在电台节目中感叹，学校在 3 月 31 日被告知无法开设小一班后，只有 20 天的时间来选择生存选项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校申请接受审查，但被拒绝了。其校友会随后联合起来筹款自费办小一班，但局方表示学校没有第二个选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人说，薄颜早料到，由于其入学人数下降了一段时间，而同一地区的其他学校每年都成功地吸引了学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港教师移民，让有特殊需要的孩子为新员工而苦苦挣扎&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3 >;对特殊需要儿童的担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;接受《邮报》采访的校长普遍认为，鉴于人口数量不断减少，未来还有更多坏消息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;名誉主席Langton Cheung Yung-pong香港资助小学校长会表示，学生人数下降严重，令教育界忧心忡忡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他促请政府在所有学校实施小班制，因为近五分之一的学校每个班级仍然有 30 名学生，而不是 25 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;招收非华裔学生和 SEN 儿童的学校的师生比例也可以提高，因为他们需要更多资源和人手照顾他补充说，这些学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheung 说，如果主要招收 SEN 学生的学校被取消，这些孩子将流向其他可能没有照顾他们经验的学校。这意味着如果像宝欣这样的学校消失了，其他学校将承担后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果学校没有足够的受过SEN教学培训的教师，一旦孩子出现情绪问题或扰乱课堂秩序，课堂秩序将难以维持。 ，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特殊教育需要和家长协会（一个拥有近 700 名成员的家长支持组织）总干事戴银容说，只有像宝仁这样入学率低的学校， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有特殊教育需要的学生真的需要少一些学生的课堂环境”，她呼吁教育局在招生时将一名有特殊教育需要的孩子算作两名学生，让学校&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她担心如果像宝欣这样的学校关闭，其他没有照顾SEN孩子经验的学校可能不会收留他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，最终受害的是孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“全是中文”：香港少数族裔学生碰壁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对于家庭主妇郑思丽来说， Po Yan 即将关闭是一个打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局官员打电话询问她是否愿意将她的三个大孩子搬出 Po Yan 时，她很生气，因为她最小的孩子无法上小学那里有一个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府想要让我的四个孩子四处转学，只是因为这所学校只缺一个学生入学，”她说，并补充说她还没有为她的孩子选择另一所学校。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;她说，一些将有特殊需要的孩子送到所谓的精英学校的家长，很沮丧地发现他们的孩子被同学排斥，在那里不快乐。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们的自信心在破岩增长了很多，因为老师们更多地关注弱势学生，用心去教书，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Uncertainty clouds Chinese millionaires who chased Australia’s golden visas: ‘Our life is a mess’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3224260/uncertainty-clouds-chinese-millionaires-who-chased-australias-golden-visas-our-life-mess?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 09:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/79a947ef-466b-434e-a028-b86f2d2e07a0_a01bea4c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;2018年Paul Wang离开北京老家去澳洲开始新的生活，投资 100 万澳元（680,000 美元）在一家食品加工企业，希望根据该国的投资签证计划获得永久居留权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五年过去了，他一家三口的希望仍然搁置，因为the government has put the controversial “golden visa” programme on the back burner, causing processing times to blow out, leaving wealthy migrants like Wang in limbo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We were not expecting it would take this long,” said Wang, 44. “And our life is a mess because of that. We simply cannot plan ahead with all of the uncertainty.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Australia introduced the Business Innovation and Investment Programme (BIIP) in 2012, the hope was that wealthy business owners, investors and entrepreneurs would boost the economy by bringing in capital and driving innovation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The results, though, have been underwhelming. A government review published in March found BIIP migrants contributed less to the economy than the average Australian, as the cohort, despite their wealth, tended to be older and earned lower incomes through capital returns on passive investments.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australia to retain top talent, cut &#39;worker exploitation&#39; in immigration reform&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The review estimated the lifetime economic contribution of BIIP holders at A$600,000, less than half the A$1.6 million of Australians.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After coming to power 13 months ago, Australia&#39;s Labor government shifted priority to easing shortages of critical skilled workers. Partly as a result, most BIIP permanent visas are taking nearly three years to process, up from a previous average around 12 months, and in addition to an investment cycle of four to five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang has been waiting 21 months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Similar investment visa schemes have been scrapped in Canada, Britain and Singapore as governments conclude they do not create jobs and could be a means to park speculative money.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every category of Australian visas experienced a backlog during Covid-19. As the pandemic has eased, the government has cut processing times overall, but the wait for more than 3,000 BIIP holders and their families – many Chinese – has only lengthened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some BIIP applicants plan to protest in Sydney on Friday against the government&#39;s policy shift, a rarity as Chinese migrants largely avoid public dissent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked about the visa delays, the Department of Home Affairs said in an emailed statement the government would process all visas in line with priority and planning levels, declining to comment on the complaints from BIIP holders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said a new migration strategy would be released later this year, which would include “radically reshaping” the BIIP programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The delays have raised concern that the government might scrap the BIIP programme, said Tony Le Nevez, managing director at residence and citizenship planners Henley &amp; Partners Australia, whose clients have invested at least A$5 million each in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I just don&#39;t think the investor programme is on their radar at the moment – they might overhaul it down the track. In the meantime, I think they might just keep a small window open.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government plans to shrink its BIIP allocation from 5,000 visas last financial year to 1,900 this year – less than 20 per cent of the level of earlier years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BIIP holders say they are curtailing business investment given the uncertainty, postponing life decisions and in some cases selling properties in Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Asian-Australians fear &#39;Red Alert&#39; warmongering will fuel rise in racist hate&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Some say they must hold on to loss-making businesses to keep their visa prospects alive, missing out on investments with greater returns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The forever wait means that even if I&#39;m running my business at a loss, I cannot just close shop and move on,” said Tan, a Chinese investor who owns a furniture shop in Melbourne and asked to be identified only by his surname due to privacy concerns. He has been waiting for 33 months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang, who gave up on plans last year to buy more land for his factory because of the uncertainty of his visa status, said he was prepared to offload his assets in Australia and move to the United States for his daughter&#39;s education next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I know a lot of people won&#39;t sympathise with us – we&#39;re a small group of people,” Wang said. “But we&#39;re not being treated fairly.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[With Hong Kong’s property market reeling from falling deals and prices, an uptick in rates will dampen mood further, analysts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3224215/hong-kongs-property-market-reeling-falling-deals-and-prices-uptick-rates-will-dampen-mood-further?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/15/7efa46a3-e532-45ae-86b2-01cda1a82835_2d1dcdb6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;An elevated interest-rate environment is likely to weigh on Hong Kong&#39;s secondary housing market until next year, given the possibility of further rate hikes by the US Federal Reserve and its consequent impact on mortgage rates in the city, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Higher interest rates have taken a toll on the transaction volumes of lived-in homes, which have fallen 40 to 50 per cent of this year&#39;s weekly average, according to executives from two leading Hong Kong property agencies. They expect the high rates to push prices further down in the short term.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are still many uncertainties about whether the interest rate will peak, [as a result] the wait-and-see sentiment in the market will continue,” said Louis Chan, the Asia-Pacific vice-chairman and chief executive of the residential division at Centaline Property Agency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Home prices may fall by up to 5 per cent in the third quarter, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The possibility of mortgage rates rising further has not been ruled out. The Fed, which held rates steady for the first time after 10 consecutive hikes since March 2022 to control inflation, sees one or two more increases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even the Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) CEO, Eddie Yue Wai-man, cautioned on Thursday that interest rates in the city may continue to stay at the current high level for some time before any cuts take place.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why are Hong Kong homeowners cutting prices when the market&#39;s on the rise?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The public should not take the pause in rate rise today as the end of the interest rise cycle or any rate cut in the near future,” Yue said. “They should carefully assess interest rate risks before making investment decisions or taking a mortgage loan.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the Fed embarked on its interest-rate hike cycle in March last year, the Centa-City Leading Index – Centaline&#39;s gauge of lived-in home prices – has fallen by 6.6 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Yuen Long, second-hand deals plummeted over 40 per cent month on month to 27 in the first half of June, with owners cutting prices slightly, according to Centaline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That figure compares with those collated by Midland Realty, which tracks transactions of 35 large-scale housing estates in the city. The agency said it has seen consistently lower deals since March, which fell below 100 for 14 consecutive weeks and have sunk to less than 50 since the beginning of May, according to data compiled by the agency. The weekly average stood at 34 transactions in the past six weeks, compared with this year&#39;s overall average of 73, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the short term, to lure buyers from competitively priced new residential projects, secondary homeowners eager to sell may have to cut prices further, Midland said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HSBC, Bank of China (Hong Kong) and Hang Seng Bank said they would keep their prime lending rates unchanged at 5.75 per cent, while Standard Chartered and Bank of East Asia said they would keep theirs unchanged at 6 per cent on Thursday, but the HKMA&#39;s Yue warned that “there is a chance for interest rates to rise one or two more times this year”, echoing Fed chairman Jerome Powell&#39;s hawkish note on the need to raise interest rates “somewhat further” this year to bring down inflation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong home price growth slows down sharply as rising rates sap confidence&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Since the mortgage rate has more than doubled to 3.5 per cent from 1.5 per cent before the rate hike cycle, the monthly mortgage payment for a HK$6 million (US$766,640) flat with a 90 per cent loan-to-value ratio spread over 30 years has surged 30.1 per cent to HK$25,461, according to Midland Realty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The headwind of high interest rates will only begin to ease in 2024, said Martin Wong, Knight Frank&#39;s Greater China head of research and consultancy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some buyers of small and medium-sized units may not pass banks&#39; stress tests, which will depress home prices in the short term,” Wong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US interest rate hike cycle has not yet ended,” he said, adding that there is still a chance Hong Kong banks might increase their prime rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Yue said the HKMA was not considering any changes to its mortgage policy, pointing to the nature of the property market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Property prices went down 15 per cent last year but have bounced back this year,” he said. “The HKMA will need more time to monitor demand and supply, transactions, prices and other economic data to determine if it should relax the mortgage policy.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blinken’s visit may not deliver a breakthrough in US-China relations, but watch for positive ripple effects]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3224148/blinkens-visit-may-not-deliver-breakthrough-us-china-relations-watch-positive-ripple-effects?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/15/6974a3cf-9458-445a-a46b-733479c0946e_c2b76b7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Few are expecting any meaningful breakthroughs from US Secretary of State Antony Blinken&#39;s trip to China this week. The visit won&#39;t reverse US positions on intellectual property, chip security, the South China Sea or Taiwan, but that&#39;s beside the point.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mere fact that the two sides are meeting at this high level is a sign the dangerously negative trend in the relationship has at least a chance of being repaired. Since US President Joe Biden met Chinese President Xi Jinping in Bali, Indonesia, last year, the two sides have found little common ground.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heightened national security concerns have made relations spiral even lower with the shooting down of a Chinese balloon and a near miss between forces at sea. Blinken&#39;s meetings, short of delivering major agreements, could still go a long way towards pulling back the bilateral relationship from going over a cliff. Any tangible results will be subtle, but they can have ripple effects through governments and in corporate boardrooms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past few months, the Biden administration has expressed its openness to re-engage, only to be met with a cold shoulder from China. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen recently stated in congressional testimony that “decoupling would be a big mistake” and Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin said at the recent Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore that “conflict is neither imminent nor inevitable”. The Biden administration is running a political risk of being seen as soft on China by agreeing to meet without a clear sign that something positive will come out of the talks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On China&#39;s part, the acceptance of this meeting is partly out of necessity. China desperately needs sentiment to improve among Western business executives. These talks will occur against the backdrop of significant economic stress. Foreign investment in China is falling and Chinese stocks are struggling.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;The good days aren&#39;t coming back&#39;: China&#39;s economic downturn takes a toll&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On top of these are the rising difficulties for major international financial institutions, some of which have supported China for decades. These firms are now pulling out of initial public offerings and finding China a much tougher environment in which to operate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The relationship has nearly reached a breaking point. Even former high-flying billionaire investors like Ray Dalio, a long-time China bull, said at the Forbes Iconoclast Summit in New York this week that he thinks the US and China are headed for conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unnecessary difficulties for foreign businesses are also putting a damper on relations. New application rules for visits make trips to the mainland unnecessarily difficult by requiring reams of often invasive personal information.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of US students studying in China has also dropped precipitously to around 350 for the most recent academic year. The Covid-19 pandemic might have been the initial cause, but these students aren&#39;t returning in droves, either. This compares to the nearly 300,000 Chinese students who were studying in the US in 2021-22 despite bilateral tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A heavy-handed approach to visits only accelerates corporate plans to minimise their China exposure. What was once a contrarian view of Beijing&#39;s overreach is now becoming consensus. If Beijing shows some positive momentum in relations, then the better it is for its broader economy, investment and people-to-people contact. The alternative is a more isolated China, which benefits no one.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With regard to Blinken&#39;s visit, meetings scheduled over two days is one sign both sides are taking this more seriously. While a hosted dinner might be off the table, the longer the visit, the greater the opportunities for pull-asides, or informal talks away from the main meetings. It&#39;s in those informal moments where much of the diplomatic work gets done.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To further set expectations, a certain amount of talking past each other is to be expected in any US-China dialogue. Both sides are often posturing for their home audience to prove how tough they can be on the other side. Even though Foreign Minister Qin Gang has demanded Washington “stop interfering in China&#39;s internal affairs”, Blinken is likely to bring up human rights and Taiwan. These haven&#39;t ended talks in the past, and they shouldn&#39;t be sticking points this time, either.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington also has much on the line. As sober analyses of supply chains have made clear, there is no easy cutting off of commercial ties in industries that rely on Chinese processing and manufacturing. Lazard&#39;s recently released critical materials research brief highlights China&#39;s crucial role in mining and refining materials for clean energy, healthcare and advanced electronics. While it&#39;s de rigueur in domestic politics to call for cutting ties completely, in some areas that isn&#39;t a practical reality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other areas, such as combating climate change, are also enhanced through cooperation. As the orange-tinged smoky skies over Washington last week made clear, the effects of rising temperatures and changing weather patterns do not pay heed to political borders. Any outcome that puts a visit by John Kerry, the US special presidential envoy for climate, back on the calendar makes the Blinken trip worthwhile. He has been waiting months to officially restart conversations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington also gains by continuing to show its openness to dialogue, which signals to allies and unaligned countries that nuanced foreign policy trumps any hardline policies that threaten conflict. Putting aside Dalio&#39;s concern on the inevitability of great power conflict, there is nothing inevitable about the US and China heading to war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are no guarantees that these meetings will lead to anything except more than empty talk, of course. However, dialogue is the best chance for more to happen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the meeting is simply an airing of grievances akin to the Seinfeld “Festivus” episode, minus the humour, then it will be clear further dialogue is unlikely. That will be a choice made by officials, not historic inevitability.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[At least 15 dead after truck hits bus carrying elderly passengers in Manitoba, Canada]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224258/least-15-die-after-truck-hits-bus-carrying-elderly-passengers-manitoba-canada?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 07:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/1dd0e138-e36d-4e31-91f5-72d044bf71a0_561ddea3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;At least 15 people were killed in the Canadian prairie province of Manitoba on Thursday after an articulated truck hit a small bus that was carrying a group of mainly elderly people, local police said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The crash is one of the most lethal road accidents in recent Canadian history. Separately, the Winnipeg Free Press newspaper said the victims had been on their way to a local casino.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The crash occurred at the junction of two major roads near the town of Carberry in southwestern Manitoba, 170km (105 miles) west of Winnipeg.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ve been able to establish that at least 15 people have been confirmed deceased as a result of this collision,” said Assistant Commissioner Rob Hill, who commands the Manitoba Royal Canadian Mounted Police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hill told a televised news conference that “sadly, this is a day in Manitoba and across Canada that will be remembered as one of tragedy and incredible sadness”. The bus had been carrying about 25 people, most of them elderly, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said the drivers of both vehicles were alive. They declined to say who might have been responsible for the crash.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Media reports initially identified the vehicle as a van rather than a bus. They said it was operated by Handi-Transit, which transports the elderly and those with disabilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Canadian Broadcasting Corporation showed a still photo of a white minivan-sized vehicle that had been burned out. It also showed a picture of a blue truck with a smashed-in front.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Watch this&#39;: Australia wedding crash bus was going far too fast, police say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wheelchairs and crumpled walking frames remained near tarpaulins covering bodies at the site, the Winnipeg Free Press said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a tweet, Prime Minister Justin Trudeau lamented what he called “incredibly tragic” news.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m sending my deepest condolences to those who lost loved ones today, and I&#39;m keeping the injured in my thoughts. I cannot imagine the pain those affected are feeling,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My heart breaks hearing the news of the tragic accident near Carberry,” Manitoba Premier Heather Stefanson said on Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In neighbouring Saskatchewan, 16 people died in April 2018 after a truck hit a bus transporting a junior hockey team on a rural road. The truck driver was sentenced to eight years in prison in 2019.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s ‘blank paper’ graduates fear years of remote learning and no experience make them unemployable]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224211/chinas-blank-paper-graduates-fear-years-remote-learning-and-no-experience-make-them-unemployable?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/15/526a190a-05b2-4f12-9bb7-5b2b4e8ddef4_939659e8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;After fishing for more than 50 positions across various job portals, Connie Xu finally got a nibble – the chance to interview for an internship with a company in a major Chinese city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 22-year-old, who graduated this month with a degree in Chinese language and literature, considered herself a good candidate for the position, with the necessary skill set and classroom experience from projects at university. So, the Guangdong native travelled 90 minutes for the interview, anticipating that this could be her shot at gainful employment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It did not go as she had hoped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They said I&#39;m a greenhorn. In the words of my interviewer, I am a piece of blank paper without any actual work experience,” she recalled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, she continues to search. And she is hardly alone in struggling to find a job, especially among her fellow fresh graduates – all 11.58 million of them – entering China&#39;s workforce this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unemployment rate among Chinese aged 16 to 24 continued its rise in May to an all-time high of 20.8 per cent, up from the previous record-breaking 20.4 per cent in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s highly restrictive zero-Covid policy, which endured for nearly three years of the pandemic and featured citywide lockdowns, was abruptly abandoned in December, but the effects continue to be felt among the world&#39;s largest workforce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Much of the class of 2023 spent nearly all of their formative college years cut off from in-person learning and internships, and now many are struggling to convince employers that they can handle a real job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Four years of university, and we were stuck on campus for three years,” Xu lamented.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Miriam Wickertsheim, a Shanghai-based recruiter for foreign companies, said that fresh graduates she spoke to recently – those who studied for their undergraduate degree from 2019 to 2023 – feel more unattractive to recruiters after basically earning their degrees online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Their interviewers said they only learned remotely, so there were fewer social activities and fewer opportunities to work face-to-face, to develop teamwork and social skills,” she said. “Employers said they would just wait for the next batch of graduates.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that many small, private Chinese companies, which traditionally provide the first jobs for a lot of fresh graduates, suffered during the pandemic and are still trying to recover.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even if companies are putting up job openings, they are replacement positions instead of expansions. These are not positions that could be junior or graduate level,” Wickertsheim said. “It takes quite a lot of time and resources for a company to take a fresh graduate and teach them to a point where they are adding economic value to the company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At the moment, when the business climate is challenging, a lot of companies are reluctant to make those kinds of investments, especially when young graduates often have a certain turnover [rate] and higher volatility.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What is China&#39;s youth unemployment rate and why does it cover ages 16 to 24?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;At the same time, a lot of young people now are holding degrees that are simply not in demand, said Wickertsheim, who has worked in China for more than 13 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Graduates a decade ago studied engineering or finance or accounting, because this is what their parents or teachers recommended to them, so they could for sure find a job. Now, a lot of people have been brought up in a growing economy, and they are more at liberty to study something they find interesting, so that might make it a little bit more challenging to find work.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, China&#39;s youth unemployment rate keeps breaking records and continues to spark heated discourse across the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With one out of every five members of the 16-24 demographic unable to find a job, the central government has vowed to address the worsening trend that comes at a time when a bumpy post-pandemic recovery has led to weak consumer demand and mixed investor sentiments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 1, China&#39;s Ministry of Education announced a nationwide 100-day campaign “to guide graduates to take the initiative to seek jobs, and help more college graduates find employment as soon as possible, before and after leaving school”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For China&#39;s undergraduates, their job hunt typically begins in the fall semester of their final year, when major companies and public institutions hold campus-recruitment drives and aim to fill most of the headcount for their junior roles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The following spring-recruitment period, usually between March and May, fills any leftover quota and usually features fewer positions for pending graduates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But even those who do manage to land a job – often with their university&#39;s help – might not find themselves in the most advantageous position.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mo Haonan, a construction engineering major in Hangzhou, landed himself an internship through a recruitment drive organised by his university. He said the school invites companies that are actively hiring to job fairs, in a bid to expedite the hiring process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, his employment was short-lived, as the 21-year-old was laid off by his company weeks after helping out on a project.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;More freedom&#39;: China&#39;s youth embrace &#39;flexible&#39; work in bleak job market&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“They just treat us as cheap, dispensable labour. After finishing one project, they couldn&#39;t get any more clients, so they just fired us without much compensation,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And now, he fears, it could appear to future interviewers and corporate recruiters that he was laid off because of poor performance, which he said is not true, but nonetheless makes him feel a degree of shame.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, there is somewhat of a silver lining for fresh graduates, according to Eddie Cheng, an executive recruiter for Chinese companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Underperforming or non-essential middle-management positions are usually the first to go during lay-offs, while companies might open up more management-trainee positions, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some companies actually fire middle or senior positions and hire fresh graduates because they are cheaper. They are more willing to pay less money to hire a fresh graduate and train them up [for a few years]. The cost of hiring a general manager could be used to hire more than 30 fresh graduates,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can China&#39;s economy handle an unemployment crisis?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Xu, with her degree in hand, says she is exhausted from the endless job hunt. Asked whether she would still have majored in the same degree if she could do it all over again, she said she was of two minds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On the one hand, choosing Chinese language and literature seems more conservative for me, because this major is versatile, and there are many job options related to this major available for the civil service exam. I am also interested in Chinese language and literature,” she said. “However, when it comes to finding a job, other majors can accomplish the same.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the foreseeable future, Xu said she believes that those without internship experience will continue to be the first to have their resumes eliminated early in the application process. And she noted that even her friends who have earned outstanding grades have yet to land a job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Companies are all rushing to cut jobs, how will they hire? Even if they do, they will employ those who can take on multiple roles. This batch of graduates was locked down in school for three years, where do we get our industry experience from?”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>