<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Chinese citizens’ mistreatment a reminder Sino-Russian ties aren’t all wine and roses]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231078/chinese-citizens-mistreatment-reminder-sino-russian-ties-arent-all-wine-and-roses?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/339aa515-5870-4d20-b249-2031e9c83933_7eff4f1c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;上个月底，五名中国公民在俄罗斯边境受到不公平待遇时，中国人驻俄罗斯大使馆采取了不同寻常的举措，公开猛烈抨击莫斯科。中俄关系已今非昔比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯总统普京笨拙地侵略乌克兰后中俄关系的转变，让北京更愿意表达不满，呼应了中国人民对俄罗斯对待同胞的愤怒。无论两国政府在公开场合表现得多么亲密，两国人民之间在幕后却长期存在不信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅行作家科林·图布伦 (Colin Thubron) 沿着天然边界阿穆尔河踏上了一段非凡的旅程俄罗斯和中国之间。在去年 10 月出版的《阿穆尔河：俄罗斯和中国之间》一书中，图布伦通过大量描述俄罗斯人和中国人之间的强烈敌意和深刻的相互猜疑，生动地描述了这段经历。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;图布伦生动地回忆了古代的战争。过去的蔑视、冒犯以及不平等条约的持久影响，仿佛这些历史事件在当事人的脑海中仍然记忆犹新。俄罗斯人有根深蒂固的仇视中国的历史，这源于中俄两国地理上的接近，以及两国边境地区人口的严重失衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾任国防部长兼俄罗斯联邦司令的阿列克谢·库罗帕特金将军日俄战争期间的俄罗斯军队曾表示，如果取消中俄边界，允许中国人像俄罗斯人一样自由地迁徙到西伯利亚，西伯利亚最终将被中国化，而俄罗斯人将被迫迁出西伯利亚。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯人民友谊大学教授尤里·塔夫罗夫斯基认为，当中国提出远东发展倡议时，俄罗斯官员保持谨慎态度，并牢记这些担忧，尽管没有公开提及任何事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国在俄罗斯远东：地缘政治定时炸弹？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;另一方面，中国公共话语和学术界持续存在不满情绪俄罗斯在清朝衰落期间从衰弱的现代中国中获得了最大的领土优势。俄罗斯帝国对满洲的剥削是铁证如山。考虑到中国的审查制度，这种趋势变得更加重要，因为公开表达这些感受意味着中国政府的认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2011年，李健创作的中文歌曲《贝加尔湖》引发了悲伤的表达中国公民就其国家历史上对俄罗斯的领土让步提出了抗议。与此同时，中国企业对该湖的浓厚兴趣促使其在周边地区进行了大量投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这反过来又促使俄罗斯于2019年抗议中国新建工厂可能造成的潜在环境污染。塔夫罗夫斯基认为，这种历史领土叙事在俄罗斯和中国民众的民族心理中根深蒂固。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有什么比个人经历更有力量的了。 2015年至2017年，我在莫斯科国立国际关系学院攻读政治经济学硕士学位。作为一名土生土长的中国学生，我在寻求参加与中国相关的讲座时遇到了令人沮丧的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管获得了高级院长的签字许可，但我还是多次被俄罗斯汉学家拒绝，因为教授只想要当地的俄语学生参加。据教授说，关于中国和俄罗斯的讲座的某些方面，我作为一个中国人不应该知道。在这种情况下，我相信大多数中国人都会问，这与中国人在“百年屈辱”中所经历的歧视有何不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然越来越多的俄罗斯人学习汉语，但俄罗斯的教育和语言交流却很缓慢。中方无助于建立真正的信任和文化理解。尽管中俄官方关系显着升温，但值得注意的是，中国精英的后代大多在西方国家而不是俄罗斯接受教育。中国政府最近试图让中学生不再专注于英语学习，但收效甚微。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国和俄罗斯政府的发展，个人之间长期缺乏信任的情况现在看来可能微不足道。避免将这些情绪武器化。然而，不信任的地缘政治影响可能是深远的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯 HSE 大学的中俄专家亚历山大·卢金 (Alexander Lukin) 认为，美国可能的政策变化对俄中和解的影响可能小于俄罗斯对俄罗斯的担忧。中国的自信日益增强。自信主要源于两个因素——不断增强的实力和历史记忆——而中国两者兼而有之。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[17 killed in Niger in first major jihadi attack since coup, fuelling Western fears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3231341/17-killed-niger-first-major-jihadi-attack-coup-fuelling-western-fears?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 03:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/b6d14269-3b21-4735-93f1-0de672a56c0d_a1cdb63a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;叛乱分子在半年来的首次重大袭击中丧生 17 名士兵，近 24 人受伤西方列强担心尼日尔的精英总统卫队上个月发动的政变正在削弱西非萨赫勒地区反对圣战暴力的罕见盟友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日尔是该国最后的民主国家之一撒哈拉以南地区，法国和美国有大约2500名军事人员在那里训练尼日尔军队。法国还与其前殖民地开展了联合行动，但自政变以来，巴黎和华盛顿暂停了军事行动，给圣战分子更多的喘息空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二下午，一支军事分队在法国村庄之间移动时遭到袭击。国防部周二在国家电视台上表示，位于蒂拉贝里地区的博尼和托罗迪。伤员被疏散到首都尼亚美。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苏凡研究所记者兼高级研究员瓦西姆·纳斯尔表示，这是六个月来尼日尔军队首次遭受重大袭击，这是局势可能升级的令人担忧的迹象。中心，一个智囊团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们今天看到的是圣战交战派系、伊斯兰国组织和[基地组织附属组织伊斯兰努斯拉特穆斯林联盟]，都在标记他们的领土因为政变造成的安全真空。这绝对应该在两个组织之间持续战争的背景下看待。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邻国威胁要对政变采取军事行动，政变的支持者周三表示，他们将登记志愿者参加战斗并帮助满足其他需求，以便军政府有一份名单，以备不时之需。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位组织者 Amsarou Bako 声称，军政府没有参与寻找志愿者来捍卫政变，尽管它意识到这一倡议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚区域冲突的可能性有多大。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;西非集团为尼日尔可能的干预启动了“待命部队”&lt;/h3>;&lt;许多巴祖姆的支持者已被噤声或躲藏起来，支持总统的集会很快被警方取缔。自政变以来，被废黜的总统穆罕默德·巴祖姆政权的几名部长和政界人士已被拘留，人权组织无法接触到他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西非区域集团西非经共体表示，它已启动“待命状态”创始人之一巴科周二表示，将于周六在尼亚美以及入侵部队可能进入的城市（例如边境附近）启动招募活动尼日利亚和贝宁这两个国家已表示将参与干预。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管双方都发出信号称，尼日尔和西非经共体之间的对峙没有缓和的迹象，但地区紧张局势正在加深。愿意和平解决危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，军政府在拒绝了西非经共体多次谈判努力后表示愿意与西非经共体进行对话，但不久之后指控巴祖姆“叛国罪”并召回其大使&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士表示，政变持续的时间越长，随着军政府巩固权力，进行干预的可能性就越小，这可能会迫使国际社会接受现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯周二表示，仍有外交空间让该国恢复宪法统治，并表示美国支持西非经共体的对话努力，包括其应急计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据一位美国官员称，新任美国驻尼日尔大使凯瑟琳·菲茨吉本预计将于本周末抵达尼亚美。美国已经近两年没有驻该国大使了。一些萨赫勒专家表示，这使得华盛顿接触关键人物和信息的机会减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尼日尔政变领导人“将以叛国罪起诉被废黜的总统巴祖姆”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;而该地区和西方国家则在争夺对于如何应对，许多尼日尔人确信他们很快就会遭到入侵。这个拥有约 2500 万人口的国家是世界上最贫穷的国家之一，居民希望新政权能让国家走上一条新道路。星期三在尼亚美，热切的当地人表示他们会尽一切努力保卫国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我和我的孩子们热爱这些士兵，我邀请年轻人加入军队，发展我们的国家和村庄”，住在路边棚户区的尼亚美居民阿马杜·哈瓦 (Amadou Hawa) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日尔志愿部队的细节仍然模糊，但邻国的类似举措取得了不同的结果。布基纳法索的志愿战士被招募来帮助军队打击圣战叛乱，他们被人权组织和当地人指控对平民犯下暴行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴科是组织尼日尔志愿者的组织的负责人之一，说尼日尔的情况有所不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[布基纳法索的志愿者]正在与拿武器攻击自己兄弟的布基纳法索人作战……与我们不同的是，我们的人民将反抗入侵，”他在英语。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pig kidney works in donated body for over a month in step toward animal-human transplants]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231339/pig-kidney-works-donated-body-over-month-step-toward-animal-human-transplants?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 01:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/41d32d7b-2723-4b9f-b965-fb18bc927505_6f4809b1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;外科医生将猪肾移植到脑死亡的人体内，并持续了一个多月工作正常——这是纽约团队希望最终在活体患者身上进行手术的关键一步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国各地的科学家正在竞相学习如何使用动物器官来拯救人类生命，并捐赠了遗体为研究提供了一次非凡的预演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约大学朗格健康中心周三宣布的最新实验标志着猪肾在人体内发挥作用的最长时间，尽管是一个已故的人 - 而且它还没有结束。研究人员将在第二个月内追踪肾脏的表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个器官真的能像人体器官一样工作吗？纽约大学朗格尼移植研究所所长罗伯特·蒙哥马利博士说：“到目前为止，它看起来就是这样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月 14 日，蒙哥马利在为一名已故男子更换肾脏时说道，“它看起来甚至比人类的肾脏还要好”。莫里斯的家人相信，有一天，猪肾可能有助于缓解可移植器官的严重短缺，“Mo来自纽约州北部的米勒捐献了自己的遗体用于该实验。 57 岁时，他突然去世，患有先前未确诊的脑癌，排除了常规器官捐赠的可能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我为此苦苦挣扎，”他的妹妹玛丽·米勒-达菲 (Mary Miller-Duffy) 谈到她的决定时说道。但他喜欢帮助别人，“我认为这就是我哥哥想要的。所以我把我的兄弟献给了他们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他将被载入医学书籍，他将永远活下去，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港医生敦促居民随着肾移植率下降，成为捐赠者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;几十年来，由于人们的免疫系统攻击外来组织，动物移植或异种移植的尝试都失败了。现在，研究人员正在使用基因改造的猪，以便它们的器官更好地匹配人体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，在监管机构的特别许可下，马里兰大学的外科医生将基因编辑的猪心脏移植到一名垂死的男子体内，该男子患有心脏疾病。选项。他只活了两个月，就因器官衰竭而失败，原因尚不完全清楚，但为未来的尝试提供了教训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接下来，美国食品和药物管理局不是做最后的努力，而是考虑是否允许对志愿者患者进行猪心脏或肾脏移植的一些小规模但严格的研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约大学的实验是旨在加快此类临床试验启动的一系列进展之一。同样在周三，阿拉巴马大学伯明翰分校报告了另一项重要成功——一对猪肾在另一具捐赠体内正常工作了 7 天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肾脏不仅仅产生尿液，它们还提供广泛的尿液。体内的工作。在《JAMA 外科杂志》杂志上，UAB 移植外科医生 Jayme Locke 博士报告了实验室测试，记录了基因修饰猪器官的性能。她说，为期一周的实验表明它们可以“提供维持生命的肾功能”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此类实验对于回答“在我们不会将某人的生命置于危险之中的环境中”的剩余问题至关重要。 ”，纽约大学肾脏移植外科医生蒙哥马利说，他也接受了自己的心脏移植手术，并且敏锐地意识到需要新的器官来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;超过 100,000 名患者在国家的移植名单上，并且每年都有数千人在等待中死去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马里兰州的 Muhammad Mohiuddin 博士警告说，目前尚不清楚死者的尸体会在多大程度上模仿活人患者对猪器官的反应。但他表示，这项研究让公众了解异种移植，这样当需要在活人身上再次尝试时，“人们就不会感到震惊”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“他救了我的命”：之前的捐赠让中国妈妈走上了快速通道新肾脏&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;此前，纽约大学和阿拉巴马大学伯明翰分校的一个团队在已故受者身上测试了猪肾移植仅两三天。纽约大学的一个团队还将猪心脏移植到捐赠的身体中，进行了三天的严格测试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，猪的器官如何对更常见的人类免疫攻击做出反应，这种攻击需要大约一个月的时间才能形成？只有更长时间的测试才能证明这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;手术本身与他所进行的数千次手术并没有什么不同，“但在你内心深处的某个地方，你正在做的事情是巨大的......认识到这可能会产生蒙哥马利说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;手术的时机非常谨慎。那天一早，亚当·格里塞默 (Adam Griesemer) 博士和杰弗里·斯特恩 (Jeffrey Stern) 医生飞了数百公里，来到位于弗吉尼亚州的 Revivicor Inc. 饲养转基因猪的设施，并取回了缺乏会立即被人类免疫系统破坏的基因的肾脏。&lt;/p>;&lt;当他们赶回纽约大学时，蒙哥马利正在从捐赠的身体中取出两个肾脏，因此毫无疑问即将到达的猪版本是否有效。一个猪肾被移植，另一个被保存起来以供实验结束时进行比较。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个技巧：外科医生将猪的胸腺连接到移植的肾脏上，希望有助于训练免疫细胞的腺体能够增加人体对器官的耐受性。否则，该团队将依赖当今移植患者使用的标准免疫抑制药物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你总是很紧张，”格里塞默说。看到它如此迅速地启动，“我感到非常兴奋，也感到如释重负”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些实验应该持续多长时间？阿拉巴马州的洛克表示，这一点尚不清楚，道德问题包括一个家庭能舒适多久，或者这是否会增加他们的悲伤。因为用呼吸机维持一个脑死亡的人很困难，这也取决于捐献身体的稳定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在她自己的实验中，捐献的身体足够稳定，如果不需要进行研究的话一周后结束，“我认为我们可以走得更久，我认为这带来了很大的希望”，她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong, Thai police arrest 4 in joint operation after officers uncover drug syndicate smuggling heroin inside plaster lion statues]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3231340/hong-kong-thai-police-arrest-4-joint-operation-after-officers-uncover-drug-syndicate-smuggling?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 01:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/cc5b8d44-422b-4a9d-b695-14a93b970264_9510eb9b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港和泰国警方在跨境反恐怖袭击中逮捕了四名城市居民- 缉毒行动，警方查获超过 12 公斤疑似海洛因和可卡因，价值 1,200 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港警方周三透露了此次行动的细节，称四名嫌疑人（两男两女）是前一天被捕。调查人员表示，一个香港贩毒集团将海洛因块从泰国走私到香港，并将其藏在石膏狮子雕像内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两名香港男子在元朗区被捕，并被关押在两名女子在曼谷被警方拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;75岁旅客因涉嫌在体内藏匿可卡因在香港被捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;缉毒局总督察查耀光警方表示，警方根据与东南亚国家同行交换的信息，发现该集团通过空运​​从泰国进口海洛因，警方于 7 月开始行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该集团在当地招募成员，并将他们送往泰国以获得药品供应。查姆说，这些成员随后将毒品藏在货物中，然后将其运回市区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经调查，警方在元屏山一村屋拘捕两名男子，年龄分别为38岁和26岁。周二上午，警方涉嫌串谋贩运危险药物。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;3名抵达香港的旅客因体内藏有可卡因被捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方在香港发现了几只破碎的石膏狮子雕像。查姆说，公寓和三块海洛因砖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方在打开另外三座完好的雕像后，发现了另外七块海洛因砖，总重 3.5 公斤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当天晚些时候，这名38岁男子被护送到元朗的家中，警方在那里发现了387克强效可卡因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曼谷警方逮捕了两名香港女子，据称她们属于同一犯罪集团，并查获24块砖块，即8.4公斤海洛因，以及包装工具和狮子雕像模具。他们目前被警方拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;查姆警告居民不要试图通过帮助毒品走私集团来赚快钱，并表示那些被判犯有贩运罪的人可能面临无期徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;男子案件将于周四在屯门裁判法院审理。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How India is gaining ground in its Indo-Pacific maritime contest with China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231069/how-india-gaining-ground-its-indo-pacific-maritime-contest-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/eb989a80-8367-4a72-978e-791372530206_50a6f939.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;8月10日，中国军舰海洋二十四号海监船访问斯里兰卡首都科伦坡。它的抵达恰逢澳大利亚东海岸的马拉巴尔演习。为期 10 天的演习涉及来自四方安全对话成员国的印度、日本、澳大利亚和美国的潜艇和飞机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在前往悉尼海岸的途中，印度海军军舰途经巴布亚新几内亚和所罗门群岛，表明印度对加强与太平洋国家的军事和外交关系越来越感兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些事态发展反映了中印之间日益加深的海上竞争。近年来，印度制衡中国在印度洋地区日益增强的影响力的努力已开始在南海和太平洋地区取得进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的海上航线经南海和马六甲海峡延伸至印度洋。印度洋在斯里兰卡的港口分裂。一条路线经北部阿拉伯海通往波斯湾，另一条路线经亚丁湾到达地中海。这些路线被中国领导人视为海上“生命线”，由中国人民解放军 (PLA) 负责保卫，并由控制或经营沿线数百个港口的中国公司提供情报和后勤支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度的主要港口海上边界从孟加拉湾和安达曼海，穿过马六甲和新加坡，一直延伸到波斯湾、亚丁湾和非洲东海岸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首次举行马拉巴尔演习此前在澳大利亚举办过，印度洋地区、东海、菲律宾海和关岛也曾举办过。迄今为止，印度尚未参加有争议的南海地区的海上演习。这样的举动目前不太可能发生，但将具有极大的对抗性 — — 并且只有中国在斯里兰卡的汉班托塔、巴基斯坦的瓜达尔港或缅甸的皎漂港建立永久海军存在的情况下才可能发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果中国这样做，将获得对印度海军在印度洋地区行动的独家监督，尤其是增强其地区海洋意识和作战知识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了防止这种情况，印度似乎采取了三管齐下的方法：加强其在印度洋地区的军事行动。海军作战能力，与印度洋地区国家培养军事和外交关系，特别是通过建立海外海上监视设施，并通过海军演习和军事条约争取志同道合国家的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度计划到2030年通过三艘航空母舰、200多架海军战斗机、五艘核动力潜艇和更多P-8I海上侦察机增强其反水面和潜艇战能力。它还正在升级其在安达曼和尼科巴群岛的军事和威慑能力。这可以帮助其监视中国在缅甸可可群岛及其他地区的海军活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度还推出了沿海监视雷达系统，在孟加拉国、斯里兰卡、马尔代夫、塞舌尔和缅甸。在毛里求斯阿加莱加岛上建立军事基地，据报道配备了印度军舰的停靠设施和 P-8I 飞机的跑道，也可以帮助其追踪中国潜艇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度的此类行动和投资将只会增长，只要中国将其在印度洋的活动限制在偶尔部署军舰，就应该足够了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但印度也与战略伙伴建立了法律框架和作战后勤，以表明其准备采取集体行动如有必要，将对中国采取军事行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度的演习，包括马拉巴尔演习，旨在增强与日本、澳大利亚、美国和法国的军事互操作性。它与美国的军事协定也让它受益于共享情报和获得区域海军后勤的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果中国扩大在印度洋的军事足迹，并在有争议的喜马拉雅边境向印度施压，印度可能会有更多方式惹恼中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;姿态转变的迹象正在出现。印度不仅将东南亚视为其武器市场，而且还参加了东南亚国家联盟最近的海上演习。虽然演习仅限于无争议的南海地区以避免激怒中国，但据报道，它们受到了中国的密切关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度首次表示支持 2016 年海牙裁决，该裁决驳回了该裁决北京对争议海域的主张有利于菲律宾。它还继续与东盟成员国讨好并合作开发其沿海监视雷达系统和信息融合中心网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么东盟公开支持美国在该地区的存在可能不会令中国感到不安&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;印度在南海的贸易路线虽然是次要利益区，但在其战略考量中正变得越来越重要。印度不断扩大的外交关系和在南太平洋岛屿的海上存在也表明，它越来越愿意在更广阔的印度太平洋地区与中国竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但印度与东盟和太平洋岛屿的接触只是为了获得外交胜利积分并确保经济收益；其海军演习和巡逻主要增强其在南半球的软实力。它仍然缺乏与中国在印太地区影响力相匹敌的经济和军事实力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于印度在 2020 年与中国发生边境冲突后无法夺回领土，越南和印度等国家不太可能夺回领土。菲律宾在与中国的海上争端中将依赖印度的军事支持。相反，印度可能会与该地区其他大国联合起来，加大对中国的集体压力，同时避免采取可能引发反击的军事措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s construction sector seeks to bring in 3,910 workers under labour import scheme to offset shortfall]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3231336/hong-kongs-construction-sector-seeks-bring-3910-workers-under-labour-import-scheme-offset-shortfall?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 00:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/78792468-af9e-46af-a3e2-78d438c58c8c_72e8bd8f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港建筑业已要求根据该市计划引进近 4,000 名工人，进口劳工，占该行业配额的近三分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些要求包含在周三午夜截止日期前几小时向发展局提交的11份申请中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“发展局该局将按顺序处理申请，预计审核过程将于9月底完成。” “首批输入劳工将于今年第四季抵达。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一轮申请已于7月17日开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港于2017年推出输入劳工计划。 2018年至2022年间，香港低技能雇员人数减少16万人，预计6月引进2万名工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港首批引进机场员工最早12月开始工作&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;该计划允许建筑业输入最多12,000名劳工，而航空业和运输业可分别输入6,300名和1,700名劳工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该局周三表示，申请获得批准的企业应采取行动采取聘请有资质的劳务公司招工、代办签证等措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;建造业下一轮申请将于10月1日开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港建造商会会长林建荣表示，申请数字反映雇主只会按工程阶段招聘工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“雇主须视乎建造工程的进度，聘用具体工种。”他们在最好的时间需要的工人，”他解释道。 “如果工人已经到了，但需要等待，雇主就会承担费用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会会长表示，预计建造业的配额将在两轮或三轮申请后完成&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民主建港联盟议员颜文宇表示，申请数量显示雇主需要时间来处理新政策并准备文件。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要符合输入劳工的资格，他们需要办理一定的程序，包括在申请前四个月进行本地招聘，所以即使人手充足，他们也不一定能在第一轮通过。他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些雇主也没有提交申请，因为第一批工人可能会在圣诞节和农历新年假期左右开始工作，届时建筑工地可能会关闭。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;颜建议当局在内地设立跨境培训中心，帮助工人在来港前获得必要的资格，降低雇主的潜在成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据劳工法根据进口计划，只要公司保障当地员工的就业，香港就可以绕开劳工顾问委员会引进建筑、运输和航空领域的工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港运输运营商申请进口1,600名内地工人华裔司机&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;雇主在申请引进劳工之前必须在本市物色候选人，并维持每引进一名工人两名当地雇员的比例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;引进工人的工资必须不低于相关工作的月工资中位数。雇主还必须为根据该计划引进的人员提供住宿。符合资格的公司必须持有价值不少于10亿港元（1.27亿美元）的持续公共部门建筑合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划得到了市领导李家超及其关键决策的批准六月的行政会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府早前透露，运输业已申请从内地引进1,600名小巴及旅游巴士司机，占该行业配额的94%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在航空方面，已提交了涉及近2,900名劳工的申请。该数字约占该行业配额的 45%。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= “color:orange” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Woman awarded US$1.2 billion in revenge-porn case after ex-boyfriend created fake Pornhub profile to share explicit photos]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231326/woman-awarded-us12-billion-revenge-porn-case-after-ex-boyfriend-created-fake-pornhub-profile-share?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/b4bb95dd-c49c-431a-987c-1000384a9603_d277257f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;德克萨斯州一名自称多年来生活在恐惧之中的妇女获得了超过 10 亿美元的奖励据当地新闻媒体 KHOU 11 报道，陪审团在色情报复案中向陪审团支付了 100 美元，远远高于她的律师的要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法律文件中仅显示该女子为无名氏 (Jane Doe)，她曾与该男子约会过，名叫贾马尔·杰克逊·马克斯 (Jamal Jackson Marques)，四年后他们的关系于 2021 年结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正是在那时，骚扰开始了，杰克逊在 Facebook、Twitter、Dropbox 和她的律师 Pornhub 上发布私密照片和视频据 KHOU 11 报道，布拉德福德·J·格莱德 (Bradford J. Glide) 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每天都是我，醒来，我在检查，我在努力阻止它，我在努力限制它，”一位女士告诉 ABC 13。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据当地新闻媒体报道，她补充道，“这种经历是毁灭性的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他们交往期间，简·多伊曾同意私下分享一些亲密的事情。与杰克逊的合照。然而，法庭文件称，她已明确表示（无论是明确还是含蓄），这些照片不得透露给任何其他人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但法庭文件称，前男友开始非法传播这些私人照片。 and videos by publicly uploading them to multiple social media and other online platforms, often accompanied by identifying features such as her name and home address.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jackson took the invasion of privacy further, gathering additional material by secretly logging into Jane Doe&#39;s mom&#39;s home security system to spy on her via its audio and visual features, according to court documents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman&#39;s lawyers did not immediately respond to Insider&#39;s request for comment. Jackson could not be reached for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Court documents, as well as remarks by her lawyer to ABC 13, showed that Jackson went to great lengths to share the private material, creating fake profiles on platforms including Twitter, Facebook, and YouTube.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Miss Universe cuts ties with Indonesia organiser accused of sexual harassment&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He would then send messages and emails containing hyperlink URLs to Jane Doe&#39;s friends, family, and coworkers, according to court documents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jackson also created a public website with a Dropbox folder attached, which contained intimate images, court documents said, along with a page impersonating her on Pornhub, a lawyer told KHOU 11.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additionally, Jackson tagged the social media accounts of Jane Doe&#39;s workplace and gym on social media, directing them to links containing the photos and videos, according to court documents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“His purpose is to ruin her,” the woman&#39;s lawyer, Gilde, said, per KHOU 11.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adding to the torment, Jackson gained unauthorised access to Jane Doe&#39;s bank account, using her money to cover his own rent, while further subjecting her to relentless calls and messages from concealed phone numbers, according to court documents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Texas made it a felony to share intimate photos or videos of someone without their consent in 2015, with the law updated in 2019 to include the intention of harming the person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The case went to a jury last week, which took just 30 minutes to reach their verdict, ABC 13 reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jane Doe was awarded US $1.2 billion, more than the US$1 billion her lawyers had asked for, but it is unlikely she will receive anywhere near that much&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regardless, her lawyer Jacob Schiffer told KHOU 11 that the ruling sends a powerful message: “Do not mess with Texas and do not mess with Texas women.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the original article on &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[WTO finds China acted ‘inconsistently’ by imposing additional duties on certain US imports]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231334/wto-finds-china-acted-inconsistently-imposing-additional-duties-certain-us-imports?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 23:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/57e82fe6-0261-4bb3-bfa6-7c358a631a9f_4a9c6479.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China violated its fundamental trade commitments when it imposed tariffs on US$2.4 billion worth of US products in retaliation for former President Donald Trump&#39;s steel and aluminium duties, the World Trade Organization (WTO) said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a ruling published on Wednesday, a panel of three WTO experts agreed with Washington&#39;s claims that China&#39;s tariffs denied the treatment as a so-called most favoured nation, and that Beijing violated other trade concessions it made when it joined the WTO.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The organisation&#39;s most favoured nation principle is a commitment by its 164 members to treat other signatories in an indiscriminate manner or else provide compensation in the form of trade concessions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China slams US Chips Act subsidies at WTO as tensions ratchet higher&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Either China or the US may appeal the ruling within the next 60 days. If Beijing appeals, it will act as a veto because the WTO appellate body has been non-functional since 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Commerce Ministry statement said that it had noticed the finding from the WTO panel, and is studying the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dispute dates back to the early days of Trump&#39;s trade war when his administration imposed 25 per cent tariffs on global steel imports and 10 per cent tariffs on aluminium imports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US metal tariffs, which were aimed at curbing an influx of cheap Chinese steel and aluminium, provoked a response from Beijing, which filed a WTO complaint and imposed tariffs on a range of imported US goods including aluminium waste and scrap, pork, fruits and nuts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US responded with a counter dispute alleging the Chinese duties and separately claimed that the metal tariffs were necessary to protect US national security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In December 2022, a separate WTO panel said the US metal duties were not justified under the WTO&#39;s national security exemption in a ruling that the Biden administration strongly rejected. Trump&#39;s tariffs on Chinese steel and aluminium still remain in effect.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The office of the US Trade Representative on Wednesday said it was happy with the WTO panel report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The United States is pleased with the World Trade Organization (WTO) panel report released today, recognising that the US Section 232 actions on steel and aluminium are security measures, and that the People&#39;s Republic of China (China) illegally retaliated with sham &#39;safeguard&#39; tariffs,” the USTR said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s Wang Yi urges closer ties with South Asia under Belt and Road Initiative]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231331/chinas-wang-yi-urges-closer-ties-south-asia-under-belt-and-road-initiative?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 22:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/8f712556-711b-4df6-93b1-13afe7893176_200d7551.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Top Chinese diplomat Wang Yi has called for closer ties with South Asian countries – urging them to “share the benefits of China&#39;s growth” and its massive infrastructure push in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China and South Asia should build “a development community” for the long-term stability and prosperity of the region, Wang told the opening ceremony of the 7th China-South Asia Expo in the southwestern city of Kunming on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prime Minister Dinesh Gunawardena of Sri Lanka, who is on an official visit to China, was chief guest at the event. The vice-presidents of Nepal and Laos, and the deputy prime minister of Vietnam also attended.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang, the foreign affairs chief of China&#39;s ruling Communist Party and recently reappointed as foreign minister, also called on countries in the region to deepen strategic trust and increase mutual support on international and regional matters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[We should] join hands to advocate an open regionalism, build closer regional cooperation, jointly safeguard the interests of developing countries and jointly defend international justice,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The economic bond between China and its southern neighbours could be made stronger by increasing inter-connectivity under Beijing&#39;s flagship Belt and Road Initiative, which includes massive cross-border infrastructure projects like the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC) and the planned China-Nepal railway, Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China welcomes South Asian countries to continue to ride on China&#39;s development momentum and share the benefits of China&#39;s growth,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also called for deeper trade ties and the alignment of systems and standards to boost global supply chain links, as well as more people-to-people exchanges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The China-South Asia Expo is part of Beijing&#39;s efforts to promote stronger links with regional countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The four-day event this year is being co-hosted by the Chinese Ministry of Commerce and the Yunnan provincial government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Participants include South Asian countries like India, Pakistan, Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, Nepal and the Maldives, as well as Southeast Asian nations and members of the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership, according to the organisers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The expo was launched in 2013, when President Xi Jinping initiated his signature belt and road strategy to extend China&#39;s global reach through infrastructure and investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Asia, with its strategically significant land and sea routes, has a key role in the ambitious connectivity plan stretching into the Middle East, Africa and Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For instance, the CPEC is the “flagship” project of the initiative, with China pledging US$62 billion for ports, oil and gas pipelines, power plants, roads and railways in Pakistan, its key strategic partner in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Over the past 10 years, we have consolidated our unity and cooperation and jointly maintained a safe and secure environment for development in the region. We have continued to build the belt and road together and have made encouraging progress in connectivity, infrastructure, trade and investment,” Wang told guests at the expo.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Latest Pakistan terror attack casts light on growing cost of Chinese investment&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;However, there have been some hurdles along the way.巴基斯坦的“一带一路”项目遭遇了当地的一些阻力以及包括恐怖袭击在内的安全威胁。 In the latest such incident, Balochistan militants attacked a convoy of Chinese workers on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Sri Lanka, China&#39;s development plans have been accused of worsening the country&#39;s debt crisis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India, the largest country in South Asia, has refused to back the initiative, given an unresolved border dispute with China as well as their strategic rivalry, and concerns about the geopolitical implications of some of the Chinese-led projects in South Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping speech calling for patience released amid economic gloom]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3231318/xi-jinping-speech-calling-patience-released-amid-economic-gloom?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/3eaa50e2-3d17-4480-b07b-db61e1d06899_ef617ff1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As China&#39;s economic slump worsens, a Communist Party mouthpiece has highlighted a speech given by President Xi Jinping calling for patience and resilience in the pursuit of “the national rejuvenation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi was addressing hundreds of top party members during the February 7 speech, part of which was published in the official Qiushi journal on Tuesday – hours after Beijing released more disappointing monthly economic data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The party journal regularly highlights internal leadership speeches months after they are given.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tuesday&#39;s article emphasised the difficulties of modernising a country of China&#39;s size and said its unique development model was still its best hope.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It asked the public to take the long view and stay focused, balancing progress and stability with sustainability.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should first consider the size of the population and the large rural-urban development gap. We cannot be ambitious and unrealistic, but we cannot simply follow the beaten path,” Xi was quoted as saying by Quishi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should be patient [with a historical perspective] and move forward in a steadfast manner.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi gave the speech months after his historic third term as party leader began in October and ahead of the annual parliamentary meetings in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He repeated his major policy initiatives – “common prosperity”, the green economy and upholding socialist values as the cornerstone of China&#39;s development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The part of the speech published in Qiushi focused on the task of steering one of the world&#39;s most populous countries towards a national renaissance and stressed the need for patience and perseverance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A super big population can provide sufficient manpower and a super big domestic market, but it also brings about a series of difficulties and challenges,” Xi told his new team in February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is quite a challenge just to make sure 1.4 billion people are fed.然后是就业、分配、教育、医疗、住房、养老、育儿等问题。 They are all not easy to resolve and they all involve an astronomical number of people.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The article came after China published a raft of weak economic data showing sluggish retail sales, industrial production and property investment. Beijing has stopped releasing youth unemployment data, which hit a record high of 21.3 per cent in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest economic data has prompted fears about the country&#39;s slowdown, which analysts say will not be turned around by measures such as interest rate cuts that were also announced on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is also reeling from widespread flooding in recent weeks, while there is growing pressure from demographic problems such as a low birth rate and a rapidly greying society.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi also spoke about the middle-income trap, where countries fail to emerge as high-income.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some developing countries have almost reached the threshold of developed countries in their process of modernisation, but they have fallen into the middle-income trap and been stuck in stagnation for a long time or even backtracked substantially,” Xi said. “One of the reasons is that they have not resolved [social] polarisation and stratification.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi said the common prosperity policy was a “long-term mission” that must be carried out persistently and make continuous progress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Calling the policy the essence of Chinese modernisation, Xi condemned Western modernisation, saying it maximised the interests of capitalists and was characterised by “wars, slavery, colonisation and exploitation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Common prosperity – a policy aimed at narrowing the wealth gap – has caused anxiety among entrepreneurs and foreign companies in recent years, but Beijing denies it is seeking to suppress private enterprises.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alfred Wu Muluan, an associate professor at the National University of Singapore&#39;s Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy, said the Qiushi article was aimed at boosting confidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At a time when an economic crisis is looming, the party wants to paint a rosy picture … to ensure people that the goals Xi has set are realistic and that China&#39;s path is unique and better than the West&#39;s,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong prepares for arrival of 4,500 passengers aboard Spectrum of the Seas, authorities vow transport chaos will be averted]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3231328/hong-kong-prepares-arrival-4500-passengers-aboard-spectrum-seas-authorities-vow-transport-chaos-will?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 22:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/767ae5e6-fb4c-4097-b394-78791b3246b4_47568ad0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong authorities have expressed confidence in their ability to ensure the smooth return of cruise ship Spectrum of the Seas on Saturday, two weeks after its docking caused a logistics fiasco affecting more than 5,000 passengers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deputy Chief Secretary Warner Cheuk Wing-hing earlier held a second meeting with tourism authorities, transport officials and the terminal operators to devise plans for the ship&#39;s return to the Kai Tak Cruise Terminal, the government on Wednesday said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Tourism Commission, the Tourism Board and the cruise terminal operator have been in close contact with the cruise line in the past week to work together to make proper and orderly transportation arrangements for disembarking passengers,” a spokesman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The cruise company will disembark the passengers in batches, provide them with sufficient traffic information on board and understand their transport options in advance.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 1,100 of the 4,500 passengers carried by Royal Caribbean International&#39;s Spectrum of the Seas would take part in shore trips arranged by the cruise line on Saturday, while the rest would mainly use public transport to head to various sightseeing destinations, according to the government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ship returned to the city on August 4 after a nearly two-year absence and the thousands of passengers overloaded transport at the terminal. Hundreds were forced to wait in line for taxis or buses, in some cases for as long as 45 minutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities responded by introducing incentives for taxis – a HK$50 (US$6.40) cash coupon to top up their petrol tanks – and free shuttle buses to key attractions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, the government said that two additional bus routes, 20R and 25R, would take passengers between the cruise terminal and Tsim Sha Tsui and Kwun Tong on Saturday, with the special service able to carry 900 passengers every half an hour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 22R route would continue to collect passengers to the Kai Tak MTR station, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Cruise control? Hong Kong&#39;s measures for tourist ships to avoid terminal jam&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Citybus said the 20R route would stop at the Victoria Dockside, Star Ferry Pier and Peninsula hotel. The entire journey would take about 25 minutes, with a headway of 10 to 15 minutes, the bus operator said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;KMB said the express route 25R would not make any stops between the cruise terminal and the APM mall in Kwun Tong and arrive at intervals of 10 to 25 minutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three shuttle bus services would take passengers to Mong Kok, Admiralty and the Garden Road peak tram station, while the original 22R route to Tsim Sha Tsui would also stop at the West Kowloon Cultural District and Kowloon station on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong cruise terminal operator rejects commercial revamp, stresses role as port&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The government added it expected a strong demand for taxis on the day, given the cruise ship was only in the city for one day. Officials vowed to improve real-time information updates for cabbies while continuing to offer the HK$50 coupon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tourism sector lawmaker Perry Yiu Pak-leung said the announced plan was a “huge improvement” but warned its effectiveness would still depend on the real-time situation after the ship docked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The government should have another string for its bow in case of emergencies, such as having other kinds of vehicles standing by if no taxis are willing to come,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last Saturday, Secretary for Culture, Sports and Tourism Kevin Yeung Yun-hung said authorities had learned a lesson from the chaos and pledged to improve transport arrangements immediately.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apart from Spectrum of the Seas, three other ships operated by Resorts World Cruises were scheduled to berth on Wednesday, Friday and Sunday.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>