<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Vietnam detains prominent climate activist on tax evasion accusation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222798/vietnam-detains-prominent-climate-activist-tax-evasion-accusation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 19:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/d63cffe6-7715-4dc5-8b15-a27fbfbd2fdb_209da937.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;她的丈夫在周五，在面临指控的环保主义者名单中又增加了一个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旨在解决该国一些最紧迫的环境问题的非政府组织 Change 的创始人 Hoang Thi Minh Hong 被拘留周三在胡志明市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我可以证实自 5 月 31 日以来，Hong 一直因逃税指控被临时拘留，”Hoang Vinh Nam 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong 创立2013 年的变化，重点是动员越南人，尤其是年轻人，采取行动应对紧迫的环境问题，包括气候变化、非法野生动物贸易和污染。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;越南的下龙湾如何受到污染以及正在采取什么行动清理它&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她去年宣布，在越南独裁政府以逃税罪判处四名环境人权捍卫者 Nguy Thi Khanh、Mai Phan Loi、Bach Hung Duong 和 Dang 入狱后，Change 将关闭Dinh Bach。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“越南有选择地使用其模糊和有缺陷的税法来针对环保主义者和气候变化活动家，并对其进行出于政治动机的起诉，这是一个新的、极其令人不安的事态发展，”该委员会亚洲区副主任菲尔·罗伯逊 (Phil Robertson) 说。人权观察。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“主要环保活动家 Hoang Thi Minh Hong 是这场加速镇压的最新受害者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;50 岁的 Hong 因其工作而广受认可：她加入了2018 年在纽约哥伦比亚大学参加奥巴马基金会学者计划，并被福布斯评为 2019 年最具影响力的 50 位越南女性之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Khanh，全球知名的气候和能源活动家，曾获得高盛环境奖Khanh 于 2018 年入狱近一年，然后于上个月获释。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为越南最知名的环保组织之一，Green ID 的创始人，Khanh 是这个共产主义国家为数不多的挑战环保组织的人之一政府增加煤电的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社区律师和非政府组织工作人员 Dang Dinh Bach 致力于告知那些健康和生计受到煤炭项目和其他污染行业威胁的人们。他被判处五年徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国任意拘留问题工作组认定他的监禁是非法的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;亚裔澳大利亚人泪眼婆娑的越南 TikTok 引发了“贫民窟”旅游业的强烈反对&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;越南已承诺到 2050 年实现净零碳排放，一些富裕国家去年承诺筹集至少 155 亿美元帮助该国摆脱化石燃料。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;在越南倡导人权的非营利组织 Project 88 的联席主任本·斯旺顿 (Ben Swanton) 表示，洪的被捕表明“与其宣传相反，越南政府不尊重法治，不希望民间社会参与该国的能源转型”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周四回答有关 Hong 被捕的问题时，外交部副发言人 Nguyen Duc Thang 说：“越南一直申明其强有力的致力于环境保护和应对气候变化、绿色和可持续发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在越南，个人、协会和组织、非政府组织依法依规正常运作，同时，他们必须遵守法律并为自己的活动承担法律责任。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China food security: wheat crops face ‘unprecedented’ risks as world heats up, study finds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3222765/china-food-security-wheat-crops-face-unprecedented-risks-world-heats-study-finds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/64ec7935-330e-49d4-8983-7725b908993f_55e38cf2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;热浪将在全球范围内变得更加频繁——一项新的气候分析表明这是一种趋势将对包括中国和美国在内的小麦生产国产生严重影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个国际科学家小组表示，全球变暖将导致季节性模式的变化、极端温度和干旱将降低作物产量预测，并补充说世界应该为气候变化引起的粮食不安全做好准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了减轻影响，来自英国、荷兰、美国和津巴布韦的研究团队建议农业生产者开始种植更多的热量-耐小麦品种，同时扩大粮食系统以减少一个地区的失败可能破坏世界粮食供应的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了进行比较，研究人员使用 1981 年的数据来准确了解气候正在进行的变化。分析表明，当时大约 100 年才可能发生一次的热浪，现在可能在美国中西部每六年发生一次，在中国东北部每 16 年发生一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;如何极端降雨正在对中国的水稻作物造成越来越大的损失&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在最坏的情况下，虽然可能性不大，但中国和美国的小麦产量在同一季节或与其他国家同时歉收主要农作物、食品价格和供应可能会在全球范围内受到影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究结果于周五发表在同行评审的研究期刊 npj Climate and Atmospheric Sc​​ience 上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生长季节因为冬小麦作物从秋天开始——它们在春天开花，在夏天收获。当温度超过 27.8 摄氏度（82 华氏度）时，植物开始遭受热应激。如果温度上升到 32.8 摄氏度，关键酶就会开始分解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国东北，一次破纪录的干旱事件有 63% 的几率同时也是一次创纪录的高温事件，在这种情况下，研究发现，世界上大部分的小麦都产自中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是世界上最大的小麦消费国和生产国。政府数据显示，去年中国生产了近 1.4 亿吨农作物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，中国当局加大力度确保有足够的粮食养活该国 14 亿人口，特别是面对全球动荡和乌克兰战争等影响进口和供应链的事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周，中国异常大雨促使地方当局加快收割和烘干受损小麦&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国北方的持续降雨和高湿度——中国在安徽、湖北和陕西部分地区的小麦生产基地所在地——已经导致发芽受损，这被称为收获前发芽。小麦还感染了植物病害，可能导致更高的毒素风险，从而限制了最终用途应用，例如烘焙。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;警告美国和泰国农民：中国将种植 90% 的小麦到 2032 年它的粮食产量&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“中美之间的合作可以帮助激发气候变化适应和建立有弹性的粮食系统，”弗里德曼营养科学与政策学院副教授 Erin Coughlan de Perez 说。波士顿塔夫茨大学，也是该研究的主要作者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coughlan de Perez 说世界应该准备好面对粮食不安全的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在农业部门，这意味着减少高温和干旱对作物影响的弹性战略，例如，通过种植新的耐热小麦品种，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“就更广泛的粮食系统而言，这意味着多样化，以便一个地区的失败不会对世界造成毁灭性的影响。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，除了出口变化等因素外，气候变化的影响也在发生，这些因素可能会引发小麦价格上涨，并可能导致粮食短缺– 发展中国家的粮食不安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们只回顾过去以了解未来可能发生的灾难，我们将大大低估当前和未来的风险，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我们需要利用气候科学来更新我们的风险认知，并能够想象今天可能发生的难以想象的、揭示前所未有的气候事件，这些事件将对农业造成可怕的后果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div >;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong housewife sentenced to 1 year in psychiatric hospital for strangling to death mentally disabled son]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3222799/hong-kong-housewife-sentenced-1-year-psychiatric-hospital-strangling-death-mentally-disabled-son?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 20:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/d30bd27b-8746-4b98-bc4e-fbf65e489cf1_b9d6ef4f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名承认勒死其智障儿子的香港家庭主妇被判在精神病院接受了一年的住院治疗，因为一名法官发现，如果她获准提前出院，她的抑郁症可能会复发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大法官苏珊娜·达尔马达·雷梅迪奥斯 (Susana D&#39;Almada Remedios) 周五告诉高等法院考虑到陈雪萍反复发作的抑郁症，在中国大陆出生的陈雪萍被安置在屯门小榄精神病院接受治疗符合她的最大利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Remedios 拒绝判处这名妇女缓刑或监禁，这将有效地让她提前获释。她已被还押近两年零九个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港男子，66 岁，疑因窒息 39 岁的女儿而自杀&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我完全理解她的孩子，她的丈夫和她自己希望团聚，”法官在宣判时说。 “我不能忽视的是被告目前的精神状况。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;49 岁的被告最初被控谋杀，原因是她在葵涌村的家中杀死了患有癫痫病的儿子黄发伦，但控方以她的精神问题为由，接受了她关于减少过失杀人罪的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong 六岁时被诊断出患有中度智力障碍和自闭症，并患有癫痫症。他必须接受定期的精神病治疗和药物治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭获悉，陈于 2020 年 9 月 4 日至 5 日午夜左右用一块红色塑料桌布勒死了王，桌布形状像一根有四个结的绳子。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这起悲剧发生在死者因年满 21 岁而离开一家专为智障人士而设的宿舍几天后。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港法官表示她可能不会监禁少年杀死刚出生的女儿&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在杀人前不久，这名家庭主妇给她的丈夫和一个朋友发短信说她太累了，再也无法忍受照顾她的儿子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还要求这对夫妇照顾她现年 15 岁并正在上中学的双胞胎儿子和女儿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈的丈夫是一名出租车司机，此后辞去了工作以照顾剩下的孩子，法院审理。这家人现在靠政府津贴生活，但据说父亲有一些精神问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，辩护律师黛安·克雷宾 (Diane Crebbin) 强调了陈的家人和朋友写的减轻处罚的信件，他们将她描绘成一个充满爱心的人, 有爱心和勤劳的母亲，在非常困难的情况下让她的家人在一起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克雷宾敦促法庭考虑辩护精神病学家的意见，他说在压力大的环境中拘留被告，这样作为精神病院，可能对她的康复没有好处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果她[被判]小榄[精神病中心]，我会为她感到难过，”律师说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;但 Remedios 指出了由两名政府精神病学家编制的其他五份报告，其中一名自陈被还押以来曾与陈见面 39 次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两位医生都同意陈患有精神分裂症复发性抑郁症。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭听说这名家庭主妇的康复没有任何进展，一名精神科医生也对她是否愿意遵守门诊治疗计划表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我有对被告及其家人将要经历并将继续经历的痛苦表示同情——尤其是被告，在她的余生中，知道她已经结束了她如此深爱的儿子的生命，并在这样做的同时所以试图结束自己的生命，”法官说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她强调：“这一罪行的根本原因是被告的抑郁症......总的来说，我对最合适的判决方式感到满意是通过入院令。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过失杀人罪最高可判处无期徒刑，但因减轻责任而被定罪的人可获得较轻的刑罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr >;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In South Asia, drones are connecting remote villagers to life-saving services ‘like never before’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3222749/south-asia-drones-are-connecting-remote-villagers-life-saving-services-never?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/d862c669-0178-410c-bb5c-216b93136321_664225e8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;去年 12 月，当蛇咬解毒剂不得不被紧急运往印度偏远的 Ziro 山谷山区时，印度人当局转而使用最快的交通工具——无人机送货。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在喜马拉雅山脉深处，一次典型的旅程将包括危险的汽车旅行、乘船穿越冰冷的河流，然后是艰苦的上坡，视情况而定，最多可能需要 8 个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在 28 分钟内就完成了，”运送抗蛇毒血清的无人机公司 Tech Eagle Innovations 的创始人维克拉姆·辛格 (Vikram Singh) 说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该公司现已在偏远多山的梅加拉亚邦东北部建立了一个无人机基地，这是同类枢纽中的第一个，连接到 50 公里（31 英里）半径内的大约 15 个偏远地点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;拥有世界上最高的山脉、广阔的沙漠和沼泽地，南亚正押注无人机连接到以前几乎无法获得基本服务的偏远地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无人机的使用得到了很大的推动2021 年 8 月，印度政府放宽了严格的无人机政策，将操作无人机所需的许可证数量从 25 个减少到 5 个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界经济论坛提供了一个模板，说明如何在Medicines From the Sky 项目与南部特伦甘纳邦政府一起启动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前印度至少 10 个邦已经进行了无人机使用试验，开辟了“前所未有的进入偏远地区的通道，使拯救生命的医疗成为可能”世界经济论坛航空航天和无人机领域的印度负责人 Vignesh Santhanam 说：“前所未有的交付。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过克服地理挑战和提高交付效率，无人机已成为提高医疗保健可及性的重要工具，特别是在服务欠缺的地区，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度尼西亚的“无人机医务人员”向孤立的 Covid-19 患者运送物资&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年 12 月，印度联邦政府扩大了与生产相关的制造业激励措施一些工业产品，包括无人机和无人机组件，以推动行业发展并降低产品成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度 14 亿人口中的大多数人由大约 30,000 个政府运营的初级医疗保健中心提供服务。但是，由于地形复杂和天气危险，大约 5% 的中心无法进入医疗供应商——有时甚至是患者——。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数医疗用品通过公路运输，但大流行病加强了对更好到达的需求因为政府力求为印度广大人口中的每一位成年人接种疫苗，并共享关键药物和氧气供应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度公共卫生基金会副主任 Suresh Munuswamy 说，20 人之间的任何地方40% 的药物在不同的州没有达到需要的程度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你需要有一个系统的方法来满足州政府的需求。大约 20% 到 40% 的药物没有达到需要的程度。这就是我们需要一个高效的供应链系统的地方，”他说，并补充说最大的漏洞是在从地区仓库到初级保健中心的最后一英里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在印度，最后一英里可能延伸到他说，250 公里，有时由于缺乏运输资金，医生不得不自己取药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但无人机已经证明了它们的用处，因为在山洪等灾害期间，第一批药物总是通过它们运输.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为各州将在未来六个月内开始规范服务，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TechEagle 的 Singh 说他的公司现在与七个州政府的卫生部门合作，使用无人机最多可承载 5 公斤的有效载荷，飞行速度可达 120 公里/小时（每小时 74.6 英里）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前的无人机机队可以在“黄金时段”期间运送应急物资，可以患者的生死攸关，包括蛇咬伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度无人机计划在该国取得的成功正在提高尼泊尔等邻国的采用率，尼泊尔拥有世界上最高的珠穆朗玛峰，其地理位置与印度的丘陵地区相似&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2015 年造成 9,000 人死亡的尼泊尔毁灭性地震期间，国际援助机构引进了无人机来帮助进行破坏测绘、搜索和救援、拍照以及运输应急物资。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;无人机公司 Nepal Flying Labs 的执行董事 Uttam Pudasaini 说，“我们确定了来自尼泊尔的年轻人来展示如何使用无人机”。一个项目还涉及与非营利性 Birat Nepal Medical Trust 合作，从 Pyuthan 偏远地区的两个城市收集了 1,000 个结核病诊断样本。该项目运行了 500 多个航班。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s soaking wet wheat faces more weekend rain, putting farmers at risk of greater losses]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3222782/chinas-soaking-wet-wheat-faces-more-weekend-rain-putting-farmers-risk-greater-losses?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/407bb1a7-ee7d-4166-8fc9-403292341544_0e244d90.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;预计周末雨水将继续浸透中国中部的河南省，当地农民正在在持续的洪水进一步破坏占中国小麦产量四分之一以上的地区之前，争分夺秒地收获。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据省气象台的预测，河南中、西部和南部地区将经历温和的天气周六下午至周日晚上强降雨，全省部分地区降雨量可达 80 毫米（3.15 英寸）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 5 月 25 日以来的强降雨和高湿度已经影响了数百万吨未收割的小麦，导致枯萎病和收获前发芽，对世界上最大的粮食生产国和消费国的产量构成严重威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;罕见的降雨在收获前夺走了数百万吨的中国小麦&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;为应对危机，国有储备粮集团中储粮周五表示，将向其河南分公司运送 3,000 多台干燥和储存设备，同时开放其 115 个仓库——占地约 80 公顷（200 英亩）的总烘干面积——用于全天候烘干谷物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还将为农民提供免费卸货、烘干和住宿服务，这家国有巨头表示，其措施将有助于处理超过每天 1,000 吨小麦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京一再表示粮食安全是当务之急，习近平主席称农业是气候变化、供应链动荡和气候变化中“极其重要的国家安全问题” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国气象局在周五的新闻发布会上表示，极端天气状况可能会持续整个月，预计中国大部分地区的降雨量将高于&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与 2022 年 6 月相比，长江三角洲，包括上海和江苏、浙江和安徽省的部分地区，本月的气温也可能上升一到两摄氏度，副主任高荣说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年夏天，中国的长江流域经历了有史以来最严重的干旱之一，大约 40 摄氏度（104 华氏度）的气温威胁着该国的作物和能源供应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;河南省农业农村厅表示，截至周四晚间，全省仅收割了1956万亩（130万公顷、322万亩），占河南省麦田总面积的23%，总面积为8500万亩.该省的收获预计将于 6 月 15 日完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地方当局将持续的倾盆大雨称为“十年来最严重的收获前降雨”，设立了 2 亿元人民币（28.3 美元）的万）紧急基金周二。这笔钱将用于烘干小麦，帮助农民确保收成，并弥补他们损失的收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北京通过严格考核地方干部加强粮食安全&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;河南省政府还从邻近省份进口收割和干燥设备和机械，以帮助加快这一过程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地媒体报道称，由于土壤潮湿，农民难以收割小麦，使收割所需的时间增加了一倍&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国其他地区，如陕西省西北部和中国东部的江苏省，在过去一周也出现了前所未有的降雨量，当地农民报告作物腐烂。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;陕西当局同样调动了更多的机械和人力来加快收割，同时在高速公路沿线设立了接收点，以确保粮食到达烘干和储存设施。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chanel rents space vacated by Victoria’s Secret, Forever 21 in Hong Kong’s Causeway Bay in boost to shopping district]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/property/article/3222792/chanel-rents-space-vacated-victorias-secret-forever-21-hong-kongs-causeway-bay-boost-shopping?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 19:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/a4cb5022-43f9-4973-8f81-905047ebd197_216dfe4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chanel 在香港铜锣湾，这可能是该市自 2020 年冠状病毒大流行以来最大的此类交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家法国奢侈时装公司租用了地面、一楼和四楼，以及根据官方记录，从一楼到四楼的立面，在国会大厦中心使用了三年。记录没有提及租金，但当地媒体明报和 HK01 报道称，香奈儿将为约 19,000 平方英尺的空间每月支付超过 300 万港元（382,810 美元），即三年超过 1.08 亿港元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;租约于 5 月 16 日开始，有两种续约选择，每一种选择三年。现场正在进行翻新工程，开业后将成为香奈儿继时代广场和利园两家购物中心、崇光百货化妆品专柜和化妆品香水店之后在铜锣湾的第五家分店位于希慎广场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香奈儿发言人证实，该时装屋的化妆品品牌 Chanel Beauté 将入驻该空间。 Capitol Centre 的租赁办公室拒绝置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bridgeway Prime Shop Fund Management 的创始人兼首席执行官 Edwin Lee 表示，香奈儿的租约“肯定会提振市场，尤其是铜锣湾”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “在目前恢复正常的情况下，铜锣湾落后了，”Lee 说，并指出尖沙咀 (TST) 和旺角从 Covid-19 中断的影响中恢复得更快。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，现在 [Chanel] 突然租下了价值 300 万至 400 万港元的空间，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新店开业之际，香港的游客人数持续上升。 2019 年该市发生社会动荡之后，在大流行病造成损失之前，旅游业和零售额已经萎缩。铜锣湾曾经是世界上最昂贵的购物区所在地，最近 2021 年 11 月，Prada、Louis Vuitton 和 Burberry 等品牌选择不再续租。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这座城市放弃了它之后当地房地产代理公司 Dorbo Realty 的董事总经理 Rickey Chan 说，由于采取了社会隔离措施并在今年早些时候全面重新开放了边界，每天的游客人数已跃升至近 100,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;8.92 亿美元的香港从大亨手中夺取的办公楼挂牌出售&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;边境重新开放后，对奢侈品、手表、珠宝和时装的需求增加，目前的商店租金是 2013 年至 2013 年高峰期的 30%陈说，2014年，很多租户会在市场全面回暖前租住商铺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;铜锣湾、尖沙咀、旺角及中环等核心区的商铺租金已回升5至10元Chan 补充说，今年上半年的平均租金为 5%，下半年将进一步上涨 5% 至 10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 和 Bridgeway 的 Lee 都表示，Chanel 的租约将是香港最大的租约自 Covid-19 爆发以来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“超级一线品牌”重返铜锣湾肯定会带动整个地区的人气，Lee 说。 “今年，租金 [增长] 将超过价格，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于美国利率见顶、香港经济增长，今年核心购物区的商店租金可能会上涨 20% 至 30% Lee 补充说，恢复正常和游客回归。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港、新加坡的商业地产交易抵御区域性低迷：MSCI&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自维多利亚的秘密以来，国会大厦中心的空间一直空置2020 年 6 月提前关闭门店。这家美国内衣品牌于 2017 年签署了一份为期 10 年的租约，租用五层楼，总面积为 50,000 平方英尺，估计每月 700 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Victoria&#39;s Secret 的租约约为 50比之前的租户——美国时尚品牌 Forever 21——为该空间支付的价格低 %。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Next stage of China’s diplomacy should focus on addressing ‘external risks’, foreign ministry says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222795/next-stage-chinas-diplomacy-should-focus-addressing-external-risks-foreign-ministry-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 19:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/bb18fe8f-cfb7-4dd7-a6e2-60f39a2aa187_5f2a1d4e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国下一阶段应重点提升应对“外部风险”的能力中国外交部周五发表的一篇文章称，它将把资源分配给“关键挑战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他最近发表的两篇言论的想法。这是党领导最近开展的一项指导党员学习习近平政治意识形态运动的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它发表在《人民日报》上，当时中美关系几乎在各个方面都处于紧张状态，从文章称，在习近平外交思想的指引下，维护国家利益的工作取得了“突破”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;其中包括“强烈打击外部干涉和极端压力”，指的是北京处理与以美国为首的西方国家的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部将把“重点和资源用于应对关键挑战和提高防范和化解外部风险的能力”，文章称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它没有详细说明“关键挑战”是什么。在 3 月中国最高立法机关年度全国会议的开幕词中，习近平罕见地提到美国：“以美国为首的西方国家对中国实施全方位遏制和打压，给中国带来了前所未有的严峻形势。对国家发展的挑战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，欧盟和美国官员呼吁与中国“去风险化”而不是“脱钩”，但这个模棱两可的词仍然让北京难以接受。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;外交部部长助理华春莹周三在她的推特账户上发文称，“去风险实际上就是脱钩”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平思想的“通俗”指南&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在周四的新闻发布会上，中国外交部发言人毛宁在回应美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯关于去风险化的言论时表示，中国是“机遇之源，而不是风险之源”，真正的世界面临的风险是“实践……引发集团对抗并酝酿新冷战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《人民日报》周五发表的文章称赞近年来与 10 个国家建立正式外交关系，这些国家已经削减在转向北京之前与台北的关系是“巩固国际社会对一个中国（政策）的坚持”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它说中国实际上阻止了外部势力的干涉，北京已经实现了香港的历史性转变由乱到有序，由有序走向繁荣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部“有效开展国际舆论斗争，不断挫败对我国（利用）台湾、新疆、香港、西藏的攻击抹黑、流行病、人权和其他问题，”它说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还为北京在多年敌对后促进沙特阿拉伯和伊朗之间关系恢复的作用感到自豪，文章称这一努力“推动了中东的‘和解浪潮’”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在提到乌克兰危机时，文章重申了北京的立场及其在促进和谈方面的作用，同时称赞其与俄罗斯的关系“更加成熟、更加坚强”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文章呼吁增强“奋斗精神和能力”，这是习近平近年来强调的一个词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“面对外部风险挑战，斗争要有方向、有原则，”文章称，要有策略、有弹性地“坚决斗争”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Redevelopment of Hong Kong’s only private low-rental housing estate pushed back further 2 years, with 2,000 flats to be available by 2029]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3222790/redevelopment-hong-kongs-only-private-low-rental-housing-estate-pushed-back-further-2-years-2000?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 19:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/b306f57b-bd90-4a55-97fb-e2d2194d5e52_2c00cb6c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港唯一私人廉租房重建计划将延后by a further two years, the firm behind it has said, making its 2,000 flats only available to the market in 2029.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong Settlers Housing Corporation on Friday said current residents of Tai Hang Sai Estate in Shek Kip Mei would be given until March 2024 to move out and surrender their units before redevelopment work began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We had to postpone the schedule to give the residents more time to decide their rehousing arrangements,” said a spokesman from the firm, which is associated with property giant Henderson Land Development.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;300,000 more Hong Kong public housing tenants to declare property every 2 years&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The project is now set to be completed in 2029, instead of the previously estimated 2027. It aims to provide 3,300 flats – more than double the current 1,600 units.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 1,300 of the new homes will be used for rehousing existing tenants, while the remaining 2,000 will be allocated to the Urban Renewal Authority to be sold as so-called starter homes. The initiative offers flats at below-market price for first-time buyers who cannot afford to buy on the private market, but also do not qualify for public housing under the government&#39;s Home Ownership Scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the corporation&#39;s spokesman on Friday, 82 per cent of current tenants, or 1,012 households, had submitted their eligibility assessment forms, which determine the number of people in a family and their assets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of them, 676 households were deemed eligible for rehousing and given two options: move back in upon redevelopment completion or leave permanently.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both options would include allowances of varying degrees, depending on the number of people in the household.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A family of four, for example, would receive a rental allowance of HK$810,000 (US$103,000) and a payment of HK$54,000 to settle in interim housing on their own or apply for transitional housing through social workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Families would be given a one-off allowance of about HK$1 million, on top of a HK$27,000 removal payment, if they decided to depart for good.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, another 324 households were considered ineligible for rehousing for various reasons, including owning other properties, enjoying public housing benefits or no longer living in their flat any more.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These families would still be given a special removal allowance of up to HK$700,000, the firm said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The remaining 12 per cent of residents, or 224 households, had not handed in their forms, with the organisation adding that it was “unclear” why they were being unresponsive since they were not in need of help from social workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong Golf Club shares baby owl video in bid to halt housing plan for course&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He warned these residents may face repossession without compensation if they continued to refuse to hand in their forms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If we were forced to come to this final step but still offered them the same compensation, I think it would be unfair to the other residents who responded in a timely manner,” the spokesman said. “It poses a moral hazard.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But some tenants have cried foul and accused the developer of moving ahead without their agreement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kate Au Yeung Kit-chun, who leads a group of residents from the estate refusing to accept the latest arrangements, called the corporation&#39;s statements “outrageous” and accused them of running a “black box operation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Wait for Hong Kong public housing drops to 5.3 years as more flats become available&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;She said many of the so-called unresponsive tenants had indeed replied by handing over an alternative form explaining why they rejected the arrangements, with reasons including that they wanted a “flat for a flat”, or that the firm had failed to respond to queries or clarify terms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The corporation emphasised on Friday that residents of Tai Hang Sai Estate were renters, not homeowners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government has launched initiatives to ease the city&#39;s housing crunch, including providing affordable flats for first-time homebuyers in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Urban Renewal Authority in 2019 offered around 500 flats in Ma Tau Wai as starter homes, which were sold at discounts of up to 38 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities also plan to sell another site in Tsuen Wan for such projects in this financial year, with a target to provide about 1,000 affordable homes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Edith Lin&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU could agree to new sanctions on Chinese firms next week, diplomats say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3222783/eu-could-agree-new-sanctions-chinese-firms-next-week-diplomats-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 18:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/4c261659-bbcf-474d-ab78-5fc633d7f643_7c8a4bb3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;EU sanctions on Chinese firms accused of funnelling banned European goods to the Russian military could be agreed as early as next week, according to diplomatic sources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eight companies based in mainland China and Hong Kong are on a draft list of entities accused of reselling European chips and microelectronics that can be used in high-grade weaponry, such as cruise missiles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As part of previous sanctions packages, Russian buyers have been banned from accessing such goods that are made in Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sanctions would be sure to ratchet up tensions between the European Union and China, which has repeatedly warned Brussels that it will retaliate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the final details of a broader 11th package of EU sanctions since the invasion of Ukraine are still being haggled over, two diplomats said they were confident of a breakthrough next week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A third diplomat expected the package to pass in the coming weeks, before foreign ministers meet in Brussels on June 26.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Greece and Hungary oppose listing the Chinese firms, said two diplomats close to the talks. But while sanctions require unanimity among the EU&#39;s 27 members, they were confident that these countries would not block the overall bundle on what is considered a relatively uncontroversial point.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some EU capitals are uncomfortable with the idea of replicating the long-arm sanctioning techniques of the United States, but there is also conviction that third countries should not be providing loopholes through which European goods can reach Russia&#39;s war machine.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Czech foreign minister calls for more united EU-US approach to China&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Four of the listed companies have already been sanctioned by the United States: Chinese outfits 3HC Semiconductors and King-Pai Technology, and Hong Kong-based firms Sinno Electronics and Sigma Technology. Also listed are Hong Kong entities Allparts Trading, Asia-Pacific Links, Tordan Industry and Alpha Trading Investments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A more contentious element of the package is a new instrument that would allow the EU to restrict certain exports to an entire country as a last resort, where it is deemed to have consistently flouted sanctions and where diplomatic efforts to resolve the situation fail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Failure to agree on this tool has delayed the passage of the latest raft of punitive measures. Germany has proposed restricting shipments to entities instead of countries. But even if it was adopted, diplomats said it would be more likely to target Central Asian and Gulf countries rather than China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has repeatedly warned the EU against sanctioning its companies and its representatives have said it will respond in kind.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the European side imposes sanctions on Chinese companies without providing us with any solid evidence to show that these companies are engaged with activities that may circumvent or that have circumvented the EU sanctions on Russia, then we certainly will retaliate,” said Fu Cong, the Chinese ambassador to the EU, in an interview with the New Statesman last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I understand this 11th round of sanctions is aimed mainly at preventing circumvention. If the EU side has evidence that Chinese companies are engaged in such activities, please show us the evidence,” he continued, adding that Beijing would be willing to help Brussels investigate the breaches.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While European businesses have generally toed the line in supporting sanctions, they will be nervously eyeing the travails of US memory chip firm Micron Technology, which was blocked from Chinese markets after Beijing said it was a national security risk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the move is widely seen as part of an escalating tech war. Washington is trying to keep advanced semiconductors and the technology used for making them out of Chinese hands, with Beijing forced to respond.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Asia gets most Russian dark fuels after EU embargo – China, India main importers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;There are also concerns in the business community that Brussels is reducing the bloc&#39;s competitiveness, as it looks to become more geopolitical.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 20, the EU is set to propose an economic security strategy which will include some initial guidelines on screening outbound investments destined for China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plan is to prevent European companies from investing in Chinese hi-tech businesses that may have links to the military – in sectors such as robotics, artificial intelligence, semiconductors and quantum computing – amid concerns over the transfer of vital know-how and technologies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Businesses are worried about the proposal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“BusinessEurope does not support by principle introducing limitations on outbound investment. Only in exceptional cases where serious security concerns are effectively proven this could be a last resort measure,” read a report last month from a major lobby group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The private sector should be consulted to ensure that the measures adopted are effective whilst fully preserving the EU&#39;s global competitiveness.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan privacy watchdog warns ChatGPT-maker OpenAI about user data]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222787/japan-privacy-watchdog-warns-chatgpt-maker-openai-about-user-data?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 18:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/5b5f6a66-faf3-4f75-a885-53af4764ee94_180ef733.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Japan&#39;s privacy watchdog said on Friday it has warned OpenAI, the Microsoft-backed start-up behind the ChatGPT chatbot, not to collect sensitive data without people&#39;s permission.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OpenAI should minimise the sensitive data it collects for machine learning, the Personal Information Protection Commission said in a statement, adding it may take further action if it has more concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regulators around the world are scrambling to draw up rules governing the use of generative artificial intelligence (AI), which can create text and images, the impact of which proponents compare to the arrival of the internet.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;AI poses &#39;extinction&#39; risk comparable to nuclear war, pandemics: experts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While Japan has been on the back foot with some recent technology trends, it is seen as having greater incentive to keep pace with advances in AI and robotics to maintain productivity as its population shrinks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The watchdog noted the need to balance privacy concerns with the potential benefits of generative AI including in accelerating innovation and dealing with problems such as climate change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan is the third-largest source of traffic to OpenAI&#39;s website, according to analytics firm Similarweb.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OpenAI CEO Sam Altman in April met Prime Minister Fumio Kishida with an eye to expansion in Japan, ahead of the Group of Seven (G7) leaders summit where Kishida led a discussion on regulating AI.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EU, a global trendsetter on tech regulation, set up a task force on ChatGPT and is working on what could be the first set of rules to govern AI.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;ChatGPT boss says AI won&#39;t spark mass jobs extinction&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the meantime, the rapid spread of such chatbots has meant regulators have had to rely on existing rules to bridge the gap.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Italian regulator Garante had ChatGPT taken offline before the company agreed to install age verification features and let European users block their information from being used to train the system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Altman last week said OpenAI had no plans to leave Europe after earlier suggesting the start-up might do so if EU regulations were too difficult to comply with.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Are Galaxy, MGM casinos betting on Thailand amid Macau shift?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222769/are-galaxy-mgm-casinos-betting-thailand-amid-macau-shift?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.02 17:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/1265d0b5-92bd-4334-9d77-4f37f2a463ce_f6e38e28.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Two of the world&#39;s top casino operators are laying the groundwork to potentially establish gambling facilities in Thailand as the industry looks to hedge against a deteriorating outlook in Macau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Galaxy Entertainment Group and MGM Resorts International are studying the potential of opening casino resorts in the country, according to the people, who asked not to be identified because the matter is private. Galaxy, the gaming, retail and hospitality group controlled by billionaire Lui Che-woo, is also exploring starting gaming operations in the United Arab Emirates, some of the people said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A representative for Galaxy didn&#39;t comment on its plans. MGM didn&#39;t immediately respond to a request for comment sent outside business hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The early efforts to enter new markets reflect casino operators&#39; anxiety over a deteriorating outlook for Macau, which once pulled in six times the gaming revenue of Las Vegas and delivered historically high returns. China wants the enclave to shift away from gambling toward entertainment and has cracked down on high rollers it suspects of money-laundering while imposing heightened scrutiny on gaming activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While China&#39;s reopening has sparked a tourism surge that helped Macau&#39;s gaming revenue return to about 60 per cent of the pre-Covid level in May, the boom could fade later this year as pent-up demand eases and increasing flight capacity sees more Chinese head overseas. It&#39;s also likely to take years for the city to add more attractions and non-gaming events to draw in enough visitors to fill the gap left by VIP gamblers, who used to account for half of total gaming revenue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the potential for both Thailand and the UAE to legalise casinos in coming years, operators are seeking to get a head start.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thailand is one of the world&#39;s major tourism destinations, particularly for visitors from other parts of Asia. Pre-Covid, Chinese were the largest group of tourists to the country, accounting for about 28 per cent of total foreign arrivals, followed by Malaysians and Indians. The UAE could pull in as much as US$6.6 billion of gaming revenue annually and eventually surpass Singapore, home to the renowned Marina Bay Sands resort, according to Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Angela Hanlee.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;After decriminalising cannabis, Thailand may gamble on casinos to revive economy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Galaxy has already set up offices in both Thailand and the UAE to promote its operations in Macau, while also using that local presence to glean on-the-ground information, according to people familiar with the matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MGM, which is set to manage an entertainment resort in Dubai, has set up a base in Thailand and was one of a number of firms that spoke with a Thai parliamentary committee looking into legalising casinos, the people said. The discussion took place before May&#39;s general election and, while it&#39;s unclear what legislation the new government will enact, the committee&#39;s proposal that several casino resorts be established was approved by the House of Representatives in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Separately, Las Vegas Sands has repeatedly expressed interest in Thailand. Chief Executive Officer Robert Goldstein said during an earnings call in January that the group is “looking hard” at the country and would love to have a presence in the market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The companies are in a good financial position for expansion. Galaxy maintained more cash than debt through Covid-19, due to the company&#39;s conservative financing and spending strategy over the past two decades. MGM&#39;s so-called asset-light model has seen aggressive sales of properties that are then leased back, bolstering its cash position, while Sands&#39; US$6.25 billion sale of its Las Vegas properties has provided it with ample funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While any entry into new markets depends on Thailand and UAE removing legal restrictions, the industry expects change is on its way. Even though Thailand is still in the throes of a leadership transition, the casino resort proposal won cross-party support and is widely expected to be given the green light by the new government.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Macau casinos hit the jackpot as return of mainland tourists fuels revenue surge&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Bloomberg News reported last month that there have been early discussions in the UAE on legalising gambling and some operators have held informal talks with authorities, though senior government officials have said there are no imminent plans to allow the pastime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wynn Resorts is planning what it&#39;s calling a US$3.9 billion “gaming” resort that&#39;s fuelled speculation the ban may be lifted. MGM Chief Executive Officer Bill Hornbuckle said on a recent earnings call he anticipates further developments on the legalisation in coming months.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 02 Jun 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>