<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong must lay out conservation park blueprint before building I&T hub on wetlands, planning experts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3224402/hong-kong-must-lay-out-conservation-park-blueprint-building-it-hub-wetlands-planning-experts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 23:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/0083f6d7-fde7-4ee7-b4ce-0333824e3ecf_625ffb86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港政府应该充分解释它计划如何在专家表示，在推进这项雄心勃勃的提案之前，将在与中国大陆接壤的湿地上形成新城镇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城市规划委员会成员在政府最近一次关于 627 的简报会上发表了上述言论-公顷（1,549 英亩）的新田科技园项目，其中一半已指定用于创新和技术 (I&amp;T) 用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划旨在在剩余土地上提供 50,000 多套住房，涉及填海约 90 公顷的鱼塘和创建三宝树湿地保育公园，以抵消对环境的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“根据我们的指导方针，这 90 公顷的土地中有许多实际上是湿地保育区……破坏如此大量的湿地需要详细的解释，但目前甚至没有公园的蓝图，”董事会成员 Billy Hau Chi-hang 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Colliers 表示投资者需要详细信息规划中的北部大都会 IT 中心&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hau 表示，他认为政府试图淡化靠近鸟类栖息地的湿地的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;董事会成员也是一名香港大学生物科学首席讲师，敦促政府为保育园区提供详细建议，包括其边界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科技馆的 I&amp;T 部分的总面积将相当于深圳创新中心和技术区越过边界。预计政府将在今年年底前为特定功能标记某些区域，并正在探索直接向领先的科技公司授予场地以吸引他们来到这座城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hau 周五对当局表示失望尚未提供有关公司是否有开设商店的任何需求的任何数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“将牺牲 90 公顷的湿地来创建技术中心。政府难道不应该给我们提供显示供求的实际数字，以便我们在未来批准土地申请时感到放心吗？”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;董事会成员罗淑君回应侯的担忧，并呼吁政府明确制定保育计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;常任发展局局长何佩玲，董事会主席，表示官员们希望在今年晚些时候透露更多细节之前评估成员的想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们不启动该项目，土地生产过程将被推迟，不能与创新科技及工业局尽快为投资和业务提供土地的目标齐头并进，”何说，他指的是政府最早在 2026 年分配创科用地的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;北都统筹办公室主任邱卓恒表示，保护区的具体细节将在年底前公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望采用一些渐进的方法，例如收回一些私人鱼塘进行开发，以最大限度地提高我们的环境容量。”新田项目是该办公室职权范围内的几个开发计划之一，是北部都会计划的一部分，该计划旨在将 30,000 公顷土地变成新界的经济和住房中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，城市规划者批准了一项新的计划允许土地所有者在地块之间转移发展潜力的机制，以加快九龙两个地区的城市更新，以及保护有价值的建筑和创造社区空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计将出台所谓地积比率转移的新指南在委员会审查的未来土地申请中发挥作用。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan can suggest how to govern it after unifying with mainland China, PLA strategist says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3224334/taiwan-can-suggest-how-govern-it-after-unifying-mainland-china-pla-strategist-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/3a583b31-444c-4b23-a90b-27efb831025f_a9c2e5e4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;只要大陆统一后，台湾可以提出自己的治理理念一位大陆军事战略家表示，不要违反“一个中国”的原则——驻台北的分析人士表示，这一建议表明双方之间的理解差距有多大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在重要的是什么中国人民解放军陆军中将何雷在最近结束的香格里拉对话期间表示，就是要为“两制”找到新的解决方案，让“一国两制”对台湾有效。在新加坡举行的国防会议上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在回答有关北京将如何让自治岛屿更容易接受统一的问题时补充说，“台湾有聪明人可以提出建议”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四年前，中国国家主席习近平在北京主持关于与台湾统一的周年纪念会议时提出了同样的主张。台湾是一个拥有 2400 万人口的自治岛屿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Andrew Yang Nien -dzu，前台湾国防部长说，他的言论凸显了北京和台北之间的理解鸿沟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北京的‘一国两制’方案在台湾没有市场，台湾人认为这是杨说，他用的是台湾的官方名称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台湾已明确表明其立场，即中华民国是一个独立的主权国家。如果北京真的要谈判，那么它必须明确其对中华民国的立场，否则就真的没有谈判的余地。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京认为台湾是一个最终会统一的分裂省份与大陆，必要时使用武力。它强调，它的目标是根据其“一个中国”原则实现和平统一，即大陆和台湾是一个国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国国防部长在台湾问题上的强硬路线“给该地区的信息”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;北京也明确表示，不会放弃对台湾使用武力，以遏制外国干涉台湾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;何雷认为，台湾问题是“中国民权的延续”。战争”，于 1949 年结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台湾是中国的内部问题，是内战的延续，”他说。 “这就是为什么中国军队被称为人民解放军——因为[台湾]还没有解放，中国还没有统一。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在执政的蔡英文[政府]民进党要推动台独，邀请外国干涉，”他说。 “这就是为什么我们不能放弃使用武力……我们仍在打解放战争。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自倾向独立的民进党的蔡当选后，台海两岸的关系已跌入低谷2016 年当选总统，并在三年前赢得第二个任期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾将在 1 月举行总统选举——蔡英文无法谋求第三个任期——两岸关系再次成为关键的选举议题。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;包括美国在内的大多数国家都不承认台湾是一个独立国家。然而，华盛顿反对任何使用武力改变现状的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台北国立台湾大学退休教授张亚中表示，“一个国家，两种制度”未能认清现实台湾由中华民国政府统治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果北京的立场是内战还没有结束，那么它需要一个三步走的解决方案[统一]，第一步是和平协议结束两岸敌对，”张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这将有助于为统一谈判铺平道路，只有最后一步是讨论台湾可能采用什么政治制度。”&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;解放军打断台湾总统与空军军官的无线电通话&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;台湾高雄海军学院前教官陆立士说，如今的台湾年轻人对两岸关系的理解与他们不同&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，台湾人相信，香港近年来的政治动荡表明，一个国家、两种制度的模式是失败的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;台湾防务专家池乐义表示，贺的言论仅表明北京与台北在未来关系上的分歧已经扩大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北京需要明白，共和国中国现在是一个真正的民主国家，而中国大陆的政治局势比中华民国政府统治该国时还要糟糕，”池说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你怎么能说服台湾人民给予在‘一个中国’的框架下，回到更落后的状态？”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s physical fitness improves, but more than half of population fails to get enough exercise, survey finds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3224397/hong-kongs-physical-fitness-improves-more-half-population-fails-get-enough-exercise-survey-finds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 21:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/fce6b355-7172-49c5-8bcc-5a8dbf5ad28f_d4359116.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港的体质在过去十年普遍改善，但超过一项调查显示，仍有一半的人口没有得到足够的锻炼，许多人患有肥胖症。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府周五公布了民意调查结果，发现不同国家的大多数身体健康参数都有所改善年龄组与大约 10 年前的类似调查相比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;年龄在 17 至 79 岁之间的成年受访者在心血管耐力、肌肉力量和耐力等方面的成绩优于 2012 年调查中的受访者.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7至11岁的儿童和12至16岁的青少年，心血管耐力也较佳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“数据显示，香港人的整体体质略有改善与10年前相比，我们估计这与近期运动氛围和意识的改善有关，”中文大学运动科学与体育学系许世全教授说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参与调查的许女士将进步归因于香港运动员在国际体育比赛中取得的成绩，以及政府更好地促进运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民意调查还发现，53.8%的人成年受访者没有达到世界卫生组织 (WHO) 推荐的身体活动水平——成人每周进行 150 分钟或更长时间的中度至剧烈身体活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约三分之二的儿童接受调查并与世界卫生组织为该年龄组推荐的水平——平均每天 60 分钟中等到剧烈的身体活动相比，约有一半的青少年没有进行足够的运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“仍有超过一半的青少年居民平均没有达到世界卫生组织建议的体育活动水平，”许说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项由社区体育委员会主导并由康乐及文化事务署协调的调查还发现，超过根据世界卫生组织的体重指数，三分之一的男性和超过五分之一的女性肥胖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约三分之一的儿童受访者和超过四分之一的青少年受访者被发现超重或肥胖。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;处于危险之中：香港调查发现超过十分之一的人患有心脏病&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 17 至 79 岁的人群中，超过十分之三的男性和超过五分之一的女性患有心脏病发现患有高血压。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员表示，最受成年人欢迎的运动包括球类运动、跑步和散步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但该群体进行足够运动的主要障碍包括缺乏&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;儿童和青少年最喜欢的体育活动包括球类运动和游泳。但他们强调，恶劣的天气、疲倦和过多的功课等问题是锻炼的主要障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该调查是同类调查中的第三次，于 2021 年 7 月至去年 12 月期间进行。它分析了 8,419 名年龄在 7 至 79 岁之间的人的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了鼓励更多居民锻炼身体并改善人们的体质，许建议通过教育和宣传提高公众对世界卫生组织推荐的身体活动水平的认识，并鼓励人们定期检查自己的锻炼和健身水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，应该定期发布全市范围的研究结果，并呼吁引入自我评估移动应用程序，以便人们可以监控自己的个人身体变化健身。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;跑步消耗多少卡路里？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hui 还建议当局制定简单的、以家庭为基础的锻炼指南，并促进更多适合家长和家庭的健身活动。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;康乐及文化事务署助理署长洪德全表示，政府提倡运动和改善市民体质的计划，包括提供更多设施和举办更多活动， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，政府还将加强宣传和教育，鼓励人们养成经常锻炼的习惯，并引入自我评估工具，以便公众可以监测他们的健康状况，并建议每五年在全市范围内进行一次调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港教育大学健康与体育学系副系主任 Lobo Louie Hung-ta 表示，结果令人震惊，尤其是儿童肥胖率，他说这可能会在未来造成社会问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些孩子长大后可能会肥胖，这会给社会带来巨大的医疗成本，”他解释说。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;他补充说，肥胖是高血压和糖尿病等慢性病的危险因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Louie 说当局应该加强对不同年龄段人群的健康促进，包括在学校提倡健康的生活方式，例如运动、饮食控制和优质睡眠。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，这些工作应该在跨部门的基础上进行，包括卫生和教育局。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Vaccinations against mpox to be extended in London after cases spike]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224399/vaccinations-against-mpox-be-extended-london-after-cases-spike?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 22:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/95608d09-1cad-4847-a5da-b342f8c76a22_8fda70b2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在最近病例激增后，伦敦的 mpox 疫苗接种将延长，英国卫生安全局 (UKHSA) 已宣布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去几周，首都诊断出 11 例新病例，其中大多数未接种疫苗的人和三名只接种了一剂疫苗的人疫苗，根据 UKHSA 的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家疫苗接种计划将按计划在 7 月底结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mpox，以前称为猴痘，是一种罕见的感染，最常见于西方国家或地区中非。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然症状可能很轻微，但感染会导致异常的皮疹和水泡、发烧、头痛、肌肉疼痛、疲惫和淋巴结肿大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UKHSA 表示最高mpox 的风险主要存在于男同性恋者、双性恋者或其他男男性行为者相互关联的性网络中。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;猴痘病将由世卫组织重新命名为 mpox&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Susan Hopkins 教授，首席医学顾问在 UKHSA，他说：“我们对最近病例的增加做出反应至关重要，这就是我们在伦敦延长 mpox 疫苗接种的原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果您住在伦敦或经常去那里或出国旅行并且有性别并且有资格接种疫苗，请务必考虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“疫苗接种计划在全国范围内对所有符合条件的人开放，直至 7 月底，我会敦促所有尚未接种第一针或第二剂疫苗。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2023 年初以来，英国报告了 21 例 mpox 病例，其中大部分病例发生在伦敦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 4 月， UKHSA 表示，截至 12 月 31 日，英国报告了 3,732 例确诊和高度可能的 mpox 病例，导致针对感染风险较高的人群引入了疫苗接种计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;一剂疫苗在接种 14 天后可提供 78% 的病毒保护，而第二剂旨在提供“长期保护”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有资格接种疫苗的人包括男同性恋者、双性恋者或其他与拥有多个性伴侣的男性发生性关系的男性、参与集体性行为或在场内发生性行为的男性，以及在现场工作的任何工作人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卫生部长 Maria Caulfield尽管疫苗接种计划取得了成功，但仍呼吁保持警惕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于迅速采取行动向最脆弱的人群推广 mpox 疫苗，最近几个月全国的总体病例数一直很低，”她&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但是，我们必须保持警惕，鉴于最近在伦敦发生的病例，将首都的 mpox 疫苗接种计划延长第一剂和第二剂是正确的。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China should avoid seeking global ‘kingship’ amid US tensions, academic says ahead of Antony Blinken visit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3224366/china-should-avoid-seeking-global-kingship-amid-us-tensions-academic-says-ahead-antony-blinken-visit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/9074bcf6-abfa-4b92-b8e5-6182ac7a057f_bff7d60c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京不应谋求全球“王权”，而应建设亚洲共同体专门研究中美贸易战的清华大学金融学教授表示，这是对抗华盛顿脱钩努力的第一步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京研究所金融学讲座教授鞠建东长期以来一直主张中国在全球经济治理中发挥更大的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在本周最新一期《清华金融评论》上发表的评论是在美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯对中国进行为期两天的访问之前发表的，他是在世界最大的两个经济体之间的紧张局势升级之际，将于周日抵达北京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不要宣布王权，稳定市场并促进共享。 [这是我建议的]大国竞争战略，”他在 5,500 字的研究论文中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们需要划定以中国为主导的市场边界。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;鞠的学术文章不一定反映北京决策者的想法，但凸显了学者、经济学家、投资者和普通中国公民对瞬息万变的国际地缘政治的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;遏制中国的措施，从 2018 年开始的贸易战，供应链脱钩努力到回流激励措施，将数百家中国公司列入 10 月份宣布的高端芯片禁令黑名单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些措施是由于许多经济学家预计中国经济规模到 2030 年左右将超过美国，因此有望增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，美国占全球经济规模的 25% 左右，高于中国的 18% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ju援引国际组织的估计称，中国将在2030年至2040年间取代美国成为世界最大经济体，但其在全球经济中的份额可能无法超过30%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“历史数据表明，占世界[国内生产总值]不到30%的中国，经济实力不足以谋求全球霸权，”他说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了应对美国不断加强的遏制，鞠呼吁加大力度巩固中国的海外市场，并促进其市场范围内的知识、专长和技术的共享。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“具体路径是建立一个与中国经济密切相关的经济体的‘亚洲共同体’，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国应该考虑单方面向亚洲共同体内的其他经济体开放，这不仅限于他说，只要亚洲国家同意世界贸易组织下的非歧视、透明和自由贸易规则，就可以将关税降至零。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部设在日内瓦的跨国贸易机构的权威已经由于美国阻止任命新法官，使其上诉机构的职能陷入瘫痪，因此受到损害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ju 建议“亚洲共同体”谈判可以从发展中经济体开始，包括蒙古、柬埔寨、巴西、智利和肯尼亚，然后扩展到马来西亚、印度尼西亚、越南和新加坡，把说服日本、韩国和印度的艰巨工作留到最后。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;外部压力加大，中国叫嚣加入CPTPP贸易集团&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;“建设一个拥有 20 亿至 25 亿人口的亚洲共同体是现实的，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是 15 国区域综合组织的成员Economic Partnership 与东南亚国家联盟以及日本、韩国、澳大利亚和新西兰一起表示有兴趣加入跨太平洋伙伴关系全面进步协定 (CPTPP)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CPTPP被视为由日本、加拿大和澳大利亚等发达国家组成的更高标准的贸易和投资集团，而英国原则上同意加入11国协定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，拜登政府，七国集团推动基础设施建设以对抗中国的“一带一路”倡议，加强其印太经济繁荣框架的工作，同时还提议与韩国、日本和台湾建立“芯片 4”联盟。&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UN demands urgent action after Greece migrant boat tragedy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224392/un-demands-urgent-action-after-greece-migrant-boat-tragedy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 20:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/8d8c25c1-1018-4333-a6ad-d73408af657d_8aba417c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;联合国周五呼吁深入调查移民船沉没事件希腊本周据信已造成数百人死亡，并采取紧急行动防止进一步的悲剧发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，一艘满载移民的渔船在伯罗奔尼撒半岛倾覆沉没，造成至少 78 人死亡。大约有 104 人被发现还活着。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然当时船上的人数仍不清楚，但联合国周五指出，各种目击者的说法表明人数在 400 到 750 人之间。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;联合国难民和移民机构在一份联合声明中呼吁“采取紧急和果断的行动，以防止在地中海最近发生的悲剧发生后进一步发生海上死亡，这是几年来最严重的悲剧”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们坚称各国有义务共同解决地中海搜救行动中存在的危险漏洞，并指出“立即营救海上遇险人员的义务是国际海事法的一项基本规则”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特别是，他们拒绝将那些试图在这种情况下提供帮助的人定罪，并重申“海上搜救是一项法律和人道主义义务”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些机构还坚持认为，搜救救援行动应始终以防止海上生命损失的方式进行，并表示他们欢迎希腊下令对最终导致船只倾覆的情况进行调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;堡垒希腊移民船悲剧归咎于欧洲的政策&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;同时，联合国人权办公室呼吁对“可怕的悲剧”进行“彻底”调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发言人杰里米劳伦斯在日内瓦告诉记者，需要调查“人口走私者和人口贩子并确保将他们绳之以法”，更广泛地说“有很多问题需要提出”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Federico Soda，负责人国际移民组织紧急部门表示，这场悲剧再次表明，地中海的移民过境方式需要改变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很明显，目前的地中海方式是行不通的”，他说在声明中。 “年复一年，它仍然是世界上最危险的移民路线，死亡率最高。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国难民署副主任吉莉安·特里格斯 (Gillian Triggs) 还强调欧盟有义务“将安全和团结放在首位”其在地中海行动的核心”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鉴于地中海地区难民和移民流动的增加，集体努力，包括加强所有地中海国家之间的协调、团结和责任分担……是必不可少的拯救生命，”她在声明中说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s delayed Asian Games in Hangzhou gets support from local tech firms including Ant Group and ByteDance]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224363/chinas-delayed-asian-games-hangzhou-gets-support-local-tech-firms-including-ant-group-and-bytedance?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/7b164108-d477-4cc1-b7ec-bff468e8e587_972a4542.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国延期的亚运会，多项运动会定于今年在杭州举行9 月，获得了金融科技巨头蚂蚁集团、智能手机品牌 vivo 和短视频平台抖音（中国版 TikTok）等本土科技公司的赞助支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蚂蚁的移动支付应用支付宝是官方支付合作伙伴，杭州亚运会数字生活服务平台合作伙伴。周四，它赞助了第一届亚运会数字火炬传递，超过 2100 万人通过在应用程序中搜索“亚运会”注册成为数字火炬手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蚂蚁集团是其关联公司阿里巴巴集团控股有限公司，也拥有邮报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;字节跳动旗下的短视频平台抖音表示，它正在与国家广播公司中央电视台 (CCTV) 合作，并将直播所有活动根据该公司发布的微信官方文章，其平台上的比赛将在抖音上发布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抖音上将提供完整的回放以及大量关于运动员的视频、比赛新闻和运动技巧。同样的内容也将在字节跳动旗下的新闻聚合和信息内容平台今日头条上提供。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;蚂蚁集团与中国东部杭州建立战略合作&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;杭州亚运会，由于中国严格的 Covid-19 控制，原定于 2022 年 9 月举行的会议被推迟到今年。在 15 个比赛日中，来自 45 个国家和地区的运动员将争夺游泳、田径和篮球等 40 个项目的 483 枚金牌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管许多中国科技公司采取了紧缩措施，包括减少广告预算，以在经济逆风时降低成本，预计许多人将支持该活动以提升其全球知名度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了支付宝，其他亚洲电子钱包也参与了此次活动作为蚂蚁金服跨境支付平台支付宝+主要合作伙伴的虚拟接力活动。其中包括来自印度尼西亚的 Dana、来自菲律宾的 GCash 以及来自韩国的 Kakao Pay。支付宝+将通过其新增的面向中国游客的跨境支付服务支持奥运会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;电子竞技将作为奖牌项目首次亮相亚运会，吸引了多家电脑和智能手机厂商作为官方供应商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最大的 PC 制造商联想是全球唯一赞助 2008 年北京奥运会的中国公司，它在 5 月宣布成为奥运会 PC 和 IT 服务的官方供应商。中国智能手机制造商 Vivo 周四宣布，它将提供其 iQOO 系列作为电子竞技赛事中使用的智能手机的独家供应商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，中国社交媒体和视频游戏巨头腾讯控股已经看到了三个其电子游戏《英雄联盟》、《王者荣耀》和《和平精英》被选中用于杭州亚运会的电子竞技比赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家总部位于深圳的科技巨头去年 1 月成为了亚运会主办方亚奥理事会和腾讯公司高级副总裁马晓义表示，将支持杭州亚运会电子竞技的筹备和发展，支持亚洲电子竞技产业的发展。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在去年 5 月宣布延期之前，杭州亚运会已经吸引了多家中国科技公司的兴趣，包括国有电信网络运营商中国移动和中国电信，以及杭州的一些公司- 的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国监控摄像头巨头海康威视于去年 1 月签约成为奥运会的官方赞助商。该公司承诺通过为赛事提供安检、交通调度等多个领域的智能服务，助力打造“智能亚运会”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉利旗下品牌帝豪、英伦、吉利、全球鹰阁与沃尔沃早在2019年就与主办方签署协议，成为杭州亚运会首家官方合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China and US revive drug control talks in lead-up to Blinken trip]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224390/china-and-us-revive-drug-control-talks-lead-blinken-trip?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/29d3b941-84be-4472-9a88-3be4272d7e55_a5a62bd3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中美周四恢复禁毒合作谈判，之后恢复讨论暂停 10 个月，就在美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯访华前几天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国家药品监督管理局副局长赵军宁会见美国食品药品监督管理局副局长安迪·弗里斯特根据 NMPA 的一份声明，在北京就政策、立法和国际事务进行了交流，并“就 2023 年及未来的合作交换了意见”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中美药品监管机构之间的合作不仅有助于声明援引赵立坚的话称，“促进两国监管协调，也为全球药品监管领域合作打下坚实基础。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望双方能够共同努力， the cooperation plan into practice, so as to better protect and promote public health.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the statement, Fristedt said she was happy with previous cooperation outcomes and “looks forward to more cooperation in the future”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing suspended the cooperation with Washington in August in retaliation for a visit to Taiwan by then US House speaker Nancy Pelosi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before Pelosi&#39;s visit, cooperation on drug control, in particular on fentanyl , had been a key area of the relationship despite other tensions between the two countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Drug cooperation is also expected to be on Blinken&#39;s agenda when he meets Chinese leaders this weekend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The top US diplomat was originally scheduled to visit China early this year but the trip was put on hold after a suspected Chinese spy balloon was shot down over US waters in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Mexico says it will give China proof of fentanyl smuggling&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Fentanyl overdoses cause tens of thousands of deaths each year in the US, with deaths related to the drug rising from 5.7 per 100,000 people in 2016 to 21.6 in 2021, according to US data.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China had been considered the main source of illicit fentanyl entering the US until 2019, when Beijing imposed stricter export controls at the US&#39; request.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US says China remains the main source for key ingredients but the final production capacity has largely moved to countries like Mexico.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past year, the US had imposed multiple sanctions against Chinese entities and individuals allegedly involved in fentanyl trafficking, sanctions that China has protested against.&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;In May, the US Treasury Department&#39;s Office of Foreign Assets Control announced sanctions against seven entities and six individuals based in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That followed similar sanctions introduced in April against two Chinese companies and four nationals for allegedly supplying precursor chemicals used for fentanyl production to drug cartels based in Mexico.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China had warned that “unreasonable” US sanctions could create “obstacles” for cooperation to tackle the fentanyl crisis.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thailand seeks to re-engage Myanmar junta with Asean meeting, says letter, sources]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3224394/thailand-seeks-re-engage-myanmar-junta-asean-meeting-says-letter-sources?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 21:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/777b0565-6089-442d-8143-8dc46000595f_e36670bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Thailand&#39;s caretaker government is proposing to “fully re-engage” Myanmar&#39;s military rulers and has invited Southeast Asian foreign ministers to an informal meeting on Sunday in an effort to jump-start a stalled peace plan, according to a letter seen by Reuters and sources aware of the invitation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The proposal was made in a June 14 letter from Thailand&#39;s Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai to his Association of Southeast Asian Nations (Asean) counterparts, seen by Reuters on Friday and confirmed by three sources with knowledge of the planned meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 10-member Asean - which includes Myanmar - has barred the junta&#39;s ruling generals from its high-level meetings over its failure to honour its agreement, known as the “5-point consensus”, which included calls for an immediate end of hostilities, dialogue between all parties and the granting of full humanitarian access.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The current Asean chair, Indonesia, has declined to attend the meeting, according to three sources. The nation&#39;s foreign ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The foreign ministry in Thailand – expected to have a new government by August following an election last month – declined to comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia last month cited progress in its behind-the-scenes efforts to engage multiple parties in Myanmar&#39;s conflict in a bid to advance a peace process agreed in April 2021 by Asean leaders and Myanmar&#39;s military, two months after it seized power in a coup and launched a deadly crackdown on opponents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Myanmar has been embroiled in violence since the coup, with the military battling on multiple fronts to try to crush an armed pro-democracy resistance movement formed in response to the crackdown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Human rights and some United Nations experts have accused the military of committing widespread atrocities. The junta says it is fighting terrorists who aim to destroy the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The letter from Thailand&#39;s foreign minister did not explicitly say that Myanmar&#39;s junta-appointed foreign minister had been invited to the meeting. However, two informed sources said the Myanmar minister had been invited.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The letter said the proposed meeting would be “part of the initial steps” of the peace process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It cited a meeting last month at the Asean summit in Indonesia where “a member nation” made an unequivocal statement that Asean should fully re-engage with Myanmar at the leadership level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A number of members supported the call and some were willing to consider, there was no explicit dissenting voice,” Don said in the letter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Myanmar state media condemned the United Nations as “rotten” on Friday, days after the UN special envoy for the country stepped down and the world body slammed curbs on aid for cyclone survivors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The state-backed Global New Light of Myanmar published an opinion piece entitled “The Picture of Irrelevance”, accompanied by a photo of the UN headquarters in New York. “Inside, it is infested with egos. Its core is rotten,” the piece said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The arrogance, ignorance and self-interest have so polluted their minds that they are either in denial of how irrelevance (sic) their existence has become … or just simply incompetent and incapable of seeing the reality.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UN special envoy for Myanmar Noeleen Heyzer stepped down this week after an 18-month tenure in which she was criticised by both the junta and its opponents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Singaporean sociologist was tasked with urging the military to engage in political dialogue with opposing groups, and end a bloody crackdown it launched after toppling the government of Aung San Suu Kyi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She visited last August and met junta chief Min Aung Hlaing and other top military officials in a move criticised by rights groups as lending legitimacy to the generals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This week another one of them &#39;bites the dust&#39;, in connection with Myanmar,” the op-ed said, without mentioning Heyzer by name.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These people should be given no role in finding solutions for the problems Myanmar is facing,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Solutions for Myanmar will come from within and with the help, cooperation and understanding of the neighbours and friendly countries.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month Heyzer met Zin Mar Aung, the foreign minister of the National Unity Government (NUG) dominated by lawmakers ousted in the coup, which is working to topple the junta.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The military has declared the NUG a “terrorist” organisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Friday&#39;s article comes as the UN struggles to get access to areas in western Myanmar devastated by the deadly Cyclone Mocha last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday the UN denounced the junta&#39;s “unfathomable” decision to suspend travel authorisations for aid workers trying to reach more than a million people in cyclone-ravaged Rakhine state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Agence France-Presse&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong teachers should avoid physical contact with students during photos, refrain from using nicknames, education authorities say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3224385/hong-kong-teachers-should-avoid-physical-contact-students-during-photos-refrain-giving-pupils?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 20:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/1b65e988-91de-4e78-aa23-189fd8ab0f30_86613cf3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Teachers in Hong Kong should avoid physical contact with students while taking photos with them and refrain from using nicknames, according to new training materials from the city&#39;s education authorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Education Bureau on Thursday said the training kit was aimed at enhancing teachers&#39; professional values and conduct, as well as helping them to better nurture students.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Teachers are role models for students and shoulder the important responsibilities of passing on knowledge and skills, enlightening students and cultivating character,” it said in the learning materials. “Their words, deeds, ethics and values have a profound impact on students&#39; growth.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong professionals could face jail for not reporting suspected child abuse&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wong Kin-ho, chairman of the Hong Kong Education Workers Union, on Friday said the training kit gave schools the opportunity to inform teachers about their expectations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some teachers may not be sensitive to their actions, like a male teacher might arrange a supplementary class with a female student alone,” he said. “A clear instruction on handling student-teacher relationships will be beneficial to both the teachers and the school management.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 2020-21 school year, educators have been expected to take part in at least six hours of training every three years on their professional roles, values and conduct.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Schools receive four case studies to be discussed with teachers. While the materials include some notes from the bureau, they did not spell out how schools should penalise the educators referred to in the fictitious examples.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In one of the scenarios, a student receives the nickname “Quail” from his classmates because he is shy. The boy is later surprised when his teacher also uses the name while telling others not to bully him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the bureau, the teacher in the example had neglected the student&#39;s feelings and, through his actions, could have prompted others to use the nickname.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Calling students by their nicknames affectionately to show friendliness is not appropriate,” the bureau said. Educators should also refrain from the practice even if the pupils had no objections, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Teachers should maintain a professional image … students should be taught to respect others,” it wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police recommend installing CCTV cameras in classrooms to prevent crime&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In another scenario, the bureau said a teacher lacked sensitivity by participating in party games with students that involved using physical contact to pop balloons, as well as putting his hand around the shoulders of both boys and girls when taking pictures with them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also described the games as “indecent, obscene and offensive”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He failed to recognise his professional identity as a teacher and maintain his own professional image … he should point out to students that the games have inappropriate notions and should not turn a blind eye,” the bureau said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When taking pictures, teachers should consciously maintain an appropriate social distance with students … the teacher has made unnecessary physical contact with students and it could lead to misunderstandings.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Viral photos of final liberal studies exam prompts official warning in Hong Kong&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The third example involved a teacher using social media to post vulgar, defamatory and insulting comments about a restaurant owner who she disagreed with. She also attempts to dissuade others from visiting the eatery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This move has tarnished the professional image of teachers and violated society&#39;s expectations and confidence in teachers,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Teachers should avoid making “inappropriate posts” on social media, even if the content was private or limited to friends only, the bureau added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong on Friday said he believed the materials would help teachers to avoid making irresponsible remarks, and also remind them to keep a respectful distance from students to prevent misunderstandings.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 20:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia’s Putin thanks UAE leader for Ukraine help, hails growing economic ties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3224386/russias-putin-thanks-uae-leader-ukraine-help-hails-growing-economic-ties?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.16 20:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/96072634-b409-4a45-9720-edfd53ece377_7d722a12.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Russian President Vladimir Putin on Friday thanked the president of the United Arab Emirates for his efforts in freeing prisoners of war in Ukraine and hailed what he said were expanding economic ties between Moscow and Abu Dhabi.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin made the comments during talks with UAE President Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed al-Nahyan on the sidelines of Russia&#39;s annual economic forum in St Petersburg, where UAE companies are prominent unlike many Western counterparts who have stayed away because of the Ukraine conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The UAE, like Saudi Arabia, is a member of the OPEC+ oil alliance that includes Russia and it has maintained good ties with Moscow despite Western pressure to help isolate and punish it for sending tens of thousands of troops into Ukraine in February 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Some Arab leaders ignored Russian invasion, Zelensky says on Saudi trip&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The UAE has not joined Western sanctions against Moscow, while Dubai, long popular with Russian tourists, has become a magnet for Russian business people over the past 16 months, with busy direct flights to Moscow and expanding economic ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I know that the Emirates&#39; economy and the social sphere are developing really actively under your leadership and, in this sense, for us of course the Emirates is a very good and comfortable partner,” Putin told the UAE president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Relations between Russia and the Emirates are developing really successfully,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The UAE has helped mediate at least one sensitive prisoner exchange between Russia and Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The exchanges] matter to specific people, and that is always the most important thing, so thank you very much for that as well,” Putin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sheikh Mohammed, who called Putin “my friend” according to a Kremlin transcript, said his nation was ready to help further on Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“... if you think that the Emirates can play a role in the stabilisation of the situation there, in humanitarian issues – we are ready to assist in every way possible,” it cited him as telling Putin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The UAE continues to support all efforts aimed at reaching a political solution through dialogue &amp; diplomacy...,” he tweeted separately after the meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sheikh Mohammed said he hoped the UAE could welcome one million Russian tourists this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 16 Jun 2023 20:50:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>