<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Chinese student accuses hotel butler of sexual assault at luxury 5-star resort in the Maldives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224771/chinese-student-accuses-hotel-butler-sexual-assault-luxury-5-star-resort-maldives?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/474f3d8f-054a-48f1-9975-43124a837ce2_b8bcf275.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名中国学生指控一名酒店管家在期间对她进行了可怕的性侵犯她住在马尔代夫的一家五星级度假胜地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名独自旅行的受害者在社交媒体上详细描述了她的遭遇，并表示中国驻印度洋岛国大使馆已通过电子邮件发送她说他们已敦促地方当局进行调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称性侵犯和强奸未遂事件发生在两周前的法里岛丽思卡尔顿度假村。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名成员拒绝透露姓名的丽思卡尔顿马尔代夫营销团队向《南华早报》证实，警方正在对这名女子的指控进行调查，但拒绝进一步置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地媒体报道，据媒体报道，没有人被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称受害人于 6 月 18 日在她的推特和小红书社交媒体账户上详细讲述了她的遭遇，甚至还点名并张贴了她据称的照片&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还张贴了似乎是马尔代夫警方和马累环礁度假村附近一家健康中心的文件，以证实她对 6 月 11 日发生的袭击事件的指控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这名妇女说，她所谓的袭击者进入她的房间，借她的手机——在她不小心弄坏了她的手机之后——就在这时，所谓的袭击开始了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称受害人立即通知酒店工作人员并声称在警察到达之前，一些物品已从现场移走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，警察从她的嘴里采集了拭子，加上度假村从现场移走的物品，并告诉她返回她正在学习的澳大利亚。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称受害者已返回澳大利亚，她呼吁马尔代夫当局确保正义得到伸张，并要求度假村道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获得更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China publishes white list of deep fake providers to preserve national security and ‘core socialist values’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3224775/china-publishes-white-list-deep-fake-providers-preserve-national-security-and-core-socialist-values?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/e8e05e88-6941-4041-b665-b9370fcedfc5_8b349df7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国互联网监管机构发布了首批“深度造假”技术获批供应商名单随着当局寻求将快速发展的技术纳入国家安全保护伞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国家互联网信息办公室 (CAC) 周二发布的“白名单”列出了 41 种算法的所有者，其中包括技术巨头腾讯、百度和拥有南华早报的阿里巴巴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些算法是根据 1 月 10 日生效的《互联网信息服务深度合成管理规定》备案的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该法规涵盖可以影响公众舆论或社会的深度合成服务提供商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深度合成通常被称为“深度伪造”——“深度学习”和“伪造”的结合。中国监管机构将其定义为使用技术（包括深度学习和增强现实）生成文本、图像、音频和视频以及创建虚拟场景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CAC 敦促深度合成服务提供商尽快注册。名单显示，已备案的数十家企业涉及文本生成图片、客户上传图片或视频剪辑、智能客服等业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白名单包括有关他们的算法、公司名称、产品名称和用途以及备案号的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“严厉处罚”即将到来，因为中国旨在制定打击网络欺凌的新规则&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京出台据 CAC 称，该条例旨在加强对深度合成服务管理的监管，弘扬“社会主义核心价值观”，维护国家安全和公共利益，保护公民和企业的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是其中之一由于担心人工智能的潜在偏见及其在错误信息和深度造假图像传播中的作用，第一批采取行动监管快速发展的人工智能行业的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在与以美国为首的政府关系紧张期间西方国家，中国已经把国家安全变成渗透到治理方方面面的关键范式。在2014年出台的“全面国家安全”框架下，涵盖政治、经济、国防、文化、生态、网络空间等16个安全领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在国家安全会议上委员会上个月，习近平主席警告说，中国面临着更加复杂和困难的国家安全问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他敦促官员们做好应对“最坏情况和最极端情况”的准备，以便他们能够承受“大风大浪，甚至是危险的风暴”，据国家新闻机构新华社报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在与华盛顿的技术战中，北京禁止其主要基础设施运营商购买美国存储芯片制造商美光科技生产的产品，引用“相对严重”的网络安全风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;假的还是真的？人工智能引发对美国 2024 年白宫竞选的担忧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“虽然深度造假技术可以造福人类，但它也会给国家安全带来风险和威胁，”浙江大学美国研究中心教授刘国柱说，去年5月在国际安全研究杂志上写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“深度造假对中国政治的主要挑战体现在宗教极端分子和民族分裂分子的渗透和分裂活动中，”刘写道，同时注意到西方指责中国侵犯人权而北京否认的新疆和香港问题。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blinken’s China trip could pave way for Xi-Biden meeting at Apec summit, analysts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224782/blinkens-china-trip-could-pave-way-xi-biden-meeting-apec-summit-analysts-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 20:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/af2b2f6f-828d-4459-886a-53e9bc9aa462_2f05f6c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯对中国的批评性访问可能为习主席铺平道路- 分析人士表示，拜登会晤和贸易关系解冻表明北京和华盛顿相互承诺继续高层接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯期待已久的中国之行是美中两国之间最高级别的接触自习近平主席和拜登总统去年在巴厘岛会面以来，双方都承认中国是坦诚、深入和建设性的，因为这两个超级大国之间的关系因印度太平洋地区的关税、技术限制和军事活动而紧张。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士指出，布林肯访问期间的积极交流为习近平和拜登在 11 月亚太经合组织 (APEC) 峰会期间举行会晤带来了希望，但需要做更多工作才能促成会谈。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;王毅敦促美方将APEC峰会重新定位为印太战略&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国社科院美中关系专家卢翔表示与布林肯的会面可以被解读为两国达成了习近平和拜登在旧金山APEC会议期间会面的“默契”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为双方可能已经达成内部共识两位领导人将在 11 月举行一次顺利和建设性的会谈。习主席甚至可能对美国进行正式访问，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果双方能够在未来四个月内在具体问题上取得突破，那么我们可以更加乐观关于中美关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四川大学国际关系学教授庞仲英说，布林肯的访问，以及中国最高外交官王毅和美国国家安全顾问杰克沙利文去年在奥地利的会晤月，都在为领导人在 11 月的 Apec 峰会上会面做准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从外交的角度来看，如果 [中国外长] 秦刚在峰会，希望在秋季举行，习近平和拜登会面的机会会大大增加，”庞说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平出席 [APEC] 将表明中国非常认真地促进两国之间的健康关系.如果他缺席，这将表明双边关系已经偏离轨道，”庞说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯在为期两天的北京之行中会见了中国高级官员，包括与习近平的最后一刻会面，并与高级外交官王和外交部长秦分别进行了 10 多个小时的讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方同意通过联合工作组推进磋商，以解决两国关系中的“具体问题”，包括一个小组来解决芬太尼的国际走私——上个月美国宣布制裁中国公司运输化学品制造药物后，这是布林肯议程上的一个关键项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他们没有在人权、拘留等方面取得任何突破美国公民或恢复自美国前众议院议长南希·佩洛西 8 月有争议的台湾访问以来暂停的两边军事沟通渠道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国际事务教授朱峰-南京大学中国关系学院称布林肯访问期间的对话是自去年习拜登会晤以来“最具建设性”的对话，表明双方致力于继续高层对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“双方双方对恢复高层对话和接触总体上感到满意，”他说，但补充说，最重要的不是恢复对话，而是能否建立对话机制和渠道，让双方沟通解决重大关切。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平和布林肯结束中国之行，誓言稳定关系以避免冲突&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;位于华盛顿的史汀生中心中国项目主任孙云表示，布林肯之行本身就是“进步”，自从2月份的气球事件后就被推迟了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说他的访问为未来的交流打开了大门，但她并不期望立即取得突破，尤其是在诸如此类的“结构性挑战”上&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次访问开启了未来讨论的可能性，但我认为目前我们不应该期待具体的主要成果，”她说。 “美国和中国之间的任何问题都无法提供 [a] 简单的快速解决方案。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国加大了对中国的技术限制，包括游说其盟友限制半导体出口——这是北京的关键因素军事发展——对该国而言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;军事紧张局势也有所加剧，本月早些时候，一艘中国军舰被指控与一艘美国驱逐舰进行“不安全”的近距离接触，华盛顿继续向台湾出售武器北京声称拥有主权的统治岛屿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但布林肯在访问期间反复提出的改善危机沟通和军对军渠道的需求没有取得任何进展。布林肯在周一晚间结束访问前的新闻发布会上说：“中国尚未同意推进这一进程。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，美国并不寻求与中国“脱钩”，但会需要通过不向北京提供“可能被用来对付我们”的技术来维护自身利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在台湾问题上，布林肯表示，他重申美国致力于其“一个中国”政策，并且确实不支持台独，但会坚守根据《台湾关系法》向台北作出的承诺，确保台湾有能力自卫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chong Ja Ian，美中关系副教授在新加坡国立大学，美国和中国在这些问题上的基本立场继续存在分歧，“在任何重大变化之前还有一段距离”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说恢复对话是“一个开始”，但“光靠谈话并不能保证关系会改善”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“王毅的宣读将当前华盛顿与北京的紧张局势归咎于美国。习近平对布林肯的公开表态表明，他期待美方更加努力地修复关系。这当然会让北京摆脱困境，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平的最高外交政策顾问王毅敦促美国“深刻反思”并处理与北京的分歧，同时将华盛顿对中国的“错误认知”导致两国关系恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他要求美国解除对北京的“非法和单边”制裁，停止对北京的技术遏制，同时强调中国不会在台湾问题上妥协，“核心其核心利益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;可能需要布林肯访问北京才能缓和美中紧张局势&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;习近平在与布林肯的会晤中敦促华盛顿采取“理性的态度”务实的态度”，并将他们的积极声明付诸行动，致力于稳定和改善美中关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国社会科学院的卢说，北京利用这些会议向美国传达了其“战略清晰度”美国，包括台湾，以及中国提到的“具体问题”可能指向他们的贸易争端，与其他未解决的问题相比，他预计贸易争端很快就会取得进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯表示，更多的美国高级官员可能会未来几周将访问中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们普遍预计美国财政部长珍妮特耶伦和商务部长吉娜雷蒙多将很快访问中国。随着美国审查是否保持特朗普时代对大量中国商品征收的关税，两国商务官员最近开始重新接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但台湾仍然是一个棘手的问题，需要更好的卢说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国该说的都说了……需要美国在行动上表现出一种克制。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan’s export orders fall for ninth straight month in May, but chip sales to India, Malaysia, US offer hope]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3224772/taiwans-export-orders-fall-ninth-straight-month-may-chip-sales-india-malaysia-us-offer-hope?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/41a0d9a6-60c3-4f88-b9c6-7eb81475d462_5169dcd0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾出口订单，靠全球采购其高科技硬件，如周二公布的数据显示，由于海外需求疲软，半导体芯片在 5 月份连续第九个月下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上月出口订单额同比下降 17.6%，至经济部表示，456.8 亿美元。 4月份这一数字下降了18.1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是因为5月份来自中国和香港、北美和欧盟的订单更低，”胡锦礼说，台北国立阳明交通大学商业与管理研究所教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“半导体[和]电子产品的出口订单仍处于低水平。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部数据显示，5 月份来自中国大陆和香港的订单下降了 20.9%，而欧洲买家的订单下降了 34.9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国购买台湾商品的交易下降了下降 22.9%，尽管它仍然是 5 月份台湾最大的出口订单来源地，达 146 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;购买台湾消费电子产品的承诺下降了 16.6%，消费电子产品是 5 月份销售额最高的类别，销售额为 154.7 亿美元，同比下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;信息和通信产品订单下降 9.5% 至 126.2 亿美元，而塑料和化学品订单均下降超过 30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;工作宏基 CEO 表示，在家办公将扭转 PC 销售下滑的局面&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;科技占台湾 8200 亿美元经济的 30%，该岛供应全球约 60% 的半导体芯片。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在冠状病毒大流行的头两年之后，世界大部分地区对科技硬件的需求逐渐减少，在此期间消费者购买了额外的个人电脑、平板电脑和手机用于在家工作和学习。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;自去年以来，通货膨胀、高利率和对经济衰退的担忧使消费者情绪低落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国会预算办公室预测，美国经济在 2023 年将增长不到 0.1%，尽管外部分析师预测&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在中国紧张局势和供应链担忧的背景下，台湾吸引了更多日本投资&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;欧盟委员会表示，今年欧盟经济增长应达到 1%，而分析师据估计，中国的国内生产总值将增长 5% 左右。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾内阁本月早些时候表示，它已设定目标，通过寻找新市场将年度贸易额提高 10%，达到 1 万亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;它表示将通过“打开新的世界市场”来实现其出口目标，以抵消中国大陆需求下降的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度、马来西亚和美国的买家已经提高了他们的总金额来自台北的财政部数据显示，至少从 2021 年初开始，台湾的半导体芯片支出就已增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;绿色和平组织举报违反劳工规定，台湾外来务工人员的声誉受到打击&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;从美国采购从 2022 年 1 月的 2.047 亿美元增加到上个月的估计 2.964 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同期对印度的销售额从约 3000 万美元跃升至 1.45 亿美元，而马来西亚买家获得了 7.516 亿美元上个月台湾芯片的价值为 6.683 亿美元，而 2022 年 1 月为 6.683 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度正在加紧其增值电子产品制造以出口和国内市场，而马来西亚正在发展国内科技硬件行业.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国正试图重新调整全球供应链，使其远离中国大陆，但同时仍靠近台湾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但“总体而言，结构性转变需要更多时间，因为工厂需要时间来本月早些时候，穆迪分析公司驻新加坡的经济学家 Heron Lim 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 Lim 表示，台湾“不会出现大的复兴”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大规模生产香港 Natixis Corporate &amp; Investment Banking 亚太区首席经济学家 Alicia Garcia-Herrero 说，2 纳米芯片的数量——由于省电和速度而成为世界上最先进的——最终应该会提升台湾的全球出口。&lt;/p>; p>;全球最大代工芯片制造商台积电预计 2025 年开始量产 2 纳米芯片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Garcia-Herrero 补充说，现有的先进芯片并没有提升出口订单，因为美国和台湾限制对中国大陆的出口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于芯片禁令，对中国的订单已经减少，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获得更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Boss of missing Titanic submersible once called his industry ‘obscenely safe’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224779/boss-missing-titanic-submersible-once-called-his-industry-obscenely-safe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/0ca0d8ae-ea53-44a9-a952-c5f2eeaeb1fc_e9274709.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Titan 潜水器背后的公司创始人此前曾将他的行业描述为“淫秽的安全”，并抱怨客船法规阻碍了创新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据了解，OceanGate 首席执行官 Stockton Rush 在本文发表时正登上 Titan，这艘潜水器于周日与水面失去联系，引发了恐慌为了他的安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据海岸警卫队的说法，截至周二早些时候，这艘船与其他四名乘客一起出发去查看泰坦尼克号的残骸，据信该船还剩下 70 到 96 小时的氧气。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rush 为推动与潜艇世界截然不同的商业潜水器行业所做的努力已在媒体上得到充分报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;失踪的泰坦尼克号旅游潜水器上有哪些人？ &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Rush 在 2019 年的一次采访中描述了这个行业，他说几十年来该领域没有发生过伤害，并补充说：“这是非常安全的，因为他们有所有这些规定。但它也没有创新或成长——因为他们有所有这些规定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;OceanGate 没有立即回应 Insider 在工作时间以外发送的置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但它网站描述了对“高水平操作安全”的承诺和 Titan 的“无与伦比”的船体监控安全系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rush 的简介出现在史密森尼杂志上，描述了他为扩大人类探索深海，称他为“勇敢的发明家”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它记录了拉什对探索的热情，以及他为激活私人潜水器市场所做的努力，该市场长期以来因海上发生的工业事故数量而受到抑制潜艇工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1993 年的一项法规对安全标准和谁可以驾驶潜水器进行了严格的新控制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rush 称这些发展“可以理解但不合逻辑”，他认为法律是根据该杂志，他用心良苦，但哀叹它对商业创新造成的窒息影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他对安全的评论是对美国政府对海洋研究的重视程度如此之低的广泛遗憾的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;救援队竞相寻找在大西洋失踪的泰坦尼克号旅游潜艇&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2019 年，拉什的公司开始宣传乘坐泰坦号前往著名沉船泰坦尼克号沉船的商业旅行，宣传一项实验性设计，其碳纤维材料船体比其他车辆轻得多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，据该杂志报道，在该公司未能为其签约的研究支持船获得适当的许可后，旅行被推迟了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为周二，定位和联系泰坦的努力仍在进行中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阅读原文&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Use the law to tackle terrorism in Xinjiang, China’s security chief says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3224769/use-law-tackle-terrorism-xinjiang-chinas-security-chief-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/43339d1e-9e33-43b4-9d12-cf3fe7bc1302_3eb6745e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;安全人员应利用中国的法律基础设施在该国打击恐怖主义和极端主义&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据官方通讯社新华社报道，这是中共中央安全局局长陈文清在周日结束的对该地区为期五天的访问中传达的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“[当局应]依法坚决打击恐怖主义和极端主义犯罪，”陈在去年底担任中央政法委员会主任后首次访问该地区时说。&lt;/p>; p>;“[我们应该]加强配套法律法规建设，推动执法和司法问题在制度层面得到解决，”他说，并强调需要“科学”地对待立法工具。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“[我们应该]推进严格执法，巧妙运用法律工具维稳打击犯罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[我们应该]推进公正司法，让各族人民对正义有信心&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示，反恐工作应该“常态化”，当局应该引导各族人民自觉地建立“国家意识、公民意识和法律意识”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;在 10 月的第 20 次党代会期间，陈被提拔为最高安全职位和政治局 - 党的 24 名核心成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为该委员会的负责人，他负责监督该国的警察、检察官、法官、监狱和高级间谍机构。在 10 月晋升之前，陈是该国的国家安全部长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国政府被指控对新疆的维吾尔族和其他穆斯林族群成员进行大规模迫害。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;但北京否认了这些指控，并坚称该地区的安全措施对于打击恐怖袭击是必要的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在 2015 年出台了第一部反恐法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以下内容年，新疆发布了在该地区实施该立法的具体指示。地方当局还在 2017 年发布了关于该地区“去极端化”工作的规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管国际社会批评中国政府在新疆的行动，但习近平主席称赞北京在 2020 年的该地区政策“完全正确” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京坚称自 2017 年以来新疆没有发生恐怖袭击。但从 1990 年到 2016 年，该地区发生了“数千起恐怖袭击”，导致“数百名无辜者死亡”和警察”，据中国官员称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从 2016 年到 2021 年，该地区由西藏自治区前党委书记陈全国负责监管，陈全国以对安全的强硬态度着称。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;陈全国是 2020 年因“严重侵犯人权”而受到美国制裁的多名新疆官员之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人权仍然是许多发达国家外交议程上的一个问题&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯 (Antony Blinken) 在周一结束的为期两天的北京访问中提出了此事。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Xpeng seeks to be first major Chinese EV maker to launch right-hand drive cars as it targets Hong Kong market]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3224773/xpeng-seeks-be-first-major-chinese-ev-maker-launch-right-hand-drive-cars-it-targets-hong-kong-market?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/af0aebb9-39da-404f-85e6-8efcc3fd56b4_b82e3794.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国电动汽车 (EV) 初创公司小鹏将目光投向香港计划明年在该市推出右驾车型，以与特斯拉等老牌竞争对手展开竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家广州汽车制造商副董事长兼总裁 Brian Gu 表示，小鹏汽车将提供一种不同于香港街头现有电动汽车的车辆，将以其先进的技术和独特的设计吸引本地客户，加强其走向全球的战略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们进入时，我们将可能面临相当大的竞争，”他在南华早报中国会议的主题演讲中说：香港 2023。“但我们确实认为我们的产品将具有不同的吸引力。我们希望确保我们在中国开发的技术也可以在香港使用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gu 表示右驾车型可能会在 2024 年底进入香港市场。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;这是中国主要电动汽车制造商之一以右驾车型进军香港市场的第一步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xpeng 的国内竞争对手 – 位于上海和总部位于北京的 Nio理想汽车 – 尚未公布在香港销售电动汽车的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这三家公司被视为中国对美国汽车制造商特斯拉的最佳回应。他们都组装配备初步自动驾驶技术、先进的车载娱乐系统和高性能电池的电动汽车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们现在只生产左舵车型，其中大部分在大陆销售。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“右手驾驶是 [整个电动汽车] 市场的很大一部分，”顾说，并补充说小鹏汽车决心将自己打造成为一家强大的全球电动汽车公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 2020 年底，该公司开始向欧洲出口电动汽车，希望在发达经济体与特斯拉和其他外国竞争对手一较高下。它的海外销售数字没有公开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gu 说，它的两款新车型 G9 运动型多用途车 (SUV) 和 P7 运动型轿车的部分产品将在两周内交付给欧洲客户.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国电动汽车制造商在国际市场上是强有力的竞争者，因为他们有好的产品和合理的价格，”黄河科技学院客座教授张大卫说。 “在高端市场，中国企业需要根据当地司机的需求开发一些新车型。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，市场研究公司 Canalys 发布了一份报告，预测中国汽车制造商的电动汽车出口量可能达到 130 万辆根据中国汽车工业协会 (CAAM) 的报告，今年的出货量几乎是去年 679,000 辆汽车出货量的两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xpeng 以开发使用激光雷达（光雷达）的自动驾驶技术而闻名检测和测距）传感器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，Xpeng 制造的一些汽车在其 X NGP（Navigation Guided Pilot）软件（类似于特斯拉的全自动驾驶（FSD） ) 系统，获得地方当局批准投入运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是第一家获得北京交通部门批准其半自动驾驶技术的中国汽车制造商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该系统已在上海、广州和深圳获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gu 表示，小鹏汽车未来将减少小鹏汽车中使用的激光雷达数量，以降低生产成本，并使周围的驾驶员能够负担得起自动驾驶技术世界。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong environmental groups join forces to sound warning over potential loss of bird haven because of new IT hub development]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3224776/hong-kong-environmental-groups-join-forces-sound-warning-over-potential-loss-bird-haven-because-new?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 19:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/d4670219-ac10-4ce6-8113-bff624375d9d_62e3ecf0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港环保组织警告说，248 公顷（613-英亩）靠近中国大陆边界的鸟类天堂，如果不采取保护措施保护生态系统，则指定用于开发 IT 中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;九个组织周二表示，拟议的“三田科技园”计划新界区可能危及多达117种具有特殊保育价值的鸟类，例如极度濒危的白头潜鸭和濒危的黑脸琵鹭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鸟类保护区的面积是新界的13倍the size of Causeway Bay&#39;s Victoria Park.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Damage to wetlands there could threaten migratory bird populations in the East Asian-Australasian Flyway,” Wong Suet-mei, a conservation officer at the Hong Kong Bird Watching Society, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong explained the flyway was one of the major migratory routes for birds in a span from New Zealand to Alaska. It supports 50 million migratory birds a year, including 32 threatened and 19 near-threatened species.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other activist groups involved in the campaign to protect the site include the Conservancy Association, Green Power, Greenpeace and World Wide Fund for Nature.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The proposal to earmark 627 hectares of land in the city&#39;s northwest to establish an innovation and technology hub and provide more than 50,000 homes was put forward by the Development Bureau last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is also a key scheme under the planned Northern Metropolis megaproject, promoted by the government as a new driving force for economic growth and integration with the mainland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About two-fifths of the San Tin Technopole, 248 hectares, is regarded as biologically sensitive, with areas such as wetlands, fish ponds and water catchment zones.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Land granted under Hong Kong technopole cannot be left vacant, sold arbitrarily&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Then chief executive Carrie Lam Cheng Yuet-ngor said in 2021 that the Northern Metropolis would include three wetland conservation parks covering a total of 1,220 hectares, including a 570-hectare site in Sam Po Shue, in Yuen Long.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong added that the wetlands in the proposed technopole had a “close ecological connection” with the Mai Po Inner Deep Bay Ramsar Site, a nearby nature reserve designated in 1995 for migratory bird and mangrove conservation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation Department last August launched a feasibility study on establishing a wetland conservation park system in the Northern Metropolis. The department&#39;s report is expected to be published in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Development Bureau in the meantime announced the San Tin Technopole proposal in May and started a three-month public consultation programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Development Bureau earlier said the San Tin Technopole would affect only 90 hectares of wetlands and fish ponds.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Don&#39;t build I&amp;T hub on Hong Kong wetlands without conservation park plan: experts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Wong said research done by the green groups identified 205 bird species in the proposed development area, which was also home to 19 critically endangered and endangered species.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that the black-faced spoonbills found in the area were 30 per cent of the city&#39;s population and 1 per cent of the global total.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United Nations Convention on Biological Diversity ruled a wetland should be considered of international importance if it regularly supported 1 per cent of a population of a single species or subspecies of waterbird.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kristy Chow Oi-chuen, a campaign officer for the Conservancy Association, highlighted that about 141 hectares of the Sam Po Shue wetland conservation park overlapped the San Tin Technopole proposed site, which raised concerns about the integrity of the protected area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Development Bureau proposed the San Tin Technopole plan before the Agriculture, Fisheries and Conservation Department released the complete ecological science survey results,” she said. “It is in contrast to the planning intention of a wetland conservation park.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post has contacted the Development and the Environment and Ecology Bureaus for comment.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As Singapore gears up for 6 Coldplay shows, Malaysians lament hardline opposition to UK band]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3224777/singapore-gears-6-coldplay-shows-malaysians-lament-hardline-opposition-uk-band?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 19:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/925696d7-4906-4ea4-8063-3fb40ac58601_767e14da.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;British rock band Coldplay will become the first-ever act to play for six nights at Singapore&#39;s National Stadium, as overwhelming demand for tickets for next January&#39;s shows compelled organisers to add two additional dates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Concert promoter Live Nation said at midday on Tuesday that tickets for all six shows – including two dates added at the last moment – were sold out just 24 hours after presales opened. Some 200,000 tickets were sold for the first four concerts between January 23 and 27.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Organisers did not immediately confirm the total number of tickets sold following the decision to add two gigs on January 30 and 31, but hinted at the possibility of more ticket releases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The extended run is a major shot in the arm for the island republic&#39;s 55,000-seater National Stadium – which last year was taken over by the government from private ownership amid criticism of being a white elephant unable to attract top-tier events.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The stadium, part of the sprawling Singapore Sports Hub, is also slated to host five of Europe&#39;s biggest football teams including Liverpool FC and Bayern Munich in July as part of a weeklong football festival.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In neighbouring Malaysia, where Coldplay will perform just one show – despite intense fan clamour for more dates – social media commenters lamented agitation by Islamic conservatives over the hosting of concerts that they said might have turned off the five-piece band led by Chris Martin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The concert was the talk of social media in Singapore, with a mix of rants from fans who failed to buy tickets, memes about Coldplay&#39;s “permanent residency” in the country and posts of elation from those who will watch the band live next January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tickets were available for purchase online as well as by phone and in person at post office branches.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On TikTok and Reddit, some posted play-by-play instructions on how to succeed in securing tickets online, where some 1 million virtual queue numbers were issued. “Don&#39;t panic!” one commenter wrote, should the screen momentarily freeze when it is your turn to pick your tickets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Frustration with the virtual queue also translated into memes. “When your queue number is more than 1 million and you end up seeing a blank page, 403 page, get kicked out, have to queue again and then see no more seats left,” read one such gag by Instagrammer Yeolo.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Dejected Malaysia Coldplay fans call for 2nd show after missing out on tickets&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Reaction to the Coldplay bonanza in Singapore was not as lighthearted in neighbouring Malaysia, where tickets for the sole concert to be held on November 22 were snapped up within three hours on May 16.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The hardline Islamist Parti Islam Se-Malaysia, one of the ruling administration&#39;s more formidable opponents, had suggested that hosting the likes of Coldplay was indicative of the government&#39;s intent to “nurture a culture of hedonism and perversion”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday, the country&#39;s Arts, Life Events and Festivals Association said such sentiment was likely the reason why there was only one show in Malaysia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Syed Saddiq Syed Abdul Rahman, leader of the youth-centric Muda party, lamented how having even just one concert in Malaysia had proved to be problematic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While we&#39;re over here arguing over Malaysia hosting concerts, countries out there are grabbing golden chances to generate economic surplus,” he wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since Singapore returned to normalcy following the Covid-19 pandemic, concertgoers in the republic have been spoiled for choice, with artists choosing to stage gigs there due to its high air connectivity and quality of venues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent months, tickets for concerts by Hong Kong&#39;s “Heavenly Kings” Aaron Kwok and Jacky Cheung, as well as gigs by Irish band Westlife, K-pop girl group Blackpink, South Korean star Suga of BTS and Taiwanese diva A-mei, sold out soon after they were released for sale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung Sau Yee, a senior lecturer in digital marketing and branding at Singapore&#39;s Polytechnic School of Business, was quoted in The Straits Times as saying that the high demand for concerts in the post-pandemic era could be down to a mindset of “missing out on certain experiences and not being sure if they can experience it again”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia-friendly Kazakhstan cancels concert of pro-Ukraine war singer Grigory Leps]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3224766/russia-friendly-kazakhstan-cancels-concert-pro-ukraine-war-singer-grigory-leps?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 18:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/eda574b8-f1a5-4793-83f2-375ccdf21d75_99eae2a7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Central Asian Kazakhstan has cancelled a concert featuring Russian singer Grigory Leps following a wave of outcry over his support of the invasion of Ukraine, local officials announced on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ex-Soviet republic retains close ties with Moscow but tries to maintain diplomatic neutrality on Ukraine in an effort to keep good ties with both Russia and the West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Kazakhs are speaking out on social media against Russian singer Grigory Leps, who supports the Russian occupation of Ukraine. The group organising the concert decided to cancel it,” said officials from the southeastern Almaty region.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ukraine prepares &#39;biggest blow&#39; as it claims recapture of 8 villages&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The decision to cancel came a few days after Leps promised to do everything possible to help Russia&#39;s military.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ll do everything we can for our military, whether that&#39;s singing or financially supporting our soldiers,” he said during a forum in Saint Petersburg in mid-June, according to local media reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also supported another artist&#39;s proposal to give a million roubles (US$12,000) for every Ukrainian tank destroyed in the conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vladimir Yuriupin, Leps&#39; manager, minimised the cancellation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s not a big deal. We can do without Kazakhstan. We support our country and will continue to do so,” he said on Russian news website Gazeta.ru.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong on a mission: John Lee underscores ‘value-added super-connector’ role, globetrotting efforts to win business, lure talent]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3224754/hong-kong-mission-john-lee-underscores-value-added-super-connector-role-globetrotting-efforts-win?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 17:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/b964df54-e12b-4762-b068-e6c7666347b5_2aa1f902.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s leader has underscored the city&#39;s role as a “value-added super-connector” now on a global mission to win business deals and lure talent, revealing it is well on its way to attracting nearly double its goal of importing 35,000 workers every year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu on Tuesday told the South China Morning Post&#39;s China Conference: Hong Kong 2023 that it was important to maintain the city&#39;s international status and connections, while telling positive stories in light of “growing volatility and tensions in geopolitics”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities had received 84,000 applications under schemes to lure talent as of the end of last month, with about 49,000 approved, Lee said. The city leader rolled out various measures to attract workers from mainland China and abroad in his maiden policy address last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is solid proof of Hong Kong&#39;s attractiveness for global talents to come and settle, live and work,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trend suggested the city would attract nearly double its initial target of 35,000 workers annually, Lee added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee, who marks his one-year anniversary in office on July 1, also said his administration had gone all-out in promoting Hong Kong following the end of the pandemic. Stringent travel restrictions triggered by Covid-19 had dealt a blow to the city&#39;s business environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The pandemic has made it a global trend to &#39;work from home&#39;, and in many aspects, working from home has proven to improve work efficiency ... However, my team and I don&#39;t just &#39;work from home&#39; in attracting talents and enterprises,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why are mainland Chinese professionals dominating Hong Kong&#39;s talent hunt?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We have travelled abroad to tell the world that Hong Kong is back in business, back in the business of creating opportunities, back on the world&#39;s centre stage.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee said he would lead a “high-profile business delegation” to a number of members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations this summer. The trip follows visits to Thailand for the annual Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum&#39;s Economic Leaders&#39; Meeting in November and the Middle East in February, both of which he said had successfully attracted potential investors to the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;John Lee jetting off to Middle East, Southeast Asia no fix for Hong Kong: experts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The coming trips would come at an “opportune time” to underline the city&#39;s strengths in regional economic development and the benefits it could bring both to Asean members and the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership, the world&#39;s largest free-trade agreement. Hong Kong has applied to join the agreement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee reiterated his administration&#39;s commitment to innovative in financial and economic development, while stressing the city&#39;s edges in being “super-connected” to the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are more than a super-connector. We are a value-added super-connector. We have professional services, we have a lot of professional workforce,” he said. “We don&#39;t just connect. We help people to grow and help people to thrive.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>