<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: Intel and Nvidia continue to push purpose-built chips for training AI systems in China amid US export restrictions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3227447/tech-war-intel-and-nvidia-continue-push-purpose-built-chips-training-ai-systems-china-amid-us-export?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/12/b37021c6-8458-4b35-aa00-cc71c9a55c73_8f3caf86.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;半导体巨头英特尔公司带来了其最新的人工智能（AI）深度处理器-中国大陆对美国限制的先进芯片的巨大需求催生了对 Nvidia 公司走私图形处理单元 (GPU) 的大量场外交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京举行的新闻发布会上周二，英特尔高管展示了该公司的 Gaudi2 处理器，这是一款不受美国出口限制的设备，作为对 Nvidia 优质 A100 GPU 的回应，后者广泛用于训练人工智能系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新举措根据最新的年度报告，英特尔在中国的收入占其 2022 年总收入的 27%，这突显了尽管华盛顿实施出口管制，广阔的大陆市场对美国半导体技术提供商的持续重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此前，英伟达今年早些时候努力在中国推出其旗舰产品 A100 和 H100 GPU 的修改版本，以遵守美国的限制，并为大陆客户保持供应线畅通，新的人工智能开发项目在中国蓬勃发展，以创建类似的服务。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年8月，美国商务部禁止英伟达和AMD公司向中国出售部分先进芯片。 Nvidia 被指示停止销售其 A100 和 H100 GPU，而 AMD 则被禁止向大陆出口其 MI250 芯片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这使得中国的人工智能行业争先恐后地从 Nvidia 购买有限的先进芯片供应。用于训练人工智能系统的 GPU 近乎垄断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;强劲的需求甚至为走私 GPU 创建了快速增长的市场，例如 Nvidia 的 A100 和 H100 设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据 Nvidia 网站称，A100 Tensor Core GPU 为用于人工智能、数据分析和高性能计算应用的全球领先数据中心提供支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于英特尔来说，中国的需求强化了其提供服务的承诺公司执行副总裁桑德拉·里维拉（Sandra Rivera）兼任公司数据中心和人工智能集团总经理，在北京举行的新闻发布会上表示，客户“拥有广泛的硬件选择”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她英特尔表示，Gaudi2 旨在降低进入门槛，增强大陆客户“通过云和智能边缘技术部署人工智能，帮助构建中国人工智能未来”的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英特尔宣布与总部位于山东省东部的全球第二大人工智能服务器制造商浪潮集团合作，为大陆市场打造全新 Gaudi2 驱动的机器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Habana Labs，英特尔数据中心团队，专注于人工智能深度学习学习处理器技术最初于去年 5 月在美国推出 Gaudi2，据称该处理器的训练吞吐量性能是 Nvidia 用于 ResNet-50 计算机视觉模型和 BERT 自然语言处理模型的 80GB A100 GPU 的两倍。&lt;/ p>;&lt;h3>;中国公司 UCloud 增加了获得先进 Nvidia 芯片的市场不确定性&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;英特尔推出最新产品之际，中国的人工智能雄心可能面临更多困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国政府据《华尔街日报》今年早些时候报道，据称正在考虑限制中国公司使用美国云计算服务，这将阻止亚马逊网络服务和微软公司利用先进人工智能芯片的力量造福其大陆客户。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《华尔街日报》上个月的报道，据说美国也在考虑采取升级行动，将 Nvidia 改版的 A800 GPU 纳入其出口禁令。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Solomon Islands may lead way as China eyes greater South Pacific role]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227469/solomon-islands-may-lead-way-china-eyes-greater-south-pacific-role?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 19:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/12/554ca4ed-8c65-487b-82ba-daf4ccc72402_4a2fcb4f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;南太平洋可以为中国“一带一路”倡议提供“新焦点”据外交观察员称，所罗门群岛总理玛纳西·索加瓦雷本周将进行访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;索加瓦雷周一会见了中国国家主席习近平，两国领导人承诺建立“全面战略伙伴关系”并形成“习近平对索加瓦雷表示，“我们的友谊虽然来得晚，但正在引领中国与太平洋岛国的关系。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;去年，所罗门群岛政府因与中国签署秘密安全协议而受到美国的批评。两国政府均未发布该协议的完整版本，但自那时以来，中国已向所罗门群岛提供了更多的警察培训和装备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该岛传统的警察部队合作伙伴澳大利亚也通过加强警力予以回应本周，索加瓦雷与李强总理签署了一系列协议，涵盖发展、贸易、基础设施和治安，使中国能够维持所罗门群岛警察再驻扎三年。他还邀请中国领导人“早日”回访。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;澳大利亚国防部长在所罗门群岛进行安全会谈&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这是中国后疫情时期外交的一部分宾夕法尼亚州巴克内尔大学国际关系教授朱志群表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然北京试图修复与西方列强的关系，但其重点一直是巩固与发展中国家的关系，而中国在这些国家享有优势。朱补充道：“我认为南太平洋是‘一带一路’的新重点，合作潜力巨大。 “一带一路”倡议已经在其他发展中地区留下了足迹。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;索加瓦雷于周日抵达，开始为期一周的访问，他将访问北京以及江苏省和广东省。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，他所罗门群岛政府与台北断交四年后，在北京开设了大使馆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，中国是所罗门群岛最大的贸易伙伴，并于 2021 年成为第二大官方发展援助捐助国澳大利亚智库洛伊研究所的报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二宣布新的中国与所罗门群岛协议后，澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤办公室表示，有人担心警察合作计划“将引发进一步的地区竞争” ”以及意图的透明度”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朱指出，随着美中竞争加剧，这些小岛国可能面临来自华盛顿和北京的压力，要求选边站队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他说，“这需要这些小国的政治智慧来操纵与大国的关系。”但太平洋岛国通常不会像西方那样对中国抱有怀疑态度，并根据自己的发展利益做出判断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;山东省聊城大学太平洋岛屿研究中心教授于雷表示，在西方援助减少的情况下，所罗门群岛正在向中国求助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新冠疫情严重削弱了该国的经济和发展水平。 “以美国为首的西方国家有足够的财力向太平洋岛国提供急需的切实援助。”于说，美国、澳大利亚和新西兰的通货膨胀进一步限制了援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;他说，相比之下，中国政府希望寻求海外市场和投资目的地，可以向这些发展中国家提供大宗商品和低端制造技术和专业知识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这意义重大”余说，加强与太平洋岛国的关系，消除美国基地的军事威胁，对中国具有战略意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥斯汀·斯特兰奇，该大学国际关系助理教授香港特区行政长官表示，索加瓦雷的访问“显然有强大的基础设施目标支撑”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国在所罗门群岛开设大使馆以对抗中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“自建交几年以来以前，经济基础设施项目显然是双边关系的重要组成部分。”他举例说，例如中国为所罗门群岛建造了 7500 万美元的体育场，以举办 2023 年太平洋运动会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;中国科技巨头华为去年还根据一项涉及北京 6600 万美元贷款的协议建设 161 座移动电信塔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯特兰奇表示，尽管所罗门群岛和其他太平洋岛国市场规模较小，但它们对中国海外基础设施投资有吸引力的目的地，“特别是在已经从中国政策性银行借入大量资金的较大发展中国家，类似的机会可能正在减少”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;未来的基础设施项目可能包括卫生、教育和其他领域”，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些项目对国内政治领导人来说具有经济和政治价值，而其他主要捐助者，在这种情况下是澳大利亚或美国，不会资助或建设这些项目。这使中国政府能够以独特的方式为东道国政府提供此类发展资本。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China needs to ‘proactively defend’ against spies, state security minister says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3227443/china-needs-proactively-defend-against-spies-state-security-minister-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/12/cffa783e-142e-4685-b86f-9aee669d33b8_7b555e66.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国必须“积极防御”间谍活动，以加强国家安全和共产党的领导在扩大的反间谍法生效近两周后，中国国家安全部长表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈一新在周二发表的杂志文章中写道，中国需要利用大数据、区块链和技术的力量人工智能来应对间谍威胁。他表示，由于更加不可预测的全球环境带来的风险，需要采取更严格的国家安全措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席已告诉官员为“最坏情况和最极端的情况”做好准备，就像中国和美国一样各州政府都在努力管理它们之间的关系。出于国家安全考虑，两国都采取措施限制对方国家一些公司（尤其是科技公司）的市场准入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，中国立法机关投票决定大幅修改 2014 年起的反间谍法。反间谍法扩大了国家安全执法机构间谍活动和调查权力的定义。它禁止针对政府和秘密机构的网络攻击，以及未经许可获取“涉及国家安全和利益”的文件、数据和信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国的发展现在站在了新的历史起点上，”陈在书中写道。中国法学会主办的《民主法制》杂志是一个宣传党的思想和法律观念的政府控制团体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“外部环境和安全形势发生了重大变化。各种可预见、不可预测的风险挑战、险阻甚至‘狂风巨浪’，都对国家安全工作提出了更高的要求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，反间谍行动虽然必须积极主动，它们应该是有效的，而不是“盲目地进行反间谍斗争”。陈还警告执法部门不要滥用权力，并表示应依法收集证据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的政治敏感案件，例如有关间谍指控的案件，缺乏透明度——审判不公开宣布，而是进行审理&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国近年来以涉嫌从事间谍活动为由拘留了多名外国人。澳大利亚外交部长黄英贤三月份表示，在中国对被拘留的记者成蕾进行国家安全审判一年后仍未做出判决，这令人深感担忧。今年 1 月，黄还对澳大利亚作家杨恒均的延迟判决表示担忧，杨恒均自 2019 年以来一直因间谍罪名在中国被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国当局还在 2019 年拘留了安斯泰来制药公司的一名日本员工。三月北京。加拿大公民迈克尔·斯帕弗 (Michael Spavor) 和迈克尔·康明凯 (Michael Kovrig) 因被指控窃取中国国家机密而于 2018 年被拘留。在加拿大与华盛顿达成协议放弃美国的引渡请求后，加拿大释放了华为技术公司高管孟晚舟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在国家安全部“最近”的一次党委会议上，陈敦促国家安全机构根据周二中央政法委员会的一份声明，开始修改反间谍法的“实施细则”，以反映并详细说明如何使用新立法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在会议上表示，还应该为各个内阁部门起草更具体的规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈还表示，各机构应在中国境外通过媒体和网络宣传该法律。他在杂志文章中也呼应了这一点，文章最后呼吁官员“讲好国家安全工作的故事”，让国际社会更好地了解中国的法治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国政府已批评扩大的反间谍法给外国公司、记者和研究人员，特别是那些进行尽职调查的人带来了新的风险。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korea’s latest missile launch ‘raises alarms’ it’s serious about shooting down US planes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227456/north-koreas-latest-missile-launch-raises-alarms-its-serious-about-shooting-down-us-planes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/12/a0f0376c-dae9-43a7-90da-939e5d0f6a5e_f285d67f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;朝鲜最近发射的远程导弹正在危险地增加朝鲜分析人士表示，这个拥有核武器的国家将兑现其击落在其水域附近活动的美国间谍飞机的威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;遭受制裁的朝鲜发射了据信是洲际弹道导弹 (ICBM) 的导弹周三早上，来自平壤附近地区的。据韩国军方称，导弹从高空弹道发射后，飞行了约 1,000 公里，然后落入水中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国总统尹锡烈和北约其他印太伙伴国家领导人在立陶宛举行的北约峰会期间批评了这次发射，呼吁共同应对导弹和核威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[导弹发射]再次表明大西洋和太平洋地区的安全尹说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜研究大学政治学教授杨武镇表示，周三的发射旨在对美国的侦察飞行发出警告，一艘核潜艇即将抵达韩国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这一举动令人震惊地增加了朝鲜实施击落飞越其专属经济区的美国间谍飞机的威胁的可能性”，尽管国际法允许其他行为杨说，朝鲜在大约三个月内首次发射洲际弹道导弹，此前平壤向华盛顿就美国间谍机在朝鲜水域附近飞行和一艘美国核潜艇即将抵达韩国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就在一天前，朝鲜领导人金正恩的强势妹妹金与正发表声明，声称一架美国间谍飞机进入韩国朝鲜专属经济区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她威胁说，朝鲜将对美国在朝韩海域边界以外的朝鲜海上经济区内的侦察飞行采取“明确而坚决的行动”，并表示这“令人震惊”事件可能会发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，朝鲜国防部发言人指责美国间谍机最近侵入其领空，并威胁称无法保证此类飞机不会被击落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;美国和韩国驳回了朝鲜的指控，并敦促朝鲜不要采取任何引起敌意的行为或言论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;值得注意的是，金与正周一表示她已被“授权”梨花大学政治学教授朴元建表示，向美国发出这些警告，意味着她正在执行命令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当金与正表示她正在执行任务时，朝鲜往往会采取行动。”受领导人委托发出这样的警告。”他告诉《亚洲周刊》。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;朝鲜表示，在威胁击落一架美国间谍机后，它击退了美国间谍机&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2020 年，金与正表示，她被“授权”警告朝鲜边境城市开城的朝韩联络处将被摧毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该办公室很快就被炸毁，这是对朝鲜的强烈愤怒。该教授表示，时任韩国总统朴槿惠对朝鲜采取强硬立场，导致朝韩交流戛然而止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，朝鲜国防部谴责了美国的计划自 1981 年以来首次在不久的将来向朝鲜半岛派遣战略核潜艇，并警告此举可能“引发实际上最严重的核冲突危机”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2023 年 4 月的峰会上，韩国和美国同意“进一步提高朝鲜半岛战略资产的定期可见性，美国核弹道导弹潜艇即将访问韩国就证明了这一点”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国尹要求统一部对朝鲜不要软弱&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;杨说，潜艇可能会在7月18日左右抵达，届时美韩“协商小组”将举行首次会议，讨论“延伸威慑”针对朝鲜的战争在首尔开幕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;朝鲜国防部发言人在周一发表的一份声明中指出，朝鲜于 1969 年击落了一架美国 EC-121 侦察机，造成 31 名美国人全部遇难。 1994 年在朝鲜，一架美国直升机与一架美国直升机发生冲突，导致两名飞行员之一丧生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你无法将当前的紧张局势与朝鲜没有核武器时的过去进行比较。为了避免核战争，我们必须再次给外交一次机会，而不是盲目地继续几十年来收效甚微的制裁和压力。”杨说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三的发射似乎也是为了分析人士称，朝鲜承认上个月大肆吹嘘的太空卫星发射失败而丢了面子，这鼓舞了士气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也是在结束朝鲜半岛停战协定签署 70 周年之前进行的。 1950-53 年朝鲜战争于 7 月 27 日举行，朝鲜庆祝胜利日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梨花大学国际研究教授莱夫-埃里克·伊斯利 (Leif-Eric Easley) 表示，华盛顿和首尔认识到需要加强联盟合作，以安抚朝鲜。韩国公众并阻止朝鲜的侵略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国战略资产的明显访问不会改变韩国防御的能力，但确实表现出协调实施延伸威慑的政治意愿，”他&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然而，平壤正在利用美国飞机和潜艇的行动作为借口，挥舞并进一步发展自己的武器。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《韩国时报》的补充报道&lt; /p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese foreign ministry’s arm in Hong Kong slams United States for renewing city’s ‘emergency status’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3227460/chinese-foreign-ministrys-arm-hong-kong-slams-united-states-renewing-citys-emergency-status?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 19:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/12/07217eb5-1681-4658-ae20-f716852143c0_f694f466.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京驻香港外交部门猛烈抨击美国延长&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部驻香港特派员公署发言人周三在一份声明中表示，香港“紧急状态”是一种“弄巧成拙”和“霸权”行为。不赞成并坚决拒绝”美国总统乔·拜登延长香港国家紧急状态的决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登的前任唐纳德·特朗普在北京实施《香港国家紧急状态法》后于 2020 年 7 月首次宣布国家紧急状态。在经历了数月的反政府抗议后，香港国安法生效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该行政命令每年更新一次，撤销美国授予香港的特权。其中，根据该命令，香港不再享受特殊经济待遇，敏感技术也不能出口到香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港护照持有者也将受到与中国护照持有者相同的待遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登在周一致国会的​​致辞中表示：“香港的局势，包括最近[北京]采取的从根本上破坏香港自治的行动，继续构成不寻常和非同寻常的威胁，这其很大程度上源于美国以外，关系到美国的国家安全、外交政策和经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，我决定有必要继续[ &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;悬赏香港活动人士及镇压筹款“全球警告”：叶刘淑仪&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;驻港公署发言人表示&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美方又故伎重演，滥用国家安全概念，将香港与美国“国家紧急状态”挂钩，虚假指责‘香港局势’对美国国家安全构成威胁，并继续根据美国国内法对香港实施单边制裁。”所谓“国家紧急状态”显示了美方在搞乱香港、利用香港遏制中国失败后的挫败感和“纸老虎”本质。这只会让世界更清楚地看到美国是多么自私、无底线和霸权。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港领导人反驳国安法范围的“唱衰”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;发言人补充道：“谎言永远是谎言，单边制裁都是废纸。香港善政繁荣的历史潮流不可逆转，‘一国两种制度’持续成功的趋势不可阻挡。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还呼吁华盛顿停止其“政治闹剧”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“别人可以通过施压和制裁迫使我们容忍国家主权、安全、发展利益受损的日子已经一去不复返了。”发言人表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们敦促美方立即停止这场自辱性的政治闹剧，停止‘借港制华’的如意算盘，不要在错误的道路上越走越远。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，英方政府还更新了对香港的旅行建议，称国家安全法适用于城市内外的活动，适用于所有人，无论国籍或居住地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港国安警察已发布逮捕令报告指出，针对居住在香港以外地区（包括英国）的个人进行搜查令和经济奖励。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“您应该意识到，发表或支持批评香港和中国当局的政治言论，包括在网上和在社交媒体上发布的内容可能会被视为[国家安全法]下的犯罪行为，并可能会在香港受到起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“那些支持自己被认为从事违反国家安全法活动的个人的人国安法也可能根据同一法律面临起诉。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国安警察突击搜查逃犯罗冠聪的家中&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，香港国安在周三的一份声明中表示，政府指责美英抹黑国家安全法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府发言人指责华盛顿违反国际法原则和国际关系基本准则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发言人表示延长香港紧急状态的举动只是为了干扰香港的治理、法治和社会繁荣稳定，注定会失败。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Czech-French writer Milan Kundera took on life’s absurdity through satire and poetic prose]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227461/czech-french-writer-milan-kundera-took-lifes-absurdity-through-satire-and-poetic-prose?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 19:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/12/a5af971e-f071-4a83-af05-14429aa4c232_cf9ed66f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;米兰·昆德拉，《生命中不能承受之轻》的作者，其黑暗、挑衅性的小说深入探讨了周三，米兰·昆德拉故乡布尔诺市米兰·昆德拉图书馆的发言人表示，他已经成为人类状况之谜。他享年 94 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不幸的是，我可以确认米兰·昆德拉先生在长期患病后于昨天（星期二）去世，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昆德拉在巴黎的公寓去世，法国是他的收养国，自 1975 年从共产主义统治的捷克斯洛伐克移民以来一直居住在那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不仅捷克文学，而且世界文学也失去了一位最伟大的当代作家，也失去了一位伟大的当代作家。”昆德拉图书馆馆长托马斯·库比切克 (Tomas Kubicek) 对公众捷克电视台表示：“昆德拉的作品也是被翻译最多的作家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;捷克总理彼得·菲亚拉 (Petr Fiala) 表示，昆德拉能够“吸引各大洲的几代读者” &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;科马克·麦卡锡，美国文学的黑暗天才，去世，享年 89 岁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;昆德拉经常被誉为诺贝尔文学奖的热门人选，但他从未声称自己是诺贝尔文学奖得主。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过他特有的讽刺和诗意的散文，昆德拉试图表达生活中所有令人信服和荒谬的事物，并借鉴了他自己因持不同政见而被剥夺捷克国籍的经历。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;他在他的批评著作《小说艺术》（1986）中说，生活“是一个我们一直都知道的陷阱：我们不经要求地出生，被锁在一个我们从未选择的身体里，并注定去死。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昆德拉于 1929 年 4 月 1 日出生在布尔诺镇，当时属于捷克斯洛伐克。他的父亲是一位著名的钢琴家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他曾在布拉格学习，并在那里加入了共产党，翻译了法国诗人阿波利奈尔的作品，并创作了自己的诗歌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还在一家学校任教。他的学生包括未来的奥斯卡获奖导演米洛斯·福尔曼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然他声称忠于共产主义，但昆德拉写作的独立精神很快让他陷入了麻烦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他1950 年被开除党籍，1956 年重新入党，并于 1970 年布拉格之春改革运动（他被视为在其中发挥了作用）被镇压后再次被开除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昆德拉的第一部小说《笑话》 1967 年出版的一部关于一党制国家的黑色幽默作品导致了他在捷克斯洛伐克的写作禁令，同时也让他在祖国出名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1975 年，他和妻子维拉去了捷克斯洛伐克。他流亡法国，在雷恩大学担任助理教授四年。 1979 年，他们被剥夺了捷克国籍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他的第二故乡，他于 1981 年成为公民，随着他的小说译本的出现，例如《生活在别处》（1973 年），他的声誉和成功不断提高。以捷克斯洛伐克为背景，讲述了一位诗人被共产主义政权所困的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《笑忘书》（1979）通过七个相互关联的叙述有趣地探讨了政治、历史和日常生活中遗忘的本质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《纽约时报》在 1980 年评价说，这本小说“才华横溢、独创性”，“文笔纯洁、机智，引人入胜；它也很奇怪，有一种将我们拒之门外的陌生感。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昆德拉是一位“对性着迷的作家，并且容易突然（如果优雅的话）跳入自传、抽象沉思和最近的捷克历史， ”《泰晤士报》评论员约翰·厄普代克说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迄今为止，他最著名的作品《生命中不能承受之轻》于 1984 年出版，并于 1987 年拍成电影，由朱丽叶·比诺什和丹尼尔·戴-刘易斯主演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;这部小说是一个关于个人和集体层面上的自由和激情的道德故事，以布拉格之春及其流亡后果为背景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昆德拉的批评者说他背弃了他。捷克同胞和持不同政见者在他流亡法国后决定禁止将他的法语书籍翻译成捷克语。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2008 年，一家捷克杂志指责他在共产党统治下担任警察线人，他在被否认为“纯粹的谎言”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013年，昆德拉在中断13年后出版了他的第一部小说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《无足轻重的节日》讲述了巴黎的五个朋友的故事，获得的评价褒贬不一。 《大西洋月刊》指出其“近乎难以理解的讽刺”，而《卫报》则认为其“臭不可闻”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《纽约时报》称，昆德拉“必须告诉我们的内容似乎不太相关”。 “你不禁想知道，如果他留在捷克斯洛伐克，或者停留更长时间，他的演变会是什么样子。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年，捷克共和国恢复了他的国籍，并于 2023 年米兰昆德拉图书馆在他的家乡布尔诺开业。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.最好&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia 1MDB scandal: alleged Jho Low aide Jasmine Loo arrested as crackdown continues]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227463/malaysia-1mdb-scandal-alleged-jho-low-aide-jasmine-loo-arrested-crackdown-continues?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 19:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/12/adcfe37b-6dca-4cad-9de8-9e339f9c3cbd_155d4dfd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;马来西亚当局周三表示，Jasmine Loo Ai Swan 是 1MDB 的主要同谋scandal mastermind Jho Low, had been arrested in Kuala Lumpur, signifying another major development in efforts to track down those responsible for the multibillion-dollar plunder.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Home Minister Saiffudin Nasution said in a press conference that Loo – formerly a legal counsel to the 1MDB state fund – was arrested last Friday and was currently in remand for questioning at the Dang Wangi police station in the capital city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Loo was detained under Section 409 of the penal code relating to criminal breach of trust, Saifuddin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The minister, conveying a message from Loo&#39;s lawyer, said she was willing to cooperate with Malaysian authorities. Pressed by reporters on the circumstances behind Loo&#39;s sudden emergence in Malaysia and her whereabouts before her arrival in the country, Saifuddin declined to reveal further details.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest detention comes as the government of Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim steps up efforts to bring Low back to Malaysia to face legal charges for his role in the 1MDB corruption scandal. While media reports have placed Low as being in China, Malaysian officials have not confirmed this and Beijing has in the past reacted angrily to suggestions that it was harbouring the billionaire.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The former prime minister Najib Razak, with whom Low had a close relationship, is currently serving a 12-year jail sentence after a conviction linked to the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Loo is believed to have led a flamboyant lifestyle in the 2010s, during the heyday of the plundering, and before the 2018 Malaysian general election which saw Najib&#39;s rivals take power on an anti-corruption platform. Loo is said to have fled Malaysia soon before that poll, along with several others linked to Low.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like Low, Loo was often seen with US celebrities, including with singer Alicia Keys at the luxurious French ski resort Courcheval in 2016. A year earlier, her signature was recorded on a purchase document of a US$4.5 million luxury condominium unit at New York&#39;s Madison Avenue through a shell company, using funds misappropriated from the Malaysian fund.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Along with Low, Loo was charged in absentia in 2018 – after the election that toppled Najib – on money-laundering charges linked to the scandal&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three others were similarly charged and subjected to an Interpol red notice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She has also been in the sight of Malaysia&#39;s central bank, which issued a wanted poster for her and her 1MDB colleague Casey Tang Keng Chee as early as 2015&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January, a Kuala Lumpur high court granted the Malaysian government ownership of Loo&#39;s two luxury cars and cash of 22,600 ringgit (US$4,800) in a civil forfeiture under the country&#39;s Anti-Money Laundering, Anti-Terrorist Financing and Proceeds of Unlawful Activities Act 2001.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After she stopped servicing her mortgage, her condominium in Kuala Lumpur&#39;s upscale Mont Kiara neighbourhood was similarly forfeited to a bank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Loo&#39;s arrest came after the surprise death of another 1MDB-related figure, Kee Kok Thiam, who was the employee at Jho Low&#39;s private equity company who allegedly oversaw Najib&#39;s bank account to ensure that it remained flush with cash for the prime minister to use.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kee&#39;s death, which the family said was due to a stroke, sparked speculation among Malaysians as it happened just weeks after he was apprehended by authorities after returning to the country from hiding in Macau.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong public bus firms not required to adopt distance-based fares, minister says after concerns raised over misuse of HK$2 subsidy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3227452/hong-kong-public-bus-firms-not-required-adopt-distance-based-fares-minister-says-after-concerns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 18:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/12/e9dc09e6-f972-4489-85b8-d360aa351ae2_58bf529d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong will not require its franchised bus firms to charge commuters based on the distance they travel instead of a flat fare, a minister has said, after the move was floated to resolve concerns that a HK$2 (25 US cents) transport concession for the elderly could strain the government&#39;s coffers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawmakers on Wednesday suggested implementing section fares for public buses and argued the policy would reduce the amount paid by the government to franchised firms when those using the concession for elderly and disabled residents took more expensive long-haul routes for short trips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official figures showed public expenditure on the scheme had almost quadrupled, going from about HK$296 million in 2012 to HK$1.2 billion in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;More than 670 people caught in 9-day Hong Kong crackdown on train fare dodgers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But the Transport and Logistics Bureau considered it “inappropriate” to require public bus operators to fully adopt section fares on buses, according to Secretary for Labour and Welfare Chris Sun Yuk-han.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Full implementation of section fares may result in more short-haul passengers travelling on long-haul routes, taking up the capacity of long-haul routes and affecting long-haul passengers,” he said in response to a question from lawmaker Adrian Ho King-hong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If franchised bus operators have to increase the trip frequencies for their long-haul routes, it would also aggravate the burden on road traffic.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He told the Legislative Council&#39;s transport panel that the occupancy rates for long-haul buses could become “too low” and lead to a waste of resources if passengers alighted midway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Introducing more section fares may also lead to duplication of resources with existing short-haul routes or other public transport services, upsetting the delicate balance among various public transport services,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that 1,025 cases involving the suspected abuse of the HK$2 scheme had been discovered between March 2021 and February of this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But panel chairman Ben Chan Han-pan said the government should not shy away from implementing section fares.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is the lack of section fares that has put a heavy burden on the public money,” the lawmaker added. “With section fares, we can save the public money, and it is in the government&#39;s interest to do so.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan also urged authorities to discuss appropriate section-fare schemes with public bus operators.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking against implementing the section fare, legislator Michael Tien Puk-sun said it was not a viable method for alleviating the government&#39;s financial burden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If we fully implement section fares on all public bus routes, bus companies will not have enough income to cover their expenses. Then they cannot do anything but increase fares, which will eventually upset residents,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What you need to know about Hong Kong&#39;s controversial transport subsidy scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tien, a former chairman of the Kowloon-Canton Railway Corporation, instead advised the government to amend the HK$2 concession and have it reimburse passengers 80 per cent of their fare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Passengers pay HK$2 regardless of journey distance now, and this does not make sense,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said that while authorities were currently focused on clamping down on residents abusing the scheme, they were already discussing possible amendments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Chinese University associate professor of economics Terence Chong Tai-leung argued that franchised bus firms should adopt section fares as it was essential to peg the cost to the distance travelled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The biggest problem of the HK$2 scheme is that the fares are not pegged to the distance, which is the root of &#39;taking long-haul routes for short journeys&#39;,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong passengers cheating HK$2 fare scheme face arrest, officials warn&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Acknowledging that requiring public bus operators to adopt the policy while they held franchises would be difficult, he said: “The government should put introducing section fare into the terms while renewing the franchise.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A government-commissioned consultancy study from 2020 estimated that the cost of the public transport subsidy scheme could go from HK$6.9 billion in 2026 to HK$8.6 billion by 2031. The figures would account for about 5.3 per cent and 5.5 per cent of each respective year&#39;s social welfare expenditure, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Transport Department launched a two-month campaign to tackle the illegal use of the scheme on June 26, warning that those caught abusing it could be arrested and prosecuted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deputy Commissioner for Transport Macella Lee Sui-chun at the time said the department would focus on combating subsidy abusers, but would not prevent beneficiaries from taking long-haul routes for short-distance trips.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong correctional services suspends 7 officers arrested in connection with alleged gang rape of woman at party]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3227455/hong-kong-correctional-services-suspends-7-officers-arrested-connection-alleged-gang-rape-woman?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 18:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/12/4571e309-54b0-412e-9cd5-6666c5a1d0a4_45b40edb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Seven prison officers have been suspended from duty after being arrested in connection with the alleged gang rape of a woman in a Hong Kong flat, the Post has learned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three suspects were accused of raping the 31-year-old woman in a Mirador Mansion flat on Nathan Road in Tsim Sha Tsui in the early hours of Sunday, a source said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post has learned that a preliminary investigation revealed that some of the other four suspects were allegedly standing around the bed masturbating during the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong firefighter arrested in Japan for alleged rape of woman&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The source said the woman told police she was drunk and passed out before she was raped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The investigation showed she met a 31-year-old man and a 34-year-old woman in Lan Kwai Fong entertainment hub in Central last year, and they became friends. The man claimed he was a Correctional Services Department employee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Saturday night, she and the 34-year-old woman went to the Tsim Sha Tsui flat to attend a party. The 31-year-old man and seven correctional officers were also attending. They all played card games and drank.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong taxi driver arrested on suspicion of raping teen in back of cab&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Soon after midnight, her two acquaintances left, leaving her and the other seven men in the flat, the source said. They continued to drink. The woman later passed out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When she woke up after daybreak, she found herself naked and alone in the flat. She left and made a report to police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After gathering evidence, detectives from the Yau Tsim district crime squad arrested the seven correctional officers aged 23 to 31.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of Wednesday afternoon, the suspects were still in police custody.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Correctional Services Department, the officers have been suspended from duty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The department attaches great importance to the conduct and ethics of correctional officers and has strict disciplinary requirements,” its spokesman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If any staff member is in breach of the law or discipline, the department will handle it in accordance with the law and will not tolerate any wrongdoing.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Between January and March this year, police handled four reports of rape. There were 10 cases in the same period last year.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Cash or kids? Online backlash as Chinese matchmaker says people on US$700 a month with children better off than super-rich with no offspring]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3227195/cash-or-kids-online-backlash-chinese-matchmaker-says-people-us700-month-children-better-super-rich?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/11/9ef12c56-57f9-4238-a663-8b7b92f5d207_b3781a91.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A comment by a matchmaker in China claiming that a married person with children earning 5,000 yuan (US$700) a month is better off than a single person worth 500 million yuan (US$70 million) has started a values debate on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The matchmaker, surnamed Wang, from Zhejiang province in eastern China, went viral after expressing her views on marriage and children when asked by a vlogger, Xiaoluo, on July 1, the Hangzhou Daily reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What would you say describes an excellent person? A person with family and kids,” Wang said in the video.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang then compared a person with a monthly salary of 5,000 yuan versus a wealthy person worth 500 million yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think the wealthy person is not as good as my son. My son has offspring, which means that our country has a future,” Wang said but did not provide any further justification for her sweeping claims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Xiaoluo posted the video and it trended in China, Wang faced backlash over her comments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Upset by the avalanche of critical comments about her traditional Chinese view of marriage and children, Wang asked Xiaoluo to give her an opportunity to defend herself in a second interview shared online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaoluo apologised to Wang for not asking her permission to publish the video and suggested they make another video to clarify her views.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang, who has been a matchmaker for more than 30 years, said that she used her son as an example to highlight the importance of marriage and restated her belief that a single rich person could not be happier than a less wealthy person with a family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For the next generation, we don&#39;t care about anything else,” Wang added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The only evidence Wang gave to support her claim was the case of a single woman born in the 1980s who came to Wang looking for an “ideal” boyfriend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said the woman believed it was more important that the man was young rather than having a lot of wealth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should respect her traditional values,” Xiaoluo said in reply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then Wang said that she has seen many parents picking up children from school with electric bikes and motorcycles and asked rhetorically if single and childless rich people driving luxury cars seeking youth and beauty were better off.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Who do you think is happier?” Wang asked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the time of writing, the story had attracted 45,000 comments on Douyin alone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “500 million yuan is not as meaningful as the next generation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person asked: “Who says a person with no kids isn&#39;t happy? My happiness is much more important than having offspring.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In mainland China, incessant pressure from parents and society for young people to get married and have children as soon as they can, and in some cases, forcing them to do so, remains a socially acceptable mindset and behaviour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent decades China has been experiencing a decline in both marriages and births, creating a looming demographic cliff as the population rapidly ages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The annual marriage rate dropped from 0.77 per cent in 2017 to 0.54 per cent in 2021, according to data in the 2021 Civil Affairs Statistical Bulletin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, data from the Ministry of Civil Affairs showed that only 8.13 million couples wed in China, a 12 per cent drop from the previous year and the seventh consecutive year of decline.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba, Tencent and Meituan praised by Beijing for helping China’s tech progress in new sign of attitude change]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3227421/alibaba-tencent-and-meituan-praised-beijing-helping-chinas-tech-progress-new-sign-attitude-change?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.12 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/12/b1cf3815-71e6-4cd8-a6ac-4f1f72078677_29c341fc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Group Holding, Tencent Holdings and Meituan are among a handful of tech companies praised by China&#39;s powerful economic planning agency for their roles in supporting the nation&#39;s technological progress and economic growth, a fresh signal that Beijing is putting on a friendly face towards Big Tech firms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong shares of Alibaba closed at HK$89.85 on Wednesday, up 1.24 per cent. In its latest research note, brokerage UOB KayHian set a HK$130 target for Alibaba, implying a nearly 45 per cent upside from the current value.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tencent closed at HK$340, up 1.86 per cent, while Meituan closed at HK$127.3, up 4.34 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three major internet platforms have been under intense regulatory scrutiny over the past two and half years, as Beijing moved to curb the “irrational” expansion of capital and pursue common prosperity, in a process that saw trillions of dollars wiped off company valuations, thousands of jobs eliminated, and the gap between Chinese and US tech giants widened.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Beijing&#39;s attitude took a big turn in late 2022, as it began to highlight the positive role played by internet platforms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, Tencent, China&#39;s largest social media and video gaming company, was praised by the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC) for bolstering the development of artificial intelligence (AI) chips and service robots.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shenzhen-based firm was recognised for its investment in Enflame Technology, an AI chip start-up focusing on semiconductors used in cloud data centres and supercomputing, as well as Yunji Technology, which produces “internationally competitive” robot products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;E-commerce conglomerate Alibaba, owner of the South China Morning Post, was recognised for helping to innovate and transform the agriculture and service industries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huitongda Network, a logistics company in which Hangzhou-based Alibaba holds a 19.1 per cent stake, has provided services to more than 27,000 stores in some 500 townships, the NDRC said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meituan was applauded for putting money into chips and industrial robots, including Rong Semiconductor, a company that makes 12-inch wafers and performs wafer-level packaging and testing, as well as VisionNav Robotics, a logistics-robot manufacturer that has sold more than 2,000 products in over 15 countries and regions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Platform companies have “not only gained substantial returns through investments, but also boosted high-level scientific and technological self-reliance efforts … and contributed to the promotion of high-quality development”, the NDRC said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The high-profile endorsement of Big Tech companies marks a sharp contrast to two years ago, when Beijing was cracking down on internet firms in the name of antitrust and data security. Alibaba and Meituan both received big fines for abusing their market positions, while Tencent was punished multiple times for failing to report previous merger deals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From January to May, profits of Chinese internet firms surged 43 per cent, reaching 57.6 billion yuan (US$7.9 billion), according to a report released by the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology last month.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 12 Jul 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>