<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China’s Quora-like platform Zhihu embeds AI feature on Q&A service, joining other mainland tech firms in ChatGPT frenzy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3222114/chinas-quora-platform-zhihu-embeds-ai-feature-qa-service-joining-other-mainland-tech-firms-chatgpt?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/28/3c7956b7-8b36-4faf-aecf-7aa0c7db7efe_4f775d6e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;知乎开发了新的搜索功能使用人工智能 (AI) 算法完成任务，类似于美国初创公司 OpenAI 的 ChatGPT 背后的内容生成技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最大的知识共享平台运营商知乎将立即开始内部测试据官方报纸《科技日报》周六的一篇报道援引该公司首席技术官李大海的说法，该功能的“搜所聚合”在英文中翻译为“搜索聚合”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;该报告称，根据用户对特定主题的搜索，新功能将提取和编译用户生成的答案以提供综合结果，这“提高了访问信息的效率”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;知乎使用它与总部位于北京的 AI 初创公司 ModelBest 共同开发的大型语言模型 (LLM)，这家在纽约和香港上市的公司在 4 月份领投了一轮融资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At当时，知乎和ModelBest表示，他们正在联合培养名为“知海图AI”的LLM，并探索其在中文问答服务热榜板块的应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;LLM是一种深度学习学习算法，可以根据从海量数据集中获得的知识识别、总结、翻译、预测和生成文本和其他内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，ModelBest 还推出了自己的类似 ChatGPT 的聊天机器人，名为 Luca，即能够起草文件、翻译文章和分析图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些最新的消费者 AI 发展是在互联网监管机构中国网络空间管理局 (CAC) 警告说生成 AI 等先进技术——以聊天机器人应用程序 ChatGPT 为例的几天后出现的，这在大陆不可用——可能对该国的治理、监管和劳动力市场构成“严重挑战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国互联网监管机构警告生成人工智能和其他先进技术带来的风险&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;知乎和 ModelBest 的单独公告反映了中国科技公司如何充分利用人工智能的进步，同时小心翼翼地遵守北京监管和控制互联网上类似 ChatGPT 服务快速发展的努力&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在线搜索服务提供商百度、电子商务巨头阿里巴巴集团、人工智能公司商汤科技和语音识别开发商科大讯飞各自推出了自己的替代服务，以替代 ChatGPT，后者在中国推出后风靡全球。十一月。阿里巴巴拥有邮政。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，CAC 公布了一套针对类似 ChatGPT 服务的新规则草案。它要求在中国提供生成式人工智能服务的公司采取措施，防止歧视性内容、虚假信息以及损害个人隐私或知识产权的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，北京仍表示支持这一新兴行业的发展。中国共产党的第二大决策机构政治局上个月的季度会议得出结论，中国必须“打造创新生态系统，同时兼顾风险防范”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden and McCarthy reach final deal to prevent default, now must sell to Congress]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222126/biden-and-mccarthy-reach-final-deal-prevent-default-now-must-sell-congress?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 07:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/fd735534-2952-4722-9d4a-ef81c7af1e66_bdefd2c5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登说他和众议院议长凯文·麦卡锡达成了最终协议，避免在周日下午两人再次会谈后，美国历史性违约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们有好消息。我刚刚和议长麦卡锡谈过了。我们有一个两党预算协议，”拜登在白宫告诉记者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他敦促国会两院通过立法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登和麦卡锡现在都必须说服他们的盟友支持该方案，同时平息各自政党左翼和右翼的挫败感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六晚些时候宣布的妥协包括削减开支，但有可能激怒一些立法者，因为他们仔细研究了让步。拜登从特拉华州返回后在白宫告诉记者，他有信心该计划会提交到他的办公桌上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡锡在国会大厦的讲话中也充满信心：“在一天，人们可以齐心协力，通过这一决定。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;未来的日子将决定华盛顿是否能够再次勉强避免美国债务违约，就像它之前多次做的那样，或者是否全球经济陷入潜在危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国，违约可能导致金融市场冻结并引发国际金融危机。分析人士表示，数以百万计的工作岗位将消失，借贷率和失业率将飙升，股市暴跌可能会抹去数万亿美元的家庭财富。这几乎会粉碎 24 万亿美元的美国国债市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;焦虑的退休人员和其他人已经在制定未付支票的应急计划，预计下一次社会保障付款很快就会发生，因为全世界都在关注美国的领导地位受到威胁.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登和麦卡锡“原则上”达成美国债务上限协议&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;麦卡锡和他的谈判代表将该协议描述为为共和党人提供的服务，尽管它远未达到他们寻求的全面削减开支.白宫高级官员正在向民主党立法者通报情况，并直接打电话给一些人以争取支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着周日的拖延，谈判人员努力撰写法案文本，立法者提出了问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡锡周日在国会大厦告诉记者，该协议“并没有得到每个人想要的一切”，但这在分裂的政府中是意料之中的。私下里，他在电话会议上告诉立法者，民主党“一无所获”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在预计 6 月 5 日政府违约美国债务之前，需要双方的支持才能赢得国会的批准。预计立法者最早不会在周二之前从阵亡将士纪念日假期周末返回工作岗位，麦卡锡已向立法者承诺，他将遵守在投票前 72 小时发布任何法案的规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谈判者同意共和党的一些要求，即增加食品券领取者的工作要求，众议院民主党人称这些要求是不可能的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有了协议的大纲，就可以起草立法方案并与立法者分享众议院最早将于周三投票，参议院将于下周晚些时候投票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妥协的核心是一项为期两年的预算协议，该协议将在 2024 年基本保持支出持平，同时提高支出国防和退伍军人，并在 2025 年将上限提高到 1%。同时将债务上限提高两年，将动荡的政治问题推到下届总统选举之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;努力实施更严格的工作要求在接受政府援助的问题上，共和党人取得了一些他们想要的结果。 49 至 54 岁领取食品券援助的人如果身体健全且没有受抚养人，现在必须满足工作要求。拜登能够为退伍军人和无家可归的人争取到豁免权。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登在数小时内表示对美国债务协议“充满希望”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该协议对具有里程碑意义的《国家环境政策法案》进行了修改指定“单一牵头机构”开展环境审查，以期简化流程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;按照共和党人的要求，它停止了一些资金来雇用新的国税局代理人，并撤销了约 300 亿美元用于冠状病毒救助的资金，保留 50 亿美元用于开发下一代 Covid-19 疫苗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在财政部长珍妮特·耶伦告诉国会美国可能在 6 月 5 日（四天）之前违约其债务之后，这笔交易达成了比之前估计的要晚——如果立法者没有及时采取行动的话。提高国家的债务上限（目前为 31 万亿美元）允许更多借贷来支付已经投保的账单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡锡在众议院的共和党人中仅占微弱多数，极右翼保守派可能会拒绝任何交易，因为这不够充分因为他们试图削减开支。通过与民主党人妥协，他冒着失去自己成员支持的风险，为新议长设置一个职业挑战时刻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为你会让大多数共和党人投票支持这项法案”麦卡锡周日在福克斯新闻上说，并补充说因为拜登支持它，“我认为会有很多民主党人也会投票支持它。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院民主党领袖哈基姆杰弗里斯约克在哥伦比亚广播公司的“面向全国”节目中表示，他预计民主党会支持他，但他拒绝提供具体数字。当被问及他是否可以保证不会出现违约时，他说：“是的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，新民主党联盟中 100 人的温和派团体给予了至关重要的支持，他们在一份声明中表示声明相信拜登和他的团队“提出了一个可行的、两党合作的解决方案来结束这场危机”，并正在努力确保该协议将得到双方的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联盟可以为麦卡锡提供足够的支持以弥补他所在政党的右翼成员，他们甚至在该法案的措辞公布之前就表达了反对意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也减轻了拜登的压力，因为拜登因屈服于他们所谓的人质而面临进步派的批评- &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领导国会进步核心小组的华盛顿州民主党女议员普拉米拉·贾亚帕尔告诉哥伦比亚广播公司，白宫和杰弗里斯应该担心核心小组成员是否会支持该协议。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How the former boss of Hong Kong stock exchange is helping Macau connect overseas investors to mainland China’s small businesses]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3222106/how-former-boss-hong-kong-stock-exchange-helping-macau-connect-overseas-investors-chinas-small?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 08:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/28/8e182a1f-510d-49aa-bcd5-33c3bc772bf2_25df0b09.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周应群，28岁湖南人，曾在美业工作在沙龙行业工作了十多年，从没想过有一天他会敲响 IPO 的钟声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但当他作为区域经理工作的美发护理公司 Judy 先生上市了一种全新的安全产品时今年早些时候在澳门，这个害羞的年轻人说他欣喜若狂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我非常非常兴奋。能够参加这样一个意义重大的仪式，我感到非常荣幸和兴奋，”周说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周在 2020 年作为普通员工加入 Judy 先生，有机会帮助公司去年开了一家新店，拥有百分之十的股份。由于没有任何抵押品，周某几乎不可能获得银行贷款，所以周某从前任老板李小佳联合创办的投资平台微连借了剩下的钱来实现这一目标。香港证券交易所运营商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Judy 先生最近成为首批在澳门微通金融资产交易所（MCEX）上市一种名为每日收入义务（DRO）的新金融产品的约 4,000 家公司之一).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MCEX 于 3 月底在前葡萄牙殖民地推出，是第一家获得 DRO 许可的全球交易所，机构投资者可以交易这些 DRO，这些机构投资者的资金流向了小企业——主要是商店和小零售店服装——在中国以换取他们日常收入的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Micro Connect 的使命的核心部分是通过为该国的&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此过程中，它还旨在帮助发展澳门的金融业，因为该市正试图将其重点从博彩业转移到娱乐和创新领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过MCEX，澳门可以在为中国的小微经济引入海外资本方面发挥作用，这符合其发展具有自身特色的金融业的目标，”Micro Connect 企业发展负责人 Samson Cheng 说。 &lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;分析师表示，澳门已被大湾区的香港和深圳、中国东部的上海和新加坡等金融中心包围，旨在将自己定位为促进金融创新的替代目的地，这在其他地方可能是不允许的.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“澳门正在尝试以一种不与香港等现有金融中心直接竞争的方式[发展金融业]走自己的道路，因为它们在各种服务和基础设施方面已经成熟， ”澳门城市大学金融学院院长 Adrian Cheung 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过 MCEX 计划，小型和微型企业（通常适用于员工人数少于 10 人的公司）能够在类似于首次公开募股 (IPO) 的上市中筹集资金，而无需交出其公司的股份或控制权。它的额外好处是让机构投资者能够获得另类投资工具，使他们能够立即获得每日现金收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国有超过 7000 万家小微企业，他们的总数根据 Micro Connect 的数据，每年的资金需求估计在 12 万亿元人民币（1.71 万亿美元）至 13 万亿元人民币之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治中立立场 [及其] 优惠的商业和外贸环境，”香港行政长官贺一诚在本月的 Beyond Expo 技术会议上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的中小企业 (中小企业）总是难以获得资金。尽管当局多年来一直呼吁银行增加对中小企业的融资，但许多人仍然面临这个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国烧烤连锁餐厅汉阳馆的首席运营官段涛表示，该公司一直在关注近几年开始尝试不同的融资方式，例如风险投资和私募股权，但所涉及的过程很漫长。与此同时，银行贷款有严格的还款时间表——这在 Covid-19 的三年期间给承压的小企业带来了沉重压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的上海分行在去年封锁期间关闭了三个月，所以收入为零，”段说。 “如果我们从银行借钱，他们就不会关心我们挣不挣钱。无论如何，我们都必须按时偿还贷款。但是有了 Micro Connect ……在这个意义上，我们都拥有了更大的灵活性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过新的交易所，Micro Connect 能够退出其对某项业务的投资。所谓的 DRC——Micro Connect 与小企业签订的合同——被换成可交易的金融工具，即 DRO，投资者可以在交易所自由买卖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小公司可以发行额外的 DRO 以通过交易所寻求更多资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过 DRO 获得资金并不便宜。根据 Micro Connect 的数据，年度融资成本约为 12% 至 13%，尽管小企业受益于 Micro Connect 分担收入风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Micro Connect 正在努力启动 DRO 市场的下两个阶段这个夏天。附加发行将允许小企业向投资者发行额外的 DRO 股票以筹集更多资金，而二级交易流程将实现类似于任何交易所股票二级交易的功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司计划允许当前渠道中的 70 至 80 家机构投资者（主要是资产管理公司、证券公司、银行和持牌家族办公室）参与市场并开始买卖 DRO。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Micro Connect 是明年通过 DRO 计划将上市企业数量增加两倍，达到 10 万家，通过 MCEX 筹集约 90 亿元至 150 亿元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司希望将该平台的范围扩展到中国以外，进入Cheng表示，未来将在东南亚等地区逐步成为小微企业的主流融资渠道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Cathay Pacific discrimination scandal must herald a bill banning anti-mainland bigotry]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3221918/why-cathay-pacific-discrimination-scandal-must-herald-bill-banning-anti-mainland-bigotry?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/c4f4eed5-bab2-4a91-9e27-615edc0d4d78_05bc586c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;我喜欢新的开始。你要放下所有的情感包袱，让过去的事过去，重新开始。因此，在香港旗舰航空公司国泰航空再次发生丑闻的情况下，可能是时候进行改变了，从一个新名称开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正如首席执行官林绍波在内部会议上所说备忘录指出，国泰航空“必须谦虚反思，深入审视我们的文化，并采取具体措施”从歧视丑闻中恢复过来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空机组人员被指控在最近的一次从成都飞往香港的航班，这一事件迅速从公共关系噩梦演变成政治危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;管理层确实迅速采取行动，发表了大量声明并一再道歉。他们立即解雇了三名违规的机组人员，并回击了国泰航空空乘人员工会，将不良行为归因于士气低落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，很明显，这种情况不会消失。在飞行员被指控“缓慢滑行”以赚取更多报酬后，这只是该航空公司传奇中最新和最具爆炸性的转折。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自马可波罗写下他的故事“国泰之路”以来已有很长时间了.当时的欧洲和阿拉伯旅行者称中国北方为“国泰”，但在今天的香港，这个名字可能会引起麻烦。一个名字最不应该提醒人们的是中国分裂的时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;时代变了，这起歧视丑闻注定要被政治化。行政长官李家超迅速公开表达愤怒和失望，指责国泰机组人员伤害香港和大陆同胞的感情，破坏他所谓的“香港现有的文化和尊重的价值观，礼貌和包容”。李光耀在广州出席粤港合作周开幕式。这发生在对他来说最糟糕的时候。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但我们不应该责怪官员对航空公司造成的压力。保持沉默从来都不是一种选择——政府是该航空公司的股东，在 Covid-19 大流行期间曾使用公共资金救助国泰航空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然该航空公司的高级管理层进行了一些自我反省，香港政府现在被迫面对它长期以来试图粉饰和回避的事情：香港的歧视文化。李先生提到的“尊重、礼貌和包容的城市现有文化和价值观”实际上是一个神话——我们希望拥有的东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看看非华裔少数民族儿童如何一直被剥夺机会教育系统尚未解决语言障碍问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府已向招收非华语学生的学校提供​​更多资助，但正如平等机会委员会去年发现的那样，问题仍然存在。该委员会还一直试图说服政府和立法者修改该市的反歧视法，将“种族内歧视”包括在内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我记得几年前与一位资深政治家的一次艰难谈话，当时该市正准备立法禁止种族歧视。香港人和中国大陆人之间的紧张关系在当时是显而易见的，并且这种紧张关系继续反映在最新的国泰事件的后果中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我问立法如何解决该市对大陆中国人的公然歧视。这位资深政治家的回答让人难以接受：不会——我们是同一个种族，因此他们不会受到保护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们现在可以理解这会让很多人感到多么恼火。我们同属一个种族，但事实仍然是，许多人仍未受到反歧视法例的保护。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;约半数香港人表示城市中普遍存在歧视：调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;即便如此，委员会在推动反对种族歧视的立法时遇到了阻力。沸腾的紧张局势被淡化为“孤立事件”。香港对大陆人的敌意，绝对不符合讲好香港故事的说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会议员简伟文表示，“立法应该是最后的手段”。她说：“如果种族歧视如此严重以至于必须通过立法来解决，那是非常可悲的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;也许最近的国泰丑闻可以说服她和她的同事，现在是时候采取行动了契税。如果现在不采取行动，那将是“相当可悲的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As more Chinese graduates explore rural jobs, comparisons with Mao Zedong’s campaign fail to pass muster]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3222090/more-chinese-graduates-explore-rural-jobs-comparisons-mao-zedongs-campaign-fail-pass-muster?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/28/1eaa822f-494a-4437-b035-f5ab1342a167_5c8372a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在最近的毕业季，Wendy Li 推广了旨在鼓励中国人的政府支持项目&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种以不同的名义开展的运动并不是什么新鲜事，但在广东省珠海市一所大学的学生会工作的本科生李，说今年申请人数增加了两倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们今年似乎变得更有吸引力了，”她说。 “我们学校有 400 名学生，大约有 40 名学生报名了。在过去的几年里，大约有十几个人会这样做。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在就业压力越来越大和国家主席习近平呼吁“振兴农村”以缩小城乡发展差距。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现代举措让人想起毛泽东时代的“下乡”运动，包括广东计划将 30 万大学毕业生送往农村&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据2月份出台的行动计划，毕业生将作为基层干部、企业家或志愿者，为“人才回流、资源回流、项目回流”贡献力量。 ”去年在全省五个相对贫困的城市扩大了在全省范围内每年向农村地区输送至少 2,000 名毕业生的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些举措旨在在严峻的劳动力市场中为年轻人提供更多就业机会，他说广东省政府智库广东改革研究会执行会长彭鹏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前所未有的毕业生数量，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国 16-24 岁年龄段的失业率上个月创下 20.4% 的历史新高，而 3 月份为 19.6%。与此同时，今年将有创纪录的 1158 万大学毕业生——大约相当于比利时的人口数量——进入就业市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些政策的第二个目的是振兴农村，那里的人才和技术是最需要的，”彭说。 “农村地区是中国现代化道路上的薄弱环节，必须振兴农村——最高领导层已将其纳入国家战略。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着青年失业率的恶化，中国 4 月份经济数据的 5 个要点&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;但他表示，此类计划与毛泽东在 1960 年代和 70 年代的运动不同，当时城市地区的数百万年轻人被命令到偏远的农村生活和工作，以打破贫富之间的阶级壁垒。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这可能会让人们记住历史，但现在这不是一场被迫的运动，你是否去取决于你，”他说。 “此外，农村地区只是年轻人的一种选择。这与过去不同，当时人们被迫前往指定区域。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时，这些目的地包括云南省和北大荒——北大荒——中国的一片广阔地区，大部分是农田&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1969 年，十几岁的习近平被下放到陕西省延安农村贫瘠的黄土高原，在那里待了 7 年，后来评论员将他的“下放岁月”视为有助于磨练他作为国家领导人的素质的成年礼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于今天的许多参与者来说，这样的项目更像是从大学到工作的过渡——因为找到一份理想的工作变得更加困难——而不是长期的—— &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 届毕业生李青自今年年初以来一直在江苏省扬州市乡镇政府的乡村振兴计划中工作，她说她正在准备&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“去年毕业的时候有点迷茫，不知道自己到底想要什么，”她说。 “另外，我考研没及格。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以当我看到这个机会时，我认为这可能是一个很好的过渡选择，尤其是在我的家人建议我成为公务员的情况下。”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;每月有“几千元”的住宿费和交通费补贴，她说这份工作至今教会了她“除了做人的方式和政府严谨的工作作风”。&lt;/ p>;&lt;h3>;随着北京推出 15 条计划，毕业生面临“新的障碍和挑战”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我不会向那些想继续学术研究或正在寻找一份全职工作，因为前者没有太多的时间学习，而对于后者来说，这样的经历对他们以后的工作帮助不大，也不会让企业老板看上你在招聘过程中会有所不同，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李说，她所在的珠海大学的大多数参与者将在乡村学校担任教师或志愿者，或者担任村干部，帮助监测人们返贫的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;服务两年后，他们可以选择留下来或到其他地方寻找新工作，她说，并补充说，许多人会选择参加公务员考试，因为他们通过参加竞选获得了额外的资格分数。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“据我所知，很少有人真正像当局希望的那样留在这些村庄定居，”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;人才红利能否使中国保持竞争力人口减少和老龄化？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;广东省省会广州市一所大学的二年级学生 Joan Huang 说，她对此类项目不感兴趣，因为她看不到农村地区的职业前景。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“坦率地说，我认为这项举措只是让人们在基层政府机构的初级职位上做家务，”她说。 “这些地区的经济不好，毕业生几乎不可能创业，除了奶茶店。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“大型基础设施或智能农业可能有机会，但这些&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果你进入本地公司，工资会很低，可能不足以支付你家人的大学学费。如果再回到大城市，农村的工作经验就没用了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的城乡收入差距虽然在过去十年略有改善，但仍然很大。根据国家统计局的数据，去年农村居民的平均可支配收入为 20,133 元（2,853 美元），而城市地区为 49,283 元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;强调中国不可能成为真正的强农不强村，习近平敦促地方政府不仅要吸引大学生，还要吸引外出务工的企业家和农民工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们应该引导毕业生、有能力的人12月召开的全国农村工作会议上，他在全国农村工作会议上说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民大学农业与农村发展学院教授表示，人才是受益于中国产业转移和脱贫攻坚的欠发达地区最需要的资源之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;首先，研究生人数超过本科生即将在北京毕业&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“在中西部地区，一些产业和企业在脱贫攻坚中崛起，有的从深圳、广州等富裕地区转移到那里，”他说。说。 “现在他们需要进一步发展的人才。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于个人来说，生活在小镇可能并不比在大都市更糟糕——一个人在小镇工作可能只需要几个年头就可以买房了。”年。生活质量并不比大城市差。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Janice Wang，28 岁，三年前回到了她在浙江省安吉的家乡——政府加大投资吸引她回到农村，生活成本更低，生活节奏更慢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016 年大学毕业后，她在城里当老师，但在 2020 年搬回老家开始经营民宿。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;虽然刚毕业的大学生很难在农村看到未来，但她说，当教师工作积累了一些积蓄后，在农村创业已成为一个理想且可行的选择。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我们这里有修好的道路、良好的公共设施和新鲜的空气，”王说。 “我每天都会遇到不同的客人。工作并不轻松，但感觉更自由、更快乐。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她不必担心租房或买房，因为她经营的房子是她的家产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “Business is not bad, despite some negative influence from pandemic lockdowns in recent years,” Wang said. “There has been an increasing number of retired people, and they have great demand for travelling and cheap accommodation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So overall, I have much less pressure living this way.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea court approves warrant to arrest man who opened plane emergency exit door]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222124/south-korea-court-approves-warrant-arrest-man-who-opened-plane-emergency-exit-door?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 05:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/52cb3821-ed6a-45af-962a-af873052c474_ba24a38f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A man who opened an emergency exit door during a flight in South Korea was formally arrested on Sunday and faces up to 10 years in prison on a charge of violating the aviation security law, officials said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a preliminary questioning, the 33-year-old told investigators that he felt suffocated and tried to get off the plane quickly, according to police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Sunday, a District Court in Daegu approved a warrant to formally arrest the man. Police earlier sought the arrest warrant, citing the graveness of the crime and a possibility the man may flee, according to Daegu police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Twelve people were slightly injured on Friday after the man opened the door of the Asiana Airlines Airbus A321-200, causing air to blast inside the cabin and terrifying passengers.一些人作证说，他们遭受了严重的耳痛，并看到其他人尖叫和哭泣。 A video shared on social media shows passengers&#39; hair being whipped by air blowing into the cabin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Normally, the emergency exit doors cannot be opened mid-flight due to the difference in air pressure inside and outside the aircraft. But during Friday&#39;s incident, the man succeeded in opening the door, probably because the plane was flying at a low altitude while preparing to land and there was not much difference in pressure, according to Asiana Airlines officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Transport Ministry said the plane was at 700ft (213 metres) when the man pulled the door open.这架载有 200 人的飞机正准备从南部的济州岛起飞，经过一个小时的飞行，降落在大邱。 They included teenage athletes on their way to a track and field competition, according to Asiana Airlines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I wanted to get off the plane soon,” the man, whose face was covered by a black hoodie, a cap and a mask, told reporters at the court ahead of its review of his arrest warrant. “I&#39;m really sorry to kids,” he said, in a likely reference to the teenage athletes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Daegu police said they have up to 20 days to investigate the man before determining whether to send him to prosecutors for a possible indictment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Jobless man who opened Korea plane door mid-air &#39;wanted to get off quickly&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;If convicted, he faces a maximum sentence of 10 years in prison for breaching the aviation security law that bars passengers from handling entry doors, emergency exit doors and other equipment on board, according to the Transport Ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Daegu police said the man, whose surname is Lee, told them that he was under stress after losing a job recently and that he wanted to get out of the plane soon because he was feeling suffocated just before landing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The people who were taken to hospitals were mainly treated for minor problems such as breathing difficulties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asiana Airlines said in a statement that starting from Sunday, it had stopped the sale of emergency exit seats on its 174-seat A321-200 planes and the 195-seat A321-200s as a safety precaution. Lee was seated near the emergency exit, airline officials said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 05:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A tale of two summits: to the G7, China is an economic bully; to Central Asia, it is a vital partner]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3221846/tale-two-summits-g7-china-economic-bully-central-asia-it-vital-partner?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/26/158c4b63-36f4-498c-818d-f4df3cbb77d7_d0578288.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The inaugural China-Central Asia Summit and G7 summit were two of the most prominent international events so far this year. Both kicked off on the same day, May 19, and revolved around China – even though it is not a member of the Group of Seven – and ended up with rather different conclusions about China&#39;s global influence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the G7 summit in Hiroshima, Japan, China&#39;s growing economic might was one of the biggest concerns.公报称，七国集团“将寻求解决中国扭曲全球经济的非市场政策和做法所带来的挑战”； that the G7 will “foster resilience to economic coercion” and “increase our collective assessment, preparedness, deterrence and response to economic coercion”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A separate G7 statement on economic resilience and security spoke of “a disturbing rise in incidents of economic coercion that seek to exploit economic vulnerabilities and dependencies and undermine the foreign and domestic policies and positions of G7 members as well as partners around the world”. It also lamented that economic coercion “undermines the functioning of and trust in the multilateral trading system” and “ultimately undermines global security and stability”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statement did not name China but the accusation was clear. However, when examined closely, the claim may actually fit the United States better, considering the type of “economic coercion” it is capable of: trade wars, sanctions, dollar weaponisation, violations of the international order – the list goes on. Even its allies have fallen victim to its economic coercion, especially in the face of its “America first” policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Inflation Reduction Act is a clear example of US protectionism at the expense of its allies. The European Union, Japan and South Korea have all strongly criticised the legislation – which subsidises American makers of electric cars and batteries, among others – as “discriminatory” and against “international trade rules”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EU continues to negotiate with the US on this, while South Korea has decided to provide billions in financial support for its battery makers to stay competitive in the US – by adding plants there. This is an example of American economic bullying, violation of the principles of free trade and the market economy, and undermining the development of the global economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But does the US care, and think about showing more respect for its allies and the international rules? Washington&#39;s foreign policy has, for years, been based on insisting that others abide by the world order it dominates, while it gets to make exceptions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Were all the other G7 members comfortable with the joint communique on China&#39;s “economic coercion”? After all, they also have valued trade relationships with Beijing. So, perhaps the issue here is not so much China&#39;s economic coercion as America&#39;s delusion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Standing in stark contrast to the G7 summit – which featured accusations aimed at China, but little in the way of substantive deals – was the China-Central Asia Summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the meeting, Chinese President Xi Jinping and his counterparts from five Central Asian countries – Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan – signed the Xian Declaration and adopted a long list of summit outcomes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This included 54 major cooperation consensuses and initiatives, 19 platforms proposed by China for multilateral cooperation and nine documents on multilateral collaboration. The six countries will also establish mechanisms for future meetings at both the leader and ministerial levels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The summit outcomes covered fields such as transport, commerce, investment and industry, agriculture, energy, customs and people-to-people exchanges, and more, as China proposed to expand economic and trade relations, deepen connectivity, increase energy cooperation, promote green innovation, enhance development capabilities, strengthen dialogue and maintain regional peace.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One may argue that most of the initiatives were led by China, but it takes two to tango. Central Asia is crucial to China as an important energy supplier and corridor to Europe. At the same time, China&#39;s strong foreign investments and service export capabilities are needed by Central Asia. In speeches at the summit, Central Asian leaders spoke highly of China&#39;s growing global role and attached much importance to cooperation with Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has become a key force in ensuring global security and stability, and in promoting technological and economic development. This makes cooperation with Beijing indispensable and important in achieving sustainable development. Deepening relations is in line with the fundamental and long-term interests of all six countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;A weakened Russia leaves China with security gaps in Central Asia&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While certain powers regard Central Asia as an arena for geopolitical games, instigating “colour revolutions” and inciting ethnic conflicts and religious disputes, China has always tried to be a trustworthy neighbour and reliable partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing seeks to engage with sincerity, and cooperate based on the principle of mutual benefit. China not only respects the development paths of different countries, but also considers the interests of its partners, with no strings attached to economic cooperation – and will not interfere in their internal affairs. China&#39;s initiatives can bring about tangible benefits and are a win-win result.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the pursuit of well-being and development based on mutual respect and trust, in accordance with the international order, counted as “coercion”, then maybe more countries would happily submit to it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 03:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Turkey’s incumbent Recep Tayyip Erdogan claims victory in presidential run-off; votes still being counted]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222123/turkeys-incumbent-recep-tayyip-erdogan-claims-victory-presidential-run-votes-still-being-counted?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 02:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/212eaae2-a6e4-41b8-8cfc-038e4d80eb82_c7283afe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Turkey&#39;s incumbent President Recep Tayyip Erdogan declared victory on Sunday in his country&#39;s run-off election, extending his increasingly authoritarian rule into a third decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With nearly 99 per cent of ballot boxes opened, unofficial results from competing news agencies showed Erdogan with 52 per cent of the vote, compared with 48 per cent for his challenger, Kemal Kilicdaroglu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his first comments since the polls closed, Erdogan spoke to supporters on a campaign bus outside his home in Istanbul.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I thank each member of our nation for entrusting me with the responsibility to govern this country once again for the upcoming five years,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He ridiculed his challenger for his loss, saying “bye bye bye, Kemal,” as supporters booed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The only winner today is Turkey,” Erdogan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Istanbul, Erdogan supporters began celebrating even before the final results arrived, waving Turkish or ruling party flags, and honking car horns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The outcome could have implications far beyond Ankara. Turkey stands at the crossroads of Europe and Asia, and it plays a key role in Nato.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan&#39;s government vetoed Sweden&#39;s bid to join Nato and bought Russian missile-defence systems, which prompted the United States to oust Turkey from a US-led fighter-jet project. But it also helped broker a crucial deal that allowed Ukrainian grain shipments and averted a global food crisis.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Recep Tayyip Erdogan positioned to extend rule in Turkey run-off election&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The competing news agencies get their data from completed ballot box counts that are gathered by personnel on the field, and are strong in different regions, explaining some of the variation in preliminary data. Turkey&#39;s electoral board sends its own data to political parties throughout the vote count but does not declare official results until days later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan, who has been at Turkey&#39;s helm for 20 years, was favoured to win a new five-year term in the second-round run-off, after coming just short of outright victory in the first round on May 14.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The divisive populist finished four percentage points ahead of Kilicdaroglu (pronounced KEH-lich-DAHR-OH-loo), the candidate of a six-party alliance.埃尔多安的表现是在严重的通货膨胀和三个月前毁灭性地震的影响下实现的。 It was the first time he did not win an election where he ran as a candidate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two candidates offered sharply different visions of the country&#39;s future, and its recent past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This election took place under very difficult circumstances, there was all sorts of slander and defamation,” the 74-year-old Kilicdaroglu told reporters after casting his ballot. “但我相信人们的常识。 Democracy will come, freedom will come, people will be able to wander the streets and freely criticise politicians.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to reporters after casting his vote at a school in Istanbul, Erdogan noted that it is the first presidential run-off election in Turkey&#39;s history.他还赞扬了第一轮的高投票率，并表示他预计周日的参与率会再次高涨。 He voted at the same time as Kilicdaroglu, as local television showed the rivals casting ballots on split screens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I pray to God, that it (the election) will be beneficial for our country and nation,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Critics blame Erdogan&#39;s unconventional economic policies for skyrocketing inflation that has fuelled a cost-of-living crisis. Many also faulted his government for a slow response to the earthquake that killed more than 50,000 people in Turkey.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Turkey braces for momentous run-off election as Erdogan has lead&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the mainly Kurdish-populated province of Diyarbakir – one of 11 regions that was hit by the February 6 earthquake – 60-year-old retiree Mustafa Yesil said he voted for “change”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m not happy at all with the way this country is going.让我明确一点，如果本届政府继续执政，我看不到未来有好事，”他说。 “I see that it will end badly – this administration has to change.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mehmet Yurttas, an Erdogan supporter, disagreed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I believe that our homeland is at the peak, in a very good condition,” the 57-year-old shop owner said. “Our country&#39;s trajectory is very good and it will continue being good.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan has retained the backing of conservative voters who remain devoted to him for lifting Islam&#39;s profile in Turkey, which was founded on secular principles, and for raising the country&#39;s influence in world politics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan, 69, could remain in power until 2028. A devout Muslim, he heads the conservative and religious Justice and Development Party, or AKP.埃尔多安通过 2017 年以微弱优势赢得废除土耳其议会治理制度的公投，将总统职位从一个主要是仪式性的角色转变为一个强大的办公室。 He was the first directly elected president in 2014, and won the 2018 election that ushered in the executive presidency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first half of Erdogan&#39;s tenure included reforms that allowed the country to begin talks to join the European Union, and economic growth that lifted many out of poverty.但他后来采取行动压制自由和媒体，并将更多权力集中在自己手中，尤其是在土耳其称其政变未遂后，政变是由驻美国的伊斯兰神职人员法图拉·葛兰策划的。 The cleric denies involvement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan&#39;s rival is a soft-mannered former civil servant who has led the pro-secular Republican People&#39;s Party, or CHP, since 2010. Kilicdaroglu campaigned on promises to reverse Erdogan&#39;s democratic backsliding, to restore the economy by reverting to more conventional policies, and to improve ties with the West.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a frantic effort to reach out to nationalist voters in the run-off, Kilicdaroglu vowed to send back refugees and ruled out peace negotiations with Kurdish militants if he is elected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A defeat for Kilicdaroglu would add to a long list of electoral losses to Erdogan, and put pressure on him to step down as party chairman.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Iraq bid to link Asia and Europe in US$17 billion road and rail project&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Erdogan&#39;s AKP party and its allies retained a majority of seats in parliament following a legislative election that was held on May 14.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sunday also marked the 10th anniversary of the start of mass anti-government protests that broke out over plans to uproot trees in Istanbul&#39;s Gezi Park, and became one of the most serious challenges to Erdogan&#39;s government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan&#39;s response to the protests, in which eight people were convicted for alleged involvement, was a harbinger of a crackdown on civil society and freedom of expression.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following the May 14 vote, international observers pointed to the criminalisation of dissemination of false information and online censorship as evidence that Erdogan had an “unjustified advantage.” They also said that strong turnout showed the resilience of Turkish democracy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Erdogan and pro-government media portrayed Kilicdaroglu, who received the backing of the country&#39;s pro-Kurdish party, as colluding with “terrorists” and of supporting what they described as “deviant” LGBTQ rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kilicdaroglu “receives his orders from Qandil,” Erdogan repeatedly said at recent campaign rallies, a reference to the mountains in Iraq where the leadership of the outlawed Kurdistan Workers&#39; Party, or PKK, is based.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The election was held as the country marked the 100th anniversary of its establishment as a republic, following the collapse of the Ottoman Empire.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 02:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia condemns US senator’s comments on the death of Russians]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3222122/russia-condemns-us-senators-comments-death-russians?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 01:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/a841b321-2e70-41e1-af7b-ddd474df0b10_a26db3b5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Russia on Sunday condemned US Senator Lindsey Graham for telling Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky during a visit to Kyiv that US support for Ukraine was the best money Washington had ever spent and that “the Russians are dying”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a meeting on Friday, Zelensky told Graham that “now we are free”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“And the Russians are dying,” Graham said, according to a video supplied by the Ukrainian presidential press service.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the next part of the video edit, Graham says with a smile: “It&#39;s the best money we&#39;ve ever spent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The exact chronology of Graham&#39;s remarks was unclear from the video supplied by the Ukrainian presidential press service.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Ukrainian president&#39;s office did not immediately reply on Sunday to a request for a full transcript of Graham&#39;s remarks at the meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia condemned Graham&#39;s comments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is difficult to imagine a greater shame for a country than having such senators,” Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov was quoted as saying by the Shot Telegram channel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russian Security Council deputy chairman Dmitry Medvedev called Graham, a 67-year-old Republican, an old fool.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Backlash as US lawmaker urges Russians to &#39;take out&#39; Putin to end Ukraine war&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The old fool Senator Lindsey Graham said that the United States has never spent money so successfully as on the murder of Russians,” said Medvedev, who served as Russia&#39;s president from 2008 to 2012 and as prime minister from 2012 and 2020. “He shouldn&#39;t have done that.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As usual the Russia propaganda machine is hard at work,” Graham told Reuters in an emailed statement on Sunday, referring to Medvedev&#39;s comments about his Kyiv visit, which he had used to urge Washington to send more weapons to Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Graham said he had mentioned to Zelensky “that Ukraine has adopted the American mantra, &#39;Live Free or Die.&#39; It has been a good investment by the United States to help liberate Ukraine from Russian war criminals.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: “Mr Medvedev, if you want Russians to stop dying in Ukraine, withdraw. Stop the invasion. Stop the war crimes. The truth is that you and (President Vladimir) Putin could care less about Russian soldiers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian presidential adviser Mykhailo Podolyak said in Twitter comments on Sunday that the best investment the United States and the West could make was “in a complete and unconditional victory of Ukraine.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 01:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UK government to ask supermarkets to cap prices of basic food items as cost of essentials continues to rise]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222121/uk-government-ask-supermarkets-cap-prices-basic-food-items-cost-essentials-continues-rise?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 01:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/2370d246-4ad8-4d89-ba80-be3675fc41cb_ffeb7648.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The British government is looking at plans to have retailers cap the prices of basic food items such as bread and milk, the Telegraph newspaper reported, as the cost of such essentials continued to rise in the double digits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, asked about such price controls, health minister Steve Barclay told BBC TV it was “not my understanding” on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prime Minister Rishi Sunak&#39;s government is in talks with supermarkets on a deal similar to one in France where major retailers charge the “lowest possible amount”, the Telegraph reported on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PM&#39;s office did not respond to Reuters&#39; request for comment on the report, which cited sources within the government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My understanding is that the government is working constructively with supermarkets as to how we address the very real concerns around food inflation and the cost of living and doing so in a way that is also very mindful to the impact on suppliers,” Barclay told the BBC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Britain has western Europe&#39;s highest rate of inflation for food, with prices up more than 19 per cent over the past year, the worst such run since the 1970s. Household budgets have also been strained by surging energy prices, driven higher partly by the war in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UK Post Office used racist slur to describe black, Asian suspects in scandal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Major supermarkets such as Tesco and Sainsbury&#39;s have announced price cuts on some food items in recent weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The British Retail Consortium (BRC), which represents all the major supermarkets, blamed the government&#39;s new regulation for many of the costs, and urged it in a statement to simplify rules “rather than recreating 1970s-style price controls.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This will not make a jot of difference to prices. High food prices are a direct result of the soaring cost of energy, transport, and labour, as well as higher prices paid to food manufacturers and farmers,” BRC&#39;s Andrew Opie said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Jewish groups and city officials protest against Roger Waters concert in Frankfurt]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222120/jewish-groups-and-city-officials-protest-against-roger-waters-concert-frankfurt?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 00:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/31a826e3-ff94-428c-b41a-d282b9473a88_9be52c56.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Several Jewish groups, politicians and an alliance of civil society groups gathered for a memorial ceremony and a protest rally against a concert by Roger Waters in Frankfurt, Germany on Sunday evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They accuse the Pink Floyd co-founder of antisemitism – an allegation he denies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Waters has also drawn their ire for his support of the BDS movement, which calls for boycotts and sanctions against Israel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Frankfurt authorities had initially tried to prevent the concert taking place, but Waters successfully challenged the move in a local court.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The concert is taking place in the city&#39;s Festhalle, where in November 1938 more than 3,000 Jews were rounded up by the Nazis, beaten and abused, and later deported to concentration camps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Against this historical background, the concert should not have taken place under any circumstances,” said Sacha Stawski, a member of the Frankfurt Jewish community and head of the group Honestly Concerned, that helped organise the protests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s very frustrating” that the concert is going ahead as scheduled even though Frankfurt officials and many others tried to prevent it, Elio Adler, the head of the Jewish group WerteInitiative which supports the protest, told Associated Press.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“His words and imagery spread Jew-hatred and are part of a trend: to normalise Israel-hatred under the protection of freedom of speech or art,” Adler added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Pink Floyd&#39;s Roger Waters cancels Poland concerts after Ukraine war remarks&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Last week, police in Berlin said they had opened an investigation of Waters on suspicion of incitement over a costume the Pink Floyd co-founder wore when he performed in the German capital earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Images on social media showed Waters firing an imitation machine gun while dressed in a long black coat with a red armband. Police confirmed that an investigation was opened over suspicions that the context of the costume could constitute a glorification, justification or approval of Nazi rule and therefore a disturbance of the public peace.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Waters rejected those accusations in a statement on Facebook and Instagram, saying that “the elements of my performance that have been questioned are quite clearly a statement in opposition to fascism, injustice, and bigotry in all its forms.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He claimed that “attempts to portray those elements as something else are disingenuous and politically motivated.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During Sunday&#39;s ceremony and protests, which took place in front of the Frankfurt concert venue before Waters&#39; concert was set to begin, protesters read out loud the names of 600 Jews who were rounded up at the Festhalle on November 9, 1939, the so-called Kristallnacht – the “Night of Broken Glass” – when Nazis terrorised Jews throughout Germany and Austria.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The organisers also held a joint Jewish-Christian prayer for the victims of the Nazi terror in Frankfurt. The city&#39;s mayor as well as the head of the local Jewish community were set to speak at the protest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, some of the around 400 protesters handed out fliers to concertgoers and waved Israeli flags. Others held up banners with slogans such as “Israel, we stand with you” or “Roger Waters, wish you were not here” in reference to Pink Floyd&#39;s famous song Wish You Were Were, German news agency dpa reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Protesters in Munich rallied against a concert by Waters earlier this month, after the city council said it had explored possibilities of banning the performance but concluded that it was not legally possible to cancel a contract with the organiser.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, the Polish city of Krakow cancelled Waters&#39; gigs because of his sympathetic stance toward Russia in its war against Ukraine.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 00:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>