<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Indian tourists flock to Southeast Asia as China’s reopening falters]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3227934/indian-tourists-flock-southeast-asia-chinas-reopening-falters?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 11:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/fb1e3d66-3d15-4318-a2cf-4b26ded6f7b6_0cdb5ee2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度游客涌入东南亚，巩固了这个世界上人口最多国家的地位印度是旅行和旅游行业的主要增长市场，该行业正感受到中国重新开放速度慢于预期的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从靛蓝航空和泰国航空等航空公司到提供数千间客房的连锁酒店，企业正在利用印度的市场高管和分析师表示，新兴的中产阶级和不断增长的消费能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;航空分析师布伦丹·索比 (Brendan Sobie) 表示：“东南亚显然处于非常有利的位置，可以承受印度带来的大部分增长。”上个月举行的一次行业会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅行和旅游业对几个东南亚经济体至关重要，在 Covid-19 大流行之前约占该地区国内生产总值的 12%。根据经济合作与发展组织的数据，它还为该地区超过 4000 万人口提供了就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么新加坡和东南亚等待中国游客回国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对于大约十年来，该行业一直受到中国的推动，但四个东南亚国家的官方数据显示复苏乏力，5 月份中国游客数量比 2019 年同月至少减少 60%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;印度游客的长期增长将导致航空公司运力、酒店服务和旅游运营商的重新调整——据行业成员称，这种迹象已经显现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度可能成为下一个亚洲开发银行 (ADB) 在 5 月份的一份报告中表示，未来十年中国“在出境旅游增长方面”，尽管连通性将受到那里机场较少的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度可能会成为故事&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在旅游业作为经济支柱的泰国，印度游客的数量尽管绝对数量少于中国游客– 仅比 2019 年下降约 14%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据统计，2019 年，中国游客每天在泰国的花费约为 197 美元，印度游客每天的花费约为 180 美元，两人都在泰国停留了大约一周泰国政府数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国旅游局副局长 Tanes Petsuwan 表示，预计今年将有 160 万印度人前往泰国旅游。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月份，印度人数量超过中国人同月，有近 63,000 名印度人访问了新加坡，而访问印度尼西亚的印度人仅超过 64,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度航线非常强大，”泰国航空公司首席执行官 Chai Eamsiri 表示，该航空公司每年执飞 14 趟航班。每周有 70 架飞机飞往中国（疫情爆发前约为 40 架），每周有 70 架飞机飞往印度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;未来十年，泰国窄体飞机机队规模可能翻倍，其中一部分将部署到印度，Chai 表示。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度廉价航空公司靛蓝航空已订购 500 架空客窄体喷气式飞机以满足该地区的需求，该公司表示，印度和东南亚之间的航线“强劲增长”，每周执飞 100 多个航班.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将在 8 月份推出飞往雅加达的航班，以及飞往新加坡的更多航班，”靛蓝航空全球销售主管维奈·马尔霍特拉 (Vinay Malhotra) 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总体而言，座位数按计划安排索比说，截至 6 月，中国和东南亚之间的航班比新冠疫情爆发前的水平下降了 57%，但从印度飞往该地区的航班已恢复至 90% 左右。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度人正在帮助维持一个职位- 连锁酒店业的疫情反弹，其中包括美诺酒店 (Minor Hotels)，该公司在东南亚拥有 45 家酒店，拥有 6,000 多间客房。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度市场一直是我们的主要客源市场之一，”首席执行官 Dillip Rajakarier 表示，补充说，这家连锁酒店（在曼谷上市的 Minor International 的一部分）加强了在印度的营销力度。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;6 月，Pratyush Tripathy 和四位朋友乘坐了一辆二加一的航班。 - 从印度城市加尔各答飞往曼谷的半小时航班，享受为期五天的假期，大部分时间在芭堤雅海滩度假村及其周边地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次旅行的费用在 40,000 至 60,000 印度卢比（484 美元）之间Tripathy 表示，每人 726 美元，大约相当于飞往欧洲的航班费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 33 岁的软件专业人士在解释他们的决定时说道：“这会节省您的时间和金钱。”访问东南亚，印度人通常比欧洲国家和美国更容易获得签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年 1 月至 6 月，从印度飞往曼谷的航班预订量比去年同期增长了 270%据印度在线旅游门户网站 Cleartrip 称，2019 年同期为 2019 年同期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国游客选择留在国内，削弱东南亚经济复苏&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;泰国央行预计今年游客数量将达到 2900 万人次，到 2024 年，这一数字将达到 3550 万。这仍然低于 2019 年近 4000 万的创纪录水平，但泰国央行预测，该行业将有助于推动 2023 年整体经济增长至 3.6%，明年增长至 3.8%，而同期增长率为 2.6%。泰国旅游理事会副主席 Somsong Sachaphimukh 表示，到 2022 年，泰国旅游业必须了解印度人的偏好，特别是在食品和娱乐方面的偏好，才能从这一激增中获利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“如果我们不迅速调整，邻国将会吸引这些游客，”索姆松说。 “泰国有很多东西可以提供，所以这是一个很大的机会。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Ong Beng Seng got caught up in Singapore corruption probe: 6 weekend reads you may have missed]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3227932/how-ong-beng-seng-got-caught-singapore-corruption-probe-6-weekend-reads-you-may-have-missed?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 10:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/07a5f3d7-a862-42f0-8fcc-9335dcd8bcf3_ee62b806.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;我们从上周末报道的香港、中国大陆、更广泛的亚洲地区及其他地区与我们的读者产生共鸣，并阐明了热门问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果您想查看我们的更多报道，请考虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;中国最早的文明迹象可以追溯到几千年前，许多古老的文化和政治传统至今仍然存在。但新出现的证据帮助研究人员在早期人类活动与中国文明的根源之间建立了更长的连续性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此处阅读完整的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ong近来卷入新加坡最引人注目的腐败调查的亿万富翁明成（Beng Seng）并不缺乏最高级的说法：他是这个城市国家最富有的大亨之一，是一级方程式特许经营权所有者俱乐部的大人物，并且一直是四十多年来，他一直是东南亚的权势人物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这里阅读完整的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这位艺术家创作了多幅金鱼画，据说是受到他在摩洛哥的时光的启发，但他看到的中国艺术或陶器可能是催化剂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这里阅读完整的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这是他们的该国首次参加全球男子或女子足球赛事，球员们意识到了其影响，包括对海外菲律宾人的影响&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此处阅读完整的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;香港同性恋运动会的组织者面临着一些外国官员和参赛者的压力，他们表示将远离 11 月的赛事，以避免“意外”违反香港严格的国家安全法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阅读完整故事在这里。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们答应了！”前议员叶秀惠上个月在 Facebook 上发表了一篇欢乐的帖子，宣布她在槟城与亚特兰大的伴侣订婚。越来越多的马来西亚人居住在海外，享受同性关系，远离该国保守派的反对。她是其中之一。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这里阅读完整的故事。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 10:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: Black Sea grain deal in peril; Crimean bridge faces ‘emergency’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3227937/ukraine-war-black-sea-grain-deal-peril-crimean-bridge-faces-emergency?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 10:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/86c7d5b5-6b63-488e-940e-24f8a994bf16_98bfd82d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周一，允许乌克兰出口谷物的协议已经过去了经黑海，该协议将于伊斯坦布尔时间午夜（格林尼治标准时间 2100）到期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊斯坦布尔会谈没有任何消息，土耳其和联合国官员正在试图说服俄罗斯同意再次延期该协议于 2022 年 7 月首次在那里签署。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，黑海谷物倡议已帮助乌克兰出口超过 3200 万吨谷物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但由于俄罗斯迄今为止拒绝续签协议，交通已经停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些申请尚未得到各方批准，”联合协调中心的一份声明说（ JCC）负责监督该协议。 “自 6 月 27 日以来，尚未批准任何新船参加。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议签署方（乌克兰、俄罗斯、土耳其和联合国）批准的最后一艘货船是土耳其散货船 TQ Samsun 号。周日晚间，海上交通网站显示，该船从乌克兰敖德萨港穿过黑海前往伊斯坦布尔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，土耳其总统雷杰普·塔伊普·埃尔多安对再次续签该协议的前景表示乐观。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他声称自己和俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京在此事上意见一致的说法并未在莫斯科得到回应，克里姆林宫发言人很快表示，他们没有发表过这样的声明。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;普京多次威胁要退出该协议，认为该协议中允许俄罗斯食品和化肥出口的条款没有得到遵守。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该协议的主要目标，即周六，他在与南非总统西里尔·拉马福萨 (Cyril Ramaphosa) 的电话交谈中表示，向包括非洲大陆在内的有需要的国家供应粮食的计划尚未落实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 JCC 的数据，中国和土耳其是粮食运输的主要受益者，也是发达经济体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议帮助世界粮食计划署为阿富汗、苏丹和也门等面临严重粮食短缺的国家提供救济。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;“球在普京这边”：中国敦促俄罗斯推动俄罗斯续签乌克兰粮食协议&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这有助于解释为什么联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯一直在努力争取续签该协议。他支持消除俄罗斯化肥出口的障碍，并于周二就此问题向普京致信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他上周还会见了欧盟高级官员，讨论了他们对俄罗斯实施制裁的影响。它对乌克兰的入侵。但尚未就他们的会谈发表公开声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;由于“紧急情况”，连接克里米亚半岛和俄罗斯克拉斯诺达尔地区的俄罗斯建造的克里米亚大桥交通中断。 ” 俄罗斯安装的州长谢尔盖·阿克肖诺夫 (Sergei Aksyonov) 周一早些时候在 Telegram 消息应用程序上写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿克肖诺夫表示，紧急情况发生在克拉斯诺达尔地区大桥的第 145 根支柱上。他没有提供任何进一步的细节，但确实要求人们不要在桥上行驶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰皇家银行报道称，桥上听到爆炸声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯格雷通讯社Zone 频道是瓦格纳雇佣兵组织旗下一个备受关注的 Telegram 频道，报道称，凌晨 03:04（格林威治标准时间 0004）和凌晨 03:20 发生了两次桥梁袭击事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社无法独立报道核实报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰没有立即发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里米亚于2014年被俄罗斯从乌克兰吞并，但国际上承认它是乌克兰的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;这座 12 英里（19 公里）长的公路和铁路桥在去年 10 月的一次爆炸中受损，克里姆林宫称这次袭击是由乌克兰安全部队策划的。几个月后，乌克兰才间接承认发动了这次袭击。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 10:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China GDP: economy grew by 6.3 per cent in second quarter amid recovery fears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3227936/china-gdp-economy-grew-63-cent-second-quarter-amid-recovery-fears?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 10:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/30648d70-b911-491f-9ce2-52b4c56360bb_f6d94ab8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;2023年第二季度中国经济同比增长6.3%根据周一发布的官方数据，在北京努力促进冠状病毒大流行后的复苏之际。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;增长率低于中国数据提供商 Wind 预测的 6.8%，但高于 4.5% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国已将 2023 年经济增长目标定在 5% 左右。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家统计局周一发布的其他数据显示6月份零售额同比增长3.1%，低于5月份的12.7%增幅。这低于 Wind 预测的 3.5% 的增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工业生产（衡量制造业、采矿业和公用事业部门活动的指标）上个月同比增长 4.4%，高于上个月的预测。 5月份增长3.5%。这高于 Wind 预测的 2.5% 的增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;固定资产投资（北京推动经济增长的传统工具）在 2023 年前六个月同比增长 3.8% ，较今年前五个月的 4% 增幅有所下降。这高于Wind预测的3.3%的增长率。&lt;/​​p>;&lt;p>;同时，6月份16-24岁年龄段的失业率创下21.3%的新高，高于5月份的20.8%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上月城镇总体调查失业率保持在5.2%不变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更多内容敬请关注……&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Typhoon Talim: Hong Kong at standstill with first T8 signal of year to remain in force until 4pm at least]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227933/typhoon-talim-hong-kong-standstill-first-no-8-signal-year-remain-force-until-4pm-least?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 09:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/17/cacc7550-1a68-46bf-89c7-6c4a5e0339cd_5ef99bc7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港今年首个台风于周一早上让香港陷入瘫痪，股市当天休市，旅客在机场面临航班延误和取消的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港天文台还警告称，风暴潮可能导致低洼地区发生水浸。香港天气预报员于周一早些时候发布了 8 号信号，该信号将至少持续到下午 4 点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至上午 9 点，台风塔利姆已在香港西南偏南约 260 公里处集中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;h3>;台风达林逼近，香港发出今年首个T8信号&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在台风带来的风暴潮和大潮的共同影响下，水位高达约三米或以上预报员称，预计大澳将于早上出现上述海图数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“高水位可能会导致低洼地区发生水浸。公众应避免前往可能受影响的低洼地区，并远离危险地点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“海面波涛汹涌，汹涌澎湃。请远离海岸线，不要进行水上运动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;股市公告称，如果8号信号在中午之后持续，将不会进行交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港热带风暴“塔利姆”逼近，台风警报升至三号&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;机管局表示，至少16架航班取消，另有6架航班延误，主要飞往中国大陆的航线受到影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社区方面，虽然大部分学校已开始放暑假，但全日制课程已停课。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民政事务总署今早在各区设立的29个避难所共有92人避难。当局亦接获三宗树木倒塌报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除公立医院的紧急服务外，所有普通科及专科诊所均已关闭，医院管理局呼吁病人重新预约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;所有法庭及审裁处聆讯均押后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城巴、九巴及龙运巴士营运的所有日间巴士路线均暂停，惟少数提供有限度服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;港铁及轻铁服务的运行频率有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高铁正在运行，但由于塔利姆（他加禄语中的意思是“锐利”）带来的恶劣天气，可能会在短时间内暂停。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India-China relations: Modi, Xi look set to meet. Will frosty ties thaw at BRICS, G20 summits?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3227684/india-china-relations-modi-xi-look-set-meet-will-frosty-ties-thaw-brics-g20-summits?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/aed5bfd2-8f31-4ce0-b30b-1c0bd59f3209_8b0bd4a5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;几个月内，印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪和中国国家主席习近平都可能再次共处一室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但两国领导人是否会举行双边会谈并寻求修复两国严重紧张的关系还有待观察。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;令人怀疑的印度外交政策观察人士指出，新德里在最后一刻决定将本月的上海合作组织 (SCO) 峰会改为线上会议，从而消除了莫迪与习近平在场边会晤的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国领导人都将出席金砖国家峰会8 月 22 日至 24 日在约翰内斯堡举行，两周后在德里举行 G20 领导人峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，自 2019 年巴西金砖国家峰会以来，莫迪和习近平尚未​​进行外交接触。相比之下，尽管关系非常紧张，习近平在过去两年里已经两次会见了美国总统乔·拜登，第三次会面似乎正在筹备中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪和习近平之间的会面变得越来越重要，分析人士表示，在两国持续不断的边境对峙和外交冲突中，尽管这两个拥有核武器的邻国继续用军队、重型火炮和包括轻型高空坦克在内的基础设施来加固实际控制线，但两国的态度却变得更强硬。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据外交政策观察家的说法，军事指挥官之间的会谈尚未取得成果，他们现在正在密切关注领导人之间的坚冰是否最终会在即将举行的大型峰会上打破。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两国领导人最近缺乏面对面的接触，这与他们之前的友情形成鲜明对比——从 2014 年莫迪就任总理到 2020 年 6 月，他们举行了 18 次会面，并在2018 年和 2019 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度和中国军队在加勒万河谷（印度拉达克附近有争议的边境地区的一部分）发生冲突，导致双边会晤停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BR Deepak贾瓦哈拉尔·尼赫鲁大学的中国和中国研究教授表示，莫迪和习近平在下个月金砖国家峰会期间举行会晤的可能性“非常高”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迪帕克说，这样的会晤，可能会启动谈判以解决对峙。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中印“断交”可能会加剧有争议边界的“不满之夏”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我相信，如果军队之间脱离接触如果发生这种情况，并且有关摩擦点的谈判仍在继续，这可能会为习近平的未来访问（前往印度参加 G20 峰会）铺平道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度退役海军准将 RS Vasan 指出，人们对印度也有类似的期望最近的上合组织峰会在虚拟化之前举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们预计习近平将访问印度，双边关系方面的紧张局势将会有所缓解，”金奈现任总干事瓦桑说。中国研究中心。 “但这些期望已经[受到抑制]。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这两个亚洲巨人之间的关系最近已经出现裂痕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在本月的会议上在上合组织峰会上，印度是唯一反对习近平推动全球贸易增长的“一带一路”基础设施建设的国家，据报道，印度还拒绝签署《上合组织2030年经济发展战略》，因为它“警惕”“过多提及中国的口号和内容”。战略中的“外交政策”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者们陷入了紧张的紧张局势之中，印度媒体报道称，最后一名在印中国记者因签证未续签而被“驱逐”，而至少三名记者则被“驱逐”。据报道，驻北京的印度记者被禁止留在中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;火上浇油的是，印度上周就 2016 年拒绝北京“九段线”的仲裁裁决表示支持菲律宾&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后是莫迪 6 月份在美国国会的讲话，他在讲话中谈到“胁迫和对抗的乌云”给该地区蒙上了阴影，但没有公开点名中国.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪还于 7 月 6 日致电达赖喇嘛，祝愿这位流亡的西藏精神领袖 88 岁生日快乐 — — 许多人认为此举是为了刺激北京。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度这么说希望其记者能够继续在中国工作&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Gateway House 智库的杰出研究员拉吉夫·巴蒂亚 (Rajiv Bhatia) 表示，这些事件的爆发降低了人们对莫迪与习近平会面的乐观情绪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴蒂亚表示，尽管关系紧张，但依赖多边合作的旧做法“正在显示出局限性并遇到困难”。他指出，去年在巴厘岛举行的 G20 峰会上，两国领导人握手但选择不举行会谈。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“我认为（德里）没有信心在上合组织峰会期间举行面对面的双边会晤可能有助于双边关系。事实上，这甚至可能会让事情变得复杂。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度前大使巴蒂亚进一步指出，在将金砖国家论坛扩大到包括阿根廷、埃及和印度尼西亚等国家方面，双方的做法存在“分歧”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“中国人希望领先，但印度希望确保金砖国家的凝聚力和巩固不会因其突然扩张而受到影响，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;与此同时，沿着实际控制线，紧张局势已经加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伦敦智库查塔姆研究所 6 月份的一份报告发现，在有争议的阿克赛钦地区，“对印度的战略威胁有所增加”。拉达克地区，注意到人民解放军营地、四通八达的道路网络和直升机停机坪的存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于印度来说，这意味着其武装部队现在必须与大规模且可能是半永久性的军队相匹配。报告称，中国在阿克赛钦边境沿线的存在可能会持续数年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，拉达克议员孔乔克·斯坦津 (Konchok Stanzin) 在推特上声称，中国军队搭建了四个帐篷，其中三个是后来被移除，位于作为该地区部队脱离接触协议一部分而设立的“缓冲区”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;最近的中印边境冲突是否是未来暴力升级的开始？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在在德里，许多人担心悬而未决的边境对峙可能会给习近平参加印度 G20 峰会蒙上阴影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于政府来说，没有中国参加的 G20 峰会将是外交损失，但有习近平参加印度首都一位不愿透露姓名的智库专家表示，印度军队正陷入对峙，这对德里的国内政治来说是一个糟糕的预兆。他补充说，莫迪政府需要在边境取得突破G20 会议前的对峙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;智囊团专家巴蒂亚 (Bhatia) 表示，他对边界争端很快得到解决并不“乐观”，但指出中国自身的外交政策强迫这意味着习近平无论如何都有可能参加 G20 峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国可能不希望被孤立于 G20 之外。如果俄罗斯和中国不出席，那么他们担心 G20 将被允许继续推进其议程。”他补充道，目前尚不清楚俄罗斯领导人弗拉基米尔·普京是否也会出席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迪帕克教授警告说，习近平出席 G20 峰会虽然有帮助，但可能不会立即改善双边关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鉴于印度双边和国际参与的动态，印中关系不会恢复到正常水平。”在短期或中期，同样的均衡，”迪帕克说。 “双方必须管理和控制分歧，从而最大限度地减少冲突的可能性。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Just earn a little less’: Hong Kong cabbie impresses mainland Chinese tourist short on cash by waiving part of fare]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3227629/just-earn-little-less-hong-kong-cabbie-impresses-mainland-chinese-tourist-short-cash-waiving-part?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/14/f7e4519e-2c0c-4c48-b49d-4a332d5e6921_ad251506.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个关于香港出租车司机带一名内地女子去旅游的温馨故事尽管她没有足够的现金支付全额票价，但她还是选择了自己想要的目的地，这引起了其他前往这座城市的旅行者的共鸣，促使他们分享他们愉快的经历。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近有报道称，积极情绪的爆发是在当地人与在新冠大流行期间关闭边境三年后回国的大陆游客之间的紧张关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地人抱怨大陆游客行为粗鲁，抬高价格并造成交通拥堵，而一些大陆人则表示，他们一直在担心大陆游客的行为。因说普通话而受到歧视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月，香港国泰航空公司解雇了三名机组人员，他们被指控歧视一名不会说英语的内地乘客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乘坐出租车的女子她在内地社交媒体平台小红书上发帖称，她于7月1日到香港参加韩国流行歌手郑容和的演唱会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在以下时间打了一辆出租车前往西九龙站当天乘高铁返回中国大陆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，在与丈夫乘坐出租车时，她意识到自己几乎花光了所有现金，只剩下 17 港元（2.2 美元）。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她问出租车司机：“我可以只付现金吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;司机确认只收现金后，她立即道歉并建议他要么让他们出去几百米后，或者，如果他带他们到自动取款机，这样她就可以取款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;令她惊讶的是，她以为司机会感到沮丧或生气，却让她放心了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“没关系。距离不算太远，如果你不登机的话我就一分钱也赚不到。所以我就少赚一点，”他告诉那位女士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“司机真的很好。看到我着急，他还安慰我，询问行程怎么样。”她在帖子中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了表达谢意，她和丈夫送给了司机两个在网上买的菠萝包。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当出租车到达西九龙站时，车费已达到港币 49 元，“比港币 17 元贵很多”，她在帖子中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;她还准备要司机的银行账号给他转钱，幸好西九龙有ATM机，她就提取现金支付了车费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港这次遇到的香港人都很友善。在整个旅程中我说普通话没有任何问题。我会再来。”该女士说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的故事在社交媒体上引起了许多人的共鸣，他们分享了在香港的积极旅行经历。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人说：“我上周与一位友善的出租车司机有过类似的美好经历。我只有一堆硬币和一张500港元的纸币。当我们接近目的地时，我开始一边查计价器一边数零钱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“司机告诉我用我有的零钱付款。还好我零钱够多，他还免了我的行李费。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有人说：“有一次我因为着急，乘飞机时误拿了一张屈臣氏会员卡，而不是我的八达通卡。”一辆公交车。我身上只有100港元现金，但巴士司机并没有向我收费。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三个人也表示同意：“我前几天在香港，遇到的每个人都很好。晚上九点多阿姨还带我们去了金紫荆广场。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s foreign policy chief Wang Yi tells India border dispute should not define relationship]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227899/chinas-foreign-policy-chief-wang-yi-tells-india-border-dispute-should-not-define-relationship?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/16/b138bfb7-4643-42ea-9463-df7e388008e8_0599ed02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国最高外交官王毅敦促印度放宽对中国投资的限制，并补充说诸如持续的边境对峙等问题“不应定义两国之间的整体关系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅在一次区域会议期间与印度外交部长苏杰生会面时发出上述呼吁外交部长在印度尼西亚首都雅加达举行会议，并补充说，新德里应聚焦“共同利益”，与中国“相向而行”，以化解边境紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管人们期望纳伦德拉·莫迪总理和中国国家主席习近平下个月将在约翰内斯堡和 9 月在新德里面对面会晤，自 2020 年 6 月在有争议的喜马拉雅边境发生致命冲突以来，两国一直陷入军事对峙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管过去三年举行了数十次军事会谈，今年也进行了多次高层交往，但几乎没有迹象表明双方准备在这个高度紧张的问题上做出让步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪上个月访问白宫期间承诺加强与华盛顿的军事关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 6 月 25 日以来一直淡出公众视野的外交部长秦刚缺席了东南亚国家联盟 (ASEAN) 会议。据中国外交部称，印度尼西亚出于“健康原因”。秦的前任、现任习近平的最高外交政策助手王先生接替了他。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度是否会放弃南海立场，支持马尼拉海牙裁决？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周五的最新会议外交部声明称，这次会议是应印方要求举行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中印作为世界前两个发展中国家和永远的邻居，共同利益明显大于分歧，实现共同利益王说，发展和繁荣具有全球示范意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，两国应该“相互支持、相互成就”，而不是“相互猜疑”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道：“我们应该把精力和资源集中在各自的发展、改善民生和加快振兴上，而不是让具体问题决定整体关系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而印度则坚持必须完成边境部队的脱离接触在关系恢复正常之前，北京表示双方应该超越当前的争端。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王说，印度应该“与中国相向而行，找到双方都能接受的边界问题解决方案”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明称，双方同意尽快就边界问题举行下一轮军长级会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王还表示，北京方面“高度关注” India&#39;s restrictions on Chinese companies and “hopes that the Indian side will provide a fair, transparent and non-discriminatory business environment for Chinese enterprises”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the deadly border clash in 2020, India has ramped up scrutiny of Chinese investments and issued sweeping bans on more than 300 Chinese apps, including TikTok, according to Reuters. More recently the government told Chinese mobile phone companies to bring in Indian equity partners and appoint Indian executives to key roles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jaishankar said in a tweet after the meeting that he and Wang discussed “outstanding issues related to peace &amp; tranquillity in border areas”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Their conversation also covered East Asia Summit or Asean Regional Forum agenda, “BRICS [Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa] and the Indo-Pacific”, the tweet said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Chinese foreign ministry, he told Wang that “the normalisation of India-China relations is in the common interests of both sides”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Indian side is willing to properly deal with the differences between the two sides with an open mind, push the India-China relationship back on track as soon as possible, and create favourable conditions for high-level exchanges in the next stage,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ministerial gathering of 18 Indo-Pacific countries in Jakarta has been largely dominated by the intensifying US-China rivalry, the war in Ukraine and North Korea&#39;s repeated missile provocations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China and India have close ties with Russia and have refused to criticise Moscow&#39;s aggression, but that has had little impact on their own strained relationship.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India is hosting this year&#39;s Group of 20 summit in September, an event that may offer an opportunity to improve relations with China. However, the country has become increasingly vocal in its criticism of Beijing in recent weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Tilting towards Washington, has India&#39;s time over China come?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In a speech to the US Congress last month, Modi referred to “the dark clouds of coercion” and “impossible burdens of debt”, in a thinly veiled jab at China&#39;s much-criticised economic coercive measures and alleged “debt trap” diplomacy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jaishankar, during a trip to Africa early this month, also said India was not “an extractive economy” pursuing “very narrow economic objectives” in Africa – an apparent reference to China&#39;s efforts to expand its military and economic presence.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[MTR Corp to go big in Greater Bay Area, review international business but Hong Kong remains its ‘filet mignon’, chairman Rex Auyeung says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3227920/mtr-corp-go-big-greater-bay-area-review-international-business-hong-kong-remains-its-filet-mignon?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/41f8ea9d-331e-4ce0-ad5b-553356914faf_ef98264c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s rail giant the MTR Corporation will make expansion into mainland China, especially in the Greater Bay Area, a key focus of its future even as it strives to improve operations in the city by doing more with long-term strategic planning, its non-executive chairman has said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was also in the midst of an ongoing review of its international operations and would be prepared to re-look unviable sectors if needed, Rex Auyeung Pak-kuen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in a rare exclusive interview since taking over the helm as the MTR Corp&#39;s non-executive chairman in 2019, Auyeung said that, contrary to critics&#39; claims, its international business had not been a drag on its bottom line.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since taking over, he said he had felt the need to seek improvements in corporate governance, adding: “One of the things I noticed was, because of the [massive daily] nature of our business, our executive team tend to be looking at things right in front of their eyes … and may not be spending enough time on long-term planning.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s MTR Corp to invest HK$65 billion on rail asset management over 5 years&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the next five years, it would be spending 20 per cent more, to the tune of HK$65 billion (US$8.3 billion) to better repair and maintain the ageing of the 44-year-old railway network, and was prepared to raise the figure if needed, Auyeung said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the management team comes to us and, say, after further review, we think we need more, I will not close the door, because our objective is to perform,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Early detection and speedy resolution of problems were vital, Auyeung said, as he explained how the company was turning increasingly to technology to solve these issues and while he could not guarantee there would be no disruptions, the aim was to improve it beyond the current rate of 99.96 per cent of overall seamless operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The semi-privatised corporation was also on a fast track to advance technologically via a HK$300 million investment fund into start-ups that would complement its rail operations, Auyeung said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company has come under fire in recent years over several high-profile incidents, including two incidents of train derailment and two involving doors falling off. During two of these occasions, commuters resorted to walking on tracks.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong union hits out at MTR Corp after emergency exit use causes travel chaos&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;During the interview last week, Auyeung said the company and he had offered apologies before and they strove to do better but also urged the public to bear in mind the 300,000km (186,411 miles) of tunnel and 271km of rail network the company operated, with only a two-hour window each night to do maintenance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s a good wake-up call that we cannot continue to think that all these things will continue to go well, because the system is at a stage that requires a little bit more maintenance,” he said. “必须有办法在某些事件发生之前甚至之后发现问题。你能多快恢复？ There are two issues: early detection and the speed of recovery.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As part of the governance review he undertook, he said the company identified three pillars of its business with Hong Kong operations as the core, or, as he put it, the “filet mignon” of the company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, last month, in a recent government experts&#39; report on the company&#39;s rail asset management regime, its management was urged to instil a sense of ownership and responsibility in staff about operational risks, and to implement a culture of reporting and documenting useful information from frontline staff on risks management.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m representing the board and we acknowledge the government&#39;s concern. And we will work very hard to deliver what we said we will deliver in asset management, ” Auyeung said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taking up his post at the height of the anti-government protests in 2019 and in the aftermath of the construction scandal of the city&#39;s most expensive rail project, the Sha Tin to Central rail link, Auyeung said the company was always on the lookout for improvements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Is MTR perfect?”他说。 “不。它还有改进的空间。 So we need to continue to look for ways.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Auyeung saw more opportunities arising from the mainland, where he said would have “some good news” soon on transit-led development plans and were looking at least two new cities to add to 22 rail projects it already had.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m sure you&#39;ve heard of this TOD – transit-oriented development – a concept that everybody talks about around the world. And that&#39;s the kind of thing, if you ask me, that MTR is looking for, especially the Greater Bay Area,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong MTR Corp&#39;s HK$65 billion maintenance plan could be derailed. Here&#39;s why&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;As for cross-border high-speed rail services, he said the city&#39;s section of the Guangzhou-Shenzhen-Hong Kong express link carried 50,000 to 60,000 passengers a day, which was still way below 100,000 on what he called a fairly good day before the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked if the rail remained underutilised and financially struggling, he said: “I would suggest don&#39;t look at it just from a financial perspective, rather, I look at it from a total economic development perspective, it really opens up a bridge from Hong Kong to many parts of China.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the goal was to allow the MTR Corp to play a bigger role in the bay area, an emerging economic growth engine with a population of at least 86 million that aims to combine nine mainland cities with Hong Kong and Macau.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong to relaunch high-speed rail service to mainland China on Sunday&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On its international operations, he said: “We currently have international markets, those with a lot of history.对于我们现在面临的所有地缘政治问题，我严格从商业角度来看待它。我们从那个市场得到什么？ Is that the market we want to go with or do we want to stay?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He did not specify which overseas units were being scrutinised, but pointed out that the overall portfolio did well even though some individual ones had lacklustre performances.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The corporation, in which the Hong Kong government owns a 75 per cent stake, also operates rail services on the mainland and Macau, as well as overseas in the United Kingdom, Sweden and Australia. These businesses overall grew 3.9 per cent to HK$26.01 billion in revenue or 54 per cent of the corporation&#39;s total of HK$47.81 billion last year from a year earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The profit before interest, finance charges, taxation and after variable annual payment, or EBIT, jumped 54.7 per cent to HK$962 million last year from 2021, and accounted for one-third of the corporation&#39;s total of HK$2.85 billion before a non-recurring loss on a rail project in Shenzhen last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There have been some comments I heard on the street, that the international businesses divert or distract the resources.不，这不是事实，因为我们并没有拿走任何香港资源并将其投入国际市场，从而损害了本地业务，一点也没有，”他说。 “Hong Kong is our fillet mignon, I cannot afford to lose sight of the Hong Kong business.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our international business is profitable, but when you cut it into small pieces there are certain operations that need more what I call kicking,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Executive Council convenor and veteran lawmaker Regina Ip Lau Suk-yee, who has urged the corporation to ditch its overseas operations and focus on the Hong Kong home turf since 2019, told the Post that some of the company&#39;s overseas operations were superfluous.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With a large number of mega rail projects relating to the Northern Metropolis and the Kau Yi Chau artificial islands in the pipeline, [the MTR Corp&#39;s] resources will be fully stretched. It should avoid overloading its staff and distracting them from these time-critical projects with unprofitable and superfluous overseas ventures,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;MTR Corp to make Oyster Bay project &#39;as attractive as possible for developers&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Auyeung also shed light on the Sha Tin to Central rail link controversy, which took a twist a week ago when the government said police&#39;s criminal investigations continued and the Department of Justice had sought the Magistrates&#39; Courts&#39; review into the sentence involving culprit Leighton Contractors (Asia) over part of the shoddy work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The file is not closed,” he said. “Our job is to continue to give them the information that they require.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scandal, which came to light in 2018, prompted an extra HK$10 billion in costs to make it the city&#39;s most expensive rail project costing HK$90.7 billion and featuring a delay of more than two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We as a corporation have learned a lot from this situation,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Heavy rains and floods swamp northeast US as record-breaking temperatures hit the south]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3227930/heavy-rains-and-floods-swamp-northeast-us-record-breaking-temperatures-hit-south?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 07:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/9f2c0355-e3fe-4acd-8fc8-d97ed9d9fa2a_db5db137.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Heavy rains pounded an already saturated northeast United States on Sunday for the second time in a week, spurring another round of flash flooding, cancelled airline flights and power outages. In Pennsylvania, a sudden flash flood late on Saturday afternoon claimed at least four lives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials in Bucks County&#39;s Upper Makefield Township in Pennsylvania said torrential rains on Saturday in the Washington Crossing area, swept away several cars. At least four people died and three others, including a 9-month-old boy and a 2-year-old girl, remained missing, authorities said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other parts of the East Coast were experiencing heavy rain, including Vermont. Authorities there said landslides could become a problem on Sunday as the state copes with more rain following days of flooding.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My team and I continue to monitor the situation as more rain falls in Vermont.今天全州都有山洪警报。 Remain vigilant and be prepared,” Vermont Governor Phil Scott said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sunday&#39;s strong storms led to hundreds of flight cancellations at airports in the New York City area, according to the tracking service FlightAware.仅新泽西州纽瓦克自由国际机场就有超过350个航班被取消，纽约肯尼迪国际机场也有超过280个航班被取消。 Hundreds of flights were also delayed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The National Weather Service issued flash flood warnings and tornado watches for parts of Connecticut, western Massachusetts, Vermont and New Hampshire. A tornado warning was issued for an area along the Massachusetts-New Hampshire border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thousands of power outages also were reported in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New York Governor Kathy Hochul urged people to stay at home and not drive on Sunday until the storms passed. There were no immediate reports of injuries from the storms and flooding in the state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In north New Jersey, some roads were closed on Sunday as crews worked to repair stretches of fragmented concrete that had buckled under the stress of heavy rain and flooding. Local creeks washed over passageways and a rockslide blocked passage along Route 46. Thoroughfares were a mess of water and rocks covered in brown sludge.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Hot and dangerous weekend&#39;: global heatwaves scorch the US to Asia and Europe&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Pennsylvania, meanwhile, a sudden, torrential downpour turned deadly in Upper Makefield Township.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fire Chief Tim Brewer told reporters the area got about 6-and-a-half to 7 inches of rain (about 18cm) in 45 minutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were about 11 cars on the road at the time, and three were swept away.布鲁尔说，路面上有大约 4 到 5 英尺的积水。 The bodies of four people had been recovered and three people – a woman and the two children – remained missing as of midday on Sunday, Brewer said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eight people were rescued from the cars and two from the creek, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As far south as North Carolina, floodwaters were blamed on the death of a 49-year-old woman whose car was swept off a road in Alexander County late on Saturday night. A man who was in the car with her was rescued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, recovery efforts were under way in Vermont from recent days of heavy rain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Vermont Agency of Transportation said 12 state roads remained closed while 12 were partially open to one lane of traffic and 87 have been reopened that were previously closed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heavy precipitation was not the only extreme weather plaguing the United States. A scorching heatwave across the US southwest has put roughly one-third of Americans under some type of heat watch or warning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That includes brutal temperatures in the hottest place on Earth – Death Valley, which runs along part of central California&#39;s border with Nevada. Las Vegas also faced the possibility of reaching an all-time record temperature on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US Environmental Protection Agency posted air-quality alerts for several states stretching from Montana to Ohio on Sunday because of smoke blowing in from Canadian wildfires. Hochul, the New York governor, said she expected air-quality alerts to be issued for northern and western parts of New York state on Monday because of the wildfires.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Air Quality alerts are in place for much of the Great Lakes, Midwest, and northern High Plains,” the National Weather Service (NWS) said. “This is due to the lingering thick concentration of Canadian wildfire smoke over these regions.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;El Nino and climate change combining to bake world in heatwaves: scientists&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Southern Californians, who saw thermometers peak at 41-43 degrees Celsius (105-110 degrees Fahrenheit) on Saturday, face a second day of similarly brutal temperatures, with the mercury expected to top 46 degrees in parts of California, Nevada and Arizona, the NWS said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By Saturday afternoon, California&#39;s famous Death Valley, one of the hottest places on Earth, had reached a life-threatening 51 degrees. The next day, early afternoon temperatures were hovering around 47.7 degrees, amid forecasts it could reach up to 53 degrees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tourists visited the national park to get a glimpse of what the NWS warned would be “life-threatening daytime heat” set to last until Tuesday night.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The NWS has said heat is the leading weather-related killer in the United States and urged Americans to take the risk seriously.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In total, from South Florida and the Gulf coast to the Southwest, over 80 million people remain under either an Excessive Heat Warning or Heat Advisory as of early this morning,” the NWS said in a Sunday morning bulletin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities have been sounding the alarm for days, advising people to avoid outdoor activities in the daytime and to avoid dehydration, which can quickly become fatal in such temperatures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heatwaves are occurring more often and more intensely in major US cities, according to the federal Environmental Protection Agency, with a frequency of six per year during the 2010s and 2020s compared to two per year during the 1960s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This heatwave is NOT typical desert heat,” the NWS&#39;s Las Vegas office tweeted Thursday, specifying that “its long duration, extreme daytime temperatures, &amp; warm nights” were unusual.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Canada, which is suffering from warm temperatures combined with months of below-average rainfall, the amount of land burned by devastating wildfires so far in 2023 climbed to an-all time high of 24.7 million acres (10 million hectares) on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We find ourselves this year with figures that are worse than our most pessimistic scenarios,” Yan Boulanger, a researcher at Canada&#39;s natural resources ministry, told Agence France-Presse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While it can be hard to attribute a particular weather event to climate change, scientists insist human-linked global warming is responsible for the multiplication and intensification of heatwaves.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Zealand PM Chris Hipkins says Pacific region less secure due to China’s assertiveness]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3227931/new-zealand-pm-chris-hipkins-says-pacific-region-less-secure-due-chinas-assertiveness?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.17 08:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/17/a2a49e50-1806-45f9-a803-9aab679bd756_94563801.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Pacific region is becoming more contested and less secure as China becomes more assertive, New Zealand Prime Minister Chris Hipkins said on Monday, outlining the country&#39;s need to work with like-minded partners while still engaging with Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s rise and how it seeks to exert that influence is a major driver of the increasing strategic competition, particularly in the Indo-Pacific, Hipkins said in a speech to the China Business Summit in Auckland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our region is becoming more contested, less predictable, and less secure,” he said. “And that poses challenges for small countries like New Zealand that are reliant on the stability and predictability of international rules for our prosperity and security.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The relationship needed careful management but China remained a key trading partner, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hipkins&#39; speech at the annual event comes less than a month after he led a successful trade mission to China, New Zealand&#39;s largest trading partner, where he face some domestic criticism for not being as vocal on human rights and other issues as some had expected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In this increasingly complex global environment, our relationship with China will continue to require careful management,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;New Zealand PM disagrees with Biden, says Xi not a &#39;dictator&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wellington has historically taken a more conciliatory approach towards China than Australia or its other Five Eyes security partners, Canada, the United States and the United Kingdom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Common interests and concerns do not mean we will always take the same approach. Sometimes there is tactical strength in a diversity of approaches to achieve the same outcomes,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China, New Zealand should be &#39;partners, not adversaries&#39;, Xi tells Hipkins&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wang Xiaolong, China&#39;s ambassador to New Zealand said in a speech that China and New Zealand relations were healthy, stable and thriving.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is no surprise that there are differences between our two countries, given the difference in our respective circumstances. There is no inevitability though, that our countries with differing social systems and levels of development cannot coexist peacefully,” he said in a speech that followed Hipkins&#39; at the summit.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 17 Jul 2023 08:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>