<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Rocky US-China relationship could benefit from couples therapy strategies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3225473/rocky-us-china-relationship-could-benefit-couples-therapy-strategies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/1af16e30-bc17-4a2b-86ab-7471b2d4c375_4732fe69.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在任何长期关系中，冲突都是不可避免的。真正重要的是合作伙伴是否能够管理、解决和克服分歧，并随着时间的推移建立更健康的关系。这种见解既适用于国际外交，也适用于浪漫关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可以公平地说，二月份气球事件的后果并不是解决冲突的光辉典范。中美两国非但没有冷静有效地沟通，反而陷入相互指责的怪圈，导致两国关系跌至数十年来的最低谷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;值得庆幸的是，美国国务卿布林肯成功访华。北京为建立更具建设性和和谐的美中关系打开了机会之窗。双方都有责任抓住这个机会——作为世界上最重要的两个大国，两国的动态不仅影响各自国家，而且影响整个全球格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布林肯此访是美国国务卿首次访华五年后，我们与外交部长秦刚、最高外交官王毅和国家主席习近平进行了建设性会晤，但最后一次会议绝无保证。这些积极的互动发出了一个强烈的信号，即在危险地接近边缘之后，双方都认识到不能冒完全决裂的风险，并致力于使两国关系建立在更稳定的基础上。中美两国应共同努力，为两国关系奠定坚实的基础，这样未来的事件就不会像过去几个月那样破坏两国关系。为了实现这一目标，关系治疗有四个原则可以用来帮助指导发展更强大、更稳定的美中关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首先，开放和定期的沟通是任何牢固伙伴关系的基石。中美必须重新就各自的意图、关切和期望进行频繁、透明的对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首要任务是加强高层互动，为习美会晤扫清道路。乔·拜登总统将于今年晚些时候出席 20 国集团或亚太经合组织峰会。希望布林肯此行之后，美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦、商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多和拜登的气候特使约翰·克里也能到访。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下级政府之间的定期接触以及双边关系也应该恢复。特朗普执政期间的对话已经萎缩。总的来说，这些会议可以提供平台来探索合作途径，解决任何正在酝酿的问题，并在紧张局势滚雪球演变成更大的冲突之前化解紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其次，任何关系都需要强有力的机制来管理和解决冲突（当冲突发生时） 。中美两国必须建立危机期间迅速有效的沟通渠道，以及预先制定的协议来管理此类事件，以帮助在局势变得难以控制之前缓和局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使是在最严重的时候冷战期间，美国和苏联保留了沟通和危机管理的渠道，包括华盛顿和莫斯科之间的热线电话。中美之间缺乏这样的机制。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;冷战式的协议是否有助于防止中美紧张局势升级？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;从长远来看，第三点是关系治疗师可能会强调的是需要培养相互尊重、同理心和共同利益。人们经常建议正在经历困难时期的夫妻尝试理解对方，并参与共同活动或共同爱好来加强他们的联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样，各国可以通过以下领域的文化交流来培养同理心：作为教育、研究和旅游，有助于增进相互了解并减少“我们与他们”的心态。近年来，由于政治和 Covid-19 大流行，中美之间的文化联系有所减弱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国现已重新开放，但缺乏足够的往返美国的航班仍然是一个瓶颈。野村证券最近的一份报告显示，2019 年中美之间的航班只有不到 6% 已恢复，而且保留的航班价格昂贵。部分问题在于，对飞越俄罗斯领空的限制增加了这些航线的运营成本。双方要探讨如何增加航班数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更广泛地说，双方应努力促进双边社会交流。上学期，在华美国学生人数减少至仅350人左右。希望随着学生下学期的新申请，这个数字将开始上升。这也有利于促进学术交流，包括减少邀请外宾来华参加学术会议的繁文缛节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，富布赖特中国项目派出美国学者到中国进行了超过四次的访问。几十年来，他们的中国同行却走上了相反的道路。该计划于 2020 年被取消，但应该恢复，同年退出中国的和平队计划也应该恢复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后，共同的目标和合作项目在帮助夫妻加深联系方面发挥着关键作用。同样，中美两国必须找到共同点并采取有利于两国的共同举措。这不应局限于解决眼前的问题和冲突，还应涵盖气候变化和全球金融稳定等更广泛、更具建设性的主题。在这些问题上的长期合作和逐步取得的成就可以帮助两国在共同的事业下团结起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就像成功的夫妇一样，两国都必须投入时间和精力来培育他们的伙伴关系。布林肯访问后，中美两国有机会为两国关系打下更坚实的基础，这样下次意外到来时，两国关系就不会脱轨。与任何关系一样，道路上都会有坎坷，但这些可以通过仔细管理来克服。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rivalry between Trump and DeSantis deepens with duelling New Hampshire campaign events]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225645/rivalry-between-trump-and-desantis-deepens-duelling-new-hampshire-campaign-events?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/b61555f2-9589-469d-ad17-2d920e4676fc_207ce332.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二，佛罗里达州州长罗恩·德桑蒂斯和美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普之间的竞争进一步加剧两位主要的共和党白宫候选人在关键的提前投票州新罕布什尔州的决斗活动中互相嘲笑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯在霍利斯市政厅发表讲话时发誓要“真正”建造美墨边境墙特朗普作为总统曾尝试但未能完成这一任务。他还承诺以特朗普未能做到的方式摧毁华盛顿的传统权力中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来在康科德举行的共和党妇女午餐会上发表讲话时，特朗普反驳说，德桑蒂斯被迫在初选中屈居第二，并且指责州长支持削减社会保障、医疗保险和其他福利计划，以此作为控制联邦支出的一种方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了言辞之外，相互冲突的事件还显示了每位候选人不断变化的策略。德桑蒂斯回答了广泛的观众提问——这是新罕布什尔州政界的一个标志，他在上次访问该州时回避了这一问题，招致批评，认为他生硬且过于照本宣科。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，特朗普发表了一场随心所欲的演讲，以了解更多内容比小时。他没有在康科德接受提问，报道此次活动的记者被限制在一支笔中，在陪同下进入浴室，并被告知他们不能在会议中心宴会厅甚至走廊里与与会者交谈。但这位前总统在随后前往曼彻斯特的一站回答了问题，他在那里开设了新罕布什尔州竞选办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯询问了因特朗普承诺“排干沼泽”而两次投票支持特朗普的人的情况。在华盛顿，他用自己的回答与这位前总统形成了迄今为止最鲜明的对比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他没有耗尽它。今天的情况比以往任何时候都更糟糕，”德桑蒂斯说。他补充说，这样的承诺还不够远，因为下一任总统“可以重新填补它。”德桑蒂斯说，“我想打破沼泽”，并承诺通过指示将权力从华盛顿手中夺走。内阁机构将那里的员工人数减半。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法院称特朗普必须面临纽约民事欺诈索赔；伊万卡案被驳回&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯试图通过质疑前总统对全国共和党的持续控制来赢得特朗普的支持。在市政厅，州长猛烈抨击了特朗普领导下的共和党的“失败文化”，并提到了共和党许多人所预测的“大规模红色浪潮”，但在去年的中期选举中从未在全国范围内实现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我们在佛罗里达州掀起了一股红色浪潮，”德桑蒂斯说道，并指出他去年秋天轻松赢得了连任。 “但那是因为我们在佛罗里达州取得了成果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多共和党领袖仍然对特朗普非常忠诚，但有一些证据表明，对这位前总统的攻击正在引起共鸣。周二，众议院议长、加州共和党人凯文·麦卡锡在谈到特朗普时表示：“他能赢得选举吗？是的，他能赢得选举。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“问题是，他是最有能力赢得选举的吗？”麦卡锡在 CNBC 的 Squawk Box 节目中继续说道。 “我不知道这个答案。”当天晚些时候，他向保守派新闻媒体 Breitbart 澄清，特朗普“今天比 2016 年更强大。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普在自己的讲话中指出，民意调查显示他在初选中大幅领先。他抓住德桑蒂斯的说法，虽然社会保障和其他项目需要为老年人提供保障，但对于年轻人来说，可能需要“以两党合作的方式来弄清楚如何加强这一点”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你可以打赌他稍后会这样做，”特朗普在谈到削减计划时说道。 “他会对你这么做。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普还发誓要“一劳永逸地排干沼泽”，但更多地用这个口号来批评美国总统乔·拜登，而不是佛罗里达州州长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “如果你是沼泽的一部分，你就无法排干沼泽，而乔·拜登和其他对手，其中许多人，都100%拥有、控制、购买和支付，”特朗普&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前总统在很大程度上也呼应了德桑蒂斯的观点，承诺“这次选举将是我们国家首都腐败政治阶层的世界末日。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国总统候选人妮基·黑莉寻求对华政策进行重大改变&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯还被问及 2021 年 1 月占领美国国会大厦的亲特朗普暴民的情况，她回答说：“如果是为了对发生两三年的事情重新提起诉讼，几年前，我们就会输。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“那天发生的事情与我无关。显然，我不喜欢看到它，”德桑蒂斯说。 “但我们必须在这件事上继续前进。我们不能向后看。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也与特朗普发生了冲突，特朗普周二重申了毫无根据的说法，称他因选举舞弊而无法连任。许多联邦和地方官员、一长串法院、前竞选高级工作人员，甚至特朗普自己的司法部长都表示，没有证据表明他所指控的欺诈行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两位候选人的同时访问凸显了这一作用新罕布什尔州是全国第一个共和党初选州，将在决定下一届共和党总统候选人的过程中发挥作用。早期初选的大部分焦点都集中在爱荷华州和南卡罗来纳州，那里福音派基督徒占主导地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，在新罕布什尔州花时间让候选人在更多人面前测试他们的信息。倾向自由主义的选民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普在爱荷华州输给得克萨斯州参议员特德·克鲁兹后，在新罕布什尔州 2016 年共和党初选中获得第一名，帮助他获得了党内主导地位。但他的民主党竞争对手在 2016 年和 2020 年大选中赢得了该州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周二发表讲话之前，特朗普宣布他的新罕布什尔州团队在该州 10 个县拥有 150 多名敬业的活动家和组织者。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;来自亨尼克镇的萨布丽娜·安特尔 (Sabrina Antle) 表示，她无力参加康科德午餐会。她和她九岁的女儿稍后试图在曼彻斯特会见这位前总统，但在他们到达之前，活动就已经满员了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我是特朗普支持者，但我不会因为罗恩·德桑蒂斯，因为我认为他会做单口喜剧，”安特尔说。 “我只是不知道他是否有特朗普那样的态度，只是自信。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普在新录音中听到讨论“高度机密”文件&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯的竞选活动激怒了一些人新罕布什尔州共和党妇女联合会的成员在特朗普在该组织的午餐会上发表讲话的同时安排了他的市政厅。它称德桑蒂斯的活动“试图从午餐中夺走焦点”，并指出其他总统候选人围绕它安排了活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这并没有阻止德桑蒂斯，他在市政厅谈论了新的移民政策提案他周一在得克萨斯州南部发布了这一言论，并押注这一问题能够激励共和党选民，甚至是那些位于美墨边境以北 2,000 英里的选​​民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们实际上要修建隔离墙，”德桑蒂斯谈到了特朗普未能兑现的承诺。 “很多政客都在叽叽喳喳地说。他们做出宏伟的承诺，却未能兑现实际成果。找借口的时间已经结束了。现在是取得成果并最终完成工作的时候了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但佛罗里达州州长还针对新罕布什尔州周二的信息进行了调整，指出更严格的边境安全最终将有助于限制阿片类药物成瘾的破坏，尽管全国各地吸毒过量导致的死亡人数不断攀升，但这些对国家的打击尤其严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他承诺对贩毒集团采取“任何政府都没有采取过的最果断”的政策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们必须这样做，”德桑蒂斯说，“因为这将拯救生命。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Carbon Finance: How the launch of a new voluntary carbon markets claims code can help reclaim lost credibility]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3225626/carbon-finance-how-launch-new-voluntary-carbon-markets-claims-code-can-help-reclaim-lost-credibility?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/2f647e1d-3e59-4a0a-bbe7-a238dcddddd0_de5983ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;自愿碳市场诚信倡议 (VCMI) 推出了一套全球指南，以使企业能够对其购买的碳信用额做出更可信的气候声明，以抵消温室气体排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个非营利性国际机构周三发布了其“声明实践准则”，这是一本针对企业的规则手册在提出气候效益声明时要遵循。遵守该准则是自愿的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“索赔准则填补了一个关键空白，为自愿碳市场的需求方带来了诚信，”它在一份声明中表示。该准则是约 70 家（主要是跨国公司）经过 12 个月多的道路测试、一系列公众咨询和多方利益相关者合作的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然自愿碳市场有潜力帮助填补这一空白。该组织在索赔代码文件中表示，缓解气候变化的资金缺口，特别是在发展中国家，只有在高度诚信的情况下才能实现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这意味着碳信用额必须通过以下方式产生：这些活动真正超越了一切照旧，有利于东道社区（供应方），并且它们的使用可以增加整体温室气体减排，而不是取代现有行动（需求方）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “如果这两方面没有明确的高度诚信的规则，自愿碳市场将继续受到怀疑，公司将害怕投资，他们的潜力将会丧失。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该准则，之前公司购买任何碳补偿时，除了公开承诺不迟于 2050 年实现净零排放外，还必须披露其年度温室气体排放量和近期减排目标，并经科学目标倡议验证。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;他们还必须证明他们正在实现近期减排目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后，公司可以根据自己的残余排放量百分比，从三级声明中选择其中之一进行声明这将通过购买碳信用额来抵消。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在发布 VCMI 索赔代码之前，公众对今年早些时候欧洲几家媒体报道指出的一个关键类别（预防毁林项目）信用额的可信度表示担忧.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“显然，[它们]是市场中非常重要的一部分，”VCMI 执行董事 Mark Kenber 在代码发布前接受采访时告诉《华盛顿邮报》。 “目前，森林保护所获得的资金还不到保护热带森林所需资金的 3%，因此我们需要找到答案。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VCMI 于两年前在以下机构的支持下启动：资助者包括英国政府、对冲基金儿童投资基金管理公司的慈善部门、贝索斯地球基金和科技巨头谷歌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;VCMI 准则的推出将对香港产生影响，蓝筹公司正在香港寻求发展购买高质量的自愿碳信用额，以抵消他们无法通过自己的努力减少的碳足迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港还表示希望成为碳信用额交易的区域市场，架起全球碳抵消需求和中国的桥梁。潜在的信用供应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自愿信用由碳抵消登记处针对气候缓解项目针对经核实的每个单位的排放减少或清除发放。登记机构标准和方法的稳健性对于所发行信用的质量至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据数据编译器 Ecosystem Marketplace 的数据，2021 年全球自愿信用交易额较 2020 年增长近四倍，达到 20 亿美元。最受欢迎的类别包括可再生能源和林业项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kenbar 表示，VCMI 正在考虑为一些公司提供合规救济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于刚刚起步或半途而废的公司净零之旅，我们如何激励他们[在脱碳方面做更多的事情]是我们在接下来的几个月中引入灵活性的工作的一部分，”他说。 “我们希望在今年年底前推出一个对跨国公司和国内中端市场公司都有吸引力的一揽子计划。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese tourists in Thailand face jail, fine after touching ‘cute’ starfish, stepping on coral reefs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3225614/chinese-tourists-thailand-face-jail-fine-after-touching-cute-starfish-stepping-coral-reefs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/f9a312b7-0c8a-4c9e-a28c-d40118691476_7f5a1bef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;三名中国游客被指控在潜水探险期间触摸海星并踩踏珊瑚礁普吉岛的一名船员被指控违反海洋保护法，可能面临两年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这起事件上周发生在泰国拉查岛，在一群人分享照片后曝光。追踪该国环境违法行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环境部长 Varawut Silpa-archa 在 Facebook 帖子中表示，两名游客在向警方自首后承认了罪行，而第三名嫌疑人仍然在逃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;雾霾驱走了泰国游客，隔壁的农民正在刀耕火种&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;瓦拉武补充说，官员们与省旅游警察、海事办公室和组织这次旅行的公司协调追捕违法者。他没有详细说明失踪游客是否仍在追捕中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果罪名成立，游客将面临两年监禁和 20 万泰铢（5,667 美元）罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两人成立仅一个月的旅游公司为潜水团游客的行为道歉，称这是该机构的第一个中介人，并且“吸取了教训”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运营商还承诺提高人们的意识不干涉客户中的海洋野生动物，尤其是以前卷入过类似事件的中国人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们中的一些人觉得这些动物很可爱，想和它们合影留念给他们的朋友， ”《普吉新闻》援引一位公司高管的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们代表公司对发生的事情感到非常遗憾。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国社交媒体用户将愤怒的矛头指向了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些人感叹，尽管执法部门采取了行动，此类事件仍然发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两名中国游客2020 年，因在泰国中部浮潜时使用鱼枪捕捉受保护的观赏鱼而被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年，韩国女演员李烈音 (Lee Yeol-eum) 因在泰国国家海洋公园捕捉濒临灭绝的巨型蛤而被指控参加真人秀节目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海洋专家表示，泰国四分之三以上的珊瑚礁因海水温度上升和不受控制的旅游业而遭到破坏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个依赖旅游业的国家的沙地今年第一季度，海滩吸引了615万外国游客，其中中国游客超过70万。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 07:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan says it has spotted two Russian warships off its east coast]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3225644/taiwan-says-it-has-spotted-two-russian-warships-its-east-coast?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 06:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/683d7d0a-90e2-43f6-b24e-cfdbb62e47af_e2570a3a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾周二在其东海岸发现两艘俄罗斯军舰，并派出自己的飞机和台湾国防部表示，派出船只进行监视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防部在周二晚间的一份声明中表示，两艘护卫舰在台湾东海岸附近向北航行，然后“离开我们的反应区”台湾军方派出飞机和舰艇进行监视，并启动岸基导弹系统，但没有提供更多信息细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“击落它们”：台湾誓言摧毁“危险的”中国大陆气球&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国际文传电讯社周二报道称，俄罗斯太平洋舰队的一支舰艇分队进入菲律宾海南部执行远程海上通道的任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在俄罗斯入侵乌克兰后，台湾与美国及其盟国一起对俄罗斯实施了广泛的制裁.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民主治理的台湾——中国大陆将台湾视为一个分裂的领土，必须统一，必要时使用武力——过去三年定期报告中国海军舰艇和空军飞机在台湾周围活动，北京试图推行其领土主张。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong theft cases jump by nearly 40 per cent in first 4 months of the year, with police linking surge to return to normality]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3225615/hong-kong-theft-cases-jump-nearly-40-cent-first-4-months-year-police-linking-surge-return-normality?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/e743677b-8a4d-4f31-b34f-9f500787ebad_c4f649ad.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;今年首四个月香港盗窃案增加近40% 2022年同期，警方将盗窃案激增归因于该市恢复正常。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近的盗窃案大部分发生在旺角，该区预防罪案总督察蔡永玉该局表示，“鉴于该地区人流量大”，这并不奇怪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1 月至 4 月期间，警方记录了 7,167 起盗窃案，比前一年增加了 39.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“随着社会恢复正常，我们总体上看到街上的人越来越多，”Choi 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港今年早些时候取消了最后一项 Covid-19 旅行限制和社交距离规则自 2020 年以来一直处于基本封锁状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据警方称，今年前四个月，该市共记录了 27,911 起犯罪案件，比上一年记录的 19,379 起增加了 44%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;这一趋势一直持续到5月份，今年首5个月的整体犯罪案件达到35,863起，比去年同期增加10,434起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中，有3,872起被视为暴力犯罪- 比 2022 年增加 598 件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi 还透露，钱包或信用卡、现金和八达通储值卡是扒手最常盗窃的物品，其次是手机。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;79 岁的香港男子在女子承诺按摩后被抢了劳力士和戒指&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;停放的自行车也是小偷拿走的前三件物品之一，Choi 指出，许多自行车都配有脆弱​​的锁，可能会损坏自行车。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她敦促业主选择更厚、质量更高的锁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新数据包括 2,498 起商店行窃案件，而去年同期的四个月期间有 1,915 起。 2019 年疫情爆发前为 2,369 例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;超市记录的病例最多，为 999 例，但 Choi 表示，这可能与它们是该市最常见的商店类型有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;香港警方追捕使用 GPS 追踪器寻找汽车并盗窃 26 万港元的窃贼&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;建议商店经理指定员工看守使用日益常见的自助结账的顾客，最近发生的一些事件商店行窃案件涉及人们未能扫描所有物品并希望不被注意到。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方表示已恢复与零售商举行的定期安全研讨会，旨在教育他们如何防止盗窃和入室盗窃。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;该研讨会在大流行之前大约每六个月举行一次，但由于新冠疫情措施而中断了几年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在土瓜湾经营一家汽车维修店的史蒂夫·莫克(Steve Mok)参加本周最近一次会议的 50 名店主之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方因盗窃价值 950 万港元的玉器而逮捕了 53 岁的女子&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“该活动是非常有用，我们学到了很多东西，”他说。 “我们意识到，除了安装基本安全摄像头和将贵重产品锁在特殊展示盒等众所周知的方法之外，市场上还有更新、技术更先进的工具，例如红外监控系统和运动探测器&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，西贡警队表示，已与政府飞行服务队、水警及警犬队等其他部门进行特别行动，在进城人士经常出入的地区进行搜查和巡逻。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明表示，此次行动是“鉴于该地区近期入室盗窃案件数量增加”，并敦促居民与警方合作并保持警惕。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba’s cloud services subsidiary and Shanghai’s Fudan University establish new intelligent computing platform for AI initiatives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225619/alibabas-cloud-services-subsidiary-and-shanghais-fudan-university-establish-new-intelligent?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/f260826c-32fc-4f21-af5e-27b1afbc2ec5_c815a8f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴集团旗下云计算服务子公司与上海复旦大学联合推出了他们所描述的产品作为全国最大的大学云科学研究和智能计算平台，深化业务部门与主要公共机构的联系，并加大对人工智能（AI）新举措的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新计算根据阿里云周二发布的声明，复旦未来（CFFF）平台旨在训练大型人工智能模型，例如大型语言模型（LLM），用于科学研究目的。总部位于杭州的母公司阿里巴巴拥有《南华早报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在大学里，教授可能能够用科研经费负担得起云计算[服务]，但并不是每个学生都能负担得起，”阿里巴巴表示云计算创始人王健在大学校园举行的仪式上。 “我希望每个人都能利用云计算来实现自己的科研理想。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国电信作为全国最大的固网运营商和国内主要的云服务提供商，也是云计算发展的幕后推手。新的计算平台。本月早些时候，中国电信公布了在上海建立大型计算中心的计划，以支持该市的人工智能产业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CFFF项目被王描述为15年后梦想成真，反映了中国的人们对生成式人工智能作为一种战略工具下了很大的赌注，它不仅可以拯救背负债务和冠状病毒后复苏缓慢的国民经济，而且可以为该国在激烈的技术竞争中击败美国的努力提供动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;法学硕士是深度学习人工智能算法，可以使用非常大的数据集来识别、总结、翻译、预测和生成内容。这些代表了用于训练人工智能聊天机器人的技术，例如微软支持的 OpenAI 的 ChatGPT。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;复旦大学校长李进表示，该学术机构希望利用 CFFF 建立许多世界一流的模型，包括与生命科学、材料科学和集成电路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由张勇领导的阿里云（将于 9 月辞去母公司董事长兼首席执行官职务）于 4 月份公布了其对 ChatGPT 的回应，名为“统易”钱文。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;生成式人工智能、云计算和安全是 2023 年顶级技术趋势：阿里巴巴研究院&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴和其他提供商的云计算服务使企业能够购买、销售、租赁或分销一系列软件和其他数字资源作为互联网上的按需服务，就像来自电网的电力一样。这些资源在数据中心内进行管理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“企业和大学应该携手创新和人才培养，”金周二在复旦大学微信帖子中谈到与阿里巴巴的“全面战略合作”时表示云。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿里云的王先生回应了这一说法，表示他预计公司和复旦大学将进一步“深化产教融合”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而阿里云和复旦大学则这样做了。合作细节暂未透露，预计双方将帮助培养本地人工智能新人才。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;阿里巴巴从人工智能共开发计划、云降价中寻求增长&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国官方媒体最近大力支持生成式人工智能，指的是为 ChatGPT 和类似服务提供支持的算法。 A People&#39;s Daily op-ed piece published earlier this month extolled the technology&#39;s potential to help drive economic growth and become a useful daily tool.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alibaba&#39;s Cloud Intelligence Group, meanwhile, is expected to become an independent entity in the next 12 months under the e-commerce giant&#39;s sweeping restructuring plan. That would eventually enable the firm to seek a separate public listing.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Court says Donald Trump must face New York civil fraud claims, tosses case against Ivanka]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225643/court-says-donald-trump-must-face-new-york-civil-fraud-claims-tosses-case-against-ivanka?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 06:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/2563186d-1159-485c-8d7b-f5889483ef86_c5df5a1a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A New York appeal court on Tuesday rejected Donald Trump&#39;s bid to end the state attorney general&#39;s lawsuit accusing the former US president and his family business of “staggering” fraud, but dismissed all claims against his daughter Ivanka Trump and said the remaining case may be limited further.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Attorney General Letitia James&#39; civil case filed last September accused Trump of lying from 2011 to 2021 about asset values, including for his Mar-a-Lago estate in Florida and Trump Tower penthouse in Manhattan, as well as his own net worth, to obtain better terms from lenders and insurers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawsuit seeks at least US$250 million in damages from Trump, his adult sons Donald Jnr and Eric, the Trump Organisation and others, and to stop the Trumps from running businesses in New York.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Donald Trump, the Republican front-runner for the 2024 presidential election, has denied wrongdoing. He has also called James&#39; case and two unrelated criminal indictments, where he has pleaded not guilty, part of a Democratic “witch hunt.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a 5-0 decision, the Appellate Division in Manhattan said state law gave James power to police alleged “repeated or persistent fraud or illegality,” and conduct lengthy and complex investigations many years after suspected misconduct began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it said statutes of limitations prevented James, who had investigated Trump&#39;s business dealings for three years, from suing over claims that arose before July 13, 2014, or February 6, 2016, depending on the defendant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also said all claims against Ivanka Trump should be dismissed because they were filed too late, and because she was no longer with the Trump Organisation at the relevant time.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump heard discussing &#39;highly confidential&#39; documents in new recording&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The court returned the case to Justice Arthur Engoron of the state Supreme Court in Manhattan to determine which parts could proceed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An October 2 trial is scheduled. Trump was questioned under oath for the case in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is a mountain of evidence that shows Mr Trump and the Trump Organisation falsely and fraudulently valued multiple assets and misrepresented those values to financial institutions for significant economic gain,” a spokeswoman for James said. “This decision allows us to hold him accountable for that fraud, and we intend to do so.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During oral arguments on June 6, a lawyer for James said Trump&#39;s transactions did not occur in a vacuum, and that letting him commit fraud hurts honest participants in banking, insurance and real estate markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Christopher Kise, a lawyer for Donald Trump and most of the other defendants, called the decision “the first step” towards ending a case that James should not have filed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The correct application of the law will now limit appropriately the previously unlimited reach of the attorney general,” he said. “We remain confident that once all the real facts are known, there will be no doubt President Trump has built an extraordinarily successful business empire.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ivanka Trump&#39;s lawyer did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the criminal cases, Trump faces a 34-count indictment obtained by Manhattan District Attorney Alvin Bragg over hush money payments to a porn star, and a 38-count US Justice Department indictment saying he mishandled classified documents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The New York civil case is New York v Trump et al, New York State Supreme Court, Appellate Division, 1st Department, No. 2023-00717.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 06:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China reaches into Central Asia’s Silk Road past to build strategic ties of the future]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224644/china-reaches-central-asias-silk-road-past-build-strategic-ties-future?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/19/64d76a17-39d8-4c97-a6dd-46949f1c45fa_202dbed4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;When Chinese President Xi Jinping rolled out the red carpet for five regional leaders at the first China-Central Asia summit last month, the event was replete with historic symbols of the Silk Road.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Billed as the country&#39;s “first major diplomatic event” of the year, the summit was held in the city of Xian, the ancient capital of China during the Han dynasty (206BC-220AD), and the start of the Silk Road.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Few symbols from history underline China&#39;s contribution to ancient civilisations more than the Silk Road, a vast network of trade routes that connected China to societies in the Mediterranean region and Europe for 1,400 years. Today, the heritage of those transport links is being revived for a new purpose and showcased in Central Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi and his wife, Peng Liyuan, hosted a grand welcome ceremony for the Central Asian leaders at Tang Paradise, a large theme park featuring buildings and gardens that incorporates elements of the Tang dynasty (618-907BC), when the ancient Silk Road was at its peak.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China pulls on Tang dynasty Silk Road ties to secure central Asian future&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;As Xi&#39;s signature Belt and Road Initiative – a massive modern-day infrastructure and investment project that borrows from the themes of the Silk Road – enters its 10th year, Beijing seems increasingly inclined to tap the shared regional heritage as a powerful symbol of China&#39;s ties in Central Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China wants to send a clear signal to the Central Asian countries that this is the historic bond we should cherish and we should revive together,” said Yu Hong, a senior research fellow at the East Asian Institute of the National University of Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“By stressing the ancient bonds of the Silk Road, China also wants to strengthen its ties with Central Asia while further pushing forward the Belt and Road,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the summit, China&#39;s foreign ministry published a “list of achievements” by the six leaders that included cooperation and partnerships in dozens of areas, including infrastructure, energy and security. Among them, the list called for “cooperation in joint archaeology, cultural heritage conservation and restoration, museum exchanges and the recovery and return of lost cultural objects” with Central Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tim Winter, a senior research fellow with the NUS&#39; Asia Research Institute, said the Silk Road seemed to have become an important platform for promoting the idea of shared futures that were built on shared past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The historical connections between China and Central Asia also are an attempt to open up the institutional and people-people forms of connectivity beyond just infrastructure and trade. This also helps communicate to Chinese citizens the importance of regional engagement to the future development of China,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Winter, an expert on heritage diplomacy, said the fields of archaeology, anthropology and architectural conservation, had formed the basis of understanding of Silk Road history.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Heritage is not just about building ties over the cultural past, the Silk Road is about connecting histories and futures,” Winter said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coined by German geographer Ferdinand von Richthofen in 1877, the term “Silk Road” was first used to describe the 7,000 miles, or 11,265km, of routes, along which valuable commodities such as silk, porcelain, jade, gunpowder, livestock, grapes and figs were traded between China and Rome.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But beyond commerce, the Silk Road has also provided captivating stories of adventure as well as fascinating exchanges across diverse religions and cultures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the heart of the route was Central Asia, home to present-day Kazakhstan, Uzbekistan, Turkmenistan, Kyrgyzstan, and Tajikistan. The region was a crossroads for merchants travelling between China, Persia, India and the Roman Empire. Traders passed through bustling cities, like Samarkand, Bukhara and Khiva, which were famous for exotic bazaars filled with silk, spices, precious metals, gems and other goods.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China looks to central Asia as the West sees threat to US-led world order&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In 2013, during a speech at Nazarbayev University in Kazakhstan on his first overseas trip as China&#39;s president, Xi first proposed the infrastructure and investment plan that would become known as the Belt and Road Initiative – a blueprint to promote Chinese economic cooperation and connectivity with countries in Eurasia and beyond.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the last decade, Central Asia has emerged as an integral arena for the belt and road strategy. According to official Chinese data, in 2020, more than 60 per cent of Chinese investment in Central Asia was related to infrastructure, and in 2022, China&#39;s trade with the region reached a record of US$70.2 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, questions have emerged about China&#39;s loans and investments in Central Asia, where Beijing has had to contend with a host of problems, including corruption, environmental damage, and fears that China will take control of land, natural resources and job opportunities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Playing up ancient bonds could help ease those concerns, according to Yu, in Singapore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many people in Central Asia are very familiar with the concept of the Silk Road,” he said. “They tend to be more accepting of the concept of the belt and road if you put it that way that it is the modern version of the historical Silk Road.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Throughout the Soviet era, many archaeologists were deployed to uncover the history of the Russian steppe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But after the collapse of the Soviet Union, large-scale research projects stalled as the number of experts dwindled, and technology and funding sources dried up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang Shu, head of the Institute for Central Asian Studies at Lanzhou University, said a deeper archaeological collaboration could also help Central Asian countries better understand their own histories.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The archaeological evidence is most convincing because you can&#39;t make it up,” Yang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Such cooperation could not only help Chinese better understand Central Asia, but would be a great benefit to Central Asia&#39;s own historical development.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2000, Chinese archaeologists began conducting field research in Central Asia, and in 2012, a joint team of Chinese and Uzbek archaeologists started surveys and excavations at the site of the ancient city of Mingtepa in Uzbekistan, work that Chinese media said was intended “to study the civilisational processes of ancient cities and the cultural lineages and routes of the ancient Silk Road”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mingtepa, which flourished from the 2nd century BC to the 5th century AD, was an important commercial and cultural centre on the Silk Road, and is believed to have been the nearest ancient city in Uzbekistan to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, China announced the opening of the Silk Road Archaeological Cooperative Research Centre in Xian. According to Shaanxi Daily, Chinese archaeologists were expected to begin expeditions to the Ferghana Valley this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a well-known trade hub in Central Asia during the Silk Road era, the Ferghana Valley was a key transit point for Chinese silk and other luxury goods destined for Mediterranean and European markets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The valley played a particularly significant role in a chapter of Chinese history. In 138BC, during the Han dynasty, Chinese explorer Zhang Qian, who was dispatched to establish diplomatic relations and open trade routes with the people of Central Asia, ended up spending a decade there after being captured and detained by a tribe of the Xiongnu nomadic people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to historical records, Zhang married a Xiongnu woman and learned about the culture, economy and trade routes of the region before eventually making his way back to China. His valuable experience and information about the region helped in preparations for future diplomatic missions throughout Central Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was also in the Ferghana Valley that Zhang discovered the Ferghana horse, a breed known for its speed, endurance and agility. The horses were introduced to the Chinese imperial court, and were believed to have played a crucial role in military campaigns to defeat the Xiongnu, which eventually helped to cement China&#39;s status as a dominant power in the region.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Philippine tribal tattooist, 106, keeps ancient practice alive: ‘she’s the face of this tradition’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225608/philippine-tribal-tattooist-106-keeps-ancient-practice-alive-shes-face-tradition?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/10dd1d52-0855-4439-b388-81fbe824ef57_674e3521.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hunched over and sitting on a low pile of sacks outside her house in the remote village of Buscalan, Maria Oggay was oblivious of the buzz around her as dozens of excited visitors queued up to get inked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shrouded in mist, Buscalan sits on a ridge in the Cordillera mountain range and can be reached via a 12-hour drive from Manila, along zigzag roads that are prone to landslides.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last part of the journey is made by foot as visitors trek for about one hour to the village, passing breathtaking views of rice terraces and lush mountains, through crisp, cool air.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the quaint village, home to about 900 residents and the Butbut tribe of headhunters, Oggay is known as Apo Whang-Od, the oldest mambabatok, or traditional tattoo artist, in the Philippines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 106 years old, Whang-Od still practices the ancient art of batok – the technique of tattooing through hand-tapping using a lemon tree thorn and charcoal soot – that she learned as a teenager.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Through the decades, she has skilfully etched tribal designs onto the skins of thousands of people, including foreigners who make the pilgrimage to her village, promoting her culture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As long as I&#39;m still healthy and my eyesight&#39;s good, I&#39;ll continue to give tattoos,” she said, as she wiped a tearing eye.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than a decade since a Discovery Channel series catapulted Whang-Od to celebrity status in 2009, the sprightly old lady again caught the world&#39;s attention when she became the oldest model to grace the cover of the Philippine edition of the international magazine Vogue in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m happy that my photos can be seen by many people in different places. But I&#39;m also embarrassed just thinking about them looking at an ugly face,” she said, laughing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her face and name have become a brand and can be seen everywhere in the village, including coffee mugs, T-shirts, key chains, magnets and other souvenirs. A marker at the turn-off to the village from the main road declares, “Welcome! Whang-Od Buscalan Tattoo Village.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world-famous native of Kalinga province, about 300km north of Manila, has embraced modern fashion, donning a black hoodie over a white T-shirt and paisley track pants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A black knitted bucket hat adorned with sunflowers, dangling pink flower earrings and colourful beaded necklaces complete her outfit for the day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But her best accessory remains her many tattoos of different designs on her deeply wrinkled skin, marking various moments in her life, including achievements, ailments, and former lovers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The tattoo is important,” Whang-Od said in the local dialect. “When you die, all the necklaces and the earrings will go, but the tattoo will stay.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her first tattoo was a ladder and a python on her left arm that she got when she was 15.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her favourite tattoos refer to names of her former lovers. “These tattoos carry good memories. One was made by a guy from the other village as a keepsake. It&#39;s an unforgettable tattoo.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An accidental tattoo is the black ink left on her fingers from decades of tapping that has also fractured her right thumb.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s painful when I touch it,” she said. “It got twisted before and now the bone&#39;s broken.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For years, Whang-Od was thought to be the last Kalinga mambabatok since she did not marry and had no children to train in the craft, which can only be passed on within bloodlines. But from 2007, she started to train her grandnieces Grace Palicas and Elyang Wigan, to keep the ancient tradition alive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Vogue cover, coming off the Covid-19 pandemic when travel was restricted, has boosted interest to meet and get inked by Whang-Od, who now only does a signature of three dots, representing herself, Palicas and Wigan – her legacy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without her, the village and our tradition would never have been known around the world,” the 26-year-old Palicas said. “She is the face of this tradition.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past, only warriors from the Butbut tribe were given tattoos as a sign of their bravery in protecting the village.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now, everyone wants to get a tattoo, a piece of the artwork,” Whang-Od said. “I think it&#39;s a good thing that a lot of people, even foreigners, are interested in getting one.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whang-Od&#39;s popularity has benefited the entire village of Buscalan, where tattoo tourism has sparked new, lucrative sources of livelihood aside from agriculture. Residents have become tour guides, opened their houses for accommodation, and sold souvenirs, among other initiatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That additional income means residents are able to afford modern comforts. Some Wi-fi hotspots have sprouted in the village, where there is no mobile phone signal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Galvanised iron sheets and cement have replaced dried grass and wood as the materials used to build most houses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mechanised trolleys have even been set up to take supplies up the mountain, across a deep valley where a raging river flows.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jade Kuehnl, a 26-year-old British tourist, had been wanting to visit Buscalan since learning about Whang-Od three years ago. She finally went on the trip with a friend from the United States in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I feel like I&#39;m part of something,” said Kuehnl, who got the three dots tattooed on her left ankle. “I know that there&#39;s a history, that this tattoo was meant for men who fought to protect the land here, so at some point it feels a little conflicting, but it feels special.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seeing the legendary mambabatok at work brings a sense of awe and nervous excitement to visitors, who are made to sit on plastic stools as they wait their turn. The rhythmic tak tak tak sound of the tapping takes their mind off the pain that accompanies each jab.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tina Rose Gado, a 45-year-old Filipino assistant nurse, was with a group of six friends visiting from Canada.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I feel proud that I now have the mark of Whang-Od,” she said after getting inked on her left wrist. “I will really show this off.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whang-Od has prepared for death, picking a spot for her grave, near the back of her house where she gives tattoos. She said she has lived a good life, but joked that it would have been better if she had a husband and children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A foreigner she tattooed once asked her to marry him, but she turned him down: “I&#39;m too old for that stuff. I&#39;m dying,” she says, giggling. “It&#39;s hilarious to even think of an old woman getting married.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whang-Od said she hopes that people continue to visit Buscalan to get traditional tattoos even after she dies, keeping the tradition and her memory alive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If I die, then I die,” she said. “But it would be great if people would still come. As long as people will come, we will give them tattoos.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Julian Sands: human remains found in California confirmed as belonging to missing actor]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225642/julian-sands-human-remains-found-california-confirmed-belonging-missing-actor?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 05:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/5b43dbf1-5ef9-48bb-a560-69e25695974b_25626441.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Julian Sands, whose body was identified on Tuesday after he disappeared in January while hiking in California, was a British actor who shot to fame as the romantic hero in 1980s period drama A Room with a View.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 65-year-old vanished on the 10,000-ft (3,000-metre) Mount San Antonio, known locally as Mount Baldy. Last weekend hikers there found human remains, with police confirming on Tuesday they belonged to Sands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 65-year-old&#39;s breakout role was plain-speaking George Emerson in the Oscar-winning 1985 adaptation of EM Forster&#39;s novel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the hit film from producer-and-director duo Merchant Ivory (Ismail Merchant and James Ivory), he seduced the prim heroine, played by Helena Bonham Carter, in sun-drenched Tuscany. He also stripped off for a memorable skinny-dipping scene.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sands had already appeared as a British photographer in Roland Joffe&#39;s 1984 Oscar-winning drama set in Cambodia, The Killing Fields.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a varied subsequent career, Sands appeared in films as diverse as Frank Marshall&#39;s 1990 spider-themed horror romp Arachnophobia, David Cronenberg&#39;s controversial Naked Lunch and alcohol-soaked 1995 drama Leaving Las Vegas, directed by Mike Figgis and starring Nicolas Cage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sands told The Guardian newspaper in 2018 of his career choices: “I didn&#39;t want to become a Hollywood actor” and “I was looking for something exotic, things that took me out of myself”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was equally passionate about mountain climbing, telling The Guardian that he is happiest “close to a mountain summit on a glorious cold morning”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Human remains found near where actor Julian Sands went missing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The closest he had come to death was “in the early 90s, in the Andes, caught in an atrocious storm above 20,000ft with three others,” Sands told the Guardian in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We were all in a very bad way. Some guys close to us perished; we were lucky.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With angular good looks, Sands often veered towards darker roles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He starred as a son of Satan in 1989 low-budget horror film Warlock – alongside Richard E Grant as a witch-hunter – while his television roles included an appearance as a villain in US action series 24.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sands also made critically acclaimed theatre appearances, including playing former British Prime Minister Tony Blair in David Hare&#39;s play Stuff Happens at London&#39;s National Theatre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also starred in a one-man show celebrating British playwright Harold Pinter, directed by his friend John Malkovich and first staged at the Edinburgh Festival in 2011.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Actor Julian Sands missing in California mountains&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sands told The Washington Post newspaper in 2015 that Pinter “was seminal in my desire to want to be an actor, even as a high school student in the 1970s.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The actor grew up in Yorkshire in northern England. His mother was a secretary and his father did agricultural soil surveys.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He studied at the renowned Central School of Speech and Drama in London.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the success of A Room with a View, Sands moved to Los Angeles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He married writer Evgenia Citkowitz in 1990. He leaves behind three children including a son with his previous wife, British journalist Sarah Sands.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>