<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Dozens of Hong Kong tourists stuck in Okinawa seek help from city authorities as Typhoon Khanun knocks out power, disrupts flights]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3229810/dozens-hongkongers-stranded-okinawa-seek-help-city-authorities-typhoon-khanun-knocks-out-power?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 11:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/03/4a65a8a3-0e35-4165-9223-cda58b5dc402_a2f55e1d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台风卡农造成广泛影响后，数十名滞留在冲绳的香港人向移民当局寻求帮助日本县的旅行和电力中断，一些居民留在酒店里，没有电。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至周三晚间，已有 36 名居民联系香港入境事务处，请求帮助寻找交通和住宿，但日本政府周四上午表示，据报告安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台风卡努（以泰语“菠萝蜜”的意思命名）周三导致日本西南部县超过 20 万户家庭断电。该地区是香港人喜爱的旅游目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;台风卡农席卷日本冲绳，袭击中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;总部位于香港的东瀛旅行社告诉《华盛顿邮报》，三趟航班有 74 名旅客在暴风雨摧毁了该地区的电线后，其大部分行程都被困在一家没有电的酒店里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚这 74 名旅客中是否有人曾联系过香港出入境当局。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“旅行者显然不能走到街上。该旅游公司执行董事禤国全表示：“我们已为受影响的游客提供免费住宿，并正在照顾他们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;禤国全表示，一些旅游团成员原本预计会乘飞机回家早在8月1日，冲绳首府机场就因暴风雨而关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;暴风雨还干扰了原定于周四从冲绳县起飞的两架香港航空航班，另有两架航班已安排在一天后，从那霸接旅客回家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三和周四，香港快运航空的另外四个航班也受到风暴的影响。该航空公司已在周五增加四趟航班接载旅客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;禤恩表示，预计其中一个旅行团将于周四如期起飞，而另外两个旅行团将乘坐额外的航班。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;卡努转变为台风，菲律宾预计将出现大雨&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;日本国土交通省早些时候表示，那霸机场关闭后，周二和周三共有 951 架航班被取消，35 条渡轮线路暂停运营.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本气象厅将这场风暴描述为“非常强”，周四上午的最大风速为 157 公里/小时（98 英里/小时），并正在缓慢向该国西南部岛屿移动。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mobile chip giant Qualcomm shares slide amid planned job cuts as smartphones face worst slump in years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3229811/mobile-chip-giant-qualcomm-shares-slide-amid-planned-job-cuts-smartphones-face-worst-slump-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 11:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/03/6e82fa65-77c4-4c74-a959-4f4f1c95e0e9_1e9ddd65.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;最大的智能手机处理器制造商高通公司股价下跌高达 8.2%在给出本季度不温不火的销售预测后，尾盘交易中，这表明移动设备的需求仍然疲软。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高通公司周三表示，第四财季销售额将为 81 亿美元至 89 亿美元。一份声明。该范围的中点远低于分析师平均预期的 87.9 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一前景再次引发了人们对智能手机行业陷入多年来最严重衰退的担忧。高通及其芯片制造同行看到手机制造商的订单急剧下降，这些制造商的库存突然超过了他们的需要。高通高管在电话会议上表示，手机和其他电子产品零部件支出的减少将持续到今年年底。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;本周中国最大的人工智能会议在美国科技巨头中失去了光芒高通表示，该公司正在采取措施减少开支，尽管该公司正在投资新产品，以利用人工智能在智能手机上的传播。它已经在减少员工人数。上季度，高通记录了 2.85 亿美元的重组费用，其中大部分来自遣散费，并预计将进行更多裁员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们对市场持保守看法，并将积极采取额外的成本行动首席执行官克里斯蒂亚诺·阿蒙 (Cristiano Amon) 在电话会议上表示：“确保高通处于有利位置，在不确定的环境中为股东创造最大价值。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财报公布后，股价在盘后交易中跌至 118.71 美元公告。在该报告发布之前，高通公司的股价今年已上涨约 18%。这落后于芯片行业的整体上涨，费城证券交易所半导体指数在 2023 年上涨约 47%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扣除某些项目，本期每股利润将为 1.80 美元至 2 美元，高通表示。相比之下，预测价格为 1.94 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个关键问题：最大的手机市场中国的需求尚未恢复到预期水平。该地区为该公司提供了 60% 以上的销售额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高通在财报中表示，总体而言，与 2022 年相比，今年的手机出货量将至少下降高个位数百分比，表明前景略有黯淡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由于仍难以预测持续复苏的时间，且客户对购买仍保持谨慎态度，因此我们继续假设库存下降动态将是一个这家芯片制造商在演示中表示：“这一因素将持续到年底。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿蒙正在努力减少他的公司对不可靠的智能手机市场的依赖。这家总部位于圣地亚哥的公司增加了汽车、网络、计算和可穿戴设备芯片的销量，但其一半以上的收入仍然来自手机行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司的主要产品是处理器运行许多世界上最知名的手机。它还销售将苹果 iPhone 连接到高速数据网络的调制解调器芯片。高通公司的另一大部分利润来自支撑所有现代移动网络的基础技术的许可——无论手机制造商是否使用高通品牌芯片，他们都需要支付费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿蒙证实，高通的调制解调器将在新版 iPhone 将于今年晚些时候推出，但拒绝评论是否会继续在未来型号中提供这一关键组件。彭博社报道称，苹果公司正在开发自己的调制解调器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至 6 月 25 日的第三财季，利润下降至每股 1.87 美元。收入下降 23% 至 84.5 亿美元。分析师预计利润为 1.81 美元，销售额为 85.1 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;手机相关销售额为 52.6 亿美元，而平均预期为 54.8 亿美元。汽车收入较上年同期增长至 4.34 亿美元，低于预期的 4.48 亿美元。联网设备的销售额符合 15 亿美元的预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style= “color:orange” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hunter Biden made millions amid ‘nonstop debauchery’, plea agreement says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3229805/hunter-biden-made-millions-amid-nonstop-debauchery-plea-agreement-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 10:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/03/a59338e0-f848-4beb-a8fe-f24c79dc9622_ae2dc68e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;亨特·拜登从一家中国私营乌克兰能源公司赚取了超过 400 万美元根据他对联邦税收指控提出的认罪协议，拜登的认罪草案于 6 月宣布，但实际协议仅达成美国地区法官玛丽莲·诺雷卡 (Maryellen Noreika) 应媒体要求下令启封该协议，并于周三公开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该交易将导致总统的儿子承认轻罪指控且不服刑，但在该交易被搁置后诺雷卡上周对这些条款提出了质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登与特拉华州联邦检察官之间的协议中包含了一份证据，详细列出了他在 2017 年和 2018 年的收入，这两年他未能支付收入税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共和党人批评拟议的认罪是甜心交易，他们利用亨特·拜登赚到的数百万美元来辩称他的父亲也一定受益了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登周三没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登首次公开承认第七孙子、亨特的女儿&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2017 年，拜登的收入超过 230 万美元其中100万美元来自他与一家中国企业集团首席执行官成立的公司，66.4万美元来自一家中国基础设施投资公司，50万美元来自一家乌克兰能源公司，7万美元来自一家罗马尼亚企业，4.8万美元来自一家国际公司律师事务所和国内商业利益的 666,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭文件中没有指明他的收入来源，但拜登承认与中国华信能源公司、乌克兰能源公司 Burisma 和法律的关系Boies, Schiller &amp; Flexner 公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登在 2018 年赚取了超过 210 万美元。根据协议，这些高收入是在他的毒瘾持续恶化的情况下实现的。这些文件引用了拜登自己的回忆录，他在回忆录中描述了 2018 年“一个不停放荡的春夏”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据协议，拜登从他聘请的一名会计师那里清楚地了解了自己的纳税义务。会计师准备了拜登的报表并发送给他审查和签名。尽管在会计师的一再鼓励下，拜登从未签署或提交申报表。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国共和党人调查总统之子亨特·拜登的艺术品销售&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据协议，拜登未能支付他的税款。尽管有钱这样做，但还是要纳税。到 2019 年 5 月，他已经把本可以用于此目的的钱“用于个人开支，包括大笔现金提取、给孩子或代表孩子的付款、信用卡余额以及保时捷的汽车付款”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021 年 10 月，法庭文件指出，拜登 2017 年和 2018 年的纳税义务分别为 955,800 美元和 956,632 美元，由身份不明的第三方支付。文件显示，该人还支付了 45,661 美元和 197,372 美元，以解决 2016 年和 2019 年未决的税务问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《纽约时报》今年早些时候报道称，好莱坞娱乐业律师凯文·莫里斯 (Kevin Morris) 借出了超过 2 美元向拜登提供 100 万美元，以帮助解决他的税务问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登提出的认罪协议还涵盖了因 2018 年持有手枪而产生的武器指控，尽管他知道自己沉迷于非法毒品。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s household debt creeps upward, approaching warning line of International Monetary Fund]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3229755/chinas-household-debt-creeps-upward-approaching-warning-line-international-monetary-fund?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/03/66a1338f-12a1-4927-8b3d-e9c107b259fc_706d5abf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国家庭报告负债不断上升，同时仍在努力摆脱经济不确定性的阴影就业和收入下降，导致国家经济放缓，并让人质疑北京的新消费推动是否真的能放松消费者的钱包。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师似乎更担心消费者的真实消费能力，因为他们的收入增长落后于经济扩张，他们更倾向于为抵押贷款、水电费、子女抚养和自己不确定的未来进行储蓄。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家家庭债务达到全国国内生产总值 (GDP) 的 63.5%根据国家金融与发展研究所 (NIFD) 7 月 23 日发布的报告，第二季度的增长率高于去年底的 61.9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;距离最终目标越来越近。此前国际货币基金组织曾将65%的红线作为金融风险预警点。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着中国债务风险的上升，局部危机迫在眉睫&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国的债务风险不断上升。家庭债务主要以抵押贷款形式存在，截至6月底达到38.6万亿元人民币（5.38万亿美元）；以及消费品贷款、信用卡债务、私人借款和用于为企业运营提供资金的贷款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“居民消费和投资的有效需求均下降，”两位经济学家张晓静和刘雷写道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张还是中国社会科学院金融研究所所长的政府顾问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“家庭支出疲弱是主要是由于他们的收入增长缓慢，最终导致经济增长缓慢。”他们表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2008 年北京政策制定者推出 4 万亿元人民币以来，中国的家庭杠杆率迅速上升。经济刺激计划和宽松货币政策应对金融危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2008年底杠杆率仅为17.9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际清算银行估计，中国家庭债务达到到去年年底，这一数字将达到 10.76 万亿美元，占其经济产出的 61.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到 2022 年底，这一比例已超过德国的 55.2%、印度的 36.4% 和印度的 47.7%。新兴经济体的平均水平为 50%，而中国目前的杠杆率正在快速接近美国 74.4% 和日本 68.2% 的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国居民负债水平过高，收入增长缓慢正在限制消费，但根据上周季度会议上表达的观点，中国政治局目前更多地依靠内需来拉动国家增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家发展和改革委员会还推出了 20本周早些时候出台的消费刺激措施，放松了汽车和房地产的限购，同时承诺改善国家的消费环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年消费对中国GDP增长的贡献率为32.8%，低于58.3% 2021年，市场主体和家庭受到零新冠管控的严重影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国尚未“走出困境”，经济希望取决于北京的帮助&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;第二个阶段今年第一季度，疫情期间消费对经济增长的贡献率为77.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管今年上半年中国居民储蓄增长了12万亿元，占总储蓄的67% 2022 年增长 - NIFD 报告将此归因于私人融资的增加和金融去杠杆的暂时停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于债务压力，居民更有可能使用储蓄来偿还债务报告称，由于“对未来经济增长的预期更为悲观”，他们更倾向于降低资产风险，而不是消费和投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济学人智库 (EIU) 在周二发布的一份研究报告中警告说，北京的经济增长房地产和大预算消费的提振可能效果有限，因为缺乏以家庭为中心的财政转移支付等果断行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于未来工资和就业机会普遍存在不确定性，中国消费者仍保持谨慎态度，这报告补充称，这可能会进一步拖累中国的经济势头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于三年的大流行，中国家庭正在修复资产负债表，许多人增加了储蓄，并专注于偿还现有的抵押贷款政府数据显示，第二季度中国未偿还抵押贷款同比下降 0.8%，这是十多年来的首次下降。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;经验证据还表明，住房购买量的下降可能会导致家电、装饰材料、汽车等其他大件产品的销售进一步下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管房地产资产萎缩，NIFD表示中国目前并未陷入困扰日本的资产负债表衰退。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的房子是用来投机的吗？北京放开了房地产&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是，如果北京允许私营部门自行修复债务，居民可能会进一步削减消费和投资来偿还债务，从而进一步减少企业盈利，从而导致企业盈利进一步减少。反过来，减少了居民的就业机会和收入以及政府税收。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该智库建议北京应增加债务发行量，同时更大幅度地降息，以减少巨额债务的利息支出.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至6月底，中国实体经济债务总额约为380万亿元人民币，占全国GDP的283.9%，高于2022年底以来的273.1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;仅降息1个百分点就可以减少近4万亿元的利息支付，这将显着提振中国低迷的经济。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk’s Tesla gains speed in India EV race as China’s BYD gets throttled]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3229808/elon-musks-tesla-gains-speed-india-ev-race-chinas-byd-gets-throttled?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 11:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/03/9a2262eb-7d06-430d-a90a-d4cbb8bf6d11_453e623f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国在印度的损失可能是埃隆·马斯克的收益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉因其在印度投资的提议而受到印度的红地毯欢迎，而其电动汽车领域最大的竞争对手中国比亚迪则因新德里加强审查而受到冷落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;结果对于特斯拉来说，这可能是一个机会，可以就进入全球第三大汽车市场的条款进行谈判，而无需像在泰国等其他新兴市场那样面临来自比亚迪的竞争威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“未来谁胜谁负世界经济论坛的贾斯米特·库拉纳 (Jasmeet Khurana) 表示：“印度的发展将决定谁在全球电动汽车竞赛中获胜。”自 6 月马斯克与印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪 (Narendra Modi) 在纽约会面以来，特斯拉与印度官员就潜在工厂投资进行了快速闭门讨论，并计划建造一款新的低成本 24,000 美元电动汽车。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“极其重要”：印度公司选择英国生产 50 亿美元电动汽车消息人士称，过去一周这些谈判仍在继续，特斯拉讨论了其进入印度快速增长的电动汽车市场的计划的细节，莫迪亲自跟踪事态发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;不过，这些会议一直严格保密，官员们没有在社交媒体上发布与高管握手的照片，否则这在高调会议后是很常见的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，比亚迪似乎出现了退居二线。据路透社报道，在为自己在印度的 10 亿美元投资寻求批准几个月后，比亚迪不再热衷于寻求批准。进一步的挫折是，比亚迪正面临印度对其少缴进口税的指控的调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除其他担忧外，印度官员还担心中国制造的汽车及其可能获取的数据对国家安全的影响。收集。一位官员表示，印度“对中国汽车制造商感到不安”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管自 2020 年两国边境冲突以来，来自中国的所有投资在印度都面临着更严格的审批要求，但这可能会对印度汽车制造商产生巨大影响。由于中国在电池材料、电池生产和其他技术方面占据主导地位，印度电动汽车市场不断发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉也有中国供应商帮助其降低上海工厂的生产成本，现在它希望将它们带到印度——印度在与新德里的谈判中似乎占据上风。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度已告诉特斯拉，如果中国供应商与当地公司建立合作伙伴关系（就像苹果公司一样），它将允许其中国供应商进入该国做过。但与此同时，印度对比亚迪的 10 亿美元计划犹豫不决，尽管该计划也是与一家国内工程公司合作提出的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国官方报纸《环球时报》称据报道，比亚迪投资计划遭到推迟“将导致连锁反应，并打击中国企业投资印度的整体信心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比亚迪没有回应就其投资状况置评的请求。印度投资计划或进口税索赔。该公司在一份声明中指出，该公司已活跃印度市场 16 年，并在那里销售商用车和乘用车。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国电动汽车为何在泰国引起轰动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;特斯拉没有回应就其与印度官员会谈发表评论的请求。马斯克曾在 6 月表示，莫迪“正在推动我们在印度进行重大投资，这是我们打算做的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉希望到 2030 年在全球销售 2000 万辆汽车，高于 2019 年的 131 万辆。 2022 年，但在扩大上海工厂方面面临障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比亚迪是 2022 年全球最大的电动汽车和插电式混合动力汽车销售商，销量总计 186 万辆，其中绝大多数在中国。在纯电动汽车销量方面，它落后于特斯拉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“特斯拉认为主要竞争对手是比亚迪，而两家公司都在全球范围内高速扩张，”标准普尔全球移动公司的 Gaurav Vangaal 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“如果他们想要销量，就必须来到印度，”他说，并补充说，随着政府鼓励公司在当地生产电动汽车，印度也可以作为出口基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;年产量根据标准普尔全球移动公司的估计，到 2030 年，印度的轻型电动汽车产量预计将增至 140 万辆，接近预测总产量 725 万辆的 19%。到 2022 年，这一数字还不到 50,000 辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度新兴的电动汽车市场由本土企业塔塔汽车公司主导，其最畅销的 Nexon 电动汽车售价高达 19,000 美元，而中国汽车制造商 MG Motor 的 ZS EV 起价为 28,000 美元，而中国汽车制造商 MG Motor 的 ZS EV 起价为 28,000 美元。比亚迪 Atto 3 在印度的零售价约为 41,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丰田汽车、现代汽车和起亚均销售中型汽油 SUV，价格约为 24,000 美元，这是特斯拉确定的切入点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特斯拉目前不在印度销售车辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“特斯拉已经成为一款名副其实的理想产品，”AutoForecast Solutions 的 Sam Fiorani 表示。 “再加上一款专为印度市场量身定制的价格实惠的产品，它有可能在当地大受欢迎。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Dozens killed in week of deadly police operations in Brazil]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3229801/dozens-killed-week-deadly-police-operations-brazil?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 10:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/03/41665793-dedd-4233-82ad-53d4c7427090_0da5ab61.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三，里约热内卢警方针对犯罪团伙采取的行动中有 9 人死亡当局称，这是巴西安全部队一周以来的最新一次突袭行动，已造成巴西各地至少 44 人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;里约突袭行动是在警方连续几天对贩毒团伙进行致命镇压后进行的，该团伙已造成 16 人死亡。圣保罗州和东北部巴伊亚州有 19 人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;里约州警方表示，警察在对 Complexo da Penha 贫民窟的有组织犯罪头目会议进行突袭时遭到袭击，随后开枪还击。 ，位于该市北侧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越来越多的呼吁要求当局对巴西警察滥用职权的指控进行独立调查，巴西安全部队被指控在与全副武装的贩毒团伙的战争中侵犯人权。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;警方表示，里约行动是在警方收到有关帮派领导人举行高层会议的情报后采取的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当警察队伍在现场遭到枪手袭击时，发生了冲突。”州警方在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;游客逃离墨西哥豪华海滩度假村附近的致命枪战&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“11 名嫌疑人受伤”并被送往医院。 “其中九人因伤死亡。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两名警察也受伤，目前情况稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;居民将贫民窟描述为战区场景在突袭期间，当地人蜷缩在家里——大多是紧紧挤在山坡上的小棚屋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“企业都关门了。人们无法离开家送孩子上学。 “你必须躲在安全的地方，等待枪击结束，”一位不愿透露姓名的居民告诉环球电视台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方表示，附近已经设置了临时路障，以阻止枪击事件的发生。缓慢的警察前进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还说，他们在行动中缴获了七支突击步枪、手榴弹和弹药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方称，死者包括两名帮派头目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们没有报告任何逮捕事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;里约州议员丹尼·蒙泰罗 (Dani Monteiro) 指出，此次行动是在 2022 年 5 月对同一贫民窟实施突袭行动一年多后进行的，这次突袭造成 25 人死亡，是死亡人数第二多的警察&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她称这次袭击为“屠杀”，并批评了里约州州长克劳迪奥·卡斯特罗（Claudio Castro），他是安全强硬派，也是极右翼前总统雅伊尔·博尔索纳罗（Jair Bolsonaro）的盟友。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; “萨尔瓦多独裁者”因向帮派发动战争而广受欢迎&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“卡斯特罗（的）安全政策必须停止！”左翼 PSOL 党议员蒙泰罗在 X（以前称为 Twitter）上写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在圣保罗，州警方于周五发起了大规模的反帮派行动，这是 30 年来的反帮派行动后的第二天。一名老特种部队军官在港口城市瓜鲁雅巡逻时被枪杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局周三表示，迄今为止，已有 16 名犯罪嫌疑人在当地正在进行的行动中被打死，更新了此前的 14 人死亡人数。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在东北部巴伊亚州，官员同时表示，自周五以来，三个不同城市的 19 名嫌疑人在与警方的冲突中被杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局表示，在所有案件中，警方都进行了还击&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，这些杀戮引起了巴西人权组织的批评，巴西经常指控安全部队滥用权力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;圣保罗行动显示出“明显的迹象”国际特赦组织表示，“居民指控警察虐待、恐吓和酷刑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该人权组织严厉批评圣保罗博尔索纳罗的另一位盟友、州长塔西西奥·德弗雷塔斯 (Tarcisio de Freitas) “使警察暴力合法化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;左翼总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦 (Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva) 的司法部长弗拉维奥·迪诺 (Flavio Dino) 也批评了这次行动，称警方的反应“不据监督组织公共安全论坛称，去年，在拥有 2 亿人口的巴西，有 6,429 人被警察杀害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 10:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s services activity expands at quicker pace in July, lifted by summer travel season]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3229800/chinas-services-activity-expands-quicker-pace-july-lifted-summer-travel-season?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/03/9404e21d-8591-451c-bb49-ec6131e61e5b_8d701ae3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;7 月份中国服务业活动扩张速度略快，主要得益于周四的一项私营部门商业调查显示，夏季旅游旺季的业务增长，部分抵消了制造业疲软的拖累。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财新/标普全球服务业采购经理人指数（PMI）升至54.1从 6 月的 53.9 上升到 7 月，标志着整个服务业的商业活动连续第七个月扩张。 50 点的分界线区分了活动的扩张和收缩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该数据与周一的官方调查形成鲜明对比，后者显示服务业活动继续疲软。分析师表示，接受调查的公司构成和方法论的不同可能是造成这种差异的原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年年底突然取消严格的冠状病毒限制措施后，世界第二大经济体在第一季度实现了强劲反弹，但随着国内外需求减弱，近几个月复苏迅速消退。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几周当局推出了一系列政策措施来支持疲软的复苏，但细节很少，投资者正在期待&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政策方面，保就业、稳预期、增加居民收入仍是首要任务。”财新智库高级经济学家王哲表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;私人调查显示，各公司表示，经营状况的改善、客户数量的增加和新产品的发布推动了第三季度初的销售额。新业务分项指数较6月份有所回升，但仍低于系列平均水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师表示，夏季旅游可能有助于相关消费，尽管一些大件商品的销售仍然不温不火，使得7月份的情况有所改善。零售额喜忧参半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“入夏以来，顾客数量比去年同期增长了60%至70%。”杭州一家民宿服务的吴姓接待员说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更好的销售鼓励企业以自 3 月份以来最快的速度扩大薪资数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，企业的积极情绪水平降至八个月低点并下降低于系列长期趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;费用的持续增长和需求的改善导致公司的价格进一步上涨，尽管一些人表示竞争的市场压力限制了他们的定价能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;财新/标准普尔综合 PMI（包括制造业和服务业活动）从 6 月份的 52.5 降至 51.9，连续第七个月扩张。然而，增速是1月份以来的最低水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“服务业和制造业复苏不平衡是一个突出问题，”经济学家王说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia mulls banning WeChat from government devices amid ‘national security risks’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3229772/australia-mulls-banning-wechat-government-devices-amid-national-security-risks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/02/9bfc112b-0dd2-4a23-a7b5-4ecaf72b7941_dad16299.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国通讯应用程序微信不同意澳大利亚议会报告中的描述方式, including being singled out alongside TikTok as having “unique national security risks”, but said it would continue to work with Canberra over its concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday, an Australian inquiry into foreign interference through social media laid down its findings, which included recommendations on banning WeChat on government devices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, Australia banned TikTok on government devices in line with its Western allies including the United States and Britain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ We are reviewing the committee&#39;s report and recommendations in detail. As we communicated to the Senate committee, WeChat is committed to protecting user privacy and providing its users with a safe, secure and diverse platform for communicating with friends, family and businesses,” WeChat said in a statement to This Week in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Australians see benefits of strong China ties but want Chinese apps banned: poll&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;WeChat told the inquiry committee through a written response last week that it had never been asked by Beijing to spy on users.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The inquiry report also recommended that all major social media platforms in Australia be made to maintain a presence in the country, and to consider following the US in separating TikTok Australia from its Chinese parent ByteDance, should Washington be successful in doing so.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It criticised WeChat for not appearing at inquiry hearings, and TikTok for not providing witnesses sought by the committee, but praised platforms based in Western countries such as Google and Meta, which “at least recognised the fundamental importance of the checks and balances inherent in democratic systems”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report outlined the dangers of China-linked apps, which could be made to “secretly cooperate with Chinese intelligence agencies”, although it said there was “equally serious risk of Western social media companies being weaponised by authoritarian regimes to pump disinformation” into Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report has also asked Canberra to establish “a national security technology office” to “map existing exposure to high-risk vendors such as TikTok, WeChat and any similar apps”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The inquiry and report underscores specific concerns by Canberra and Australians about the Chinese government&#39;s ability to use social media to advance its political interests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Surveys such as those by the independent Australia-China Relations Institute have shown that a majority of Australians want to ban WeChat and TikTok due to their links to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But experts like Greg Austin, a cybersecurity expert on Russia and China, said while the concerns over foreign interference through such apps were crucial, the inquiry&#39;s report was flawed with parts of it being “hysterical”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The inquiry, in one sense, was an important thing to do, but I think that even at first glance it&#39;s pretty plain that it is targeted more at China than other countries which engage in political interference. It reveals a lack of sophisticated understanding of what matters in the world,” said Austin, who is also an adjunct professor at the University of Technology Sydney and a co-founder of Social Cyber Group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What&#39;s not proven in almost any of the documentation [of the inquiry] that there&#39;s a clear link between ownership and covert influence operations. For example, if one studies WeChat, one can find evidence of Chinese covert influence operations, but one can also find evidence of American covert influence operations directed directly to China.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Austin said it was irrelevant who owns the apps, as intelligence agencies could exploit any social media system for influence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A ban by Australia on WeChat would not stop other countries like Russia, Israel and the US from conducting covert influence operations in Australia … it will not stop China from conducting covert influence operations in Australia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;WeChat tells Australian inquiry China has never asked to spy on users&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The chairperson presiding over the inquiry, prominent China hawk Australian senator James Paterson, however, told the senate on Tuesday that the ability for a social media platform to be weaponised depended on the laws of the country where it is headquartered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other senators in the inquiry committee said – in additional comments within the report – they did not support the targeting of specific platforms as “they do nothing to protect Australians from foreign interference”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Banning TikTok or any other singular platform from government devices is nothing but a game of digital whack-a-mole and does nothing to protect Australians,” Greens senators Sarah Hanson-Young and David Shoebridge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Labor Senators Jess Walsh and Raff Ciccone said regulation and transparency were more important than specific targets, and any new bans should “be informed by advice from agencies”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report made a reference to a submission by two academics who said a ban on WeChat for example would hurt Australia&#39;s democracy, but did not mention submissions that social media platforms in Western liberal democracies had been found culpable of invading users&#39; privacy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week, an Australian court fined Facebook owner Meta – which attended the inquiry&#39;s hearings – A$20 million for collecting user data through a smartphone application without disclosing its actions. The fine wraps up one strand of Meta&#39;s legal issues in Australia linked to the global scandal over its use of data analytics firm Cambridge Analytica in the 2016 US election, according to Reuters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta told This Week in Asia it was currently reviewing the inquiry&#39;s report.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Former HKEX CEO’s firm Micro Connect launches fundraising platform for small Chinese businesses after capital infusion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3229791/former-hkex-ceos-firm-micro-connect-launches-fundraising-platform-small-chinese-businesses-after?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/02/08f48bb3-ad8d-47c0-aeca-f9750c4c1624_0ff4e134.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Micro Connect, an investment platform co-founded by the former boss of Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX), Charles Li Xiaojia, will on Thursday afternoon officially launch its Macau exchange that aims to help small Chinese companies raise funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official launch of the Micro Connect Macau Financial Assets Exchange (MCEX) comes on the company&#39;s second birthday and one day after it announced that it raised US$458 million in its Series C funding round, bringing its valuation to US$1.7 billion. Micro Connect has raised US$578 million in three funding rounds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The strong shareholder base and the new capital raised will support Micro Connect&#39;s effort to enhance MCEX&#39;s market structure and develop the world&#39;s largest financial market for micro and small business investing,” the company said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MCEX is not a traditional bourse as it does not trade stocks or bonds, but a new asset class called daily revenue obligations (DROs). Institutional investors can buy DRO units, which fund China&#39;s micro and small businesses in exchange for part of their daily revenue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The new exchange of Micro Connect should be able to help small companies in the mainland to get funding as they usually cannot get bank loans easily,” said Tom Chan Pak-lam, permanent honourable president of the Institute of Securities Dealers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It will also help Macau to diversify its economy by having more financial activities.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its oversubscribed Series C funding round, Micro Connect attracted investments from Sequoia Capital China, Lenovo Capital, Vectr Fintech and Dara Holdings, which also took part in its previous funding rounds. Edinburgh-headquartered Baillie Gifford is a new investor as of the latest round.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ex-boss of HKEX links overseas investors to mainland China&#39;s small firms via Macau&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Other investors from Europe, North America, the Middle East and Greater China are long-only investment managers, private equity and venture funds, university endowments, internet platforms and consumer retail groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li, 62, co-founded Micro Connect with financier Gary Zhang in August 2021 after leaving HKEX in December 2020. Its aim is to fund small businesses that fail to qualify for bank loans for expansion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The potential universe of such businesses in mainland China includes 40 million small and medium-sized enterprises and 90 million self-employed individuals, according to central government data from 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The exchange had a soft launch in March with 890 million yuan (US$124 million) worth of DROs available for trade by the platform&#39;s members, including banks, insurance companies, pension funds or other collective investment schemes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MCEX members have so far invested US$238 million in 9,000 stores in 198 mainland China cities, covering industries including food and drink, retail, culture and sports, according to its website.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong virtual bank Ping An OneConnect to expand lending to retail SMEs&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The trading platform is the second to launch in Macau after Namkwong (Group) established Chongwa (Macau) Financial Asset Exchange in August 2018 for bond offerings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These developments came after Beijing announced a raft of policies in December 2019 to diversify Macau&#39;s economy by building its financial-services industry. Among those policies is a plan to set up a Nasdaq-like stock exchange with trading denominated in yuan, but no launch date has been announced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said Hong Kong should clear the way to host exchanges like MCEX.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is a shame that this new exchange is not set up in Hong Kong, but in Macau,” he said. “Our regulators may need to review regulations to make it easier for new platforms to be set up in Hong Kong to raise funds.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 09:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Box office hit Oppenheimer tipped to be summer blockbuster in China amid pre-release hype and nude scene controversy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3229479/box-office-hit-oppenheimer-tipped-be-summer-blockbuster-china-amid-pre-release-hype-and-nude-scene?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/31/4300cf36-6cc6-498b-bb2c-f14c49c90ea9_6d93435f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Christopher Nolan&#39;s blockbuster film Oppenheimer has set off a wave of excitement among moviegoers in China ahead of the movie&#39;s scheduled release in the country later this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On July 25, Universal Pictures&#39; official account on Weibo – China&#39;s Twitter-like social media platform – announced that the film is set to open on August 30.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The highly-anticipated news for the director&#39;s large mainland fanbase arrived days after the movie&#39;s premiere in Hong Kong on July 20, and global opening on July 21.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thousands of people welcomed the announcement on Weibo, with one person commenting: “Better late than never.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The news has shocked some who thought its mainland release was “out of the question” due to the R rating it received in the United States for sexuality, nudity and language.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some people also feared that its anti-Communist content would not pass muster with strict political censorship rules in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The biopic starring Cillian Murphy, Emily Blunt and Matt Damon focuses on the life of J. Robert Oppenheimer, the theoretical physicist who led the Manhattan Project that developed the first nuclear weapons, and is known as the “father of the atomic bomb”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The film also features a hearing held after World War II, during which Oppenheimer was charged for his past Communist affiliations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Film critic influencer, Guangying Xintiandi, said in his blog that the news means the film has passed the censorship test, adding however, that “it is unknown whether the mainland version will alter lines or captions.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Expectations for the film have also been high on mainland social media as the Manhattan Project led to atomic bombs being dropped on the Japanese cities of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, which arguably resulted in Japan&#39;s unconditional surrender and the end of its invasion of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for the nude scenes, some social media observers speculate that the mainland version will copy what was done in India and the Middle East by adding a CGI black dress on topless Jean Tatlock, played by Florence Pugh, in a sex scene.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was better done this way than pruning the whole scene,” said one online observer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person guessed the nude scenes would be cropped so there was no “sensitive content” left, referring to the famous example of Chinese actress Fan Bingbing&#39;s 2014 television series Saga of Wu Zetian, in which the cleavages of female characters were expunged, leaving only close-up headshots.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Calls for a film rating system in mainland China have also been reignited online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Christopher Nolan has built a dedicated fanbase on the mainland thanks to his hit sci-fi features Inception and Interstellar, both of which made the top 10 of the Douban Top 250 Film List - algorithmically ranked according to over 170 million ratings and reviews left by users of the country&#39;s best-known ratings site.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Interstellar earned US$122 million in China, accounting for 26 per cent of the worldwide box office in 2014, according to Forbes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some mainlanders have travelled to Hong Kong to watch Oppenheimer even after the mainland release was announced in order to “watch the full version and watch it sooner”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While film influencers spread the news that several Hong Kong cinemas will exclusively screen the 35mm film of the movie in Asia, some film fans also opted for Hong Kong cinemas for a finer visual experience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong Broadway Circuit has also arranged a special 35mm screening for mainland filmgoers this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the fact that China limits the number of overseas films imported each year, mainland filmgoers took advantage of the annual Beijing and Shanghai film festivals, during which hundreds of classic and latest foreign films are screened across the two cities&#39; theatres.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another hyped blockbuster Barbie, which sparked the worldwide “Barbenheimer” phenomenon, coined because of the films&#39; similar release dates, hit mainland theatres on July 21 and instantly took off to rave reviews, especially from feminists.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese scientists calculate 1 billion-tonne carbon dioxide emissions cost of Canadian wildfires]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3229730/chinese-scientists-calculate-1-billion-tonne-carbon-dioxide-emissions-cost-canadian-wildfires?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/02/b0cac093-334b-4d9f-84f8-773fda4aeff8_43607fae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese scientists estimate that the recent Canadian wildfires caused 1 billion tonnes of carbon dioxide emissions by July 27, far exceeding Canada&#39;s greenhouse gas emissions from human activity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The area burned in Canada&#39;s fire season this year is the largest on record, according to the Canadian Interagency Forest Fire Centre (CIFFC). It reported that by the end of July, 129,800 sq km (50,100 square miles) of land had burned so far this year, compared to 14,700 sq km for the whole of 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The emissions from the wildfires are nearly double those of Canada&#39;s total greenhouse gas emissions from human activity in 2021, based on figures from the government&#39;s Environment and Climate Change Canada.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese Academy of Sciences (CAS) reported that the Institute of Applied Ecology (IAE) scientists involved in the research used remote sensing to assess rapid emissions based on emission intensity and the area burned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Zhihua, an expert in forest fires at the IAE and lead on the study, said emissions from these fires “have an undeniable impact on global climate warming”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scientists also estimated that the greenhouse effect of nitrous oxide and methane emitted from the fires is equivalent to 110 million tonnes of carbon dioxide. With the burning of permafrost, further stored methane could be released.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2022, the government agency Natural Resources Canada (NRCan) predicted that the area burned by the end of the century could double the amount of recent decades. The area burned this year already exceeds that prediction.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How wildfire smoke disrupts local weather – and fuels more extreme blazes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;NRCan said the increase in wildfires – particularly in the northwestern boreal region – was attributed in part to climate change and consequently wildfires were expected to keep increasing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The occurrence of wildfires “exceeded the scope of a natural change”, Liu told Chinese state-run media outlet CGTN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The biodiversity loss and destruction of vegetation from rapidly burning fires and the exposure of soil after a blaze can lead to secondary issues such as erosion and landslides, according to the CAS.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beyond the release of greenhouse gases, the release of pollutants such as the small air particles PM2.5 and PM10 and black carbon from the fires also have an impact on both human and environmental health, according to the Institute of Applied Ecology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The researchers said that from June 6 to 19 the shifting air pollutants caused New York City to experience its worst air pollution since 1960.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Wildfires sparked &#39;Great Dying&#39; of 250 million years ago, Chinese study confirms&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US Environmental Protection Agency&#39;s PM2.5 standard for a 24-hour average is 35 micrograms per cubic metre, but according to the researchers, during the worst periods the levels exceeded 50 micrograms per cubic metre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Zhe, a member of the research team at the Institute of Atmospheric Physics under the CAS, said the wildfire disaster was a global event because the pollutants not only travelled around North America but also to Europe, North Africa and Asia with westerly circulation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang told CGTN the full impact of the fires “will definitely be much more serious than the existing data”.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 03 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>