<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Former Japanese prime minister Taro Aso arrives in Taiwan to give keynote speech at regional security forum]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3230288/former-japanese-prime-minister-taro-aso-arrives-taiwan-give-key-note-speech-regional-security-forum?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/12fc143f-2d17-4616-b257-519962a81573_4bd59b01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本前首相麻生太郎抵达台湾进行为期三天的访问这次访问肯定会激怒北京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为执政党自民党的副主席，这位长期直言不讳的台湾支持者是该党中访问过台湾的最高级别政治人物。自1972年日本与台北断交以来，麻生太郎一行在送行后于周一抵达台北松山机场，其成员包括日本国会议员铃木圭介和中西健二。台湾事实上的驻日大使谢长廷从东京接见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[自民党]副总裁麻生太郎的访问不仅代表了台湾与日本之间的牢固关系，也表明双方将台湾外交部表示，但没有详细说明具体是哪些领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麻生太郎预计将与台湾总统蔡英文、副总统赖清德、据外务省称，外交部长吴钊燮、前立法院院长王金平和台北市市长蒋万安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外务省表示，麻生太郎将于周二在一个地区安全论坛上发表主题演讲。周一，麻生太郎和他的代表团在新北的已故台湾总统李登辉的坟墓前向他致敬。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为其领土，必须将其置于其控制之下，必要时可以使用武力。它警告承认北京而不是台北的国家不要与这个自治岛屿进行官方接触。包括美国在内的大多数国家都不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对任何单方面武力改变两岸现状的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;全球前七大经济体中，亚洲占据了五席。强大的海军。新加坡排名第24位&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;麻生太郎的访问预计会激怒北京，北京长期以来一直对他的反北京言论感到不满，包括他在过去两年中宣称台湾的突发事件是日本的突发事件的言论。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麻生太郎在 2021 年 7 月的政党筹款活动中表示，如果台湾遭到入侵，日本需要与美国一起保卫台湾，因为“如果台湾发生重大问题，说这可能与日本面临“生存威胁”的情况并不过分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，这种情况是日本行使其权利所需满足的条件之一集体自卫，或向遭受攻击的盟友提供援助。麻生太郎说：“我们需要认真思考冲绳可能会成为下一个。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他去年和今年早些时候发表了类似的言论，呼吁大幅加强日本的防御，以应对台湾可能遭受的攻击。他强调，这还可能导致包括冲绳在内的日本领土上的军事冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计北京将密切关注麻生太郎在台湾的讲话以及与高级官员的会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;麻生太郎访问之际，北京派遣数十架战机和军舰在台湾周围执行任务，加大了对台湾的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日早上 6 点到周一早上 6 点之间，24 架中国人民解放军战机和 7 架台北国防部周一表示，有军舰在台湾周围活动，其中有 12 艘军舰跨越台湾海峡分隔台湾岛和大陆的中线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，当地新闻媒体报道称，麻生太郎将与台湾会面台湾副总统兼总统竞选领先者赖智，如果他在一月份的竞选中当选，可能会了解他的政治观点和未来政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本和韩国能否在美国峰会上缔结“历史性”安全联盟？ &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;赖智是唯一一位尚未与麻生太郎交谈过的总统候选人。赖智的对手、主要反对党国民党新北市市长侯裕义和反对党台湾人民党党魁、前台北市市长柯文哲最近都在访问东京时会见了自民党副领导人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;麻生太郎四月在东京会见了台湾富士康创始人郭台铭。在访问日本之前，郭台铭曾寻求国民党提名竞选总统，但当该党于 5 月选择侯作为候选人时，他的尝试失败了。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: Huawei to revive smartphone business on the back of fresh AI-powered operating system even as US sanctions continue to bite]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3230293/tech-war-huawei-revive-smartphone-business-back-fresh-ai-powered-operating-system-even-us-sanctions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 20:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/26a04810-6c57-4a4b-9adf-1c05d88fcd1b_e7c28256.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;华为技术有限公司预计将凭借其曾经辉煌的智能手机业务重振雄风尽管这家被列入美国黑名单的公司继续面临 5G 芯片供应的不确定性和充满挑战的宏观经济环境，但鸿蒙操作系统仍进行了最新升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“华为的旗舰智能手机正在卷土重来，”华为首席执行官余承东说道。该公司消费者业务集团及其智能汽车解决方案业务部门的高管上周五在广东省东莞市举行的年度开发者大会上表示，HarmonyOS 4 是在该大会上发布的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;余的乐观评价根据研究公司 IDC 的数据，私人控股的华为在第二季度重新成为中国大陆排名前五的智能手机供应商。华为在 2020 年第二季度超越三星电子，成为全球最大的智能手机供应商，但由于美国制裁收紧，切断了其先进移动芯片的供应，该业务随后陷入困境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在其开发商处发布会上，华为表示，HarmonyOS 4 已与公司自有的生成式人工智能模型盘古集成，提供类似 ChatGPT 的服务，包括自动消息传递和创建图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HarmonyOS 4 预计还将增强对其他产品的支持智能电动汽车等设备是华为近年来瞄准的主要领域。余承东在大会上表示，鸿蒙操作系统现已连接超过 7 亿台设备，其生态系统拥有超过 220 万开发者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一最新进展反映了华为为加强其全球业务所付出的努力，因为美国的贸易制裁继续产生影响，在今年早些时候有报道称拜登政府希望切断该公司与所有美国供应商的联系后，该公司正在权衡如何应对美中脱钩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新消息Counterpoint Research 高级分析师 Ivan Lam 周一表示，HarmonyOS 的迭代对于华为的智能手机战略“至关重要”，华为的智能手机战略旨在改善软件方面的体验，以弥补硬件方面的某些劣势。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“HarmonyOS 的目标一直是……通过在配备不太先进芯片的华为设备上创造更流畅的体验来做出巨大贡献，”Lam 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HarmonyOS 首次亮相是作为替代操作系统2019 年 8 月，即华为被列入华盛顿实体名单三个月后。根据这份贸易黑名单，华为被禁止从美国供应商购买软件、芯片和其他技术，包括从谷歌购买Android平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去一年，华为成功保持了9至9%的相对稳定份额。据 Counterpoint 的 Lam 称，该公司在全球最大智能手机市场中国的份额为 12%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二季度，该公司在中国大陆的智能手机销量份额同比增长 58%，占 11.3% Counterpoint 数据显示，在产品发布步伐恢复的情况下，华为在国内市场的份额将有所提高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果华为能够保持稳定的市场份额，那么其增长势头就可以持续下去，尽管整体来看，华为的增长势头仍然强劲。” &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国智能手机市场季度跌幅收窄，华为重回前五&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;上半年华为在中国智能手机出货量总计 1,430 万部IDC 亚太区高级研究经理 Will Wong 表示，预计到 2023 年，与去年同期相比将增长近 40%，这得益于该行业高端市场的恢复力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“其中一个“产品发布速度加快的关键原因是华为在经历了多年美国制裁的负面影响后成功优化了供应链。”Wong 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，华为仍未能推出新产品自 2020 年底以来，华为一直在推出 5G 智能手机，并且在过去几年中错过了对其高端智能手机型号的几次更新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华为在中断一年多后于 4 月份恢复了旗舰 P 系列智能手机的发布。其最新的 Mate 系列手机在跳过 2021 年更新后于去年 9 月发布。但这两款机型仅支持 4G 连接。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;受到美国制裁的华为通过地方政府协议加强了对国内市场的关注&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;根据路透社上个月的一份报告，该公司预计将在今年年底恢复 5G 智能手机的发布，因为它从当地供应商那里获得了新的芯片供应，该报告援引了多家研究公司的话说消息来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管华为已经解决了某些供应链问题并采用了国产替代品，但 Counterpoint 的 Lam 表示，采购最新相机和 5G 芯片仍存在挥之不去的不确定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在最好的情况下如果华为采购5G芯片并用在旗舰机型上，会对华为带来小幅提振，但不足以带动其销量重回市场前三。” “即使解决了5G芯片问题，生产规模可能仍会受到限制。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange “ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China innovation hub Shenzhen poised to lead economic-rejuvenation drive with 55-point plan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3230273/china-innovation-hub-shenzhen-poised-lead-economic-rejuvenation-drive-55-point-plan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 19:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/1f250612-ab3c-437d-8718-cec69d5a6de2_fd58c7e7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国南方城市深圳正在加大力度改善当地市场环境，使其成为对投资者更具吸引力并提升该地区的实力，一位改革专家表示，这可以帮助该地区度过华盛顿的技术围攻，并为该国的经济转型打开新的大门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这座城市是中国改革开放的前沿周末发布了三份文件、55项措施，通过加强法治、吸引外商、对接领先贸易规则来优化营商环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寻求转向中国所谓的“一带一路”倡议。硅谷、深圳正计划进一步借鉴国际贸易规则和海外法律，吸引更多外资，为粤港澳大湾区建设奠定更坚实的基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国各级政府都在努力重振经济，而拥有科技巨头华为技术有限公司和互联网服务公司腾讯的深圳可以提供更多经验可供借鉴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它表示将升级其服务业和巩固制造业集群，让它们更多地融入全球供应链。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“只有穿鞋的人才知道鞋在哪里”：中国出口商的艰难时期&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该市寻求加强合作与港澳在法律、审计、咨询等方面加强合作，承诺到2025年现代服务业占服务业总值比重达到77%以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年，根据政府数据，这一数字为76.2%，比十年前高出12.4个百分点，但与2020年相比仅增长0.1个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深圳也誓言要成为投资中心&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“稳定外商在深圳的市场预期，引导外资投向先进制造业等重点领域……支持设立外资研究机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港旨在使贸易规则与国际领先标准接轨，特别是《跨太平洋伙伴关系全面进步协定》(CPTPP)中的标准），这是中国极力争取加入的最先进的贸易和投资协定之一，另外还有《数字经济伙伴关系协定》（DEPA）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深圳还致力于简化外国人才和数字经济的签证办理流程。文件显示，为海外居民支付费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“深圳进一步发展的核心需要是确保高科技产业尽可能好的营商环境。”广东省改革研究会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭说，“毕竟深圳是受贸易保护主义和科技脱钩打击最严重的地方。”他补充说，深圳摆脱华盛顿围困的最好办法是打造中国最佳营商环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭表示，深圳要加强与国际规则接轨，发挥好中国经济“典范和核心引擎”作用。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“这座城市应该为整个国家探索[经济转型]道路，”彭说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国关注东盟贸易关系，但成员国担心陷入“地缘政治陷阱”&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;深圳将探索粤港澳大湾区法治合作，打造外商解决海外商事纠纷主要目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;电动汽车制造商比亚迪总部所在地文件显示，深圳还旨在促进含锂电池货物的仓储和空运业务的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为无人机制造商大疆创新的所在地，深圳将探索未来新兴产业的立法，包括文件称，上半年，深圳国内生产总值同比增长6.3%，增速高于广东省根据政府数据，这一数字为 5%，而同期全国为 5.5%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[North Korean hackers ‘breach top Russian missile maker’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3230290/north-korean-hackers-breach-top-russian-missile-maker?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 19:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/52c0d817-98d9-48d4-a843-3231149eb302_57d320ff.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;朝鲜黑客精英组织秘密破坏了俄罗斯一家主要导弹开发商的计算机网络根据路透社审查的技术证据和安全研究人员的分析，去年至少有五个月的时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社发现与朝鲜政府有秘密联系的网络间谍团队（安全研究人员称之为 ScarCruft 和 Lazarus）在位于莫斯科郊区鲁托夫小镇的火箭设计局 NPO Mashinostroyeniya 的系统中安装了隐秘的数字后门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社无法确定入侵期间是否窃取了任何数据或获取了哪些信息可能已被查看。在数字入侵后的几个月里，平壤宣布了其被禁止的弹道导弹计划的几项进展，但尚不清楚这是否与此次入侵有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，这一事件表明这个孤立的国家将如何甚至瞄准其盟友，例如俄罗斯，以获取关键技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;NPO Mashinostroyeniya 没有回应路透社的置评请求。俄罗斯驻华盛顿大使馆没有回复通过电子邮件发送的置评请求。朝鲜驻纽约联合国代表团没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部长谢尔盖·绍伊古上个月访问平壤庆祝朝鲜成立 70 周年后不久，就传出了有关黑客攻击的消息。朝鲜战争，这是自 1991 年苏联解体以来俄罗斯国防部长首次访问朝鲜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目标公司（通常称为 NPO Mash）是导弹专家表示，高超音速导弹、卫星技术和新一代弹道武器——自朝鲜开始执行制造能够打击美国本土的洲际弹道导弹（ICBM）的任务以来，这三个领域一直是朝鲜非常感兴趣的领域。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;根据技术数据，入侵大致开始于 2021 年底，一直持续到 2022 年 5 月，根据路透社查阅的该公司内部通信，IT 工程师检测到了黑客的活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;NPO马什在冷战期间作为俄罗斯太空计划的主要卫星制造商和巡航导弹供应商而声名鹊起。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;黑客深入公司的 IT 环境，为他们提供了最初发现该漏洞的美国网络安全公司 SentinelOne 的安全研究员 Tom Hegel 表示，该漏洞具有读取电子邮件流量、在网络之间跳转和提取数据的能力。 Hegel 表示：“传统上，这些秘密网络行动一直隐藏在公众监督之外，或者根本不会被此类受害者发现。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hegel 的 SentinelOne 安全分析师团队在发现 NPO Mash IT 工作人员意外入侵后得知了此次黑客攻击。在试图通过将证据上传到全球网络安全研究人员使用的私人门户网站来调查朝鲜袭击事件时，泄露了公司的内部通信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当路透社联系该 IT 人员时，该 IT 人员拒绝发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;这一失误为路透社和 SentinelOne 提供了一家对俄罗斯国家至关重要的公司的独特快照，该公司在入侵克里米亚后受到奥巴马政府的制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两位独立计算机安全专家 Nicholas Weaver和马特·泰特（Matt Tait）审查了暴露的电子邮件内容并确认了其真实性。分析师通过根据 NPO Mash 控制的一组密钥检查电子邮件的加密签名来验证连接。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我对数据的真实性非常有信心，”Weaver 告诉路透社。 “信息的泄露方式绝对是一次搞笑的搞砸”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SentinelOne 表示，他们确信朝鲜是这次黑客攻击的幕后黑手，因为网络间谍重复利用了之前已知的恶意软件和恶意基础设施来执行其他活动入侵。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;世界上最强大的 7 个海军中有 5 个在亚洲。新加坡排名第 24 位&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2019 年，俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京称赞 NPO Mash 的“锆石”高超音速导弹是“有前途的新产品”，其飞行速度约为音速的九倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究朝鲜导弹计划外国援助的欧洲导弹专家马库斯·席勒 (Markus Schiller) 表示，朝鲜黑客可能已经获得了有关锆石的信息，但这并不意味着他们会立即拥有相同的能力。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“那是电影里的东西，”他说。 “获得计划对你建造这些东西没有多大帮助，它比一些图纸要重要得多。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，考虑到 NPO Mash 作为俄罗斯顶级导弹设计师和生产商的地位，该公司Schiller 补充道，这将是一个有价值的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们有很多值得学习的地方，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个令人感兴趣的领域可能是 NPO Mash 使用的制造工艺。周围的燃料，专家说。上个月，朝鲜试射了 Hwasong-18，这是其第一款使用固体推进剂的洲际弹道导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种加油方法可以在战争期间更快地部署导弹，因为它不需要加油发射台，使导弹在发射前更难跟踪和摧毁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;NPO Mash 生产一种名为 SS-19 的洲际弹道导弹，该弹道导弹在工厂加注燃料并密封关闭，这一过程称为“放大” ”这会产生类似的战略结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这很难做到，因为火箭推进剂，尤其是氧化剂，具有很强的腐蚀性，”詹姆斯·马丁防扩散研究中心的导弹研究员杰弗里·刘易斯说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“朝鲜宣布将在 2021 年底做同样的事情。如果 NPO Mash 有一件对他们有用的事情，那将是我的首要任务，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;朝鲜称美国的台湾武器援助将地区推向“战争的燃点”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，在朝鲜境内不寻常地看到一架俄罗斯军用飞机，引发了人们对金正恩正在向弗拉基米尔·普京出售武器的担忧随着受制裁国家之间关系的加强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;FlightRadar24 的跟踪数据显示，俄罗斯空军伊留申 IL-62M 于 7 月 31 日从莫斯科飞往平壤，并于 8 月 2 日返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卫星据总部位于首尔的朝鲜新闻提供商 NK News 报道，图像显示这架飞机在平壤国际机场停留了大约 36 个小时。该新闻还跟踪这个孤立国家的航班活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航班是第一架NK News 称，自 2019 年年中俄罗斯国防部副部长亚历山大·福明访问平壤以来，俄罗斯一直乘坐这种类型的俄罗斯军用贵宾飞机前往朝鲜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平壤因疫情于 2020 年初关闭了边境，俄罗斯和朝鲜都没有报告这架飞机的情况，也不清楚机上的人员是谁。俄罗斯国防部没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭博社的补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesia still keen to court Elon Musk, ‘not worried’ by Tesla’s Malaysia base]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3230284/indonesia-still-keen-court-elon-musk-not-worried-teslas-malaysia-base?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 19:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/3a47db92-b169-4aca-9c71-3d41b31a145c_21efe06f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着印度尼西亚持续多年努力争取亿万富翁埃隆·马斯克的投资，观察家们曾表示，该国巨大的镍储量可能不会像希望的那样具有巨大的吸引力，而其对化石燃料的依赖表明雅加达对其可再生能源的推动“并不完全认真”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luhut Pandjaitan，印度尼西亚能源协调部长海事和投资部部长上个月表示，他计划在 8 月 2 日访问加利福尼亚州期间与世界首富进行交谈，这是在该国寻求成为区域电动汽车制造中心之际，他已无数次尝试达成协议。 /p>;&lt;p>;虽然雅加达没有确认卢胡特最终是否会见了马斯克，但卫生部长布迪·萨迪金确实在 8 月 4 日与这位企业家会面，讨论与他的卫星网络 Starlink 的合作，为偏远地区提供低成本的互联网接入。群岛的保健中心。布迪周日表示：“通过互联网，可以在线进行医疗服务咨询。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雅加达顽强地发起魅力攻势，尽管这位商人决定将特斯拉东南亚总部设在邻近的雅加达，这让雅加达感到羞愧。该公司于 7 月 20 日在马来西亚开始运营，推出了 Model Y 和 Model 3 汽车，售价从 199,000 林吉特（43,600 美元）到 288,000 林吉特不等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多印度尼西亚出版物对这一发展持悲观态度。 ，称雅加达已被“冷落”，而《雅加达邮报》则表示印度尼西亚成为主要电动汽车制造商的窗口正在关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“乘飞机穿越世界以说服潜在投资者是一项崇高的努力，但有些事情印度尼西亚的报价可能缺乏。我们拥有东南亚最大的经济体、不断增长的消费市场、电动汽车购买激励措施以及全球最大的镍储量，”该报在 8 月 3 日的社论中表示。“全球企业难道不应该争先恐后地在这里投资吗？”&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;马来西亚已经赢得了特斯拉和亚马逊的青睐。谷歌、微软会成为下一个吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;卢胡特部门的官员在过去一周一直在向公众保证，特斯拉在雪兰莪州的新地区总部并不意味着印度尼西亚被马斯克忽视。&lt;/p>;&lt; “特斯拉在马来西亚的投资不是以电动汽车工厂的形式，而是为了销售和分销，所以我们对此不太担心，”该部负责投资和采矿协调的副官 Septian Hario Seto 说道。 7月25日，我们的目标是电动汽车工厂。对于马来西亚来说，它只投资配电和充电网络。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印尼官员也发表了一些未经证实的说法，以证明他们的努力并非徒劳。去年8月，卢胡特声称特斯拉已同意购买由中国浙江华友钴业和CNGR Advanced Materials生产的价值50亿美元的印尼镍。特斯拉从未对这一说法发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年 2 月，维多多在接受路透社采访时表示，他“有信心”特斯拉会投资，因为该国拥有全球最大的镍储量，达 2100 万吨。镍是电动汽车电池的关键材料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我对[马斯克]说，如果你在印度尼西亚投资，我将在镍[采矿]方面给予让步，”维多多表示。特斯拉迄今为止尚未做出任何决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雅加达经济与金融发展研究所工业、贸易和投资研究员安德里·萨特里奥·努格罗霍 (Andry Satrio Nugroho) 表示，镍不太可能对特斯拉有吸引力。特斯拉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“特斯拉不再使用镍基电池，因此印度尼西亚很难让特斯拉在这里建立电动汽车电池工厂，”他说。 “促使马斯克转向[磷酸铁锂]电池的原因之一是印度尼西亚禁止镍矿石出口，这导致镍价上涨。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;磷酸铁锂电池不含镍或钴，并且虽然它们的能量密度比镍基电池低，但制造起来更容易、更便宜。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我们不应该胆怯”：印度尼西亚加大铝土矿出口禁令&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Nugroho不过，他表示，与马来西亚的竞争不是零和游戏。马斯克在印度尼西亚的投资仍有空间，即他的航空航天公司 SpaceX 及其子公司 Starlink，后者为偏远地区提供高速卫星互联网，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度尼西亚已经使用 SpaceX 的服务来发射卫星它的卫星。佐科威最终还需要说，该国偏远地区需要星链；这对印度尼西亚和 Starlink 来说是一个双赢的解决方案。”他指的是 Widodo 的流行绰号。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;除了销售汽车之外，特斯拉还建立了总部，提供服务马来西亚雪兰莪州的充电中心和体验中心，并将“大量”投资于全国范围内的快速充电和常规充电站网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣表示，马斯克也有兴趣推出他的充电站覆盖全国的星链卫星服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，“政治稳定”让特斯拉来到了这个拥有 3390 万人口的国家。 “当联合政府出现时，政治就稳定……当政治气氛稳定时，人们一定会来，”他在7月28日的演讲中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚是否会向新加坡出口能源&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据安瓦尔的说法，在一位前部长提出的要求失败后，是马斯克联系他进行会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“埃隆·马斯克世界上最富有的人。埃隆·马斯克比国家还富有。把他带进来是相当困难的。但是当我们稳定下来后，我并没有要求和他说话；我只是想和他谈谈。他要求与我交谈。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但分析师指出，政治稳定并不是特斯拉在该地区投资的唯一驱动力。去年11月马来西亚大选之前，该国三年内更换了三位总理，并组建了一个由安瓦尔的政党和前敌人组成的联合政府，以平息该国的分歧。相比之下，维多多自 2014 年以来一直执政印度尼西亚，其联盟在议会中占据超过 81% 的席位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，印度尼西亚在环境社会治理 (ESG) 方面表现不佳，包括一系列Indef 的 Nugroho 表示，公司用来筛选潜在投资的标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度尼西亚仍有许多问题没有得到充分遵守，特别是其镍矿行业的 ESG 方面。从那时起，特斯拉可能会撤回在这里建造[制造工厂]的意图。”Nugroho 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来有报道详细介绍了印度尼西亚苏拉威西镍矿开采中心的工人所面临的恶劣条件。许多中国公司在那里设立工厂，以及依赖化石燃料的冶炼厂的运营造成的环境破坏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于雅加达的能源观察执行董事 Daymas Arangga 表示雅加达在向可再生能源转型方面“并未完全集中和认真”，因为化石燃料仍占印度尼西亚能源供应的 60%。他表示，绿色能源的缺乏可能会降低投资者，尤其是电动汽车生产商在国内开设商店的兴趣。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thieves steal shopping trolley containing HK$530,000 as Hong Kong woman, 89, distracted]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3230291/thieves-steal-shopping-trolley-containing-hk530000-hong-kong-woman-89-distracted?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 19:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/4aa36486-574b-416c-bd5d-0286e2ea8ada_d65b0a8c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一伙窃贼偷走了装有 530,000 港元（68,000 美元）的购物车一名89岁的香港女子正在被警方追捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该女子在红磡市政大楼等待儿子时，因系鞋带而分心，遭劫匪袭击。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;警方表示，盗窃案发生在这名妇女在 50 岁儿子的陪同下从该地区三家银行的账户中提取现金后不到三小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“警官们知情人士透露，“被告知，这些钞票被装进袋子里，然后用衬衫包裹起来，然后放在手推车里。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;母子俩在红磡广场吃饭，然后去了红磡广场。 nearby municipal services building on Ma Tau Wai Road.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man went to the toilet on the fourth floor of the building about midday and left his mother with the trolley at the fourth floor lift lobby.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“An initial investigation suggested the trolley was stolen when the woman was tying her shoelace,” a police spokeswoman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong theft cases jump by nearly 40 per cent in first 4 months of the year &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Police were called and later found the trolley, without the cash, abandoned on the fourth floor rear staircase of the building.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source said the theft involved four non-Chinese men. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“An investigation revealed one of them took the trolley … and the other three acted as lookouts,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The source added CCTV footage showed three of the men ran down the rear staircase and the fourth used a lift. They were seen to jump into a taxi outside the building.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the woman withdrew the cash because she believed using the bank was not safe after she watched recent news reports that seemed to suggest the potential for war.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police hunt thieves who used GPS tracker to find car and steal HK$260,000&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The spokeswoman added the woman and her son said they did not know the thieves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No arrests had been made by Monday afternoon and an investigation by detectives from the Kowloon City criminal investigation unit continues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police statistics show that reports of theft increased by 45 per cent to 5,340 in the first quarter of 2023. There were 3,678 cases logged in the same period last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The surge in theft cases earlier sparked a warning from the city&#39;s Japanese consulate to its nationals to remain vigilant, keep an eye on their belongings and avoid using smartphones or listening to music while on the streets.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 19:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong scientists have lift-off for research project after expert wins bid for use of moon rocks and dust to study lunar volcanic activity]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3230268/hong-kong-scientists-have-lift-research-project-after-expert-wins-bid-use-moon-rocks-and-dust-study?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 18:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/cf703351-1d9f-4454-b71f-9e3bd9cf66a4_1bed927a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Rocks and dust from the moon have touched down in Hong Kong and researchers said the rare samples would help pave the way for future developments in lunar research in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dr Qian Yuqi, a postdoctoral fellow at the University of Hong Kong (HKU), on Monday unveiled the 822.6 milligrams of lunar material, which included some of the youngest moon rocks ever found.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He picked up the precious samples in person from the China National Space Administration&#39;s Lunar Exploration and Space Engineering Centre in Beijing late last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is the first time Hong Kong, as the main applicant, has obtained lunar samples. We hope to use geological methods to study the lunar magma&#39;s process, from the beginning of the eruption in the moon&#39;s core to travelling up the vent, to know more about its temperature and speed of eruption,” Qian said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He applied to borrow the samples for a year. Qian submitted a proposal and orally defended it in front of a panel of Chinese space agency experts in April against strong competition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Advanced HKU laboratory equipment can analyse elements in the sample, which will provide information about the lunar environment and formation of soil and give insights into the early history of the moon and Earth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the last 20 years, China has become one of the world leaders in space exploration, especially the moon and Mars,” HKU associate professor Dr Joseph Michalski said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re very excited about future plans along those lines and for other planetary science missions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Planetary science is not just about studying things away from Earth, but it teaches us about our own planet as well.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“By studying the ancient crust of the moon and Mars, we learn fundamental things about how planets formed, fundamental processes about how volcanoes worked and how crust evolved.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The samples were collected in 2020 by China&#39;s Chang&#39;e-5 lunar mission, and include 800mg of lunar dust and 22.6mg of lunar rock.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Preliminary research of the basalt rock samples by mainland Chinese scientists showed they were formed from magma from a volcanic eruption about 2 billion years ago, around a billion years later than the rocks collected on moon missions by the US and former Soviet Union.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qian, who has been studying a region of the moon with one of the youngest areas of mare basalts, said the samples could provide information to show that lunar volcanoes might be more active than at first thought.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong university builds case for using antidiabetic drug for anti-ageing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He and his team explained they hoped to use the samples to recreate and analyse the basalt eruption process, which formed the moon&#39;s surface.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qian said the team wanted to study other samples in the future, including rocks collected from the far side of the moon in next year&#39;s Chang&#39;e-6 mission, or from the Chinese mission to Mars scheduled for the next decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 28-year-old, who completed his first degree and doctorate at the China University of Geosciences in Wuhan between 2013 and 2022, joined HKU in March because he felt Hong Kong lacked expertise in moon studies.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Scientists work to replicate lunar soil for China&#39;s moon building project&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“HKU has a very strong earth sciences faculty with a lot of advanced equipment, but no one was specialising in lunar science,” Qian said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is going to have many lunar missions in the future and Hong Kong needs talent in this field, so I felt I could bring along my expertise here.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qian said the research was made possible by an undisclosed amount of funding from the university.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 19:20:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Did Japan win public support for Fukushima water release with ‘nationalist victimisation’?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/health-environment/article/3230279/did-japan-win-public-support-fukushima-water-release-nationalist-victimisation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 18:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/0051b088-c957-45ac-84b5-cc5d0b81e39c_66375cb4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Japan will reportedly start to release treated radioactive water from the Fukushima nuclear plant into the Pacific Ocean as soon as the end of August, a move that has barely elicited a ripple among the Japanese public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Critics of the plan to discharge around 1.25 million tons of water from the plant, where three reactors suffered meltdowns after the March 2011 earthquake and tsunami, say the public has been swayed by an effective campaign by the Japanese government – assisted by the domestic media – to convince the nation that it is safe to release the water.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That effort to win over waverers at home has been abetted by what one analyst described as “nationalist victimisation”, with the Japanese government accusing China of ignoring what it insists is sound science behind the plan, of attacking the findings of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) and being guilty of far more egregious releases from its own nuclear plants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Conservative media have for some weeks been insisting that Beijing&#39;s opposition to the release is purely for its political and geopolitical aims, a message that appears to be resonating with the public as bilateral tensions worsen over issues ranging from Taiwan to access to advanced technology and rare earth minerals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More liberal media have recently joined in the accusations that China&#39;s protests are motivated by political opportunism.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Asahi newspaper reported on Monday that Prime Minister Fumio Kishida is likely to give Tokyo Electric Power Co (Tepco), the operator of the plant, final approval to start discharging the water after he returns from a three-way summit with US President Joe Biden and South Korean President Yoon Suk-yeol at the US leader&#39;s retreat at Camp David, outside Washington DC, on August 18.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I really thought the release was going to be postponed, so this is very disappointing,” said Aileen Mioko-Smith, a campaigner with Kyoto-based Green Action Japan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A lot of issues connected with the release – primarily a lot of the questions raised by governments on islands in the Pacific that are likely to be most affected by the release – have simply not been answered,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Japanese government keeps repeating that the IAEA has declared that everything is fine and that it is completely safe to release the water. That is being repeated by the media and people are finally accepting it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ordinary people do not have the scientific knowledge to contradict everything they are being told. My sense is that the public really don&#39;t think this is the best course of action, but they also do not know how they can express their concerns and resist,” Mioko-Smith said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now the emphasis is also shifting to how China is ignoring the scientists and is being irrational for its own ends,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;I would be willing&#39;: South Korean PM offers to drink treated Fukushima water&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A July 15 report in the Sankei paper accused Beijing of fomenting opposition in South Korea to Japan&#39;s plans for the water, out of anger at Seoul, Tokyo and Washington forging closer diplomatic and security ties, adding that China&#39;s government was using a “velvet paw” to “tighten its grip” on South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Similarly, the Yomiuri Shimbun on Sunday quoted Akira Amari, secretary general of Japan&#39;s ruling Liberal Democratic Party, as saying, “China makes claims that are not scientific” and that Beijing “uses unfounded rumours as a diplomatic tool”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even left-leaning media outlets have started repeating that line in recent weeks, with an editorial in the Asahi newspaper on July 21 stating, “China is using Japan&#39;s plan to release treated radioactive water into the Pacific Ocean for political purposes amid its strained relationship with Japan”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The editorial criticised Beijing&#39;s decision to step up radiation tests on imported Japanese seafood imports, adding: “It is hard not to suspect that the Chinese government is using the issue of treated water as a way to put pressure on Japan and promote internationally the view that it is Japan that is disrupting the international order.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jeff Kingston, director of Asian Studies at the Tokyo campus of Temple University, said Japan and Tepco had been forced into “whataboutism” – accusing China of releasing more radioactive water from its nuclear plants than Japan – because earlier efforts to reassure the domestic public and foreign governments failed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Tepco has not covered itself in glory by failing to really consult local stakeholders, local fishermen, nearby residents and civil society at large,” he said. “And by failing to do that due diligence, they have sown mistrust.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the reputation of the nation&#39;s nuclear industry tarnished, Japan is “spattering its critics to deflect more criticism”, Kingston said, while the domestic “media marches in unison”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Japanese public&#39;s position on the issue has been shifted by claims that the nation is the target of unfair criticism from its rivals, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Playing the nationalist victimisation card has worked in the past for Japan, and it appears to be working again now,” he said. “I think most of those who were opposed to the release will remain opposed, but there were a lot of people sitting on the fence, and I think they will have been swayed by this new argument.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 19:20:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong civil servants will need to declare arrests instead of only convictions under new proposal]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3230280/hong-kong-civil-servants-will-need-declare-arrests-instead-only-convictions-under-new-proposal?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 18:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/712fb07f-84bd-4f62-932b-adee746eaef1_98808f25.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong authorities will require civil servants to declare arrests within a week instead of only having to disclose convictions, but a union representative said the move was not necessary and would hurt morale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for the Civil Service Ingrid Yeung Ho Poi-yan confirmed and defended the policy change on Monday. She said it would maintain the standard of the civil service.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Citing an example of a civil servant working on children-related issues who is arrested on suspicion of child abuse, she told a radio programme: “Those he or she is serving would be worried … that the government is allowing someone on suspicion to continue to provide services for children.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said that the civil servant in question could be transferred to a different position or suspended depending on the nature of the issue or stay in the current role under supervisors&#39; monitoring.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the worker is found innocent, salary deductions will be returned, according to Yeung.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The post learned that civil servants were informed about the proposal last month, but the Civil Service Bureau refused to give more details about the circular.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the statistics, 35 civil servants were dismissed in 2021-22 and another 47 in 2022-23. The number placed on compulsory retirement stood at 17 and 13, respectively.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Former Hong Kong civil servant gets suspended jail term for contempt of court&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Previously, civil servants needed to declare to the government only if they were convicted of crimes, according to Leung Chau-ting, chairman of the Federation of Civil Service Union.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Declarations should only be needed if a trial proves the officer is guilty. If he or she is innocent, why is there a need to go through all of this?” asked Leung.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also commented on the government&#39;s recent plan to speed up the procedure of sacking consistently underperforming civil servants, saying that it would discourage people from joining the service.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are only about a dozen cases of forced retirement in 190,000 people over a few years. How significant is that percentage? Making such a big deal out of this would scare the young people away,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s clampdown on poorly performing civil servants could hurt morale: union&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But on the radio show, Yeung defended the proposal, which could take effect later this year, saying that it would boost the morale of those who were capable and even aid the recruitment drive of civil servants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the proposal, the number of opportunities for civil servants to respond to criticism over their performance following an annual appraisal will be cut from four to two.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The administration has also suggested scrapping a step involving a panel review of a worker&#39;s performance. The overhaul would no longer require department heads to set up and consult an “independent panel” to review consistently poorly performing staff.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 19:20:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Strange bedfellows: China’s youth share beds with strangers to cover rent in big cities as living costs and unemployment bite]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/social-welfare/article/3229911/strange-bedfellows-chinas-youth-share-beds-strangers-cover-rent-big-cities-living-costs-and?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/c5766380-6ec1-49dd-acb6-16376cbc3cbe_66fefa7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;An unusual new budgeting trend is emerging in China&#39;s largest cities; two strangers, unable to afford to rent individually, split the cost of a room and share one bed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The arrangement, dubbed “bedmates” on mainland social media, has been adopted by young workers and recent graduates who face high unemployment and financial insecurity in China&#39;s struggling economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The popularity of the new phenomenon can be seen in the numerous posts seeking bedmates on the social media platform Xiaohongshu with hashtags like “sharing the same bed in a shared room”, reported news site Youth36kr.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a report from June on new graduates in the rental market by 58.com and Anjuke, two of China&#39;s real estate listing sites, more than 80 per cent of young people said they wanted to keep their rent below 30 per cent of their salary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For a recent graduate with an average monthly salary of around 10,000 yuan (US$1,400), this means they are spending 3,000 yuan on rent, nowhere near the average cost of a comfortable unit that is convenient to commute to work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The situation has not been helped by the country&#39;s high youth unemployment rate, which hit a record 21.3 per cent in June, reported the National Bureau of Statistics in its most recent figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is why so many people are turning to bed sharing, like strangers Xiaosha and Menghan, who only came together out of financial necessity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In October 2022, Xiaosha relocated to Beijing after being laid off from her job in Shanghai and spent three months without employment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She secured a position at an internet company close to the Xisanqi area, known for its high rents, after an influx of highly-paid professionals working for tech firms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, after three years of the pandemic involving lay-offs without compensation and labour arbitration, Xiaosha recognised the importance of saving money and aimed to keep her rental budget at around 2,000 yuan (US$280) per month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A search on Beijing&#39;s popular rental app, Lianjia, by a reporter from the Post revealed that many flats with single or partitioned rooms lacked lifts in Xisanqi, and even those under 10 square metres (108 sq ft) exceeded her budget.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I can afford a rental budget of 3,000 yuan. But why should I give that money to the owner? Why should I help the landlord pay off their mortgage?” Xiaosha told Youth36kr.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Although I&#39;m quite thrifty, I am the kind of person who can easily spend 400 to 500 yuan on a meal because at least I get to enjoy the food. But spending so much on rent is like purely paying for Beijing&#39;s property owners.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then she found Menghan on Xiaohongshu, an accounting professional with an even lower rental budget of 1,500 yuan a month, also looking for a room in the same area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two quickly decided to become “bedmates”, renting a 215-sq-ft bedroom in a 1,485-sq-ft three-bedroom flat, with each paying 1,500 yuan a month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They made an informal agreement about rules: no snoring, sleepwalking, or inviting male guests into their shared space.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are completely entrusting our personal safety during the night to a stranger,” said Xiaosha.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pair said they are not sensitive to noise and usually fall asleep as soon as their heads hit the pillow, so the experience of bed-sharing had not disrupted their sleep.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instead, it has fostered a unique style of friendship they have long missed as Beijing drifters, as the two would confide in each other about life, work, and love during the evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Perhaps, we are not just two individuals sharing the same bed to save money. We are friends who have known each other for a long time,” Xiaosha said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the “joy amid hardship” sisterhood story was not one many online commenters shared, with many adding their own negative experiences as “bedmates” in the comments section.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “This was the inevitable and only pathway to live in a tier-1 city after graduation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person said: “All I felt was agony. Those who were kidnapped by exorbitant property prices even lost the option to roll over in their own bed. It&#39;s painful, too painful!”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Justice department files appeal against judge’s refusal to ban protest song ‘Glory to Hong Kong’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3230270/justice-department-files-appeal-against-judges-refusal-ban-protest-song-glory-hong-kong?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 18:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/fe005272-47bc-4b2a-b4f1-1929f7a41c35_6553ac6a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s justice department has filed an appeal against a judge&#39;s refusal to ban the promotion of a protest song from the 2019 anti-government unrest which keeps getting mistaken for China&#39;s national anthem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A department spokesman on Monday said it had asked the Court of Appeal to review a lower court&#39;s decision to reject the proposed injunction on “Glory to Hong Kong”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong court dismisses government bid to ban protest song&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The spokesman said the move was in the interests of national security, noting that the song was used to advocate Hong Kong independence during the 2019 protests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The secretary for justice considered it necessary to appeal to put forward views and request the Court of Appeal to consider granting the interim injunction,” he said, without explaining further the department&#39;s reasons for the appeal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The move came just days after several pro-Beijing politicians urged the Department of Justice to strive for the outcome it desired.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Judge warns &#39;Glory to Hong Kong&#39; protest song ban might not have desired effect&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Court of First Instance&#39;s ruling questioned the effectiveness of a ban and said the publication and distribution of the song was punishable under laws already on the books.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A ban might not compel internet search giant Google and other technology firms to remove the song from their services, the judgment added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>