<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Evacuation ordered for more than 460 Hong Kong scout delegates to world jamboree in South Korea as Typhoon Khanun nears]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3230224/evacuation-ordered-more-460-hong-kong-scout-delegates-world-jamboree-south-korea-typhoon-khanun?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 15:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/e13221a6-ecc5-4ff0-8c13-4a367203a9a9_e2fd389b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港童军总会将撤回超过 460 名参加世界大露营的代表台风卡农受韩国影响，标志着当局早前宣布尽管天气恶劣，活动仍将继续举行的转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着台风卡农逐渐向韩国移动，香港童军总会已该协会周一在 Facebook 上表示：“我们已启动紧急应对计划，并决定在 8 月 9 日或之前离开营地。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;并补充说，世界童子军大露营的代表将尽快被转移到安全的地方&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一消息是在活动主办方世界童子军运动组织 (WOSM) 在其网站上宣布，由于即将到来的新冠疫情，所有参与者都将离开。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们紧急呼吁政府加快出发计划，并为参与者在逗留期间直至返回祖国提供一切必要的资源和支持，”WOSM 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;周六，韩国总理韩德洙在新闻发布会上表示，尽管该国正遭受极端热浪的侵袭，但盛会不会取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，WOSM 和韩国政府表示，他们已经咨询了童子军队伍，并决定狂欢活动应该继续进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;面向童子军的韩国流行音乐演唱会被推迟，但在遭受热浪袭击的狂欢活动中表演仍在进行&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在新闻稿中在周一上午发布的世界童子军大露营网站上，性别平等和家庭部长 Kim Hyun-sook 表示，活动中共有 1,296 人需要医疗帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在相关病例中，有 368 人需要医疗帮助。被昆虫叮咬、180 人晒伤、88 人皮肤损伤、46 人患有心脏病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有报道称，厕所肮脏、食物不足和服务缺乏，促使韩国总统尹锡烈要求“立即改善条件”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次盛会最初接待了 43,000 名童子军，其中大多数年龄在 158 个国家的 14 至 17 岁之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们聚集在一个露营地位于首尔西南约 180 公里处的沿海扶安郡新万金。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管热浪和疾病，韩国仍努力推进世界童军大露营&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;气温预计将徘徊在 35 度左右未来几周该地区的气温将达到摄氏度（95 华氏度），营地几乎没有阴凉区域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周五，尹命令政府提供空调巴士和冷藏车，帮助童子军和工作人员降温夏季炎热。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;原定于周日晚上举行的韩流演唱会也因气温飙升而移至8月12日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Venus Lo，19岁香港童军代表团助手表示，由于台风卡农的到来，这两天天气变得更加闷热。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国忙于从残酷的热浪中拯救4万名童军：“真正的混乱”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;“昨天，我不得不在空调巴士上休息三个小时来降温。”她说，并补充说，她多喝了当局提供的冰镇饮料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗和她的队友于7月28日，即大露营开始前四天抵达营地，帮助搭建帐篷并进行健康检查。罗说，第二天她就生病了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“气温几乎达到了40度，让我感到不舒服，”她说。虽然她自己带了药，但由于酷热，她还没有完全从夏天的感冒中恢复过来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗回忆说，她曾看到超过10辆救护车进入营地，接走中暑的参与者。上周中风送往医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;幸运的是，她说，在韩国政府宣布童子军救援计划后，情况有所改善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“更多的冰棒、冰淇淋、水和能源分发饮料。而且附近有大约10辆空调巴士，足够我们时常停留。没有我们想象的那么糟糕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说还没有回程的消息。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indian equipment for China’s Tiangong space station faces export delay]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3230215/indian-equipment-chinas-tiangong-space-station-faces-export-delay?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/e6b73108-9475-4b9a-80cc-2b109f38bde1_368da229.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度科学家在试图向中国运送科学仪器时遇到了困难在该国的天宫空间站上使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于班加罗尔的印度天体物理研究所的一个团队向印度外交部申请了星云气体光谱研究 (Sing) 装置的出口许可证，该装置涉及一个&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国天舟六号货运飞船在天宫空间站任务中升空&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是，该团队此后没有听说任何进展。 “我们两个月前就完成了所有工作。该仪器现在位于洁净室中，准备起飞，”项目负责人兼天体物理学家 Jayant Murthy 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我被告知我们的申请正在处理中，但尚未获得批准他补充说，Sing 原本应于去年抵达中国，并于 2023 年中期推出，但由于新冠疫情而被推迟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度外交部尚未对此作出回应请求置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sing被中国载人航天工程局和联合国外层空间事务办公室联合选定为天宫飞船上进行的九项国际实验之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;作为印度和中国在空间科学领域的首次合作，这台耗资5万美元的仪器将安装在天宫号上，在绕地球运行时用紫外波段扫描天空，帮助了解星际气体的成分和行为、星际气体的诞生和演化。恒星死亡以及其他科学问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管 Sing 的大部分组件（包括望远镜和摄谱仪）都是由 Murthy 和他的研究生开发的，但当涉及到太空时，事情通常会变得敏感，并且他说，印度和中国之间的紧张关系无济于事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我试图解释说，我们的仪器将指向天空，而不是俯视地球，但是“这显然行不通。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，选择在天宫上飞行的其他国际实验，包括在欧洲开发的实验，也面临着出口清关问题，但他没有透露更多细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;如果 Sing 今年能够抵达中国，它仍然有可能成为在中国空间站上运行的第一个国际有效载荷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Murthy 表示这个机会非常重要，部分原因是他的学生们在该项目上投入了大量时间，部分原因是发射费用将由中国载人航天工程局承担——否则这将远远超出他的预算限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;欧洲机构不打算派遣宇航员飞往中国空间站&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sing的设计寿命在六个月到一年之间。 “我们的数据将完全开放，我们对任何人使用它都没有限制，”Murthy 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但目前，我们能做的不多。尽管我们了解挑战，但我们仍然充满希望。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thai tourist fighting for life in Hong Kong hospital after being hit by 2 taxis, driver claims woman dashed into road]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3230220/thai-tourist-fighting-life-hong-kong-hospital-after-being-hit-2-taxis-driver-claims-woman-dashed?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 15:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/32a3f332-8c11-4c7d-ab64-8c232145de90_f6845313.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周一，一名在香港的泰国游客在医院里为自己的生命而战。在金钟政府总部对面被两辆的士撞倒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方于周日晚间因涉嫌危险驾驶而拘捕两名司机，年龄分别为46岁和82岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;31晚上10时20分左右，一岁女子过夏悫道时被撞。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港行人在观塘被两辆小巴撞倒身亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;年轻司机声称据知情人士周一透露，一名女子突然冲出，而男子在中环行车线第三车道上未能及时刹车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随后，她被另一辆出租车撞倒。”消息人士称，一名82岁男子突然转向时被一名82岁男子撞倒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该女子被送往薄扶林玛丽医院后，四肢骨折，昏迷不醒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府发言人表示，截至周一早上，受害人在医院情况危急。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月27日，一名59岁男子在观塘被两辆小巴撞倒后死亡。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;晚上 7.30 左右，他正穿过康宁路，一辆由一名 48 岁男子驾驶的小巴撞上了他。他被扔到对面车道上，被另一辆由 50 岁司机驾驶的小巴撞倒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;急救人员宣布他当场死亡。警方以涉嫌危险驾驶致人死亡罪逮捕了两名司机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年1月至6月，全市发生交通事故，已造成53人死亡、403人重伤。去年，89 起致命车祸导致 90 人死亡。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 in 4 children in South Asia already face extreme heat they ‘simply cannot handle’, UN says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3230221/3-4-children-south-asia-already-face-extreme-heat-they-simply-cannot-handle-un-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 15:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/078c5b82-dc97-4d2d-a7f9-e350fd5dd295_7ab6d5ac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;南亚四分之三的儿童已经面临危险的高温，这是有史以来最高的气温联合国周一警告说，随着气候变化影响的加大，全球气温水平将达到最高水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南亚约有 4.6 亿儿童（即 76% 的儿童）面临极端高温，而这一比例为三分之一联合国儿童机构表示，“随着世界沸腾，数据清楚地表明，南亚数百万儿童的生命和福祉日益受到热浪和高温的威胁”。联合国儿童基金会南亚区域主任 Sanjay Wijesekera 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国警告阿富汗、孟加拉国、印度、马尔代夫和巴基斯坦的儿童面临气候变化影响的“极高风险”，将极端高风险定义为“极高风险”。一年中有 83 天或以上的天温度超过 35 摄氏度（95 华氏度）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;儿童无法快速适应温度变化，也无法排出体内多余的热量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“小孩子根本无法忍受高温，”Wijesekera 说。 “除非我们现在采取行动，否则这些儿童将在未来几年继续遭受更频繁、更严重的热浪的冲击。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在这个“全球沸腾的时代”，高温已成为儿童的健康问题。世界&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自 1800 年代末以来，由于化石燃料的燃烧，全球变暖已经发生了约 1.2 度（2.2 华氏度），使热浪变得更热、更持久、更频繁，并加剧了其他天气风暴和洪水等极端情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月是全球有记录以来最热的月份，全球变暖加剧了灼热的天气，影响了欧洲、亚洲和北美部分地区的数千万人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科学家表示，世界需要适应排放所造成的高温和其他影响，并且必须在本十年大幅削减碳污染，以避免未来出现更糟的情况。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong judge orders retiree suffering from delusions to 1 year in psychiatric hospital for attacking brother with knife]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3230218/hong-kong-judge-orders-retiree-suffering-delusions-1-year-psychiatric-hospital-attacking-brother?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 14:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/f02702a9-dc6b-4fa1-8960-83b0a7af4013_4fcd06a9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名香港法官下令一名退休人员在精神病院住院一年他承认，他误认为弟弟与妻子和女儿有染，因此用刀刺伤了弟弟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官苏珊娜·达尔马达·雷梅迪奥斯 (Susana D&#39;Almada Remedios) 周一告诉高等法院，被告是前保安陈忠轩 (Chan Chung-hin)。尽管罪行性质“极其严重”，但仍需要康复而不是惩罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;64 岁的陈上个月承认了一项意图攻击 72 岁的陈周水的伤人指控。法庭获悉，陈先生于去年4月15日在天水围弟弟的住处，用30厘米的砍刀砍伤弟弟的颈部、前额和前臂。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，两人短暂挣扎，然后被告将受害者踩在地上，挤压他的脖子并踢他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;袭击者被他的嫂子和两名男子制服。据称，被告在被送往医院时处于“情绪混乱”状态，无法沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的哥哥在另一家医院住了一周，多次住院。撕裂伤和头骨骨折。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两名政府精神科医生认为陈患有严重的抑郁症，从而导致了妄想症。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官决定不再追究更严重的谋杀未遂指控。陈先生承认伤人罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港频发的暴力犯罪“未必是模仿效应的结果”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;辩护律师关文伟提交了其所写的缓刑信客户的家人证明了他的品格以及与受伤兄弟的良好关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自福建省的陈先生于2019年4月患缺血性中风后失去了工作能力，健康状况恶化，法庭听证会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关表示，他的委托人在接受政府精神科医生采访之前并不知道自己患有精神疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在宣判时，雷梅迪奥斯表示，最幸运的是受害者的妻子和她的邻居都在袭击发生时，他们在家中以便及时制止被告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果没有干预，毫无疑问，事情的结果可能会比发生时更糟糕，”法官说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;商场袭击引发香港彻底改革精神卫生服务的呼声&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她指出，陈与他兄弟的关系并不像缓刑信中试图描述的那么密切，但她承认他没有&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭采纳精神科医生的建议，判陈某到屯门小榄精神科中心接受治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;根据《侵害人身罪条例》，故意伤害最高可判处无期徒刑，通常刑期为 3 至 12 年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法院可以命令将被告送往如果确认精神状况导致犯罪，则前往精神病医院。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Shameless for traffic’: Chinese influencer detained for staging ‘sexual harassment’ restaurant incident, banned on social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3229865/shameless-traffic-chinese-influencer-detained-staging-sexual-harassment-restaurant-incident-banned?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/06/ccf5dc93-259d-4be6-9af3-b5acbb24f1c6_9fe4bc39.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位 24 岁的中国网红在网上分享了一段男性视频陌生人骚扰她喝酒的事件在网上疯传，已被警方揭发为寻求追随者的骗局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位姓沉的网红7月28日在社交媒体上发帖称，她和一位朋友正在吃一瓶酒。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国南方湖南省长沙市的一家餐厅吃夜宵时，一名身份不明的男子走近他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考虑到该男子的意图并考虑到他们的安全，沉说她决定录制这次互动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;视频中，她一开始拒绝了男子的要求，称：“我们真的不喝酒”，男子则回答：“喝一杯，我们喝一杯，做朋友吧。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沉又找了其他借口：“对不起，我们感冒了，不能喝酒。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子回答：“我们感冒的时候就喝酒。酒精会给你消毒。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“喝一杯会让我们成为朋友。我的哥们都在这里，给我点面子。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频的字幕显示，此时沉很生气，但她和她的朋友不敢面对这个男人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 男人坚持道：“喝一杯就够了。”别人向你敬酒是出于礼貌。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我只是想和你做朋友。我们交换一下联系方式，互相认识一下吧。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沉回复：“对不起，我有男朋友了，我无法加你微信。我的男朋友非常有攻击性；他有虐待倾向和暴力倾向。我实在做不到。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，男人却继续向沉施压。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“那你男朋友对你不好。最好加我； “我们对女人都是绅士。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沉女士说，她和朋友吓坏了，赶紧结账离开餐厅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该视频立即在内地社交媒体疯传。一些人还回忆起最近的一个骚扰故事，一名醉酒男子在中国北方的一家餐馆里殴打一名女子，因为她告诉他要喝醉酒。不要再在她吃饭的时候骚扰她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;针对沉女士的视频，当地警方和中国互联网当局展开了调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但很快就有消息称该视频是编造的。以及长沙警方调查此事后，沉及其支持团队编写的对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，沉告诉警方，她捏造了整个遭遇：“为了跟上潮流，吸引流量，最终获利&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月31日，沉某等三名犯罪嫌疑人被警方拘留，警方责令沉某上传视频的短视频平台封禁其账号。没有报道是哪个平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此事曝光后，舆论立即对沉进行了批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人评论：“流量无耻！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;另一位人士评论道：“他们正在对女性造成真正的伤害。如果以后真的发生这样的事情，人们可能会认为这是上演的，然后忽略它！对肇事者怎么可能只是行政拘留！”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 14:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Probe launched after 44 Hong Kong camp goers sent to hospital with diarrhoea, vomiting following spaghetti dinner]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3230213/hong-kong-authorities-investigate-after-44-camp-goers-mostly-teens-admitted-hospital-diarrhoea-and?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 14:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/a2e52f5c-d88b-4a49-8f79-cc61c5b2e1d7_9375ba66.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;超过40名香港营员（其中大部分是青少年）投诉后被送往医院周一，新界一处地点发生腹泻和呕吐事件，促使当局展开调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;知情人士称，该团伙在赛马会爱丁堡公爵训练中心晚餐时吃了意大利面条。周日下午 6.30 左右在大埔露营。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;这家巴厘岛五星级度假村不是典型的儿童夏令营&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;72 名来自马来西亚的游客中，有 44 人感到不适。一个教会组织在周六至周一期间在训练营参加了为期三天的活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消防处接到涉及多人伤亡的电话后，于早上派出 10 辆救护车前往现场。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;该24男20女，年龄8至51岁，被送往四间公立医院，包括大埔雅丽氏何妙龄那打素医院、上水北区医院、沙田威尔斯亲王医院、 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;跳入生肉蛋走私进港引发食物中毒警告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;截至周一中午，已有34名病人接受治疗并出院，政府发言人证实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卫生部门表示，卫生防护中心的工作人员已前往现场进行调查。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 14:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Black magic’ scams prompt Malaysia police warning for elderly to be on their guard]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3230209/black-magic-scams-prompt-malaysia-police-warning-elderly-be-their-guard?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 14:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/1d8381e0-63b2-4ca5-85a1-06ced520f5d5_4c37a194.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;马来西亚柔佛州警方警告公众警惕此类-柔佛州警察局长 Kamarul Zaman Mamat 表示，诈骗者通常会接近受害者并开始聊天，以获取有关其家庭和背景的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “从那里，嫌疑人会说，如果受害者不寻求帮助（通常是向萨满）来扭转命运，受害者的亲人可能会处于危险之中，或者厄运正在等待着他们，”他说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然后，受害者将被带到远离公众视线的地方，例如房子或汽车，然后要求他们交出金钱或贵重物品以进行‘治疗’或‘仪式’。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“卡马鲁·扎曼 (Kamarul Zaman) 说，受害者事后常常声称他们不知道交出金钱和珠宝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当他们清醒过来时，嫌疑人已经带着他们的钱和珠宝逃跑了。”贵重物品，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他敦促公众，尤其是老年人，外出时要保持警惕，尤其是在有陌生人接近时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“务必与家人核实Kamarul Zaman 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;黑魔法信仰如何在现代香港滋生偏见&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方在木筏后发出警告相关案件，其中包括一名 72 岁的妇女，她说 6 月份在一个菜市场，她被三名陌生人接近。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名女子只想透露自己的姓氏 Tan，她说当她试图将购物品装进车里时，第一个骗子找到了她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她想为她的丈夫寻求帮助，她的丈夫最近遭遇了不幸，导致了一系列健康问题， ”谭说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然后第二位女士走过来，说她可以推荐一位医生。虽然我觉得奇怪，但不知怎的，我还是跟着他们朝一条小巷走去。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过了一会儿，第三个女人走了过来，自称是医生的儿媳妇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“她看了我一眼，告诉我，我的家人运气不好，并建议我们去一个更安静的地方——她的车——在那里她可以告诉我更多信息，”谭说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们上了车，她开始询问我的孩子、个人储蓄和珠宝的情况。出乎意料的是，我把一切都告诉了她。然后她让我回家，把所有贵重物品放在一个纸袋里，里面装满生米，然后交给她进行仪式以驱除厄运。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tan 说她现在确信，如果她没有因为胃部不适而不得不中途离开，她就会成为 pukau（黑魔法）骗局的受害者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一个案例中，一位 68 岁的6 月 3 日，一位名叫 Ng 的老妇人在另一个菜市场遇到的三名骗子手中损失了价值约 40,000 林吉特（8,800 美元）的积蓄和珠宝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些陌生人估计年龄在 40 多岁和 50 多岁之间，他们被骗了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一个女人问吴是否知道哪里可以买到中药材。随后，另一名女子也加入进来，声称她认识一位师父，可以免费治疗，并提出开车送他们去见他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng 说，当他们上车时，她看到车里还有另一名女子。第三位女士告诉吴女士，厄运会降临到她的孩子身上，她应该向师父寻求帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们说服我回家，将我的钱和珠宝放入纸袋中，然后再与他们见面。”吴说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我只记得他们告诉我紧紧抓住纸袋，同时念诵我孩子们的名字，直到他们离开。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;令她惊恐的是，吴后来发现纸袋里只有两瓶水和一小袋米。她相信自己是被这三名女子催眠了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管此类骗局的受害者声称自己被“催眠”的案例很多，但马来西亚临床催眠协会的医疗专业人士（MSCH）表示，骗子并没有使用真正的催眠术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Pukau 或被施咒并不是催眠术。 Pukau 通常与操纵和造成伤害的意图联系在一起，”MSCH 主席 Thema Abdul Majid 博士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它是在未经同意的情况下使用的，例如迷人的语言、触摸、凝视眼睛和震惊因素被用来吓唬受害者，让他们认为如果不寻求帮助，他们可能会面临严重危险。这通常涉及交出他们的贵重物品以换取某些仪式。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thema 表示，pukau 诈骗者的行为导致催眠治疗受到负面影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“患者通常会寻求帮助催眠疗法可以解决焦虑、恐惧症、体重管理、戒烟、绝症、疼痛管理、不健康习惯、失眠、儿童或青少年问题以及药物滥用等健康问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚分崩离析来自中国的骗局“萨满”集团以老年妇女为目标，“重要的是要注意，在催眠过程中，与电视节目中通常描述的不同，患者在感到放松和舒适的同时，完全处于催眠状态。”控制......这是在同意的情况下完成的，患者可以随时睁开眼睛并拒绝任何与他们不产生共鸣的东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这绝对不是通过简单地打断我们的眼睛来让患者进入恍惚状态的做法。手指，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thema 说，马来西亚于 2006 年引入了临床催眠治疗的正式培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文首次发表于《星报》&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 14:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Will autumn visit be third time lucky for Borrell’s China-EU ties talks?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3230207/will-autumn-visit-be-3rd-time-lucky-borrells-china-eu-ties-talks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 13:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/d91f1d4d-73de-47d8-b2b4-d078c9cb2a08_f064a775.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京已确认欧盟外交事务负责人何塞普·博雷尔将于今年秋季访华，并外交部长王毅提供了两次推迟的访问的更多细节——首先是因为他感染了Covid-19，其次是时任外交部长秦刚突然缺席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交部长王毅在周日的电话中告诉博雷尔表示，“中方欢迎”欧盟外交官及其代表团“今年秋季访问并进行战略对话，通过广泛深入的交流为（双边）领导人峰会做好准备”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;年度战略对话是这是欧盟-中国峰会的必要前奏，峰会预计在今年年底前举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国外交部的消息，博雷尔表示，“我期待访问中国并开展” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们期待这次[领导人]峰会，这将从战略上引领中欧关系和双边合作的方向。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中国外交部称，乌克兰战争和尼日尔军事政变也是两人讨论的问题之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《南华早报》上个月报道称，博雷尔在雅加达举行的东盟会议期间会见王后，“暂时”同意于 10 月访问中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王代表他的前任，据说前任因健康原因无法出席原因。经过数周的猜测，秦在两周前被解除了这一职务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在与博雷尔的电话中，王重申了秦对更密切的中欧关系的呼吁——在来自中国的压力越来越大的情况下，这是中国外交政策的重点。王表示，中国正在寻求更多“对话机制”，以弥补疫情期间北京和布鲁塞尔之间交流减少的情况，并“注入新的力量”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;欧盟外交事务负责人何塞普·博雷尔(Josep Borrell)着眼于10月访华&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在其任期内，秦多次访问欧洲，游说反对欧盟“脱欧”。他警告称，这一战略可能会导致欧洲大陆的“去中国化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然双方关系取得了进展，法国和德国等主要欧盟贸易伙伴领导人访问了北京，但欧盟成员国上个月重申了减少对中国的严重依赖和脆弱性的计划，特别是在供应链方面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月，柏林发布了首份中国战略，其中包括降低德国关系风险的意图&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;德国新的对华战略转向去风险化&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据之前的报道，博雷尔打算在 7 月份取消任期期间与北京就“所有问题”进行接触访问的内容包括“伙伴关系”、“竞争”和“系统性竞争”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还预计将与秦和其他高级官员讨论“战略问题”，包括人权和俄罗斯入侵乌克兰。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;博雷尔在 7 月份接受彭博社采访时表示，他“完全保证”推迟的会议将在今年下一次中欧峰会之前举行，目标是在秋季访问中国.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 13:50:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Not just Trump: these leaders also got into legal trouble]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3230202/not-just-trump-these-leaders-also-got-legal-trouble?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 12:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/956aa233-f910-4075-a9c1-aa82577102b0_de970fdb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普上周出现在华盛顿法庭，进行他的第三次审判离任后受到刑事指控，这在美国是史无前例的事件，但却使该国与世界其他地区保持一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管特朗普的盟友抗议称，起诉政客是不发达“香蕉”的标志共和国”，这种情况也发生在法国和德国等先进民主国家。看一下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;萨科齐于 2021 年被判处一年监禁，原因是帮助一名地方法官获得一份享有盛誉的工作，以换取有关以下信息的信息法律调查。尽管这位保守党领袖上诉失败，但判决尚未执行。在另一起案件中，萨科齐因在 2012 年竞选连任失败中故意违反竞选财务规则而被判有罪。他被判处一年徒刑，但在上诉期间被缓刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2011 年，希拉克成为现代第一位被定罪的法国国家元首。离任后犯罪。 The late centre-right leader, who was too sick to attend court, was found guilty of misusing Paris city funds when he was mayor of the capital, and convicted to a two-year suspended term.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Kohl faced allegations of corruption and illegal party financing shortly after the conservative bloc lost the 1998 election against the Social Democrats. Prosecutors investigated Kohl for over a year but finally decided in 2001 to drop the case under the condition that the former chancellor pay a stiff fine, which he did.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Berlusconi, by his own reckoning, faced more than 100 probes and trials related to tax fraud, bribery and unlawful sex, among other allegations, during his political career. Italy&#39;s longest-serving post-war prime minister won decades of acquittals, but after a 2013 tax fraud conviction stuck, he lost his Senate seat and was banned from holding public office. True to form, he still pulled off a comeback of sorts in 2022, when he was allowed to run for office again and reelected to parliament.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Netanyahu, Israel&#39;s first active prime minister to stand trial, faces charges of bribery, fraud and breach of trust. Prosecutors allege the country&#39;s longest-serving premier abused his position to illicitly accept – and at times demand – fine wines and expensive cigars from billionaire friends. They also maintain he undermined the integrity of his office to win favourable media coverage. Netanyahu denies any wrongdoing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Zuma was sentenced to 15 months in prison for contempt of court in 2021, after he refused to testify at a judicial commission of inquiry into state graft during his nine-year rule. He was released on medical parole after serving a few months in jail. Zuma is currently on trial facing accusations that he accepted bribes related to a 1999 arms deal.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Gbagbo was accused by the International Criminal Court of crimes against humanity in late 2011. He spent years at The Hague before the court acquitted him in 2019, which was upheld in 2021. Gbagbo was also convicted of breaking into a branch of the West African central bank during a post-election conflict in 2011 and faced a 20-year prison sentence. He was pardoned by current Ivorian President Alassane Ouattara in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Compaore was convicted in 2022 of the murder of Thomas Sankara, the iconic African leader who died in a coup 35 years ago. He was sentenced to life in prison. Compaore is currently living in exile in Ivory Coast.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Conde, who was overthrown in a coup in 2021, has been accused of complicity in murder, abductions, sexual violence, and forced disappearances. The charges relate to deadly electoral violence in 2020 following Conde&#39;s controversial bid for a third term in office. His trial has yet to start.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Abdel-Aziz, who ruled the North African nation from 2009 until 2019, is currently on trial facing charges of abuse of office, influence peddling, money laundering and illicit enrichment. His defence lawyer has said the charges are political and intended to damage his reputation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Khama has been charged with the unlawful possession of firearms, offences that state prosecutors say occurred during his decade-long presidency that ended in 2018. Khama is currently in neighbouring South Africa, where he faces extradition proceedings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The former cricket star was just arrested and convicted of hiding the proceeds from selling state gifts when he was in power and sentenced to three years. Khan has more than 170 legal cases since being ousted from office in April last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These range from charges of corruption and murder to terrorism and violence. He was also briefly arrested in one of the cases in May, a development that sparked violence across Pakistan and a crackdown against the leader&#39;s political party.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Najib is on trial on charges of money laundering and abuse of power over the alleged misuse of 2.3 billion ringgit (US$508 million) belonging to 1MDB, the state investment fund that became the focus of a scandal that spawned multiple probes in Asia, the US and Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court hearing will resume August 14. He&#39;s also serving a 12-year prison sentence for a separate corruption conviction linked to 1MDB&#39;s former unit SRC International. He&#39;s the first former Malaysian leader to be convicted and jailed for corruption.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Thaksin, ousted in a 2006 military coup, fled Thailand 15 years ago to avoid corruption charges that he said were politically motivated. He was found guilty in absentia in four graft cases, with offences including illegally concealing shares in a telecommunications company that he had founded and conflict of interests over a state-owned bank&#39;s loan to Myanmar government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thaksin will face 10 years upon his return to Thailand, which had been slated for August 10 but was delayed to later in the month.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Estrada was impeached in 2000 on bribery and corruption accusations, but his Senate trial was cut short after a mass uprising triggered his resignation in early 2001. He was subsequently charged with plunder for allegedly receiving kickbacks, and was found guilty in 2007.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just months after his conviction, he was pardoned by his successor Gloria Macapagal Arroyo, who herself faced allegations of plundering before being acquitted by the top court.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Since its advent to full democracy in the late 1980s, almost every South Korean president has been mired in legal troubles after leaving office. Roh was sentenced to 22½ years in prison for accepting hundreds of millions of dollars for a slush fund while president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee got 17 years for a corruption scheme involving his brother&#39;s auto parts company. Park was impeached, removed from office and sentenced to more than 20 years in prison for corruption. All were pardoned by successors.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tsang became the financial hub&#39;s first former leader convicted of a criminal charge when he was sentenced for 20 months in prison for misconduct in office in 2017. Tsang failed to disclose a conflict of interest when negotiating rent for a luxury flat with a landlord applying for a broadcasting license from the city. He was later cleared on a technicality after he&#39;d served 12 months of his sentence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Army general who ruled the country between 1973 and 1990 was arrested in London in 1998 on charges of genocide and terrorism. He was released in 2000 on medical grounds and returned to Chile, where he was indicted and ordered into house arrest six years later.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Correa fled to Belgium during an investigation into his involvement with Odebrecht, a Brazilian construction conglomerate that has admitted to paying bribes to public officials across the continent. He was convicted in absentia and sentences to eight years in prison, but is plotting his party&#39;s return to power through a snap election this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Bolsonaro, the so-called “Trump of the Tropics”, is barred from running for public office until 2030 after a Brazilian court found that he abused his power by spreading misinformation about the country&#39;s electronic voting system in an effort to stay in power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, police raided his home in search of forged Covid vaccination cards allegedly used to evade travel restrictions by aides and family members. He&#39;s also under investigation for leaking classified information.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Alberto Fujimori was convicted of human rights abuses (including kidnappings and murders by government death squads), bribery and embezzlement. He has been pardoned twice and had those pardons overturned twice. Alejandro Toledo was extradited from the US to Peru in April to face trial on charges of corruption and money laundering.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alan Garcia was implicated in the same corruption scandal but shot himself in the head and died as police came to arrest him. Ollanta Humala is awaiting trial on corruption charges related to the same investigation. Pedro Pablo Kuczynski was impeached and resigned before he could be removed from office; he&#39;s now in jail awaiting trial.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last democratically elected president, Pedro Castillo, largely avoided the corruption scandal that felled his predecessors but battled with a Congress that tried to impeach him three times. When he tried to dissolve Congress, he was impeached and arrested for sedition and high treason.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Nixon resigned in 1974, 10 days after the House Judiciary Committee adopted articles of impeachment that could have resulted in his removal from office. Those articles charged him with obstruction of justice, abuse of power and contempt of Congress for attempting to cover up the burglary of his opponent&#39;s headquarters in the Watergate building – the scandal that would tag future political scandals with the -gate suffix. Vice-President Gerald Ford became president and later pardoned Nixon for any crimes he may have committed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Clinton was impeached in 1998 on two articles charging him with obstruction of justice and lying under oath arising out of his affair with intern Monica Lewinsky. The Senate failed to reach the two-thirds vote needed to remove him from office. After he left office in 2001, the Supreme Court suspended his law license, and he resigned before being fully disbarred from practising law.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Trump has racked up more legal problems than all of his 43 predecessors combined. The House impeached him twice – once on charges that he enlisted the help of Ukraine to influence the 2020 presidential election, and again after the assault on the US Capitol on January 6, 2021. He was acquitted by the Senate each time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since then, he&#39;s been indicted three times for criminal conduct before, after and during his presidency: for arranging hush-money payments to a porn actress before the 2016 election, for mishandling classified information after he left office – and now, for obstructing the peaceful transfer of power after he was voted out of office in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If convicted on the more serious charges, he could face the rest of his life in prison, but a conviction wouldn&#39;t block him from taking office in 2025 if he&#39;s elected president next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Cambodia’s king appoints Hun Sen’s son as new leader]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3230196/cambodias-king-appoints-hun-sens-son-new-leader?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 13:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/abd754dd-c1b7-4ee7-bdb1-c56afd1984fe_b0b37274.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hun Manet&#39;s nomination as Cambodia&#39;s new leader was approved by the country&#39;s king on Monday, after the 45-year-old was effectively gifted the post by his father who had ruled for nearly four decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Days after a landslide victory in July&#39;s election, Hun Sen – one of the world&#39;s longest-serving leaders – announced he was stepping down as prime minister and handing power to his eldest son.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The polls were widely decried as a sham after the main opposition challenger, the Candlelight Party, was barred from running over a technicality, with the ruling Cambodian People&#39;s Party winning all but five seats in the 125-member lower house.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Monday, following a request from Hun Sen, King Norodom Sihamoni issued a royal decree stating that he “appoints Dr. Hun Manet as the prime minister of the Kingdom of Cambodia for the 7th mandate of the parliament”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decree endorsing the Western-educated army general was shared on the Telegram channel of his father and signals the imminent end of the former Khmer Rouge guerrilla&#39;s nearly four decades at the helm of a country rebounding from decades of war and poverty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, to officially become the country&#39;s next leader, Hun Manet and his cabinet must win a confidence vote in parliament expected later this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incoming government will usher in a crop of young ministers – with some taking posts vacated by their fathers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While insisting he would not interfere with his son&#39;s rule, Hun Sen has also promised Cambodians that he will continue to dominate the country&#39;s politics.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Cambodia&#39;s Hun Sen resigns as prime minister after 38 years&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Having come to power in 1985, Hun Sen helped modernise a country devastated by civil war and genocide, although critics say his rule has also been marked by environmental destruction, entrenched corruption and the elimination of nearly all political rivals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United States, United Nations and the European Union condemned last month&#39;s polls as neither free nor fair.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hun Sen rejected those allegations and said his handover, a dynastic succession compared by some observers to North Korea, would maintain peace and avoid “bloodshed” should he die in office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also warned that should Hun Manet&#39;s life be seriously endangered, he would return as prime minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While groomed for the position for years, the eldest son of Cambodia&#39;s iron-fisted ruler remains untested in the political arena, analysts say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And there are few expectations Hun Manet will chart a more liberal path than his father, despite being educated in England and the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A member of the ruling party&#39;s powerful permanent committee, he has been the Royal Cambodian Army&#39;s commander since 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hun Manet has also met some world leaders including President Xi Jinping of China, Cambodia&#39;s main ally and a significant benefactor.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Silenced by Hun Sen&#39;s regime, famed Cambodian poet now slaves at noodle cart&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;After stepping down, Hun Sen will become president of the Senate early next year and acting head of state when the king is overseas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During his years overseas, Hun Manet earned a master&#39;s degree in the US and a doctorate in Britain, both in economics. He is also a graduate of the prestigious West Point military academy in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hun Manet has said little of his vision for the country. He won a seat in the capital, Phnom Penh, in the election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>