<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s T1 alert to remain in force throughout the day as Severe Typhoon Doksuri nears, extremely hot weather expected]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3229065/hong-kongs-t1-alert-remain-force-throughout-day-severe-typhoon-doksuri-nears-extremely-hot-weather?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 08:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/40e085a7-5c0e-4bf9-b516-483bc685e9e9_c7384a4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;此故事已作为公共服务免费提供给我们的读者。请考虑在 之前支持《南华早报》的新闻报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据香港天文台称，一号台风警告信号将于周四全天持续有效，预计天气将极其炎热。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预报员称，“多克苏里”从超强台风降为强台风，白天与香港的距离将超过500公里。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港发出T1信号，警告将持续至周四上午&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“香港盛行风将主要为北至西北风。由于地形遮挡作用，境内普遍出现强风的几率较低，但会出现海浪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Doksuri（韩语“鹰”的意思）目前正在穿越南海东北部、福建南部方向。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;天文台提醒市民远离海岸线，避免进行水上活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计周四天气“酷热”，市区气温飙升至 35 摄氏度（95 华氏度），新界甚至更高。预计周四晚些时候和周末会有几场阵雨和雷暴。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia targets Ukraine with missiles, commander says barrage repelled]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3229062/russia-targets-ukraine-missiles-commander-says-barrage-repelled?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 06:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/6a18d480-38e4-42a4-a50b-d854c2a672df_7e3ccecf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯于 2019 年 12 月对乌克兰发动导弹袭击，目标是基辅、赫梅利尼茨基和基洛沃拉德地区。周三，其空军参谋长表示，炮火已被击退。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;空军司令 Mykola Oleshchuk 在 Telegram 上撰文称，防空部队已击落 36 个目标，其中包括 3 枚“口径”巡航导弹和 33 枚 Kh-101 /Kh-555 巡航导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来的声明表明，有关攻击中使用的匕首导弹的信息仍在整理中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这一天很艰难，但是感谢所有天空保卫者的共同努力，我们击退了这次攻击！谢谢大家！”奥列什丘克写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前还没有关于导弹发射或防空活动造成损害的立即报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赫梅利尼茨基西部地区当局证实了爆炸声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们已经登记了高速目标，可能还有弹道导弹，敌人正在使用不同类型的武器，”空军发言人尤里·伊纳特 (Yuriy Ihnat) 在电视评论中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，一些导弹已飞向Starokostiantyniv市是乌克兰军用机场的所在地。他说，这些导弹的路线非常复杂，甚至一度来了个 180 度大转弯。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰能否用爱国者导弹击落俄罗斯超级武器？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;乌克兰防空系统挫败了一枚导弹。空军表示，周三下午早些时候发生的袭击，在中部城市文尼察上空击落了两枚“口径”巡航导弹，这枚导弹似乎是由黑海的一艘潜艇发射的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯于 2022 年 2 月入侵乌克兰&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯周日表示，虽然乌克兰已经夺回了俄罗斯最初占领的一半领土，但乌克兰的反攻还处于初期阶段，将在“几个月”内形成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Philippine actress Beauty Gonzalez accused of ‘grave robbery’ over wearing ‘ancestral’ gold jewellery]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3229031/philippine-actress-beauty-gonzalez-accused-grave-robbery-over-wearing-ancestral-gold-jewellery?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/3681ccbb-3e60-4f12-85d9-07995a8f2078_e9b91a3d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;菲律宾女演员美女冈萨雷斯因“粗俗”炫耀由数百年制成的珠宝而受到批评- 最近在马尼拉举行的一场由名人和政客参加的筹款晚会上挖掘出的旧黄金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冈萨雷斯穿着裸色紧身胸衣为这一场合增光添彩，并描述了她的造型，其中包括从城市出土的金项链和耳环就像 Butuan 和 Surigao 一样，作为“对菲律宾祖传黄金的欣赏”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还在 Instagram 帖子中表示，之前在首都国家博物馆和阿亚拉博物馆展出的这些配饰已经过重新设计由当地珠宝商制作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位女继承人明星拒绝透露这些作品的价格，她告诉菲律宾娱乐门户网站“我唯一能说的是你可以在博物馆中看到这些东西”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但她在上周活动中的出现遭到了资深艺术评论家玛丽安·帕斯特·罗塞斯 (Marian Pastor Roces) 和社交媒体用户的谴责，他们指责这位 32 岁的人“盗墓”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因为如果这些行为是合法的，罗塞斯在 Facebook 上写道：“一旦挖掘出来，这些文物将属于国家博物馆或 Bangko Sentral（菲律宾中央银行）。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，为了取回这些装饰品，“数量惊人”的坟墓将被亵渎。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这位时尚受害者戴着口罩和眼罩：大约有 10 个。也就是说，这条项链是根据许多人的发掘而制作的，”马尼拉的策展人补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;菲律宾试图以“玷污”声誉为由，让好莱坞的《飞机失事》电影停飞&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她还质疑冈萨雷斯的造型感：“这到底是一种致敬，表现出有罪不罚和粗鲁？无知不可能成为时尚。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冈萨雷斯也面临着菲律宾社交媒体用户的愤怒。一些人指责她穿着“残忍的、掠夺来的”考古文物，不尊重国宝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“恶心。 Instagram 上的一位用户说道：“从我们祖先身上挖掘黄金并将其变成珠宝，而不是保护其文化价值。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位用户写道：“你知道它们来自哪里，但这并不困扰你吗？你还为此感到自豪吗？这不是你应该妥协的事情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人想知道这些配件如何最终落入冈萨雷斯的珠宝商手中，以及为什么当局对历史物品的监管如此明显松懈。策展人罗塞斯回应说，“人们沉迷于普遍文化，因为没有任何后果”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;并非所有人都对她的风格宣言不感兴趣。女演员卡米·马丁 (Carmi Martin) 和模特泽纳布·哈拉克 (Zeinab Harake) 称冈萨雷斯“优雅美丽”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一起时尚失礼事件中，参议员伊梅·马科斯 (Imee Marcos) 因穿着部落服装参加小费迪南德·马科斯 (Ferdinand Marcos Jnr) 总统的第二任总统而受到土著群体的批评周一发表国情咨文。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于独裁者老马科斯政权期间伊戈洛特部落的人权受到侵犯，Siklab 菲律宾土著青年网络表示，身穿科迪勒拉服装的立法者是对其社区的“侮辱” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时也是菲律宾领导人的妹妹伊米·马科斯 (Imee Marcos) 称她的举动是对古代文化的致敬，并在社交媒体上赢得了支持者的称赞，称其“完美无缺”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong raises base rate by a quarter point to a 16-year high in lockstep with US Fed, as America resumes inflation fight]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3229063/hong-kong-raises-base-rate-quarter-point-16-year-high-lockstep-us-fed-america-resumes-inflation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 07:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/e6084f28-81ae-42e2-9037-3182944f7bdf_5db7bc7d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港金融管理局今天17个月内第十一次上调香港基本利率与美联储同步，美国央行在六周前休息后恢复对抗通胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港基准利率上调 25 个基点至 5.75%，立即生效。金融管理局（金管局）在盘前表示。这使资金成本升至 2007 年 12 月以来的最高水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几个小时前，美国央行将目标利率提高了四分之一个百分点，达到 5.25% 至 5.5% 的范围，符合市场预期。自 1983 年以来，香港的货币政策一直与美国央行保持一致，以保持香港货币与美元挂钩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们相信美联储几乎已经实现了其目标，并且应该传达这样一个事实：利率正在7 月 24 日，安联全球投资者公司全球固定收益首席信息官 Franck Dixmier 在美联储采取行动之前表示：“非常接近与其价格稳定目标相符的适当水平。” “将利率保持在较高水平，总通胀预计将继续下降，实际利率上升，应有助于收紧货币条件，并消除美联储进一步干预的必要性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今天的涨幅紧随 6 月份的休会之后，美联储停止了加息周期，以监测利率上升（在短短 15 个月内上涨了 5 个百分点）对美国经济的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联储主席杰罗姆·鲍威尔 (Jerome Powell) 离开了美联储今年进一步收紧政策的大门敞开，但他承认，他的经济学家“不再预测经济衰退”，从而将纽约股市基准指数从盘中低点提振，最终以 0.2% 的涨幅收盘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;鲍威尔在为期两天的政策会议后的新闻发布会上表示：“工作人员现在预测，从今年晚些时候开始，经济增长将明显放缓，但考虑到最近经济的弹性，他们不再预测经济衰退。” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国和香港在过去 17 个月内将官方贷款利率上调了 5.25 个百分点，从 2 月、3 月和 5 月的上调 50 个基点逐渐缩减至 25 个基点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据美联储的定价，98.9%的市场预计此次加息25个基点，其中1.1%的可能性是美联储将加息50个基点截至周三，香港金管局总裁余伟文将于今日上午在加息后与媒体会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，所有人的目光都集中在香港的商业银行看看他们是否会提高其最佳客户的优惠贷款和存款利率，或吸收更高的资金成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》上周调查的 13 名分析师中，有 11 名认为利率上涨了 12.5 至 25 个基点由于香港的融资成本较高，银行的最优惠利率有所下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了这些担忧之外，香港银行同业拆借利率 (Hibor) 一直在上升，一个月期 Hibor 升至 5.13%周三，六月份的增长率约为 3%，二月份的增长率为 2.65%。衡量企业贷款的基准三个月期 Hibor 周三从一个月前的 3.68% 攀升至 16 年高点 5.18%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港汇丰银行做好抵押贷款痛苦的准备同行预计加息：调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港“经济正在复苏，房地产需求依然存在”，本地抵押贷款经纪商 mReferral 首席副总裁曹德明 (Eric Tso Tak-ming) 表示。加息。 “加息可能会减缓[贷款]需求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港银行继2022年三次上调优惠利率后，5月份将最优惠利率上调12.5个基点，总计62.5个基点。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;汇丰银行、中国银行（香港）和恒生银行目前将其最优惠贷款利率定为每年 5.75%，而渣打银行、东亚银行和其他银行则将其最优惠贷款利率提高至每年 6%分。加息12.5个基点将使香港最优惠利率回到2008年2月全球金融危机期间降息前的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港负资产飙升至12,164例房价下跌&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;最优惠利率上升将影响香港 1.8 万亿港元（2,320 亿美元）的未偿还抵押贷款，因为借款人面临更高的每月还款额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;典型香港的还款额根据 mReferral 的计算，如果最优惠利率提高 0.125 个百分点，30 年期 500 万澳元（643,000 美元）的抵押贷款将上涨 1.6%，即每月 351 港元，达到 22,803 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;房屋借款人每月需额外支付 704 港元，即按揭还款额增加 3.1%，若加息 25 个基点，每月按揭贷款将增至 23,156 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加息将增加至每月 23,156 港元。对于刚刚摆脱衰退的当地经济来说，这是一个坏消息。香港经济在经历了前两个季度的萎缩（这是经济衰退的标准定义）之后，第一季度增长了 2.7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》上周调查的 13 名分析师对于经济何时会出现衰退有不同的看法。美联储将暂停加息行动。 7 位参与者认为 9 月份将再次加息 25 个基点，然后暂停，而另外 5 位参与者认为今天的加息将是今年最后一次加息。一位与会者对暂停的时间没有看法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这可能是今年最后一次加息，因为美联储现在依赖数据，”董事总经理 Tommy Ong 表示。 TO &amp; Associates 咨询公司。 “我预计下半年美国核心通胀将更快下降，因为租金增幅较低，工资见顶。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些预计稍后会出现暂停的人表示，强于预期的经济使得凯基证券亚洲投资策略助理副总裁表示，美联储将保持“鹰派”态度以抑制通胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在就断定我们将在 7 月加息后达到最终利率还为时过早”莫雷峰。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US lawmakers debate bill pressing Hollywood to reject China’s film censorship]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3229061/us-lawmakers-debate-bill-pressing-hollywood-reject-chinas-film-censorship?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 06:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/12db89cf-f89f-48c1-b8c3-76a07e559f88_01f6beda.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三，随着美国众议院议员提出一项法案，好莱坞与中国的关系受到密切关注。如果电影公司不承诺无视北京的审查要求，该法案将阻止他们获得联邦资助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项名为《阻止共产主义政权立即参与编辑法案》（SCREEN Act）的法案在 2017 年引起了激烈争论。该法案由田纳西州共和党众议员马克·格林提出，要求好莱坞公司向美国国务院报告在获得联邦资金或支持之前已提交北京批准在中国放映的电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;制片厂还必须提交一份协议，表明他们不会“响应或预期”而改变电影的内容。 ”北京的要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果该法案获得参众两院全体通过并成为法律，如果电影是由中国公司联合制作，联邦政府也将被禁止协助电影制片厂进行电影制作。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“中国共产党正在将其极权主义审查制度输出到好莱坞，要求美国电影业参与其邪恶议程，”格林说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些好莱坞公司“一直愿意将利润投入” “高于爱国主义”，他继续说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的电影史是我们民族文化的一部分，我们不能让它被共产主义政权淡化或操纵。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是尽管两党都反对北京在海外的审查行动，但民主党人 — — 包括该委员会的主要民主党人、纽约众议员格雷戈里·米克斯 — — 反对该法案，称该法案“过于宽泛”，对传播美国软实力“适得其反”。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;从《钢铁侠3》到《壮志凌云2》，中国如何影响好莱坞&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这项措施帮助中共达到了它想要的目的：切断其公民与外界的联系，让他们观看米克斯说：“战狼二号而不是美国队长。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加利福尼亚州民主党众议员布拉德·谢尔曼表示，该法案“是对第一修正案的攻击”，并赋予行政部门太多权力， “出于任何梦想的原因摧毁他们想要的任何工作室”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“将如此大的权力交给国务卿，你必须证明中国没有在你的背后支持。”他说：“我不希望在任何行政部门官员中看到做出任何决定时的想法。”周三的讨论是在好莱坞电影公司越来越多地面临国内外政治现实之际进行的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国每年允许上映的外国电影通常不到两打，而且它们必须经过审查程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，几部好莱坞顶级电影受到审查。在《壮志凌云：特立独行》的预告片中，观众注意到派拉蒙从机长皮特·“特立独行”·米切尔的飞行夹克上取下了台湾和日本的国旗，显然是为了安抚中国投资者腾讯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在受到批评后美国 - 据报道腾讯放弃了对这部电影的投资 - 旗帜又恢复了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，华纳兄弟公司受到热议，因为其新发行的热门影片《芭比娃娃》中包含的一张地图显示了被解释为北京在南海提出的“九段线”领土主张，导致越南禁止这部电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该工作室辩称，这条线是“孩子气的蜡笔画”，无意发表政治声明.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;越南禁令后，工作室称芭比娃娃南海地图为“孩子气的绘画”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周三，谢尔曼用芭比娃娃作为政治势力可能过度扩张的例子。格林的法案“以与电影裸露编辑相同的方式处理电影的政治编辑”，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，五角大楼表示不会向计划的电影制片人提供制作援助遵守或可能遵守北京“促进中国国家利益”的审查要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几十年来，好莱坞和国防部一直享有共生关系。五角大楼允许电影制片人在军事基地和船只上拍摄他们的项目，并参与电影制作过程。与此同时，军队也受益于军人的积极形象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加利福尼亚州民主党众议员悉尼·卡姆拉格-多夫表示，该法案反映了“当我们的开放性遇到封闭社会和反民主政府时，我们面临的长期挑战” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，她补充道：“在解决审查问题时，我们应该努力帮助美国电影以更自由、更公平的条件接触中国观众，而不是惩罚和关闭我们自己的行业，让我们的电影处于不利地位。”工人。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese ‘spy balloon’ is featured in US congressional hearing about UFOs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3229059/spy-balloon-featured-us-congressional-hearing-about-ufos?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 05:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/27/4fc226e9-f0dd-4fb5-87d0-87d060f2f2e5_040619de.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候扰乱中美关系的间谍气球事件是图表 A周三，在关于不明飞行物的国会听证会上，委员会主席将其作为联邦政府在该主题上缺乏透明度和准备的例子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院小组委员会主席、众议员格伦·格罗斯曼 (Glenn Grothman) 在开场致辞中国家安全、边境和外交事务委员会要求白宫澄清政府对不明飞行物——或者，正如五角大楼喜欢的那样，不明飞行物（UAP）——的调查，这些目击事件让美国数百万人感到困惑，威斯康星州共和党人格罗斯曼认​​为，对“侵犯美国领空的中国间谍气球”的反应是政府没有为 UAP 做好准备的一个例子，他说，政府的描述事件表明，它对美国军方击落的气球和其他三个物体“仍然不坦率”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一月下旬，有人发现一个巨大的气球漂浮在北美上空。中国官员将其识别为偏离航线的气象气球，但美国官员称其为间谍气球。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在允许其穿越非洲大陆后，五角大楼将其在南卡罗来纳州海岸附近击落2月初，取回了气球并开始对船只进行分析。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该事件在华盛顿和北京之间造成了严重的分歧，以至于美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯取消了当月晚些时候的中国之行，只是&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国完成了对中国间谍气球的回收，以研究其工作原理&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是，五角大楼官员尚未描述该气球已获得或试图获取哪些信息获得，也没有披露任何其他三个被击落的不明物体的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;负责审查军事人员报告的 UFO 事件的五角大楼办公室主任肖恩·柯克帕特里克 (Sean Kirkpatrick) 在 4 月份告诉参议院军事小组委员会， ” ，或其他容易解释的来源，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，周三，前情报官员和军事人员声称，美国政府隐藏了有关 UAP 的关键信息，这些信息不是气球。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;当被问及政府是否拥有任何 UAP 时，前情报官员戴维·格鲁什 (David Grusch) 表示，“绝对是，根据四年来对 40 多名目击者的采访”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我知道确切的情况。地点以及这些地点已提供给监察长。其中一些，对于情报委员会来说，我实际上让拥有第一手知识的人向监察长提供了受保护的披露，”格鲁施在美国空军和国家情报局担任了 14 年的情报官员。地理空间情报局补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及美国是否拥有“驾驶这些飞行器的飞行员的尸体”时，格鲁什声称“其中一些回收物附带了”“生物制品”。然而，他没有透露政府是否与“智能外星人”进行了接触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格鲁什表示，他本人没有看到任何非人类物体，并告诉专家组，他已“获悉，在格鲁施上个月在接受美国新闻网络 NewsNation 采访时也提出了类似的论点。当时国防部回应称，“没有可证实的信息来证实这一说法”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，前海军战斗机飞行员瑞安·格雷夫斯 (Ryan Graves) 作证说，他的小队多次遭遇不明飞行物，并且退役海军指挥官大卫·弗拉沃尔 (David Fravor) 表示，他在 2004 年曾跟踪过不明飞行物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两人都表示，飞行物体的操纵方式无法与美国现有技术相匹配或解释。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们补充说，美国的对手也没有拥有此类技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果UAP是外国无人机，那么这就是一个紧迫的国家安全问题。如果是别的什么，那就是科学问题了。无论哪种情况，这都是对飞行安全的担忧。”格雷夫斯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五角大楼关于不明空中现象的 2022 年年度报告涵盖了 2004 年至 2021 年期间的目击事件，在几个月后于 1 月发布——长时间延误。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该报告，163 次目击事件被描述为“气球或气球实体”，而其他则归因于无人机、鸟类、天气事件或塑料袋等空中碎片。其余 171 起报告的目击事件被标记为“无特征”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，国家安全委员会发言人约翰·柯比承认 UAP 给美国空军带来了问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国宇航局加入追捕行动对于不明飞行物，聘请专家来解决“令人费解的谜团”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们知道，其中一些现象已经对我们的训练范围产生了影响，你知道，当飞行员尝试在空中进行训练时他们看到这些东西，但不确定它们是什么，这可能会影响他们完善技能的能力。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国宇航局组建了一个由 16 名专家和科学家组成的团队， UAP 调查预计将在今年夏天的某个时候发布其调查结果。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s voluntary carbon market could relaunch as early as October to support country’s climate efforts, experts say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3229036/chinas-voluntary-carbon-market-could-relaunch-early-october-support-countrys-climate-efforts-experts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/15840108-383b-43d1-9ad3-1bf2cf60c13d_c44f19af.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;期待已久的中国自愿碳市场重启，中国核证减排量 (能源专家表示，CCER）计划最早可能于 10 月启动，以补充中国的全国碳交易市场，支持国家的碳中和目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划的重新启动可能会极大地有利于气候缓解项目，例如如林业和能源效率的提高。然而，专家表示，项目质量仍然是一个关键挑战，这可能会阻碍中国的气候努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们预计 CCER 将于今年 10 月最终重新启动，届时 CCER 交易监管公众咨询已经结束，金融服务公司路孚特 (Refinitiv) 碳分析师谭路跃 (Tan Luyue) 说道：在暂停 CCER 新项目注册六年后，CCER 计划征求公众反馈意见。拟议的指南提出了针对 CCER 项目的注册、交易、监控和处罚的更全面的监管结构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;指南草案的发布是 CCER 计划重启即将到来的最新信号。 CCER是指企业自愿开展并经中国政府认证的减排活动，包括可再生能源发电、垃圾发电项目以及林业项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CCER被视为中国国家碳排放权交易体系 (ETS) 是世界上最大的碳市场，监管着 2,000 多家电力行业的排放者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在国家碳排放交易体系下，排放者获得有限数量的排放配额根据其排放强度，可以将未使用的配额出售给需要它们抵消更高排放量的公司。他们可以使用根据 CCER 计划购买的碳信用额来抵消超过国家 ETS 目标的排放量的 5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，在 2012 年启动 CCER 后，中国的中央经济规划者，由于交易量低和碳审计缺乏标准化，国家发展和改革委员会 (NDRC) 于 2017 年暂停了 CCER 下的新项目注册。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国国家碳排放交易体系于 2021 年 7 月启动，人们普遍预计CCER计划将重新启动。负责监督 CCER 计划的中国北京绿色交易所于 2 月份宣布，已在恢复运营前完成 CCER 注册和交易系统的开发，但此后尚未披露正式日期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国和中国可以在气候政策上进行合作，但技术仍然很棘手：专家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;ESG 研究机构 Polo Heung 表示，CCER 自愿碳市场对于中国 2060 年碳中和目标非常重要，因为它可以激励对气候缓解项目的投资汇丰银行合伙人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CCER 指南强调项目的独特性，这意味着政府补贴的大型可再生能源项目或国家碳排放交易体系涵盖的项目将无权获得 CCER 积分。然而，较小规模的可再生能源项目可能会从 CCER 中受益，Heung 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们相信最大的受益者之一将是林业，因为目前保护森林和造林的价值低于传统经济中的采伐价值。”条款。 CCER 将为森林所有者提供更多的经济激励，让他们的树木保持活力。”Heung 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heung 表示，CCER 交易面临的挑战包括技术要求和 CCER 信用质量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此前CCER信贷审批流程门槛过于宽松，导致供应过剩、气候可信度和价格疲弱，这是暂停项目注册的主要原因。” “太多低质量的CCER信贷可能会削弱国家碳排放交易体系的效率，并削弱中国在气候方面的努力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了避免供应过剩，对CCER项目制定更严格的标准至关重要。香预计生态环境部在初期批准CCER项目时会更加谨慎，从而导致CCER的发行量较低。然而，Heung 表示，随着国家 ETS 覆盖范围从电力行业扩大到排放量更大的行业，对 CCER 的需求预计会随着时间的推移而增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些专家表示，尽早重启 CCER 比重启 CCER 更好。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与中国国家碳排放交易体系一样，CCER 不需要为重启做好准备。完美是优秀的敌人。 CCER的实际运行将有助于加快问题的发现和解决。”环境非政府组织环境保护基金（EDF）碳市场主任刘洪明表示。该基金一直为中国启动全国碳市场提供咨询服务。 .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why was Wang Yi brought back as China’s foreign minister after Qin Gang’s abrupt exit?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229043/why-was-wang-yi-brought-back-chinas-foreign-minister-after-qin-gangs-abrupt-exit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/01ddd55f-95ea-4b70-beef-778be76e36fb_21e24b0e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;仅七个月后，中国前外交部长秦刚突然被罢黜，这可能会引起高度关注。不同寻常，但这种反应可能符合北京的典型做法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京重新任命王毅担任这一职务的举动遵循了从最高决策机构中空降值得信赖的成员来引导共产党渡过难关的传统。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王的选择被许多外交观察家视为“最安全、最好的选择”。王在去年晋升为中共外交政策负责人之前，已担任该职务十年。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，秦在全国人大常委会特别会议上被免职，没有给出任何理由。外交部此前表示，由于“健康原因”，他无法履行职责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅重返外交部是建立在有需要时派高级党员填补较低级别职位的惯例基础上的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the 2003 outbreak of severe acute respiratory syndrome (Sars), the country&#39;s “Iron Lady” Wu Yi took on the role of health minister after becoming vice-premier and a member of the Politburo, the party&#39;s top decision-making body.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She replaced Zhang Wenkang who was removed from the post after heavy criticism of China&#39;s handling of the outbreak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More recently Zhang Dejiang, also a vice-premier, was sent to Chongqing to fill the role of party chief after the downfall of Bo Xilai, the high-flying official who was once seen as a contender for top leadership roles but was later jailed for life for corruption.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; &#39;Just tell the truth, the sky won&#39;t fall&#39;: Chinese left guessing about Qin Gang&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chen Gang, assistant director and senior research fellow at the East Asian Institute at the National University of Singapore, said he believed Wang is trusted by the top leadership to act as a “firefighter”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The recent change at the foreign ministry may be following this precedent, according to Li Tao, associate professor of government and public administration at the University of Macau, who said: “Zhang and Wang were used as ballast in a political storm.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang&#39;s return coincides with a major drive by Beijing to reboot its diplomacy after three years of Covid restrictions and put its relations with the West on a better footing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping is currently preparing to meet at least seven foreign leaders when the World University Games open in Chengdu this week, and he is also expected to attend the Brics summit in South Africa next month, the Group of 20 summit in India in September and host the Belt and Road summit in Beijing in October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is also the possibility he will travel to the United States in November for the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation summit – and all these events need the foreign minister to prepare the groundwork.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yun Sun, director of the China programme at the Washington-based Stimson Centre, said Wang was perhaps “the safest and best choice” to fill the role.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“No one could question his qualifications, and he is such a senior and authoritative person. Given China&#39;s pressing foreign policy tasks for the rest of the year, Beijing will want someone who is credible, stabilising and authoritative to hold the job,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang has a strong support base within the foreign ministry, said Zhang Dong, assistant professor of social science at Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Wang&#39;s return is expected to bring a degree of stability to the ministry and ensure that it is well-prepared for the work ahead in the coming months,” Zhang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese foreign minister switch: &#39;wolf warrior&#39;, hopes of stability&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wang has been standing in during Qin&#39;s absence over the past few weeks, including a meeting of Association of Southeast Asian foreign ministers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun said that a trip would have to be scheduled relatively soon to pave the ground for any visit to the US by Xi in November. “I think that will remain Wang&#39;s priority as well,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She did not expect the change to have a major impact on China&#39;s foreign policy, saying: “Chinese foreign ministers don&#39;t make foreign policy. They implement the policy made by the top leaders. Wang Yi will also follow the same course designated by the top, including on the relations with the US.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Afghan women despair over Taliban’s beauty parlour ban: ‘I cannot work and live as a woman’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3229045/afghan-women-despair-over-talibans-beauty-parlour-ban-i-cannot-work-and-live-woman?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/26/7aead6f9-4a96-4834-834e-8e8b9276d80a_939d55af.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Shirin booked her bridal makeover weeks ago, but instead of relaxing as beauticians pampered her, everyone in the Kabul salon was on edge, ready to hide the bride should the police appear.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shirin was the last customer at a salon in Afghanistan&#39;s capital, one of thousands across the country closed on Tuesday by order of Taliban authorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have someone on watch outside in case the Taliban arrive. If something happens, we&#39;ll put her in the bathroom or store room and look busy packing,” salon owner Aziza said. “Even if they put me in prison, I will do her makeover because I promised her.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As some beauticians fluttered around Shirin, others were busy packing up the salon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like tens of thousands of other parlour employees, they have been pushed from one of the last remaining areas of work open to women under the Taliban government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ban on beauty parlours is the latest blow not only to women&#39;s earning capabilities – with salon owners and worker salaries often the only source of income for households – but also to their social lives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We were heartbroken when we heard salons were closing because they were places where we not only took care of our appearance, but we could see friends and make new ones, chat and ease our sorrows,” said 21-year-old Bahara, a salon customer in Kabul.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Women are not allowed to enter entertainment places, so what can we do? Where can we go to enjoy ourselves? Where can we gather to meet each other?”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taliban leader claims Afghan women have &#39;free, comfortable, prosperous life&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Since sweeping back to power in August 2021, Taliban authorities have banned girls and women from attending high school and university, barred them from visiting parks, funfairs and gyms, and have ordered them to cover up in public.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Women have also been mostly blocked from working for the United Nations or NGOs, with thousands sacked from government jobs or being paid to stay at home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kamela started working in a salon a year ago when she lost her media job and was no longer able to continue her education. As the sole breadwinner for her family of five, the 19-year-old does not know what she will do without her beauty parlour pay cheque.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Closing beauty salons means all doors are closed to me, which means I cannot work and live as a woman in Afghanistan,” she said this week, braiding the long black hair of one of the salon&#39;s last clients.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Maybe tomorrow the Taliban will say that women are not allowed to breathe.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Manizha, 28, poured time and money into growing her own salon since 2018, training some 200 women to work in the industry and also become “self-sufficient”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now her 25 employees, all the main earners in their families, are back to square one and Manizha must watch as her efforts go to waste.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I worked so hard and now my achievement is reduced to nothing,” she said. “I stayed in the country and paid tax to the government, and now they are closing down our beauty salon. It is such a shame, this is a huge blow to the country&#39;s economy and to us.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the weeks before the ban went into effect, women rushed to salons to have their hair dyed and eyebrows shaped – their last chance to do something for themselves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Ministry for the Promotion of Virtue and Prevention of Vice claimed extravagant sums spent on makeovers caused hardship for poor families and some treatments – such as eyelash extensions and hair weaving – were un-Islamic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But beautician Najla felt the work was a good, ethical living.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I was doing a good job, I was able to get a bit of bread to take home. What will I do now?” said the orphan, who looks after her siblings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What do they actually want from us? They have closed all the places to women. Maybe one day they&#39;ll just say, &#39;Whenever a girl is born, bury her alive&#39;.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Over 50 whales die in Australia after mass stranding on remote beach]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3229049/over-50-whales-die-australia-after-mass-stranding-remote-beach?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/26/cf4797a3-8b48-4304-96e0-64f1c34e916e_bfd7eb4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Volunteers worked frantically for a second day on Wednesday to save dozens of pilot whales that stranded themselves on a beach in Western Australia, but more than 50 had already died.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 100 long-finned pilot whales, stranded themselves on Tuesday on the beach by the city of Albany, on the southern tip of Western Australia, south of Perth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They were first spotted swimming on Tuesday morning near Cheynes Beach east of Albany.随着时间的推移，吊舱开始靠近海滩，引起了环保官员的关注。 By 4pm, a large stretch of the shoreline was covered in beached whales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reece Whitby, Western Australia&#39;s environment minister, said it was particularly frustrating because it&#39;s not known why the phenomenon occurs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What we&#39;re seeing is utterly heartbreaking and distressing”, he told reporters. “It&#39;s just a terrible, terrible tragedy to see these dead pilot whales on the beach”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fifty-two whales had perished, and volunteers are doing what they can to try and save 45 still alive, he said. “People are committed to doing what they can to save as many whales as they can.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Western Australia state&#39;s Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions set up an overnight camp to monitor the whales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Peter Hartley, a manager from the department, told the Australian Broadcasting Corporation that the volunteers were trying to get the living whales back into the water and encourage them to swim away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are optimistic that we will save as many as we can,” Hartley said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The team tasked with helping the whales includes Perth Zoo veterinary surgeons and marine fauna experts. They have been using specialised equipment, including vessels and slings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hundreds of volunteers also offered to help – so many that officials said they had enough registered volunteers and urged other members of the public to stay away from the beach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Drone footage released by the department showed the whales clustering and forming into a heart shape before stranding themselves on the beach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is just an amazing event”, Joanne Marsh, the owner the Cheynes Beach Caravan Park told the ABC. “We&#39;ve never seen anything quite like this”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wildlife experts said the unusual behaviour of the whales could be an indicator of stress or illness within the pod. Pilot whales are highly social animals and often maintain close relationships with their pods throughout their lives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macquarie University wildlife scientist Vanessa Pirotta said the drone footage could suggest the whales had become disoriented, although she said the exact reasons for mass strandings remain unclear.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The fact that they were in one area very huddled, and doing really interesting behaviours, and looking around at times, suggests that something else is going on that we just don&#39;t know,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said she thought it unlikely the whales were trying to avoid a predator.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They often have a follow-the-leader type mentality, and that can very much be one of the reasons why we see stranding of not just one but many,” Pirotta added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident is reminiscent of one in September, in which some 200 pilot whales died after a pod stranded itself on the remote west coast of Tasmania, off Australia&#39;s southeastern coast.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The following month, nearly 500 pilot whales died after stranding themselves on two remote beaches in New Zealand.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US losing ground to China in Latin America policy and must prioritise investment in region: senators]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3229060/us-losing-ground-china-latin-america-policy-and-must-prioritise-investment-region-senators?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.27 06:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/27/4a443cf9-0de5-4771-adc9-bef7e1acf2b0_2edcae2a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Democratic senators on Wednesday took the Biden administration to task for its foreign policy approach towards Latin America, accusing it of losing ground to China as the Asian giant keeps building its clout in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bob Menendez, Democrat of New Jersey, raised the alarm over Beijing&#39;s influence during a hearing of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, echoing the sentiments of a former Panamanian foreign minister who asked about an American global economic agenda in the face of Chinese inroads.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tim Kaine, Democrat of Virginia, referenced a recent trip he took to Latin America with Menendez and voiced concern about China&#39;s Belt and Road Initiative, which entails significant investments in 21 of the 34 Latin American and Caribbean countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ve got to have something on the table to counter it,” Kaine said of Beijing&#39;s scheme comprising 40 projects involving port construction or upgrading.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Virginia senator lamented what he termed a failed opportunity with Ecuador, which in 2021 switched to a pro-American stance upon the election of Guillermo Lasso. Kaine believed Washington&#39;s neglect was enabling China to run roughshod over the Americas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Describing a Lasso overture months after his election, Kaine recalled: “He came to me [asking for] a trade deal with us. Ecuador is the only nation on the Pacific coast that doesn&#39;t have a trade deal with the United States … We didn&#39;t do it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That government has collapsed,” the senator continued. “It is likely to go back to a pro-China government in the [next] elections … We had two and ½ years to try to show this erstwhile ally that wanted to lean towards the United States. And we really did nothing”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kaine further noted the difficulties Ecuador&#39;s president faced in arranging a meeting with US President Joe Biden when visiting Washington last December. Lasso, he said, had to “practically beg to have a few minutes” with the American leader in the Oval Office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jose Fernandez, the State Department&#39;s undersecretary for economic growth, said on Wednesday he agreed with the senators&#39; criticism. And in his testimony he stated that the Biden administration was focused on issues it identified as barriers to growth, including corruption, a lack of transparency, inadequate infrastructure and government instability.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China hopes to build &#39;high-quality economic relationship&#39; with Argentina&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Kaine argued that while China presented no-strings-attached investments, the US was insisting on reforms before offering more engagement, a dynamic he called concerning. He urged the administration to prioritise investment in a region widely regarded as the US&#39;s own neighbourhood.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Menendez seconded Kaine&#39;s view, expressing frustration that Washington could not offer as much immediate aid as Beijing. The US would hold greater sway in Latin America if it could combine reform proposals with economic incentives, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Argentina could give Washington an opportunity to refine its approach, with its next general election set for October. Economy minister Sergio Massa has led presidential polling so far, but rising disapproval over high inflation, unemployment and worsening poverty have boosted the prospects of far-right candidates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, Argentine President Alberto Fernández asked the US to help mediate renegotiations of its sovereign debt with the International Monetary Fund. The Biden administration, however, has been reluctant to offer support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country has been pummelled by a historic drought that slashed agricultural exports and depleted its international reserves to their lowest level in seven years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Facing silence from Washington, Buenos Aires in June reached a new agreement with China&#39;s central bank, granting access to US$10 billion to reinforce Argentine reserves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Argentina was experiencing “an economic challenge at the moment”, Menendez said, and in its president the country had someone who was “doing a pretty decent job of trying to right the ship and meet their responsibilities”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But we&#39;re in the midst of creating pressures before an election,” the senator added, saying it was possible the US would “end up with adversaries instead of allies”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The senators&#39; criticisms extended to US policy towards Brazil, with James Risch, Republican of Idaho, noting Brasilia&#39;s deepening connections with Beijing over lithium resources. Fernandez assured the panel that the US was working on multiple critical mineral projects in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We provided technical assistance to Brazil, and we intend, going forward with the new Brazilian administration, to explore ways to pursue critical mineral projects,” said Fernandez.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;5 trade moves China has made in 2023 in the US&#39; backyard of Latin America&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Brazil could be a very valuable partner in finding critical minerals, [since] 80 to 90 per cent of them come from the PRC.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brazil holds 8 per cent of the world&#39;s lithium reserves. To boost production and exports, its government in June last year issued a decree loosening regulations on the sector and expecting investment to reach US$3.7 billion by 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, the governor of the state of Minas Gerais, where Brazil&#39;s largest lithium deposits are located, unveiled an ambitious plan called Lithium Valley, aiming to accelerate exploration of the resources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have alternative sources,” added Fernandez. “It&#39;s not only Brazil, but also Argentina, Chile and Peru. We&#39;ve got to do more in this hemisphere.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>