<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[To speak up against Western labels, China must first find its own words]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231417/speak-against-western-labels-china-must-first-find-its-own-words?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/cf5c77e4-5699-4855-91d8-7feb33a68492_8e53bd6b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;文字很重要。但当言语失败时，就会产生问题。中国面临这一挑战，一些西方词语试图解释中国的某些方面。中国已经采用了自己的语言中的一些词语，但西方认为这令人困惑或无法理解中国的语境。西方对中国的一些言论中国认为是有害的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以汉语如何教授“过去时”为例。汉语没有过去时，也没有任何与此相关的时态。但在教授西方学生时，很多中国老师都采用这个术语。当学生问如何表达过去时时，这些老师说他们可以在句子中添加“了”字，以表示所描述的动作已经发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问题是，汉语实际上并不是这样的。有描述过去事件但没有此字的句子，也有不描述过去事件但有此字的句子。结果，当老师陷入试图解释“过去时”的困境时，学生们却感到困惑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个例子是“民主”一词。这通常指的是西方以核心价值维护的政治制度。当中国在其官方文件中使用“民主”一词时，西方国家会持怀疑态度（委婉地说）。但这有助于理解语境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去时”和“民主”似乎至少在动荡的 19 世纪末和 20 世纪初就已经进入汉语。出于寻求变革的动机，许多中国学者将目光投向西方，试图将西方的语法概念强加于汉语，将西方的社会政治术语强加于中国社会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国经济的崛起，一些词语正在被取代。提出来描述其国际关系。一个例子是“冷战”。西方一些分析人士一致认为，中美之间已经开始了第二次冷战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国否认自己正在进行冷战，并多次呼吁西方放弃冷战。战争心态。但西方认为这纯粹是说说而已。为什么西方这么难理解中国真的不想冷战？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要找到答案，我们得看看西方文明的摇篮——古希腊。古希腊人在观察自然界的运动后得出结论，宇宙的一个基本特征是两个对立面之间的永恒竞争，例如黑夜驱赶白天，热驱寒冷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但古代中国人得出了一个结论：不同的结论。他们认为宇宙是和谐的，看似竞争的对立面是同一本质的各个方面，一个无缝且连续地转化为另一个。他们认为，大自然包容一切，每个人都可以发挥自己的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一理念体现在副总理刘鹤一月份在达沃斯世界经济论坛上的讲话中，他说： “我们认为，公平的国际经济秩序必须得到各方共同维护。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国处理对华关系的方式、新冷战观念的兴起以及投机性的修昔底德陷阱，都符合西方的对抗传统。中国本着其传统，一再否认自己正在进行冷战。具有讽刺意味的是，它的抗议却让这一概念变得突出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个例子是“殖民主义”一词，西方用它来描述中国与一些发展中国家之间的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几个世纪以来，西方殖民主义者以残酷的武力蹂躏当地人民。然而数百年前，当中国海军上将郑和远航至非洲时，他带了豪华礼物送给当地领导人。西方将中国对发展中国家的参与视为新殖民主义，这只是在投射其过去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但就像冷战概念一样，拒绝贴上殖民主义标签似乎对中国没有多大帮助。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论是自愿采纳还是强加，来自西方的言论都让中国陷入了语言地狱，中国永远无法发出自己的声音。只有一套基于中国经验、现实和解释的新鲜词汇才能使其自由。提出这些话的必须是中国，而不是西方。一本好的语法书可能是一个开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China-led de-dollarisation gains traction among emerging economies ahead of Brics summit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3231585/china-led-de-dollarisation-gains-traction-among-emerging-economies-ahead-brics-summit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/b0ca9256-c4f7-4e6a-866d-50a2201beed6_60d2f7e4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美元在全球贸易中的主导地位似乎受到经济扩张的挑战荷兰国际集团 (ING) 的研究显示，在下周金砖四国峰会前夕，关于货币联盟的讨论已引起人们的关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五个主要新兴国家经济体（巴西、俄罗斯）的联盟印度、中国和南非——占全球经济的 8.3%，占地球人口的 41.9%。集团代表将于周二至周四在南非举行会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;荷兰银行分析师表示：“我们怀疑，今年夏天金砖国家高级领导人会晤时，‘去美元化’主题可能会受到一些关注。”克里斯·特纳 (Chris Turner)、德米特里·多尔金 (Dmitry Dolgin) 和詹姆斯·威尔逊 (James Wilson) 在周四的一份报告中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;经济学家警告称，美元“武器化”要求北京重新考虑人民币计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;金砖四国的经济扩张可能决定他们表示，中国采用美元领域之外的商业和金融体系的速度加快，对美元作为国际货币的主导地位构成了一定的挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京加大了对华盛顿“武器化”美元的批评力度。美元过去一年半的表现，理由是西方因俄罗斯2022年2月入侵乌克兰而对其实施制裁，包括冻结俄罗斯央行资产、将其踢出Swift全球支付系统，以及拒绝莫斯科使用美元.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来，去美元化的呼声似乎越来越高，例如巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦在访问中国期间公开呼吁以本币结算，而不是通过美元在四月份。此类货币联盟是涉及两个或多个使用相同货币的国家的政府间协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，俄罗斯国家杜马副主席亚历山大·巴巴科夫表示，俄罗斯正在带头发展这一货币联盟，以促进跨区域货币联盟的发展。据金砖国家信息门户报道，一些发展中国家之间的边境贸易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这一消息预计将为全球经济去美元化趋势增添新动力——如果该货币成功发行，预计中长期内将推动美元等信用货币相对于黄金贬值。”浙商证券在 8 月 4 日的报告中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，路透社周四报道称南非官员援引金砖国家货币的说法称，金砖国家货币已不被考虑。作为一种新的全球货币，人们期望它可能会类似于非西方国家的欧元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，人民币越来越多地用于贸易结算、国际支付和外汇交易。例如，阿根廷政府通过双边货币互换计划以人民币偿还其国际货币基金组织债务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么中国的人民币国际化努力未能达到预期？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在其在周四的季度货币政策报告中，中国人民银行誓言推动人民币国际化，进一步扩大人民币在跨境贸易和投资中的使用，发展离岸市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更多经济体正在加速外汇储备的多元化，其中包括采用人民币等新兴经济体的货币。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“去美元化主要体现在央行的国际储备中，因为美元正在被贬值。”荷兰银行表示，美元在全球外汇储备中的份额到 2022 年将下降至 58.6%。 ，达到自 1995 年首次提供数据以来的最低点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从长期发展来看，美元似乎主要被亚洲货币（即人民币和[日元]）取代，” ING 报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ING 表示，中国人民银行自 2009 年以来与各国央行建立的双边互换额度是一个“旗舰范例”，表明世界摆脱对美元的依赖需要挑战其然而，鉴于美元利率的较高回报使其对私营部门具有吸引力，其在全球外汇储备中的份额在 2019 年第一季度小幅攀升至 59.2%。 2023年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于私人投资者来说，人民币的吸引力仍远不如美元，因为人民币在央行储备之外的国际资产中所占的份额在七年内从5%增长到仅6%，与去年美元的 49% 份额相比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美元继续成为国际债券市场的领先者，其在银行外债中的份额仍为 48%，在外债中所占份额为 51%。非银行部门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“流动性相对缺乏以及投资者对潜在资本管制的持续担忧可能会抑制市场的增长，”ING 表示。 “从这方面来看，人民币似乎还没有进入大多数投资者发行债券的意识。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia charges jailed US citizen Gene Spector with espionage]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3231618/russia-charges-jailed-us-citizen-gene-spector-espionage?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 00:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/49b4d1fc-9259-4639-9736-8902a78d447a_2c70e205.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;据国家新闻机构报道，俄罗斯指控一名被监禁的美国公民从事间谍活动，提高了美国总统乔·拜登政府一直在努力寻找一种方法，将几名被拘留的公民从俄罗斯带回国。因涉嫌间谍罪而被审判拘留，可判处 10 至 20 年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“法院批准了调查请求，以第 276 条[间谍]罪名拘留美国公民斯佩克特塔斯社援引法庭一位身份不明的消息人士的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新闻机构没有报道新指控的任何细节，但表示法庭开庭是闭门进行的据报道，斯佩克特承认贿赂前俄罗斯副总理阿尔卡季·德沃尔科维奇的助手，目前已被判处 3-1/2 年徒刑。新闻机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯佩克特出生于现在的圣彼得堡，然后移居美国。塔斯社称，在 2021 年被捕之前，他曾担任 Medpolymerprom 集团的董事会主席，该公司是一家专门生产癌症治疗药物的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯法院以间谍罪判处美国人保罗·惠兰 16 年徒刑&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;白宫发言人约翰·柯比 (John Kirby) 在接受 CNN 采访时表示，政府仍在收集有关此案的信息，尚未发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国务院发言人表示，他们知道针对一名美国人提出指控的报道。俄罗斯公民，正在关注事态发展，但拒绝进一步置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国一直在与俄罗斯讨论如何带回几名在莫斯科被拘留的美国公民，其中包括《华尔街日报》记者埃文·格什科维奇和前美国海军陆战队员保罗·惠兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里姆林宫已证实已与华盛顿进行了一些讨论，但一再表示只有在试验后才能考虑交换，并警告说，美国试图公开谈论谈判将破坏&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯驻美国大使阿纳托利·安东诺夫周三表示，莫斯科和华盛顿有一个有效的渠道交换囚犯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华尔街日报》的格什科维奇于 3 月份因间谍活动被捕他、《华尔街日报》和华盛顿否认了这些指控。俄罗斯称他被当场抓获。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前美国海军陆战队员惠兰因间谍罪被定罪，目前正在俄罗斯流放地服刑 16 年，华盛顿也称这些指控是虚假的。美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯本月与惠兰通电话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 12 月，美国篮球明星布兰妮·格里纳 (Brittney Griner) 在囚犯交换中获释，她因拥有电子烟弹而被判处九年监禁含有大麻油（在俄罗斯被禁止）的司法程序被华盛顿标记为骗局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2022 年 2 月乌克兰战争开始以来，美国一再要求其公民离开俄罗斯，因为俄罗斯执法机构任意逮捕或骚扰的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月，美国音乐家、前伞兵迈克尔·特拉维斯·利克 (Michael Travis Leake) 被锁在金属笼子里出庭。他因贩毒罪被捕。路透社无法联系到他置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西今年拒绝了美国引渡谢尔盖·切尔卡索夫的请求，西方情报机构称谢尔盖·切尔卡索夫是一名俄罗斯间谍，试图使用虚假身份渗透国际刑事法院（国际商会）。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UN rights chief slams Niger coup: ‘very notion of freedom’ at stake, he warns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3231615/un-rights-chief-slams-niger-coup-very-notion-freedom-stake-he-warns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 23:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/bcd5f71a-97b6-4375-a2b3-80b36c0afe08_c64a0278.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;联合国周五猛烈抨击在尼日尔夺取政权的将军们“ ”，并使该国进一步陷入苦难，要求立即恢复宪法秩序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尼日尔的自由概念正处于危险之中，”联合国人权事务高级专员沃尔克·特克在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尼日尔的自由概念正处于危险之中。” “将军们不能一时兴起违抗人民的意愿，”他说。 “枪治在当今世界没有立足之地。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的评论是在上个月的政变推翻尼日尔民选总统穆罕默德·巴祖姆之后发表的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴祖姆，63 岁，于7 月 26 日，总统卫队成员发起政变，这是尼日尔自 1960 年脱离法国独立以来第五次政变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内陆国家尼日尔因此与邻国马里和布基纳法索一起成为三年内第三个发动政变的萨赫勒国家。经历政变。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国高级外交官会见尼日尔政变领导人，进行了“艰难”的会谈&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;特克强调，尼日尔已经是世界上最贫穷的国家之一，近一半的人人民“陷入赤贫”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他警告说，政变使局势进一步恶化，边境关闭、贸易停滞、严重断电和粮食价格上涨，并呼吁“全面和人道主义援助的自由准入。”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特克感叹道，“他们选出的那些为结束贫困而开辟道路的人，却被违反宪法秩序的武力驱逐，并被政变领导人拘留。”他&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“必须立即释放他们，恢复民主。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特克对政变领导人宣布起诉巴祖姆的决定表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说：“这一决定不仅出于政治动机，反对民主选举的总统，而且没有法律依据，因为民主机构的正常运作已被搁置。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还描述了“对公民空间的压制” ，”指出有关恐吓记者和禁止国际媒体的指控“非常令人担忧”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 23:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Boy, 12, allegedly abandoned in Hong Kong hospital by mainland Chinese mother returns to family, welfare authorities say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3231616/boy-12-allegedly-abandoned-hong-kong-hospital-mainland-chinese-mother-returns-family-welfare?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 23:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/665b1f90-da48-473b-a749-cb68dcf3341b_50976e47.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名 12 岁男孩据称被中国大陆母亲遗弃在香港该市社会福利部门周五透露，根据法院命令，上个月的孔医院已被归还给他的家人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“社会福利署的社工已为该男孩制定了适当的福利计划”该部门在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前，该男孩已按照法院命令恢复由家人照顾。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方指控母亲将 12 岁的儿子遗弃在医院&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该部门补充说，其社会工作者将与家人保持密切联系，以确保他得到照顾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该案件于7月21日，陈姓男童在油麻地广华医院急症室被发现独自徘徊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈出生于香港，持有香港身份证，男童被送往屯门儿童青少年院，警方搜寻其来自内地的父母。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方初步调查显示，男童被指示告诉医院职员他有咳嗽。并出现腹泻，咨询后告知护士被遗弃。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;12岁弃婴的母亲“愿意回港”接他&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;男孩被发现后不久，警方联系了已经返回河南省的他的母亲。一位消息人士称，警方调查显示，她抛弃了儿子，希望他能在这座城市接受“更好的教育”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市领导人李家超谴责了这位母亲的行为，并警告说男孩的父母可能会因抛弃他而面临法律后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名37岁的母亲于7月29日返回香港时被捕，并被指控虐待或忽视儿童。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;两天后，市法院准许她保释，但被勒令交出旅行证件，直至 9 月 11 日恢复审判。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 23:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Country Garden to drop out of Hang Seng Index as Hong Kong’s stock benchmark adds Sinopharm in quarterly recalibration]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3231513/sinopharm-join-hang-seng-index-quarterly-review-while-country-garden-be-dropped?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 21:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/4c68e12d-c4f7-46c4-a0a5-dee01c22285c_34d18d9b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;国药集团将于下个月在最新季度审核后被纳入恒生指数恒生指数编制者在盘后声明中表示，这将使成分股数量保持在 80 只不变，而房地产开发商碧桂园控股将在成为细价股后被剔除。周五关闭。这些变化将于 9 月 4 日起生效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继 2 月份没有添加新成分股后，指数编制者已连续第二个季度向恒生指数添加了新成分股，这令投资者感到惊讶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从恒生指数于 2021 年宣布全面改革恒生指数（最终将有 100 只成分股）的计划以来，恒生指数在扩大基准方面已经落后于计划。在上次调整中，在线旅行社携程集团和黄金生产商紫金矿业集团等四家公司被纳入指数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调整后，恒生指数将覆盖 64% 的股票声明称，与目前的 65% 相比，香港市场的整体价值下降了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为恒生指数系列季度审查的一部分，Trip.com 将加入 50-声明称，该指数是在香港交易的中国公司的恒生中国企业指数成员。碧桂园旗下的物业管理公司碧桂园服务控股公司将被从指数中剔除。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于中国债务危机和人民币贬值，香港股市录得 3 月份以来最糟糕的一周&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周五，国药控股股价下跌 0.5%，至 21.20 港元，全年涨幅回落至 6.9%。碧桂园股价下跌 1.4%，至 0.76 港元，由于房屋销售下滑和流动性紧缩，今年其股价下跌了 72%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恒生指数在香港股市成分多元化方面取得了一些进展。股票基准。编制者上个月表示，在与市场参与者进行了两个月的咨询后，以香港作为主要上市地点的外国公司将有资格在 11 月份的下一次调整中成为恒生指数成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这为意大利奢侈品生产商普拉达 (Prada) 和美国箱包制造商新秀丽国际 (Samsonite International) 的加入铺平了道路。根据恒生指数，海外公司的总权重将被限制在该指数的10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恒生指数今年已下跌超过9%，成为表现最差的指数之一随着中国在 Covid-19 后的经济复苏缓慢以及与美国的贸易战持续不断，该指数在全球范围内执行关键股票指数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该指数于 1969 年推出，市值为 11.4 万亿港元（ 1.5 万亿美元）。根据彭博社数据，香港股市是亚洲第三大股市，市值达 5 万亿美元，仅次于中国（9.9 万亿美元）和日本（5.8 万亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恒生家族据编制者称，截至去年底，被动基金跟踪指数，全球管理资产达 576 亿美元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Unmakeable in America? China-targeted tariffs forcing US manufacturers to relocate abroad]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3231588/unmakeable-america-china-targeted-tariffs-forcing-us-manufacturers-relocate-abroad?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/666a7bf5-d83d-4b2b-94b3-7111f016377d_8ad7157f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当美国音频扬声器设计师和制造商 Misco 总裁 Dan Digre 时，六月份在佛罗里达州奥兰多举行的一次行业聚会上发表主题演讲时，他毫不掩饰地谴责华盛顿对中国商品征收进口关税的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关税阻碍了美国扬声器公司在美国生产产品。迪格雷对同情的观众说，这破坏了“本届政府在美国建设更多工厂的政策”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Misco 是一家小型家族企业，于 1949 年在明尼苏达州明尼阿波利斯成立，而其他制造商则留在原地不动。离开该国，前往中国追逐更便宜的劳动力和更低的成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在竞争激烈的环境中生存并蓬勃发展后，Misco 难以跟上，并将其部分业务转移到了中国。现在，它正在努力将其余产品留在美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扬声器的应用广泛：吉他、商业航空公司、军事应用和医疗设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最初决定留在美国美国认为扬声器是一项核心技术，应该在美国制造，但现在Misco处于竞争劣势，因为“在美国制造扬声器的公司支付的关税是完全在中国制造的公司的三倍”， Digre 告诉《华盛顿邮报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是因为从中国进口扬声器零部件的关税为 25%，而成品扬声器的关税为 7.5%。简而言之，对于商品制造商来说，从中国进口最终产品比在美国制造更有意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“关税的目的是保护美国工业，而不是降低其竞争力， ”迪格雷说道。 “但这就是关税的影响。这使我们的成本更高，从而降低了我们的竞争力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管将部分成本转嫁给客户，Misco 认为“不在美国生产更多产品，但具有讽刺意味的是，最终具有商业意义” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登限制美国对中国科技的投资，做出“紧急”声明&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作为对中国采取强硬态度的承诺的一部分，美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普宣布了四笔投资自 2018 年起征收关税。前两项，即众所周知的清单 1 和清单 2，分别于当年 7 月和 8 月对价值至少 500 亿美元的中国商品征收 25% 的关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接下来的几个月，清单3对另外价值2000亿美元的中国商品征收10%的税。这个数额后来被提高到25%。 2019年，特朗普宣布了清单4a，对价值至少1200亿美元的中国商品征收15%的关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在2020年，中美贸易战让全球市场陷入困境后，特朗普签署了一项清单与北京达成的第一阶段协议，允许一定程度的减税，以换取在两年内购买大量美国出口产品并对中国经济做法进行结构性改变的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议对清单进行了减税扬声器、转盘、电视、投影仪和其他电子产品等 4a 商品的税率从 15% 降至 7.5%。不过，清单 3 中的 25% 关税保持不变，其中包括制造扬声器所需的零部件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年入主白宫的美国总统乔·拜登在很大程度上维持了特朗普政府的关税水平。地方。自去年5月以来，美国贸易代表办公室一直在审查关税的必要性和影响。其评估预计将于秋季结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国贸易代表 Katherine Tai 表示，关税变化可能即将到来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为本次审查的一部分，我们正在考虑现有的关税结构，以及如何根据对美国经济部门的影响以及增加国内制造业的目标使关税更具战略性，”她的办公室在7月回应美国参议院财政委员会的询问时表示。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明称，美国贸易代表办公室将考虑是否需要采取额外的关税排除程序，以及“如何改变未来的排除以使其更有效”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;超过 300 项排除已生效，每项预计将于 9 月 30 日到期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着地缘政治不确定性的升温，中国的出口蛋糕是否正在融化？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在一封公开信中由 170 个贸易协会组成的联盟美国促进自由贸易组织 (Americans for Free Trade) 于 7 月 27 日向美国贸易代表办公室 (USTR) 发布了一份报告，敦促戴“及时”宣布继续实施现有的排除条款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该组织成立于 2018 年，“团结一致”据其 X（前身为 Twitter）社交媒体账户称，“我们正在对抗关税”。美国自由贸易协会代表制造商、农民和农业综合企业、零售商、技术公司、服务供应商、天然气和石油公司、进口商、出口商和其他供应链利益相关者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该组织表示，在过去的五年里，多年来，“美国进口商，包括我们联盟的成员，已经支付了超过 1830 亿美元”的关税，而美国贸易代表办公室关于排除的“最后一刻”决定破坏了政府“确保供应链弹性的既定目标”。&lt;/该联盟补充道，“美国家庭、工人和企业继续面临前所未有的、不确定的经济挑战”，并称自己是“对关税和需求的持续负面影响发表评论的数百个团体和公司之一”。寻求新的战略方法来解决中国的不公平贸易行为”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;华盛顿在美中贸易问题上的鹰派两党分歧日益扩大&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，低迷的制造业继续对那些支持美国的人来说是一个坏兆头行业非营利组织供应管理协会的数据显示，7 月份美国制造业活动连续第九个月收缩，这是自 2007 年全球金融危机以来最长的收缩期。 2008年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，上个月采购经理人指数为46.4，较6月的46.0略有上升，为2020年5月以来的最低水平。读数低于50表明活动正在下降。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，由于陷入困境的企业为了维持生存而削减员工人数，7 月份美国工厂就业人数降至三年来的最低水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查涵盖的 18 个行业群体中有 7 个报告称产量下降以及六月份的就业情况。这些制造商的范围从纺织厂到电气设备，从塑料到电器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国自由贸易组织在致众议院中国问题特别委员会主席、威斯康星州共和党议员迈克·加拉格尔的一封信中表示，关税已经美国“抑制了制造业”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这封信提到了 Misco 的经历，并援引该公司的话说，它认为自己“因在美国生产扬声器而受到了惩罚”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国人为自由贸易组织还为专家组指出了其他受中国针对关税影响的企业，例如一家 IT 公司表示，该公司每年为清单 3 和 4a 中指定的零部件支付了超过 3.5 亿美元的费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;美国芯片公司需要进入中国：半导体贸易组织&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但在多次尝试获得排除以及重新配置其供应链和削减成本后，该公司“现在正在考虑是否将其制造转移到中国”墨西哥，然后将产品免税进口到美国，这将导致 1,300 个美国就业岗位处于危险之中”，据该联盟称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Digre 表示，Misco 和另一家扬声器公司的产品排除请求遭到了美国政府的拒绝美国贸易代表办公室在特朗普执政期间没有做出任何解释。他批评排除审查不透明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有人知道这个过程是如何运作的。没有人知道标准是什么。没有任何证据，也没有给出任何解释，说明为什么排除请求被拒绝，”他说。迪格雷表示，他认为拜登政府应该重新考虑审查程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国自由贸易协会的美国贸易代表办公室在致加拉格尔的信中没有就政府的关税审查举行公开听证会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们认为美国贸易代表办公室必须迅速采取行动，宣布与其审查相关的决定，”该联盟写道，并认为审查必须“公平和透明”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些分析师也猛烈抨击关税适得其反。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿智库卡托研究所的克拉克·帕卡德和斯科特·林西科姆表示，政府对北京国际贸易和投资行为问题的反应“在过去一直严重不足”他们在 5 月份的美中贸易报告中表示，“无论是关税还是国内补贴，都不足以应对在 21 世纪超越中国的严峻任务”，并将该政策描述为&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美中关系取得缓慢但关键的进展：美国企业家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据该报告，穆迪分析估计，中美贸易战已导致导致美国失去约 30 万个就业岗位，而纽约联储的一项研究称，关税导致“投资放缓导致企业市值损失约 1.7 万亿美元”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Digre 表示，官员们“尽管政府意识到其政策带来的挑战，但仍处于瘫痪状态。他表示，美国有关对华政策的政治讨论“非常两极分化”和“非常有害”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于一个政治家来说，说出任何可能被视为对中国软弱的言论都是失败的论据，”他添加。 “我认为拜登政府害怕做任何政治反对派可能会说的事情，‘好吧，你刚刚让中国人受益’。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不知道他们会做任何事情，”Digre 说道，并指出 2024 年美国总统竞选的争夺正在进行中。 “我当然认为他们不会在选举前采取任何行动。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Longer Hong Kong storage time for eggs, sperm and embryos unlikely to boost birth rate, say reproductive medicine experts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231613/hong-kong-reproductive-medicine-experts-say-longer-storage-time-eggs-sperm-and-embryos-unlikely?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 22:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/3d8370c3-5806-49c4-8e38-1049d243668a_34df544d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港卵子、精子和胚胎的储存时间由10天延长to 55 years would not help to increase the city&#39;s birth rate, experts have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They explained on Friday the suggested new timespan was “unrealistic” and not suitable for Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Professor Ernest Ng Hung-yu, the former head of the division of reproductive medicine at Queen Mary Hospital, said the extension, proposed by lawmaker Regina Ip Lau Suk-yee, would have little effect on tackling the city&#39;s low birth rate because there was no real demand for a storage period of more than 10 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng explained that most people who stored reproductive material would use them within four years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are indeed people who may wish to freeze them for more than 10 years, but it is not the major problem,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We do not recommend women to bear children at an older age, which will increase the risks of complications such as post-partum haemorrhage.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was speaking after Ip, convenor of the key decision-making Executive Council and New People&#39;s Party chairwoman, suggested the change should be included in Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu&#39;s second policy address, expected to be delivered in October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ip on Thursday told the media that the proposed extension would increase flexibility for couples to have children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added her proposal was in line with Britain, which in 2022 increased its storage period from 10 to 55 years to allow people more control over child-bearing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s 10-year maximum storage period can cost up to HK$200,000 (US$25,500) in some clinics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ip&#39;s proposal came after the Family Planning Association warned that the number of childless couples in Hong Kong had reached an “alarming” level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average number also dropped to a record low of 0.9 per couple.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest census statistics also showed that only 32,600 new births were recorded in the year to June, down from 35,100 over the same period last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;Childless Hong Kong couples double in 5 years as births drop below 1 per family&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Ng said the present maximum was sufficient for those undecided about their fertility plans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that 55 years would be too long for anyone who wanted to use their own reproductive material.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“10 years is already very long.如果患者真的希望生孩子，他们会在10年内生孩子，”他说。 “If a patient would like to have children, they would not wait until they are too old.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng said if freezing centres had lost contact with the patients over a long period, the accumulation of unwanted material might cause storage problems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he added that a longer storage limit could be useful for young cancer patients, who might lose the ability to have a natural childbirth because of their treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dr Louis Chan Yik-si, an obstetrician &amp; gynaecologist, added it was uncommon for patients to retrieve reproductive material after 10 years in cold storage and doubted the proposed change would be effective.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Professor Celia Chan Hoi-yan of the University of Hong Kong&#39;s department of social work and social administration agreed with the view that a longer storage period would not help to increase the birth rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan, a specialist in fertility and infertility counselling, said overseas studies had shown that the usage rate of frozen eggs was as low as 10 to 30 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our studies often find that whether people choose to have children is based on the socio-economic environment of society and their own economic situation,” she explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Raise Hong Kong&#39;s storage time for eggs, sperm and embryos to 55 years: Regina Ip&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chan suggested that three free cycles of in vitro fertilisation (IVF) treatment to couples with fertility problems might be more effective.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added there were more than one million embryos that no one would claim in countries overseas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Religiously or ethically, some people may consider these embryos as lives,” she said. “There are a lot of debates over whether clinics could dispose of them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan, also the coordinator in China and Hong Kong for the International Infertility Counselling Organisation, said the city had no centralised system for recording frozen reproductive material because they were stored in different clinics and medical institutions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the extension is implemented in Hong Kong, the government will need to seriously consider the monitoring of the storage system,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said that extending the storage period would involve ethical, physical, and psychosocial dilemmas and that the process was not just about money and couples&#39; preferences.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said she believed that the UK government had chosen to prolong the period to 55 years because egg, embryo and sperm donation were more common there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added women in the UK could donate their eggs to storage banks, but Hong Kong did not have a similar system and people had to find donors by themselves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The proposed extension may open another door,” she said. “我们可以允许女性将未使用的冷冻卵子捐赠给银行供其他夫妇使用吗？ This can be an option.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US slaps tariffs on solar panel companies dodging China duties by finishing products in Southeast Asia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231614/us-slaps-tariffs-solar-panel-companies-dodging-china-duties-finishing-products-southeast-asia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 22:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/1388eae7-faa4-4b58-8ce4-28c57827b91f_dad9e263.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The United States on Friday will finalise a decision to impose import duties on solar panel makers who finished their products in Southeast Asian nations to avoid tariffs on Chinese-made goods, according to a senior Commerce Department official.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision, which largely mirrors a preliminary finding the agency made in December, was opposed by buyers of solar panels that rely on cheap products made overseas to make their projects competitive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it is good news for the small US solar manufacturing industry, which for years has struggled to compete with Chinese goods and is enjoying renewed investment due to subsidies in US President Joe Biden&#39;s landmark climate change law.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US House votes to repeal Biden solar tariff waiver for 4 Southeast Asian nations&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Commerce probe found that units of Chinese companies BYD, Trina Solar, Longi Green Energy and Canadian Solar were dodging US tariffs on Chinese solar cells and panels by conducting minor processing to finish their products in Cambodia, Malaysia, Thailand and Vietnam before shipping them to the US market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those countries account for about 80 per cent of US panel supplies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agency will also impose duties on New East Solar because it refused to cooperate with an on-site audit of its operations in Cambodia, the official said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other companies operating in those nations have the ability to pursue a certification process to show that they are not circumventing tariffs. To become certified, solar cells and panels must contain non-Chinese wafers and three other key components.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US has had anti-dumping duties in place for a decade on Chinese-made solar products after a Commerce probe found Chinese companies were receiving unfair government subsidies that kept their prices artificially low.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The companies and others will face the same duty rates the United States already assesses on their Chinese-made products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They will not kick in, however, until June of 2024 thanks to a two-year waiver from US President Joe Biden that was intended to ensure ample panel supplies while domestic manufacturing ramps up.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong pre-war cinema to be turned into restaurant celebrating Cheung Chau’s history and culture]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3231608/hong-kong-pre-war-cinema-be-turned-restaurant-celebrating-cheung-chaus-history-and-culture?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 21:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/584e37ab-9c71-4d72-abff-88c6b2b04f97_87d1c320.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;One of Hong Kong&#39;s two remaining pre-war cinemas will be revitalised into a restaurant that will open in 2025 and commemorate the history and culture of Cheung Chau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The long-abandoned Cheung Chau Cinema, which the government has listed as a Grade III historic building, was established in 1931. The 600-seat venue screened Cantonese and Western films until it closed in 1997.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The renovation project was announced by the Cheung Chau Culture Company on Friday as part of the second phase of a revitalisation plan, both stages of which have seen hundreds of millions of Hong Kong dollars invested.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A multicultural park next to the cinema is set to open next Monday as part of the first phase, while the cinema&#39;s main block will be turned into a Chinese-themed restaurant and launch in 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Great escapes: Hong Kong&#39;s best outlying-island guest houses&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“As there are few big restaurants that can hold many residents simultaneously, we have decided to change the cinema into a restaurant to satisfy the island&#39;s need,” company CEO Eric Chiang Chun-wai said. “We hope this new attraction can drive an influx of visitors to Cheung Chau.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company said workers had recovered pieces of pottery dating back 5,000 years during the restoration process for the cinema, leading to a three-year exploration that unearthed more than 3,000 items.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The people and material resources needed at the time caused us to spend an extra eight-digit sum of money on the project,” Chiang said. “文物的保护需要先进的技能，否则它们可能会很快被侵蚀或损坏。 Therefore, it is not easy for us as a private organisation to showcase the real potteries.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company CEO said he hoped cooperating with authorities would mean the artefacts could be replicated using 3D printing and the copies could be publicly displayed in two years&#39; time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chiang said authorities had provided assistance and professional advice during the restoration process, adding the company planned to apply for government funding after the grand opening in 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The business had also spent a lot of resources on strengthening the building&#39;s structure and conserving its original facade, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chiang said the project sought to restore the cinema to its former glory by organising film-related activities, as well as using the venue to promote Cheung Chau&#39;s history and traditional culture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Expressing his support for the renovation, an island resident surnamed Wong said he remembered paying only HK$3 (38 US cents) as a boy to watch Bruce Lee films at the cinema with his friends.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s hard for me to get used to life without this cinema … but I will still try the restaurant,” the 61-year-old fisherman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Cheung Chau pirate attack: what really happened in 1912 raid&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“It will be a good place for me to gather with my neighbours,” said Siu, another resident of the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CEO Chiang also noted the company had originally intended to develop the land for residential use, but later applied for it to be set aside for commercial purposes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The multicultural park created under the first leg of the scheme spans 3,530 square metres and consists of a cultural hub, information centre, piazza and a studio offering activities such as workshops and outdoor film screenings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ticket prices for activities will range from HK$128 to HK$268 during the trial period, before going to between HK$180 and HK$348.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Forget world domination, India won’t catch up with China any time soon]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231449/forget-world-domination-india-wont-catch-china-any-time-soon?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/17/8fddfa34-22b3-4e36-808e-0dc9b6cd88c3_b0fd427a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Last year, as Prime Minister Narendra Modi celebrated 75 years of India&#39;s independence from British rule, he called on the nation to “dominate the world”. Earlier this week, once again at the Red Fort, he evoked “Amrit Kaal” – a crucial era when the gates of opportunity open.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His “reform, perform, transform” mantra involves dreaming big. He was possibly dreaming of those halcyon days up to 1870 when India and China counted as the world&#39;s two largest and most powerful economies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But a dream does not make a plan. And in the nine years since Modi came to power, his plans to propel India to the top table of the world&#39;s most powerful economies remain largely that – plans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Harvard University&#39;s Graham Allison reminded us in a recent Foreign Policy report that about a decade ago, the late Singapore leader Lee Kwan Yew had said India would never catch up with China and would always remain “the country of the future”. Lee said: “Do not talk about India and China in the same breath” – throwing the gauntlet down to those who see India biting at China&#39;s heels and cheer India on in hopes of hobbling China&#39;s ascent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To be fair to Modi, his government&#39;s economic performance is respectable after decades of stagnation and disappointment. India&#39;s gross domestic product has grown by about 6 per cent every year on average since 2014, reaching an all-time high of 9.1 per cent last year – impressive in light of the upheavals of the Covid-19 pandemic and recession in many parts of the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But a wide range of structural reforms are needed if India is to escape the shackles of its economic past. These include the grip of caste, bureaucratic friction, impenetrable tax rules, still-chronic protection of local business magnates and import tariffs that are among the world&#39;s highest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Any country rising from such a low base must recognise that it will take many decades to achieve anything the late Lee would regard as parity with China – and that this is nothing to be ashamed of. Goldman Sachs predicted last month that by 2075, China would become the world&#39;s largest economy (US$57 trillion), with India (at US$52.5 trillion) overtaking the US (at US$51.5 trillion).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Columbia University&#39;s Arvind Panagariya has similar projections, calculating recently in Time magazine that if India&#39;s real GDP grew at 8 per cent a year into the 2040s and 5 per cent after that, and if the US continues to grow on average by 2 per cent a year, India would overtake the US in 2073.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These are big “ifs”, even for those brave enough to make forecasts a half-century away.大量数据表明印度正走向一条更加平淡的轨迹。根据艾利森在《外交政策》中的说法，早在 2000 年，中国和印度的经济价值均不足 2 万亿美元。中国花了5年时间才达到这一标准，而印度则用了14年。 Last year, India&#39;s economy was worth US$3.4 trillion – a fraction of China&#39;s US$18.3 trillion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It will take many years of stellar economic growth for India to begin matching China in economic importance, and no amount of miraculous thinking or “China plus one” investment is likely to accelerate that.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also, many other important economic indicators remain problematic. 2000年，印度约占全球制造业的1%，而中国则为7%。到去年，印度的份额已增至 3%，而中国则为 31%。 2000年，印度仅占世界出口的1%，中国占2%。 By last year, China accounted for 15 per cent of global exports against India&#39;s share of 2 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India enthusiasts celebrate the youthfulness of India&#39;s population, but ignore the reality that this is a problem rather than an advantage when they are poorly educated or even illiterate. To accommodate them, India must produce an estimated 90 million new jobs before 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Allison reminds us that China produces twice as many STEM-qualified (in science, technology, engineering and mathematics) graduates as India, spends almost three times the percentage of its GDP on research and development, and produces 65 per cent of the world&#39;s artificial intelligence patents (vs India&#39;s 3 per cent).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Bloomberg noted in April: “India is far behind China in key aspects important for manufacturing that include infrastructure, bureaucracy, attention to detail and even a sense of urgency.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Talk of &#39;Indian century&#39; is a dangerous myth masking real issues&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Supporters of India in search of a “hobble China” narrative have been encouraged by companies such as Apple and its main Taiwanese manufacturer Foxconn, which have made tentative steps to build investments in India, but ignore the challenges they have faced, and the reality that China remains their main manufacturing base.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They have ignored the withdrawals of companies like the Royal Bank of Scotland, Harley-Davidson and Citibank, and the many other companies with plans on hold. They have tended to celebrate the deliberate obstacles to prospective investment in China, even where China is a natural partner and the benefit of collaboration is huge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rather than harbouring dreams of dominating the world, India&#39;s policymakers would benefit us all by opening up their economy and recognising that even if India does not surpass China, it can still be a huge driver in the global economy. China and India together account for one third of the world&#39;s population, one third of the global consumer class, and a quarter of all consumer spending in purchasing power parity terms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 21st century may not be India&#39;s century, but it is almost certainly Asia&#39;s. Washington needs to come to terms with that, and perhaps New Delhi does too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>