<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: China’s top server makers stop orders of memory modules containing Micron chips, sources say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3221833/tech-war-chinas-top-server-makers-stop-orders-memory-modules-containing-micron-chips-sources-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/dcd1a8fa-b16d-4b3b-a01f-f2601c90a6c4_65a47183.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;包括浪潮集团和联想集团在内的中国顶级服务器制造商已要求供应商暂停据一位了解情况的供应商称，在北京对该公司的产品实施部分禁令后，包含美国美光科技生产的芯片的模块出货量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;用于服务器内存模块的 DRAM 芯片是为保护与客户的关系而拒绝透露姓名的消息人士表示，这是一种商品化组件，通常由美光和三星电子供应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;供应商需要一些时间来对新的-该人士补充说，采购了替代品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联想和浪潮没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;暂停的订单凸显了周日宣布的中国禁令已经产生的直接影响美国最大的内存芯片制造商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国市场一直是美光的主要收入来源之一，占公司 2022 年 308 亿美元总收入的约 11%。该公司预计低禁令导致​​其总销售额出现高个位数的损失，该禁令禁止中国的关键信息基础设施运营商购买其产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;受到美国贸易制裁的浪潮和联想等根据彭博社的数据，美光产品的最大买家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;禁令还影响内存模块制造商和第三方供应商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国内存模块制造商将不得不改变他们的产品组合中国杂志《财经》周一在一篇报道中援引华泰证券分析师黄乐平的话说，由于美光禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最大的内存模块生产商之一深圳江波龙电子，美光是 2018 年至 2021 年年中的最大供应商，在此期间，每年从这家总部位于爱达荷州博伊西的公司的采购量超过采购合同总额的 33%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国家互联网信息办公室 (CAC) ) 于 3 月对美光产品发起国家安全调查，以“维护关键信息基础设施供应链安全”和“防范问题产品带来的网络空间安全风险”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这标志着外国半导体公司首次被调查受到网络安全审查，并被视为对华盛顿加强对美国先进半导体技术对华出口管制的报复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CAC 没有透露它测试了哪些产品或测试它们所使用的方法。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;美国商务部周一表示，中国当局对美光的禁令和最近对国际咨询公司的突袭与该国对开放市场和透明监管框架的承诺相矛盾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部发言人毛宁在周三的例行新闻发布会上表示，国家对美光的调查是依法进行的，最新决定是基于事实的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;审查“不针对任何特定国家或地区” ，中国也不寻求排除来自任何特定国家的技术或产品，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong to honour young leaders’ contributions to city during pandemic at annual Student of the Year Awards]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3221853/hong-kong-honour-young-leaders-contributions-city-during-pandemic-annual-student-year-awards?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/323de6ab-d85a-4792-8559-70af6b29a66e_7448ec83.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着香港在 Covid-19 大流行病后重新站稳脚跟，2023 年组织者表示，年度学生 (SOTY) 奖是一个表彰帮助社区度过艰难时期的年轻领袖的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;进入第 42 个年头，这些享有盛誉的奖项延续了他们的传统，值得寻找下一代年轻领导者，希望帮助他们进一步实现自己的事业和人生目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;年度奖项选择了“采取行动推动积极变革”的主题，以表彰和支持年轻领导者做出改变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“SOTY 不仅是授予荣誉地位和声望的奖项，还是一项有益健康的计划倡议，旨在为年轻领导者提供技能组合，使他们能够进一步取得成功，”首席执行官 Catherine So 说道南华早报的作者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该奖项由青年邮报和南华早报主办，香港赛马会赞助，希望让学生有机会讲述自己的故事，同时反思今年的主题。奖项的提名于 4 月开始，并已延长至 5 月 28 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了校友分享会和颁奖典礼之外，学生们可以与其他学生领袖联系和互动，今年，SOTY 还采取了参与度更进一步，引入了一系列炉边谈话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些与来自各个领域的领先专业人士的炉边谈话和量身定制的研讨会旨在拓宽参与者的视野，同时让他们获得对以后非常宝贵的见解和建议&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有一场旨在培养创造力和创新思维的黑客马拉松。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“一切都是中文”：香港少数族裔学生碰壁&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;九个类别的提名应展示学生如何展示他们的能力，并说明他们的课外活动如何帮助推动积极的变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SOTY 将延续其传统，为学校颁发特别奖最养育环境。这将授予与学生有密切联系并鼓励他们发挥潜力的机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欢迎学校和自我提名，但如果学生通过以下方式申请，则需要推荐信或背书非学校和自我提名渠道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;贫困香港学生获得免费航班，导师计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中四至六年级（10至13年级）政府学生- 2022-23学年注册的中学有资格提名。大奖类别面向中五至中六（11 至 13 年级）开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;入围学生和决赛入围者的姓名将于 6 月公布。他们将被邀请参加单独面试。获奖者将于 7 月的颁奖午宴上公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As Philippines tweaks US-China balance, ‘mixed messages’ could upset Beijing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3221850/philippines-tweaks-us-china-balance-mixed-messages-could-upset-beijing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 09:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/a6cff793-130f-4e10-a529-d5fe14b9ee5f_9d9885e5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;菲律宾总统小费迪南德·马科斯在向美国示好时的“混合信息”可能分析人士表示，他可能会因缺乏连贯的外交政策战略而进一步激怒中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2022 年 6 月成为总统以来，小马科斯一直倾向于加强与美国、菲律宾的关系长期盟友。去年 9 月，他在纽约会见了美国总统乔·拜登，随后本月早些时候访问了白宫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马尼拉最近还根据加强防务合作协议，允许美国士兵进入靠近台湾的军事基地协议 (EDCA)，Marcos Jnr 于 5 月 4 日表示，这些网站不会被用作“针对任何国家的任何进攻行动的集结地”。中国此前曾表示反对美国扩大在菲律宾的军事存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，同一天，小马科斯在接受路透社采访时表示，台湾附近的两个 EDCA 基地将“证明对菲律宾有用”如果这种可怕的事件发生……那么我们在台湾的菲律宾国民的安全就变得至关重要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾短暂担任小马科斯副安全顾问的 Rommel Banlaoi 批评总统“发出许多混杂的信息”并给人留下他“缺乏外交政策连贯性”的印象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括国家主席习近平在内的中国高级官员可能“对小马科斯最近在军事上更密切的举动感到不满” Banlaoi 补充说。“我认为 [中国官员] 对 EDCA 和台湾问题感到非常失望，这是一个核心利益，”另一位专家说。拒绝透露姓名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但国防和安全分析师切斯特卡瓦尔扎表示，小马科斯的举动是一个“非常了解他的听众”的人的举动，而马尼拉“现在已经赌牌支持华盛顿”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“台湾难题是马尼拉对一个中国原则的承认和 [Marcos Jnr] 实现独立外交政策议程的一大谜团，”他说。 “在他试图驯服中国领导人的同时，必须谨慎处理这一安全困境，以适应我们新 EDCA 基地中美国人的需求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Banlaoi，菲律宾和平、暴力研究所所长和恐怖主义研究中心的负责人表示，他对小马科斯转向与美国建立更密切的关系感到惊讶，这违背了他早先的竞选承诺，即他不会在南中国海发生冲突时寻求华盛顿的帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“这种态度的突然转变有利于美国，肯定有非常强烈的令人信服的政治或个人原因，”他说，暗示与中国不同，美国可以动员菲律宾武装部队支持反对小马科斯。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Cabalza 表示，军​​方完全支持 Marcos Jnr 转向美国，因为“华盛顿大力支持菲律宾武装部队的军事现代化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;菲律宾的 Marcos Jnr 编织了新的外交手段，带来支持紧密联系的美国关系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;纽约的菲律宾裔美国律师鲁本·卡兰萨 (Ruben Carranza) 表示，这个令人信服的理由也可能是指悬在马科斯家族头上的法律诉讼，他曾是马科斯家族的一员五名专员正在调查 Ferdinand Marcos Snr 和他的妻子 Imelda（现任总统的父母）以及他们的亲属的不义之财。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1986 年，马科斯一家在人民支持的和平行动后逃往夏威夷起义。然而，在美国夏威夷地方法院裁定支持老马科斯的 10,059 名人权受害者提起的集体诉讼之前，小马科斯和他的母亲伊梅尔达回到了菲律宾。由于后者于 1989 年去世，马科斯的遗产和他的继承人有责任支付法院判给的 20 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小马科斯以国家元首的身份获得豁免权，可以进入美国。尽管在美国因藐视法庭而面临 3.54 亿美元的罚款，但拜登在去年会见了他，因为他未能遵守关于支付家庭资产的裁决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Carranza 指出这些是“Marcos Jnr 的决定性原因”他会在需要时转移到美国”，并补充说，“这是为马科斯服务的外交政策，而不是菲律宾的国家利益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说：“他的决定的核心...... .他将永远保护马科斯家族的财富并扩大他们对权力的控制。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于马尼拉的智库国际发展与安全合作组织的创始主席卡巴尔扎同意，小马科斯可以从中获得更多好处&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国承认海牙裁决胜诉，该裁决允许马尼拉在国际法庭上阐明其海洋权利，”卡瓦尔扎说，他指的是 2016 年联合国仲裁裁决，该裁决使北京在该公约中的广泛主张无效。南中国海。中国拒绝了这一决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北京不断涌入我们在西菲律宾海拥有主权的领土，并激怒菲律宾海岸卫士和水手，”他补充说。 “美国通过承诺的经济援助改善了与菲律宾的国防伙伴关系，而中国尚未完成南海交通线的改善，因为菲律宾人目睹了更多的灰色地带战略、电子战和未实现的经济方案来自北京。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;如果美中紧张局势升级，“友好”的菲律宾能否置身事外？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Aaron Jed Rabena，亚太进步之路研究员在马尼拉表示，小马科斯的转变有很多原因，包括他的家人在美国的法律诉讼、北京在南中国海的行动，以及总统自己通过在南海问题上采取更强硬的路线来加强其在国内的政治合法性。主权问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国是南中国海的声索国，美国不是，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种转变也让他获得了政治资本和支持Rabena 补充说，来自已故外交大臣阿尔伯特德尔罗萨里奥和退休的最高法院副法官安东尼奥卡皮奥等反对派坚定支持者。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Influencer in China dies after drinking 4 bottles of ‘Chinese vodka’ during live stream, renewing ‘do anything for traffic’ debate]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3221414/influencer-china-dies-after-drinking-4-bottles-chinese-vodka-during-live-stream-renewing-do-anything?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/23/131eed6f-e519-4ca9-9c21-e28afeeefa97_5afc4889.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一名 34 岁的网络影响者在食用超过四片后死亡直播期间喝几瓶有时被称为“中国伏特加”的白酒已成为大陆社交媒体上的热门话题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在抖音上被称为“三千哥”的中国东部江苏省男子去世了据尚游新闻报道，在 5 月 16 日凌晨 1 点开始的一场直播比赛之后。当天下午晚些时候，他被发现死在朋友家的一张桌子上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子参加比赛的视频流媒体活动此后在中国社交媒体上风靡一时。视频显示几瓶白酒放在三千阁面前的桌子上。看到他一口气喝完每一瓶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;网红的一位姓赵的密友说，当时有 100 多人登录了比赛的在线聊天室，但没有人提出任何疑虑。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“他的性格很好。他非常真诚和温柔，”赵告诉尚友新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，三千歌在四年前创业失败后开始直播。他说，三千哥专门从事在线对战直播，参与者试图用白酒喝醉对方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一段早些时候在网上流传的直播视频显示，三千哥将两瓶白酒倒进他捡来的一个大酒杯里&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵说，三千哥最近在接到邻居的噪音投诉后，开始在朋友提供的房间里直播。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直播-据相关人士称，流媒体节目运行顺利，没有参与者报告任何问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，当天晚些时候，当三千歌的朋友回到家时，他发现他脸朝下，躺在他住过的办公桌前没有呼吸-早些时候播放了饮酒比赛。他后来被确认死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他一个人死了，非常令人难过，”赵说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在撰写本文时，一条关于三千歌去世消息的微博帖子已经收到5,475 条评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人评论说：“他们为了流量和奖励什么都做。他们失去了控制并伤害了自己。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个人问道：“什么样的互联网用户喜欢看这种愚蠢的饮酒？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国影响者突破界限并经常伤害自己或其他的追随者经常登上大陆新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月，一名男子在假装被困在屋顶后拍摄了消防员营救的视频，引起了广泛批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早些时候今年 3 月，一位视频博主在谎称自己被诊断出患有肝癌后引起了众怒。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Flight risk: first, Cathay Pacific’s rude cabin crew, now its pilots. Why are staff at Hong Kong’s flag carrier so unhappy?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3221856/flight-risk-first-cathay-pacifics-rude-cabin-crew-now-its-pilots-why-are-staff-hong-kongs-flag?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/25/997c2445-e553-46f9-9904-c8e35969b32f_347d023c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港旗舰航空公司国泰航空的员工总是因为各种错误的原因登上头条.在过去的几天里，该航空公司卷入了一场不断扩大的丑闻，因为其机组人员被发现公开侮辱中国大陆乘客。最近，其飞行员被指控在飞机滑行时故意减速。在由两部分组成的系列文章的第二部分中，劳拉·威斯布鲁克和奥斯卡·刘探讨了飞行员的不满。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年前，当来自澳大利亚的高级飞行员杰里米·琼斯*加入香港国泰航空公司时，他租了一辆800尺半山单位。每月租金为 32,000 港元（4,086 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两年前，他和他的家人从富裕社区降级到香港机场附近东涌一套 650 平方英尺的公寓，租金为每月 20,000 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;和所有国泰航空飞行员一样，两年前他的工资被削减了 40%，现在高达 30% 的收入是可变的，与他的实际飞行时间挂钩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;工会表示，香港国泰航空已经失去了一半以上的高级飞行员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“账单不得不降下来。我们不经常出去吃饭。现在我们在家做饭并邀请朋友过来，”琼斯说，他和邮报采访过的所有飞行员一样，拒绝透露姓名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，城市的生活变得越来越昂贵，他和他的家庭主妇妻子去年刚刚生了一个孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在考虑在我女儿开始国际学校时每年支付 140,000 港元的学费。这位 40 岁的老人说，她三岁时我有权领取的 10 万港元教育津贴不足以弥补我的收入减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到几年前，国泰航空的飞行员都是最优秀的航空公司的品牌为驻扎在该市的员工赢得了声望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，随着航空公司的财富在冠状病毒大流行的动荡三年中一落千丈，员工的地位和士气也受到影响。该航空公司为航班和机组人员强制执行了新的、更便宜的雇佣合同以削减成本，并且为国泰航空工作不再像以前那样享有同样的声望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，随着这座城市和这家航空公司从大流行中走出来，薪水也有所下降没有恢复到接近以前水平的任何地方。更糟糕的是，在全球飞行员短缺的情况下，其他航空公司更快地投入资金解决这个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这种背景下，内部人士表示，国泰航空的飞行员很不高兴也就不足为奇了.人力短缺加上士气低落将如何影响航母的恢复？飞行员的顾虑会得到果断解决吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;过去的美好时光&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在大流行期间，国泰航空的客运量仅下降到 2019 年水平的 2%那一年的反政府抗议活动吓跑了游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于没有国内市场可以依靠，这家航空公司因现金流失而屈服。 2020 年 10 月，它裁员 5,900 人并关闭了地区分支机构国泰港龙航空，并采取了一项由政府支持的 390 亿港元的重组计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，即使在大流行之前，它就已经面临更激烈的全球竞争，并且已经开始削减其薪酬待遇。 2018 年，它为所有新员工引入了较低的起薪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到 2021 年，它将这些条款扩大到试点，过渡期是在 2022 年 12 月 31 日之前缩减住房和教育津贴。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;香港国泰歧视丑闻：机组人员为何行为如此恶劣？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在裁员之前，国泰机长每年可享受高达 120 万港元的住房津贴并不少见。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空当时表示，该合同将飞行员的工资削减了约 40%，并削减了住房和退休津贴，使他们的薪酬待遇与新加坡航空公司等海外竞争对手的薪酬待遇持平。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;但随着疫情过后旅行需求激增，航空公司提高了票价，新加坡航空公司和阿联酋航空等主要航空公司的利润创下历史新高。反过来，员工将获得奖金和更高的薪水作为奖励。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于香港是最后一批放弃严格的 Covid 限制并全面开放边界的城市之一，国泰航空仍在努力追赶竞争对手.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其工会表示，承运人必须果断采取行动，改进其合同，以在急需经验丰富的飞行员的市场中保持竞争力。许多能上赌注的人已经离开了更好的牧场。其他人在大流行期间辞职了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从 2018 年起加入航空公司的 COS18 计划飞行员的入门级二副年薪为 376,608 港元，入门级副驾驶的年基本薪水为 577,500 港元顶级船长“最高”120万港元。年度基本薪酬不包括津贴、花红和退休金供款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，在 2008 年签署名为 COS08 的合同的人，二副获得 488,964 港元，大副获得 975,504 港元，而高级副驾驶则高达 210 万港元。顶级船长。 COS08 飞行员和 COS18 飞行员的年度最高住房配套分别为 480,000 港元和 396,000 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，飞行员工资的 30% 现在是可变的，并且与飞行小时数挂钩。以前的可变部分仅为 10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些数字讲述了国泰飞行员不断变化的命运的鲜明故事。根据该航空公司 2022 年的最新年度业绩，自 2019 年以来，每年收入数百万美元的飞行员人数减少了一半，部分原因是减员，但主要是因为减薪。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国泰航空太平洋警告飞行员不要滑行缓慢、机场拥挤&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;例如，8 名飞行员每年拿回 400 万至 450 万港元的年薪，而 2019 年为 94 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;26飞行员的收入在 350 万至 400 万港元之间，而 2019 年为 248 人，而 71 人的收入在 300 万至 350 万港元之间，而 2019 年为 437 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;香港与中东争夺飞行员，只会在 2028 年再次成为航空枢纽”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港空勤人员协会上周二表示，在大流行病爆发前的 2019 年第四季度，该航空公司在国泰航空及其已解散的子公司国泰港龙航空拥有 3,840 名各级飞行员到上个月下降到 2,417 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会表示，机长人数从 1,410 人减少了一半以上，减少到 678 人，而大副人数减少了 38%，从 1,740 人减少到 1,074 人。二副人数从 690 人下降 3% 至 665 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金钱导致整体士气低落，加上大流行期间要求工作人员进行闭环安排并远离家乡的规定连续几周。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据飞行员和机组人员称，现在随着更多航班的增加而没有增加人力，这种情况正在成为麻烦的根源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;员工士气问题也在三名机组人员因在飞往香港的航班上侮辱一些中国大陆乘客的英语能力而被立即解雇后出现。工会将士气描述为“极度低落”，需要极度关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，国泰航空公司的飞行员被警告不要故意缓慢滑行，据称是为了记录更多的时间以收取更多的报酬。当局指责他们助长了香港机场的拥堵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 35 岁的英国外籍初级飞行员戴维斯·汤普森*表示，额外的滑行时间并不多。相反，这“更多地反映了飞行员不愿意为公司的效率付出额外的努力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国泰航空试图化解工会抨击管理层的侮辱丑闻&lt;/h3>;代表国泰航空飞行员的航空公司协会主席保罗·威瑟尔特 (Paul Weatherilt) 说：“在大流行期间，每个人都明白我们必须省钱。大流行现在已经结束了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Weatherilt 仍然希望合同会得到改善，称工会愿意与管理层合作“敲定一些重大改变，使工作更具吸引力，以留住员工并希望能吸引一些离开的人回来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，目前飞行员的薪酬方案在很多方面与其他航空公司的合同相似，尤其是在美国，但薪酬更高那里“有更多的保护措施”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;国泰老板警告员工歧视丑闻加强了航空公司“长期持有”的观点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国泰还需要偿还政府在&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大学航空政策与研究中心的袁志乐表示，虽然该航空公司仍处于复苏阶段，但它“可能希望在短期内更保守地改善财务状况&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他指出，从长远来看，国泰航空“在长途市场面临着来自其他枢纽航空公司的激烈竞争，在短途市场则面临着低成本航空公司的激烈竞争”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shukor航空咨询公司 Endau Analytics 的创始人 Yusof 表示，在过去的 30 年里，国泰一直保持着“业内最优秀人才”的称号，这是有代价的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们了解自己的立场他们能够在公司的薪酬和特权方面推动他们的议程。在 Covid 之前，它管理得很好，但我认为现在没有空间了，”Yusof 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;无休止的竞争&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新加坡航空集团，其中包括其预算部门 Scoot , 在上个财政年度赚取 16.2 亿美元，是 76 年来的最高净利润。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为与工会商定的利润分享奖金公式的一部分，该集团将向所有符合条件的员工支付6.65 个月的奖金和最多 1.5 个月的特惠奖金，加起来大约是八个月的工资。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡航空公司在创纪录的利润后向员工支付 8 个月的奖金&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;在大流行期间，飞行员同意减薪高达 60%，该协议在 2020 年挽救了约 400 个工作岗位。一位发言人在给《华盛顿邮报》的一份声明中表示，该航空公司“已完全恢复所有减薪措施”于 2022 年大流行期间实施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡航空集团 3 月份的客运量为大流行前的 79%，而由国泰航空及其预算子公司香港快运组成的国泰航空集团表示，它同月达到 50%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，总部位于迪拜的阿联酋航空集团公布年利润为 30 亿美元，集团收入增长 81% 至 330 亿美元。据媒体报道，该航空公司将向员工提供为期六个月的奖金。该承运人以隐私原因拒绝就此事发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据业内消息人士称，阿联酋航空恢复了大流行期间对飞行员合同的减薪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对飞行员的需求全球各地的工会都在为更高的加薪讨价还价，美国航空公司达美航空公司 (Delta Air Lines) 在一份行业领先的合同中为其飞行员提供了三年内 34% 的加薪。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港成为阿联酋航空举办招聘会，成为飞行员招聘战场&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据路透社上周报道，作为新的四年暂定合同的一部分，美国航空公司的飞行员今年将获得 21% 的加薪。&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;美国航空、达美航空、联合航空和西南航空估计今年将雇用约 8,000 名飞行员。本月，在大流行期间裁员 30% 的澳大利亚航空公司 Qantas 表示，今年计划再招聘 300 名飞行员和机组人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空首席执行官林绍波接任1 月份上任时的首要任务是提高生产力和竞争力，但在 5 月份的股东大会上透露，包括机组人员在内的人员配置问题正在影响该航空公司进一步提高运力目标的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该集团设定的目标是到今年年底达到大流行前客运航班运力的 70%，到 2024 年底达到 100%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司还必须克服培训积压的问题&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰集团公布​​ 2022 年亏损 65 亿港元（8.28 亿美元），但该公司的核心航空业务在 2022 年最后六个月反弹至盈利 22.6 亿港元。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;航空公司从今年开始增加了津贴。最资深的机长现在每月可额外领取 36,000 港元，除基本薪金和时薪外，每年可额外获得 432,000 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司还增加了机师子女的年度教育津贴至每名儿童每年的学费为 100,000 港元。飞行员工会表示，该分数之前是按英国学校基金会 (ESF) 设定的学费的 90% 计算得出的。根据 ESF，本学年的税率在 119,100 港元至 159,300 港元之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港国泰航空公布 2022 年亏损 65 亿港元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在一份声明中据邮报报道，国泰航空的一位女发言人表示，2018 年推出的合同使其“业务目标与我们的飞行员保持一致，通过奖励生产力同时在停工期间保护飞行员”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;指出基本月薪增加了 3.3%从 1 月份开始，该航空公司表示会定期审查其竞争力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该发言人补充说，该航空公司的流失率“在包括飞行员在内的所有员工群体中都已正常化”，并且已重新聘请了 250 名国泰飞行员，包括机长&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该航空公司表示，今年有望招聘 3,000 名员工，其中包括 700 名飞行员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但新措施对 Jeremy Jones 来说还不够，因为他已经决定离开香港去美国。他为申请所谓的绿卡支付了 12 万港元，并为转换他的飞行员执照支付了 8 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这完全值得，”琼斯说，并补充说他可以赚更多的钱我们。 “Hong Kong is one of the best cities in the world and I love Cathay, but not that contract.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Cathay has take-it-or-leave-it deal for pilots: salary and benefit cuts, or the door&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Gulf carriers such as Emirates and Qatar Airways are also on a global hunt for pilots.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the base salaries were comparable with Cathay&#39;s, generous allowances such as Emirates offering a four-bedroom villa for families and education allowance for school-age children, are juicy carrots. Plus, there is no personal income tax in the United Arab Emirates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some 210 pilots in Hong Kong attended an in-person recruitment fair hosted by the carrier in March, Emirates told the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to its website, an A380 direct entry captain&#39;s yearly salary is HK$1.11 million, while a first officer can earn HK$788,000 as an annual base salary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Emirates loves Cathay guys because the standard is really high,” said a former senior Cathay pilot, Jack Smith*, who resigned last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Junior pilots at Cathay have fewer options, as those who move airlines must work their way up the ranks again.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As they stay put, however, Cathay&#39;s junior pilots are being deployed for ground staff duties instead of clocking flying hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Starting from next month, cadet pilot graduates will spend up to two months at Hong Kong&#39;s airport, including frontline customer training in different positions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cathay said the trial programme would broaden the induction experience of its cadet pilot graduates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among them is Shane Yeung*, 26, a local junior pilot who joined Cathay less than three years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I haven&#39;t even touched a real aircraft since I finished the training in Australia. Yet the company calls us &#39;future captains&#39;. How ironic,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said he was asked to do ground duties four days a week, including classroom training and scanning boarding passes, which did not count as flying hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Cathay Pacific to require cadet pilots to work with customers at Hong Kong&#39;s airport&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yeung said he had no plans to leave until he completed his training, as he needed to commit to working with the company for six years. Pilots who quit the airline within six years of employment must reimburse a portion of the HK$1.1 million pilot training course fees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another local junior pilot, Samuel Wong*, who has been with Cathay for more than five years said he did not know the amount of his next pay cheque as his rostered flight times were unpredictable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The contract means salaries are pegged closer to productivity so those who fly more will take home more. “For the past six months, the fluctuation of my monthly income was between 30 and 50 per cent,” Wong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a result of the salary fluctuations, he had been unable to move out of his flat in Wan Chai, which he shares with a roommate for HK$15,000 a month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There&#39;s a lot of uncertainty in my monthly income. I barely have savings.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong equality watchdog warns Cathay staff may have breached discrimination law&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Yuen of Chinese University said the salary structure, which was based on actual flying hours, had introduced uncertainty to pilots, especially junior ones who still had ground duties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cathay may need to review the arrangement, which will affect the attractiveness of new hires,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Independent aviation analyst Brendan Sobie said the airline&#39;s recovery was delayed due to Hong Kong lifting travel restrictions much later, but with high demand for pilots globally, it needed to act swiftly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yusof of Endau Analytics said the airline&#39;s recovery was tied to the city&#39;s future as a thriving global hub. “Both share the same fate … Hong Kong needs to be in good health before Cathay can improve.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;*Names changed at interviewees request&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s Greater Bay Area to lead sustainable finance, meet capital demands of decarbonisation with green bonds, loans]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3221851/chinas-greater-bay-area-lead-sustainable-finance-meet-capital-demands-decarbonisation-green-bonds?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/25/cf0658fc-ed04-4d88-8072-aee82c042b5f_3324abc7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macau Greater Bay Area (GBA) is expected to continue its leading role in the country&#39;s decarbonisation and green-finance efforts by facilitating financing for sustainable development, experts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The GBA is leading the nation in green and sustainable finance, as its issuance of green, social, sustainability and sustainability-linked (GSSS) bonds almost doubled to 56.76 billion yuan (US$8 billion) year on year in the first quarter of this year, according to Kevin Yang, vice-president of the Hong Kong Green Finance Association, citing data from the HSBC GBA ESG Index.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong, Guangzhou and Shenzhen in particular are driving the trend, as green loans in Guangdong province and Shenzhen jumped 53 per cent and 44 per cent, respectively, year on year, in 2022, compared with 39 per cent nationwide, Yang said during the SmartHK Forum in Guangzhou on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong has always been an international financial centre,” said Kenneth Hui, executive director (external) of the Hong Kong Monetary Authority. “It can guide more international green funds to invest in the mainland&#39;s [green] projects, as in the next 20 to 30 years China needs to have much capital input to reach its decarbonisation goals.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The GBA can support the nation&#39;s overall sustainability goals by combining the strengths of Hong Kong as a financial centre and Shenzhen as a technology centre, Hui added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China needs around 100 trillion yuan to 200 trillion yuan of investment to fulfil its decarbonisation goal of peak carbon emissions by 2030 and carbon neutrality by 2060, according to data from institutions including the World Bank and HSBC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The national goals for decarbonisation and the increasing social responsibility awareness of the younger generations of high-net-worth individuals are catalysts for the demand for sustainable and green finance,” said Heidi Chui, partner of law firm Stevenson Wong &amp; Company, who has expertise in family offices and sustainable finance.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Banking sector needs more training for fintech, green finance: HKMA official&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Demand is rising for new sustainable finance products, driven in part by family offices – the corporations wealthy families set up to handle their investment and philanthropic pursuits – especially as the Covid-19 pandemic led people to pursue life beyond “wealth on paper”, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With a favourable business environment, the GBA will see continued momentum in leading China&#39;s sustainable development, she added, as market players have already proved, in earlier experiments, that participation in green initiatives can turn a profit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Greater Bay Area is Beijing&#39;s ambitious plan to create a massive, integrated economic and business hub that links Hong Kong, Macau and nine cities in the southern province of Guangdong by 2035.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How paper trails and audits are helping China battle greenwashing scourge&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The region is increasingly turning into a green finance hub in the world&#39;s second-largest economy, with green and sustainable bonds issued in Hong Kong jumping 40 per cent to US$80.5 billion in 2022 from 2021, or 35 per cent of the total in Asia according to Yang, who is also the executive director of CECEP Environmental Consulting Group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Greater Bay Area&#39;s green-finance infrastructure and the innovation of products and services are leading the country, with Hong Kong as the sustainable financial centre of the Asia-Pacific, Guangzhou as the green-finance reform and innovation pilot zone and leader of the South China carbon market, and Shenzhen as a leader in green-finance innovation,” Yang said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In reviewing power deals, Hong Kong can seize the chance to cut emissions, limit climate impact]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3221697/reviewing-power-deals-hong-kong-can-seize-chance-cut-emissions-limit-climate-impact?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/24/51092dbe-4fb0-4bfc-87a5-5f71fbd7b770_bc3b6b4c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The scheme of control agreements, signed between the government and the city&#39;s two power companies, have been instrumental in Hong Kong&#39;s efforts to stabilise energy prices and improve air quality.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To compare electricity price trends, London has experienced a staggering 103 per cent increase over the past two years, while Singapore has witnessed a 41 per cent rise. In contrast, Hong Kong has maintained relatively stable energy prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 1990s, the power sector has also made significant progress in improving air quality by reducing the emission of harmful pollutants by 92 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The recently released final instalment of the sixth assessment report by the United Nations&#39; Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change warned once again that rapid reductions in carbon emissions would be needed to avoid global temperature rises of more than 1.5 degrees Celsius. Exceeding this limit would have irreversible and lethal consequences for both humanity and nature.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The interim review of the scheme of control agreements this year presents an excellent opportunity for Hong Kong to take drastic action to reduce emissions. With electricity generation being the primary source of greenhouse gas emissions in Hong Kong, accounting for 66 per cent of total emissions, regulating this through the agreements is crucial.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agreements can be further enhanced to achieve the deep carbon reductions required to maintain the 1.5 degree C limit. There are several key steps Hong Kong can take to further accelerate its carbon emissions reduction and transition towards a sustainable future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, it is imperative to set a detailed sectorial carbon emissions pathway from now to 2050. As the Hong Kong government has committed to carbon neutrality by that date and aims to halve carbon emissions by 2035, the agreements should reflect this crucial commitment in their primary text.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Collaborating with the power sector and setting five-yearly carbon emissions targets can provide a clear road map to near-term carbon reduction. Such a pathway also provides clarity and certainty for businesses and investors, which is essential for effective decision-making and long-term planning in their decarbonisation action.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Energy Foundation China, the Greater Bay Area has high energy demand and is still in the process of building up its capacity of low-carbon resources. In fact, an additional 10GW of coal-fired facilities are expected to be constructed in the region by 2025 to meet increased power demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Therefore, directly introducing clean electricity from the Greater Bay Area grid into Hong Kong may not be a responsible approach for the city due to the insufficient surplus of renewable energy available for export from the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong officials should work towards achieving a coal-free Greater Bay Area by developing a collaboration framework with the other cities, including clear negotiation timelines and incentives for power companies to invest in zero-carbon solutions within the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moreover, transparent and accessible data is essential for establishing a foundation for green finance capacity-building and facilitating energy-efficiency improvements for homeowners. However, the current energy end-use data in Hong Kong is outdated by two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This data, along with the average and standard deviation of the residential and commercial sectors, must be made publicly available to enable informed decision-making on energy policy and efficiency measures. A public consultation should be launched to gather input on the data structure and ensure it meets the needs of various stakeholders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finally, transforming the grid infrastructure is crucial to promoting the development of electric vehicle fast-charging. As EVs become increasingly prevalent, a well-developed charging infrastructure is necessary. Hong Kong currently has limited availability of fast-charging stations above 100kW, impeding the widespread adoption of EVs. The scheme of control agreements can play a vital role in encouraging the development of fast-charging infrastructure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Exceeding the 1.5 degree limit would be akin to willingly stepping off a cliff, with irreversible consequences for humanity and nature. However, by opting for rapid, sustained and deep reductions in carbon emissions, we can mitigate projected losses and damage, while also enjoying various associated benefits such as improved air quality and better health.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong must make the right choices and steer clear of the edge of that cliff by incorporating these key measures into the review of the scheme of control agreements. We must act quickly to limit the impacts of the climate crisis, for now and for the future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Women finalists of Hong Kong’s bun-scrambling race revel in competition’s return as part of Cheung Chau festival]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3221805/women-finalists-hong-kongs-bun-scrambling-race-revel-competitions-return-part-cheung-chau-festival?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/25/68a0cc86-14db-450a-ade2-ae40e04ed393_66e6edcc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The women competing in this year&#39;s bun-scrambling race on Hong Kong&#39;s Cheung Chau have voiced their excitement about the event&#39;s comeback, along with the rest of the annual festival, after a lengthy hiatus because of the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nine men and three women make up the 12 finalists in the competition, which is set to take place at midnight between Friday and Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It has been three years since the last bun-scrambling race – it feels both unfamiliar and familiar,” said Janet Kung Tsz-shan, 2019 women&#39;s champion, who was speaking to the Post at a practice run.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kung, 29, who is a local ice climbing athlete and a registered nurse, made it into this year&#39;s final by scaling to the top of a tower in 49.66 seconds – a personal record – at a qualifier race on April 30, making her the top female performer that day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Five-time “Bun Queen” Angel Wong Ka-yan said she was “very excited” to return to the event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong qualified for the finals in second place with a time of one minute and 0.88 seconds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I feel confident about winning every year I get to take part,” she told the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Builder vows to keep making bamboo bun towers for future Cheung Chau festivals&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“But most importantly, it makes me happiest to know my friends and family have always been there to support me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both women agreed, however, that the media attention and public nature of the race added to their stress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The competition is a very hectic environment because there is a lot of noise and a lot of bright spotlights aimed at you,” Wong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You are very aware that everything you&#39;re doing is being broadcast live across television screens, and there is a media scrum afterwards. It&#39;s a lot.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Not all bun and games: behind Hong Kong&#39;s Cheung Chau Bun Festival&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Kung said: “There is a lot going through your mind as you&#39;re standing at the bottom and listening to them countdown to midnight. Even when I am just practising, my heart begins to race as I recall the first time I experienced looking up at that tower.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The athlete said she had been spending much of the past year training to overcome her nerves by taking part in international ice climbing and athletic competitions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong, meanwhile, retired as a professional climbing athlete in 2021 and subsequently opened a rock climbing gym in Kwai Chung.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have been training hard at our gym and trying to make up for the physical fitness I lost during the pandemic,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong, Kung and first-time finalist Chau Yuen-sin will be the only women competing in the race.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nine men will also tackle the tower, including familiar faces such as Jason Kwok Ka-ming, Kidman Yip Kin-man, Chung Yuk-chuen and Wong Chi-kit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 200 people sign up annually for the first round of qualifiers, which was held on April 16 this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The finalists then went on to better 85 others in another qualifying round.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Bun-believable: Hong Kong festival&#39;s bamboo towers to be two-thirds shorter&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Participants on Friday will scale the steel tower to snatch plastic buns – each of which carries a score according to their placement – in an attempt to win the different titles that are up for grabs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The champions from the men&#39;s and women&#39;s categories, along with the second and third places, are determined through overall points, while the winner of the “Full Pockets of Lucky Buns” prize is awarded to the competitor who bags the most number of individual buns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A “King of Kings” or “Queen of Queens” title, launched in 2016, is also given to champions who have won three times.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A team relay competition, with five athletes per group, was held on May 14.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most stories about the origin of the annual celebration, also known as the Cheung Chau Da Jiu Festival, say that the island was devastated by a plague in the 18th or 19th century and villagers carried out rituals such as offering buns to deities to end the outbreak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bun-scrambling race is one of the highlights of the annual event.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The competition will not be affected by an earlier announcement that the festival&#39;s decorative bun towers will be reduced in size from 45 feet (13.7 metres) to just about 15 feet because of labour shortages at the contractor that usually builds the structures.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Gabby Petito case: Brian Laundrie’s mum said in letter she’d help ‘dispose of a body’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3221870/gabby-petito-case-brian-laundries-mum-said-letter-shed-help-dispose-body?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 07:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/26/6f814b62-d8c4-4afe-87b4-14e518df5b74_d2662416.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A copy of the letter Brian Laundrie&#39;s mother allegedly instructed him to “burn after reading” has been given to the parents of his late fiancée, Gabby Petito, whom the FBI says Laundrie admitted to killing before his own death in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Florida judge ruled the undated letter written by Roberta Laundrie can be included as evidence in the Petitos&#39; civil lawsuit against the Laundries and their lawyer, according to local news station WFLA, which obtained a copy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nothing can make me stop loving you, nothing will or could ever divide us no matter what we do, or where we go or what we say – we will always love each other,” the letter reportedly reads.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you&#39;re in jail, I will bake a cake with a file in it. If you need to dispose of a body, I will show up with a shovel and garbage bags.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The letter was reportedly inside an envelope with “burn after reading” written on it. The Laundries&#39; lawyer claims the FBI already had the letter when authorities discovered Laundrie&#39;s remains in a Florida park in October 2021. The Petitos&#39; lawyer contends the letter was found with his body.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Petito, who was from Long Island, disappeared during a 2021 cross-country road trip with Laundrie, who returned to Florida alone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She died of homicide by manual strangulation, according to a coroner, while Laundrie died of a self-inflicted gunshot wound.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities say they recovered a notebook in which Laundrie allegedly confessed to killing Petito, whose body was found in September 2021 in a Wyoming national park.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why Gabby Petito case generated frenzy of attention on social media&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Roberta Laundrie claimed in March the letter was not related to Petito&#39;s death but rather an attempt to repair a strained relationship with her son. She claimed “burn after reading” referenced a book she and Brian read during his childhood.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There were some other phrases that I used in the letter, which are not found in the books I shared with Brian as a child,” Roberta Laundrie said at the time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“However, these phrases are common enough in our circle of friends and family, to describe who you could turn to in the most troubling times of your life.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, she reiterated the claim she wrote the letter before Petito and Laundrie&#39;s road trip.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China aviation: is Shenzhen stealing Hong Kong’s thunder as a go-to economic and travel hub?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3221841/china-aviation-shenzhen-stealing-hong-kongs-thunder-go-economic-and-travel-hub?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 06:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/25/b151416b-39ee-4c38-b952-18aca05712b6_943738db.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Shenzhen&#39;s aviation status appears to be taking off, and its international airport&#39;s rising appeal could eventually challenge neighbouring Hong Kong&#39;s dominance in the Asia-Pacific region by diverting some passenger traffic from the global travel hub.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While analysts say more efforts are needed to achieve such a lofty goal that would carry with it considerable economic advantages, Shenzhen Bao&#39;an International Airport turned heads this month by being named the world&#39;s most beautiful airport, by the World Air Stewardess Association.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The group still found Hong Kong to be the “best airport” overall, but the results came just a couple of months after another poll by air transport research firm Skytrax showed how far Shenzhen has come in a short time, and how rapidly the tech hub is gaining prominence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Findings from the survey by the UK-based consultancy, released in March, showed that air travellers around the world thought more highly of Bao&#39;an International Airport – placing it 31st on the World&#39;s Top-100 Airports list for 2023, compared with 57th in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong placed two spots lower, at 33rd – a sharp fall from 20th a year prior.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As Macau bets on change, what role will Hengqin play in the Greater Bay Area?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Home to the tech giants such as Huawei Technologies and new-energy automaker BYD, Shenzhen has been consolidating its footing as a go-to economic hub in the Greater Bay Area. And this has been in no small part because of the city&#39;s growing momentum in both shipping and civil aviation – two sectors in which Hong Kong has long held a regional advantage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Human traffic is often considered an important indicator of economic activities, as more people bring in more capital and technology while boosting local consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the recent May Day holiday week, in which many people travelled between Hong Kong and mainland cities, Bao&#39;an airport saw its daily passenger volume reach 182,500, according to the Transport Bureau of Shenzhen Municipality. That was compared with an average daily flow of 127,200 during the first three months of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And from January to April, Shenzhen had mainland China&#39;s second-busiest airport in terms of passenger traffic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among people living in Hong Kong who choose to fly out of Shenzhen to destinations across the mainland, travel times, costs and convenience are commonly cited – factors that could divert the flow of passengers and subsequently trigger a shift in economic considerations across the Greater Bay Area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a frequent visitor to Hong Kong, 24-year-old Li Feihu said she increasingly flies out of Shenzhen instead of Hong Kong when heading back to her hometown in Anhui province, roughly 1,000km (620 miles) away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instead of making the long journey to Hong Kong airport and going through more complex security checks, Li prefers travelling 50 minutes by train to Bao&#39;an.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s faster, and the flights are more frequent,” she said. “The process of flying back to the mainland is more complicated in Hong Kong, and there are not as many flight options as in Shenzhen.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Flights to domestic cities are also cheaper from Shenzhen than from Hong Kong, making Bao&#39;an more appealing to budget travellers in China&#39;s post-Covid reopening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for international travel, Hong Kong flights are still more affordable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To enhance its competitiveness among global airports, Shenzhen airport must expand its international flights while also facing challenges from [the provincial capital of] Guangzhou in the domestic flight market,” said Peng Peng, executive chairman of the Guangdong Society of Reform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brian Wong, founding editor of the Oxford Political Review in Hong Kong, noted that “Shenzhen caters to a more mainland-oriented demographic that benefits from its exceptional connectivity throughout the entire country, especially the Greater Bay Area”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong, on the other hand, remains an excellent gateway and entry point for folks travelling to and from China and the rest of the world,” Wong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Price hike warning as China&#39;s May Day holiday travel bookings surge&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Huan Cheng, a 24-year-old mainlander who has lived in Hong Kong for five years, said he has had more choices for mainland flights from Bao&#39;an airport since the border reopened between Hong Kong and Shenzhen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But when it comes to overseas flights, I would choose Hong Kong airport without hesitation,” Huan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shenzhen airport has gradually resumed nine international flights to London, Paris and Manila, and has increased the flight volume of 16 routes including Dubai, Seoul, Singapore and Bangkok.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China transported 2.24 million passengers on international flights in the first quarter of this year, or about 12.4 per cent of what it saw during the same period in 2019, according to the Civil Aviation Administration of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, this remains less than what Hong Kong&#39;s airport sees in a single month, with 3.1 million passengers in April, according to Hong Kong&#39;s Civil Aviation Department.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As China flights surpass pre-pandemic levels, tourists bode well for economy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The Shenzhen airport has a comprehensive domestic flight network.但香港仍然是亚太地区的货物处理和转运枢纽，因为它在国际航班网络方面具有竞争优势。 In terms of IT, safety and traffic control, Hong Kong is relatively strong,” said Ambrose Linn, a former member of the Hong Kong Logistics Development Council.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bao&#39;an airport also boasts continued improvements in terms of its services and business environment. On Wednesday, a joint venture was announced with the state-owned Shenzhen Duty Free Group to jointly operate duty-free shops in its terminals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Beijing continues to pin high hopes on the Greater Bay Area – comprising Hong Kong, Macau and nine mainland cities, including Guangzhou and Shenzhen – becoming a world-class economic and innovation centre, comparable to the bay areas of San Francisco and Greater Tokyo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, the Greater Bay Area&#39;s economy totalled 13 trillion yuan (US$1.94 trillion), of which Shenzhen accounted for nearly a quarter and Hong Kong nearly 19 per cent, according to the Hong Kong Trade Development Council.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Kandy Wong&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[At Apec, US Trade Representative Katherine Tai urges ‘worker-centric’ approach to trade policy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3221869/apec-us-trade-representative-katherine-tai-urges-worker-centric-approach-trade-policy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 06:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/26/0ea83fcf-8c67-4920-a27f-0890d9adb379_59832480.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;United States Trade Representative Katherine Tai declared on Thursday that the US under President Joe Biden has been “writing a new story” on trade after focusing for too long on “aggressive liberalisation”, calling for a “worker-centric” approach to trade negotiations and policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In her opening remarks at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (Apec) trade ministers&#39; meeting in Detroit, Michigan, Tai noted that trade officials from the 21 member economies were gathering at a time of “shared uncertainty and challenges in the global economy, including fragile supply chains, growing inequality and a worsening climate crisis”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These challenges were exacerbated through the pandemic, and increasing geopolitical tensions that we see today,” added Tai, who will be meeting Chinese Commerce Minister Wang Wentao on the sidelines of the two-day dialogue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang and his American counterpart, Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo, were scheduled to hold a dinner meeting on Thursday in Washington, according to reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former US president Donald Trump amplified complaints that China was stealing American manufacturing jobs and dumping its cheap products in the US. In 2018, the year after he took office, he imposed additional 25 per cent tariffs on Chinese imports worth US$300 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden, who became president in 2021, has largely stuck to the Trump&#39;s tariff policy while also imposing strict export controls in core technologies such as semiconductors and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The confirmation of meetings between top China and US trade officials came days after Beijing banned semiconductors from US-owned Micron in key infrastructure projects, an apparent retaliation. The US Commerce Department reacted saying the move “was not based in facts”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to reports, the Micron ban and recent raids on due diligence companies that help American firms invest in China will be high on Raimondo&#39;s agenda for discussion.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US trade officials cite China&#39;s &#39;economic coercion&#39; ahead of Apec&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing has also expressed its displeasure over Washington&#39;s moves toward a new trade pact with Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese embassy said last week that the meetings with Tai and Raimondo would provide an opportunity to “engage in dialogue through bilateral, regional and multilateral channels to address their respective concerns in the economic and trade areas”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At an event on Thursday in Detroit, Tai discussed US trade policy with two union leaders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Frederick Redmond, secretary-treasurer of the American Federation of Labour and Congress of Industrial Organization, which represents more than 12 million workers, told Tai that despite all Apec members being party to an international declaration on fundamental rights, “we can see we continue to see forced labour in our supply chains”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington and others have accused Beijing of forcing ethnic Uygurs, a Muslim minority, into factory and farm jobs against their will, citing eyewitness accounts, satellite imagery and reports by human rights groups. Beijing denies any wrongdoing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Redmond later said Tai would “let China know that if they&#39;re going to do business in the US, they have to follow the standards created by the United States&#39; workers and the US trade department”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The president of the United Auto Workers union, Shawn Fain, called for “reciprocity” in agreements with China to tackle trade “imbalance”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You can send something to China and it costs 10 times what it costs here. But then they ship stuff to America, and they flood our market with products, and we don&#39;t do the same thing,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trade frictions compounded by a fierce battle for supremacy in global influence and cutting-edge technology have plunged US-China relations to their lowest point in more than 50 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But both sides have recently signalled an interest in easing tensions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing moves to limit collateral damage from Micron sales ban&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On Monday, Wang met representatives of American firms in Shanghai, including Johnson &amp; Johnson, 3M, Dow, Merck and Honeywell, according to the Ministry of Commerce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China will continue to welcome US-funded enterprises to develop in China and achieve win-win results,” he told them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After US Secretary of State Antony Blinken cancelled a trip to Beijing in February after a Chinese spy balloon was shot down after crossing the continental US, a top State Department aide said Blinken hoped to visit “in the near future”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week, Biden predicted a “thaw” in ties, and described the balloon incident as “silly”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, reports suggest that Beijing has yet to answer Washington&#39;s request for a meeting between US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin and Chinese counterpart Li Shangfu at the Shangri-La Dialogue next week in Singapore.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 06:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>