<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[France riots: how teen Nahel’s killing is focusing anger on police tactics]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226056/france-riots-how-teen-nahels-killing-focusing-anger-police-tactics?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 13:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_analysis/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/6321446a-6db8-4f53-bdd4-e98c520bc894_93096a9a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;本周巴黎郊外一名 17 岁青少年被警察枪杀的事件已经确定法国郊区发生了大范围的骚乱，抗议者焚烧汽车、垃圾和建筑物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这起杀戮事件还引发了人们的疑问：法国自 2005 年遭受数周城市骚乱以来是否未能继续前进。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;这名名叫纳赫尔（Nahel）的青少年被枪击事件被录像记录下来，震惊了全国。它激起了警察和贫困社区年轻人之间长期存在的紧张关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它还促使人们呼吁彻底改革警察使用武器的条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;13据警方称，去年有人因在交通堵塞期间不遵守命令而在警察枪击事件中丧生。今年，包括纳赫尔（Nahel）在内的三人在类似情况下死亡，纳赫尔在接到命令时没有停下来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更普遍的是，因拒绝遵守命令而被警察杀害的人数为在增加。据警方统计，2021 年有四人在这种情况下被杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;抗议活动愈演愈烈，杀害法国青少年的警察向家人表示歉意&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在接下来的几个小时内纳赫尔去世后，法国下议院议长雅埃尔·布劳恩-皮维 (Yael Braun-Pivet) 表示，她准备重新评估一项管理警察使用枪支的法律的执行情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法律于 2017 年通过法国发生一系列极端主义袭击事件后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后，当司机不遵守命令且可能危及生命时，执法人员可以向车辆开枪&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就纳赫尔的案件而言，在初步调查得出“不符合合法使用武器的条件”后，开枪致死的警官将因故意杀人罪受到调查”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在法律出台之前，警察必须证明自卫才能证明使用枪支的合理性。自该法案生效以来，他们被授权向“其乘员可能在飞行中对其生命或人身安全或他人实施攻击”的车辆开火。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内部安全代码然而，规定只有在“绝对必要且严格相称的情况下”才允许使用武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员 Sebastian Roché、Paul le Derff 和 Simon Varaine 进行了一项统计分析将死亡人数的增加与法律联系起来，称邻国并没有出现类似的枪击死亡人数增加的情况。他们还质疑警察缺乏适当的培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2017 年法律的这一变化与警察致命枪击事件的增加之间存在非常明显的相关性，”罗奇告诉 Le Nouvel Obs 媒体。 “平均而言，枪击事件增加了 25%，致命枪击事件增加了五倍。自2017年以来，警察的做法发生了明显的转变，警察枪击事件有所增加。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了致命枪击事件外，法国警察的暴力策略也经常受到批评。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;联合国成员国谴责法国种族主义和警察暴力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 2018 年开始的黄背心抗议活动中，一位欧洲高级官员批评法国当局对反政府抗议活动的处理方式，这些抗议活动震动了该国几个月来，敦促他们“更加尊重人权”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国警方还因其对在法兰西体育场举行的 2022 年欧洲冠军联赛决赛的处理而受到严厉批评。圣但尼郊区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比赛前几个小时，警方对在拥挤、缓慢移动的队伍中被困的球迷使用了催泪瓦斯，比赛最终推迟了约 40 分钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，在反对提高退休年龄的示威浪潮中，法国警方因对抗议者过于严厉的说法而受到打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际特赦组织、国际人权联合会和欧洲委员会 –欧洲大陆主要人权机构 - 等组织都指出法国警察过度使用武力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳赫尔死后开始的法国郊区骚乱并非史无前例。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;炊具在法国反马克龙抗议活动中被禁止，招致嘲笑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;早在 2005 年，17 岁的齐德·本纳 (Zyed Benna) 和 15 岁的布纳·特拉奥雷 (Bouna Traore) 在巴黎郊区的一个变电站躲避警察后触电身亡。克利希苏布瓦在法国各地引发了三周的骚乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国范围内的骚乱在拥有大量少数民族人口的陷入困境的社区的住房项目中肆虐。尽管这些问题源于青少年的死亡，但更深层次的歧视、失业和与法国社会的疏离感等问题加剧了这些问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近二十年后，这些问题和不公正感仍然根深蒂固。在法国社会。不过，对骚乱的反应可能会有所不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2005 年没有视频，骚乱也没有这次蔓延得那么快。社交媒体也放大了最新的杀戮事件。但是，尽管 2005 年法国政府根据紧急状态法采取了残酷的应对措施，加剧了人们的愤怒，但法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙一直小心翼翼地不与任何人对抗，以避免暴力爆发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;马克龙的第一反应是说纳赫尔的死“不可原谅”。这段视频让他和他的部长们无法辩称枪击事件是正当的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，在骚乱的前两个晚上，警察在使用武力方面表现出了克制。此外，司法决定对主要嫌疑人提出故意杀人的初步指控，并继续拘留他，这可能有助于缓解紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被拘留警官的律师在法国电视频道 BFMTV 上发表讲话，该官员表示抱歉并“感到震惊”。律师洛朗-弗兰克·利纳德 (Laurent-Franck Lienard) 告诉新闻媒体，这名警官当时做了他认为必要的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他早上起床不会去杀人，”利纳德谈到这名警官时说道，其姓名尚未公布。 “他真的不想杀人。但现在他必须为自己辩护，因为他是被拘留并睡在监狱里的人。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Canada’s Alberta province calls off partnership with Chinese private equity fund that sought to invest US$10 billion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3226055/canadas-alberta-province-calls-partnership-chinese-private-equity-fund-sought-invest-us10-billion?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 13:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/6706cd62-549f-46c7-8260-2cec0e566d2e_2154f523.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;艾伯塔省政府终止了与一家中国私募股权基金的合作关系，目标金额为 10 美元投资自然资源行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拿大阿尔伯塔省的非营利组织阿尔伯塔工业中心和香港私募股权公司Can-China Global Resource Fund ( CCGRF）于 2016 年宣布建立合作伙伴关系，以鼓励整个北美地区的投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种合作关系已不复存在，”该非营利组织的传播总监卡莉·康威 (Karlee Conway) 在给路透社的电子邮件回复中表示。该发言人没有回答有关合作关系为何以及何时被取消的询问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该基金的主要投资者是中国进出口银行、总部位于温哥华的矿业公司 Hunter Dickinson 和瑞士大宗商品交易商摩科瑞 (Mercuria)。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此前未报道的事态发展正值近年来中国和加拿大之间的紧张局势升级之际，尽管路透社采访的消息人士无法证实该基金的解散是否是其直接结果。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;负责管理投资的香港 MEC Advisory、CCGRF、摩科瑞、Hunter Dickinson 和进出口银行均未回复路透的电子邮件置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我无法确认这是多伦多大学政治学教授 Lynette Ong 表示：“这与双边关系直接相关，但这确实可能是两国之间紧张局势加剧的结果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，各省政府可能会觉得被迫遵守渥太华的官方立场，或者不要过多偏离公众舆论，因为这可能会带来风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该基金唯一已知的投资是以 7.22 亿加元（5.454 亿美元）收购CQ Energy 成立于 2017 年，总部位于卡尔加里，是一家私营天然气生产服务公司。这项投资的状况尚不清楚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自加拿大于 2018 年应美国要求逮捕华为技术有限公司首席财务官孟晚舟后，北京与渥太华之间的外交关系开始恶化。孟晚舟被捕后，中国拘留了两名加拿大公民，指控他们从事间谍活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管三人均于 2021 年获释，但中加关系尚未恢复正常。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;石油富裕的阿尔伯塔省2020年向中国出口了价值45亿加元的商品，使其成为加拿大第二大出口市场。 2014年油价暴跌之前，一些中国大型国有石油公司已向阿尔伯塔省扩张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位了解该基金的人士告诉路透社，100亿美元的目标是出于营销目的，也是该基金第一阶段的目标。投资不超过10亿美元。一位人士补充说，进出口银行“在遭受重大损失后”开始研究该基金的结构，并从北京派出一名代表来撤资某些项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CCGRF 成立于 2013 年，是该基金的一部分。加拿大和中国政府之间进行双边讨论，以鼓励公共和私人资本投资加拿大的自然资源行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自孟晚舟被捕以来，两国之间的裂痕不断扩大。去年，加拿大迫使三名中国国家投资者出售加拿大关键矿业公司的股份，试图摆脱在关键矿业领域对中国的依赖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月，加拿大冻结了与中国的关系- 领导的亚洲基础设施投资银行对该机构受中国共产党控制的指控展开调查。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong out of ‘political quagmire’ and should not go down wrong path again, Beijing’s top man in city says in lead-up to July 1 celebrations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3226057/hong-kong-out-political-quagmire-and-should-not-go-down-wrong-path-again-beijings-top-man-city-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 13:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/059d2bec-8db1-42cb-ae48-c348983d6a08_591311ac.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港已逐渐“走出政治泥潭”，不应再陷进去北京最高领导人在呼吁金融中心在地缘政治紧张局势中抓住机遇时表示，方向再次错误。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中央政府联络办公室主任郑彦雄周五也对回归表示欢迎7月1日香港回归中国系列庆祝活动启动“可爱香港”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去一年，国家主权、安全、发展利益都得到了有效的保障。香港已逐渐走出政治漩涡的泥潭。我们过去看到的熟悉而可爱的香港又回来了。”他对观众说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须清醒地认识到，香港不能再走错方向、制造混乱。它不能被他人利用或欺骗。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京于 2020 年对香港实施国家安全法，作为对一年前长达数月的反政府抗议活动的回应，这场抗议活动改写了香港的政治版图。周五，这部全面的法律迎来了三周年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑还赞扬行政长官李家超领导的“务实、勤奋”的政府所取得的成就，称地缘政治变化以及“全球经济”科技和工业革命”，为香港“再次崛起”提供了巨大机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北京高级官员敦促香港抓住“超级联系人”角色&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“香港必须顺势而为，敢于竞争，参与世界利益格局重构，主动融入国家发展，绽放中国式现代化光芒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有“保持国际化优势”和践行“一个国家、两种制度”，才能走得更远&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北京新任驻港高官宣扬香港的特殊作用&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在同一活动中，李说，香港因为有国安法和“爱国者治港”原则的“保护”而变得更具吸引力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港是我们共同的家园，每个人都是香港的一员。”李说，过去一年在他的领导下，“国家安全一直是优先考虑的事情”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他告诉观众中的建制派人士要“团结社会力量”，为国家高质量发展做出贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去的 7 月 1 日是主权移交周年纪念日，每年一度的大规模民主游行是由现已解散的民间人权阵线举办的，直到新冠疫情爆发之前， 2020年发生了19大流行病。同年国安法生效后，抗议活动也变得罕见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的周年纪念活动将由政府和亲北京团体组织的庆祝活动进行，其中包括许多庆祝活动。由中国人民政治协商会议代表谭锦球领导的香港庆典协会协调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;展示中国大陆三个省份陕西、山东和辽宁的文化展览将于周五至 7 月 2 日在铜锣湾维多利亚公园举行，亲民主团体过去常常在那里组织 7 月 1 日的集会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与展览一起举办的还有香港邻近内地城市和香港企业的技术成就博览会。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为期两个月的购物节会提振香港零售、餐饮业吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;同时，26艘悬挂国旗和城市旗帜的渔船将起航作为周六庆祝活动的一部分，李先生在维多利亚港举行了庆祝活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早些时候，李已经宣布了全市庆祝活动以纪念周年，包括免费乘车和进入博物馆以及购物折扣。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong catering sector banking on 2-month shopping festival to bring 20 per cent business surge as part of July 1 celebrations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3226046/hong-kong-catering-sector-banking-2-month-shopping-festival-bring-20-cent-business-surge-part-july-1?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 12:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/862999e6-5c22-4d7e-aca4-8f66597f824e_c38ee576.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港餐饮业指望为期两个月的购物节带来20该活动是 7 月 1 日纪念香港回归中国 26 周年庆祝活动的一部分，业务量激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，约 1,500 家餐厅将对部分菜单项目进行降价，其中一些餐厅餐馆享受 29% 的折扣——意思是“支付 71% 的价格”——在“7 月 1 日”这一天发挥作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宣布了促销活动，包括免费乘车和博物馆参观本月早些时候，该市领导人提出了这一要求。消息人士称，此举将为复苏的经济提供动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但香港餐饮服务管理协会主席梁振华周五表示，该行业很难提供折扣接近30％，因为单个订单的利润只能是5％至8％。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些餐馆不介意没有利润，因为他们希望居民吃得开心。”他告诉电台节目强调商户提供折扣纯属自愿。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港零售商推出1.5亿港元折扣，优惠让人微笑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他说餐饮销售该行业仅达到了大流行前水平的 80% 或 90%，人们希望最新的促销活动和 7 月 16 日的第二期消费券可以使陷入困境的行业提振高达 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“晚上 8.30 点之后，顾客很少，因为他们的生活方式在大流行后发生了变化……居民比以前睡得更早了。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung 补充说，另一个挑战是工资上涨 15% 至 20%疫情发生后，由于招聘困难，将其归因于移民潮，导致数十万居民离开城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港粉丝在几分钟内抢购了 14,000 张 Harbour Chill Carnival 的免费门票&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;香港零售管理协会主席谢邱安仪在同一电台节目中表示，她希望周六开幕的“欢乐香港购物节”将在第二阶段展开消费券计划将提振疲软的零售市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢表示，尽管游客数量有所回升，但与疫情前水平相比，游客的购买力下降了近20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;她指出，该行业也受到当地支出减少的打击。 “边境重新开放后，更多香港居民开始出行。与以前香港人留在城市消费相比，现在本地消费市场相当疲软。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;快乐鸭香港准备6月10日橡皮鸭进港&lt;/ h3>;&lt;p>;超过150个品牌和6000家零售店将参加购物节，免费赠送咖啡和奖品，还有超市一分钟疯狂购物的机会。这些促销活动是零售业为期两个月的活动的一部分，零售业将提供价值 1.5 亿港元的折扣、奖金和其他好礼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该节日将于 8 月 31 日结束，促销活动将分为四个类别，每个类别跨越两周。它们是：百货商店和家居用品；超市、便利店和餐馆；电子产品和珠宝；以及化妆品、保健食品和时装。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China pumps out half of world’s energy storage research as US share declines]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3226010/china-pumps-out-half-worlds-energy-storage-research-us-share-declines?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 12:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/5b683bf9-9e8b-4d17-ba2a-dc8579289a6d_dcac37d2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国去年发表的储能技术研究论文占全球的50%根据来自中国多所大学和研究所的研究团队的报告，今年的论文数量比 2021 年增长了 5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，美国科学家的贡献占论文数量的 10.5%研究人员在《储能科学与技术》杂志上发表的一篇论文中表示，到 2022 年，这一主题的数字将比上一年下降 2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国已成为“最活跃的国家”报告称，在储能领域的基础研究、技术研究、集成和应用三个方面均处于世界领先水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员以“储能”为关键词搜索了Web of Science索引该研究概述了中国在该领域的研究进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在可再生能源装机方面已经处于世界领先地位，在储能方面也处于领先地位，最终容量达到 59.8 吉瓦据中国储能联盟称，到2022年，中国的大部分电力来自煤炭，储能是该国实现净零目标的关键。但缺乏大规模增加容量的方法正在阻碍现有可再生能源项目的总发电潜力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;到2025年，中国新增储能容量将超过50GW&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;例如，太阳能根据国家能源局的数据，截至 2023 年第一季度，能源占中国发电装机容量的 16.6%，但仅向电网输送可用电力的 2.73%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国仍然依靠抽水蓄能发电，并在继续建设基于该技术的设施方面处于世界领先地位。报告称，到2022年，新增蓄电容量中占比最高的是水电。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然中国拥有世界上最大的抽水蓄能容量，但其主要研究重点是其他方法，例如各种基于电池的工具以及热能和飞轮技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据去年的报告，2021 年发布的大多数研究论文都集中在抽水蓄能的替代方案上，这种情况在 2022 年仍在继续.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国在储能方面继续名列前茅，并于 2020 年启动了一项举措，以维持其全球地位。储能大挑战的目标是到 2030 年美国所有存储技术都在国内生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国比美国更容易获得材料和生产资料，但仍在努力解决研究人员发现，如果要满足现有可再生能源设施的存储需求及其能源输出，则需要解决可扩展性问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管目前的能源输出量有限，但中国仍在继续开发新的可再生能源设施据国家能源局称，太阳能和风能项目尚未得到充分利用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，报告中强调的与储能相关的研究的增加和专利的增加表明科学界正在优先创新，帮助中国扩大大规模产能。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么安全、可持续的储能是中国实现气候目标的关键&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;报告称，百兆瓦项目正在成为常态报告称，中国科学院正在研究 300MW 压缩空气存储系统，这是 2022 年众多创新进展之一。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员表示，中国在已发表研究、专利申请和储能容量安装方面将继续在全球排名中占据主导地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;明年仍将是发展的重要一年他们表示，中国的储能技术和该领域的技术预计在未来五到十年内将成为世界最好的。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Koran burning in Sweden angers Muslim world. The man who did it plans to do it again]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226031/koran-burning-sweden-angers-muslim-world-man-who-did-it-plans-do-it-again?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/c431d133-c093-4b56-bb2a-1a648f6b4817_5a2e6e59.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;几个穆斯林占多数的国家谴责斯德哥尔摩一座清真寺外焚烧《古兰经》的行为，严厉谴责瑞典外交官，称该行为煽动仇恨，不应算作言论自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抗议活动发生在一名居住在瑞典的伊拉克公民萨尔万·莫米卡(Salwan Momika)，37岁，践踏伊斯兰圣书并踩踏了几页之后周三，穆斯林宰牲节假期的第一天，在瑞典首都最大的清真寺前下车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“10天内，我将在伊拉克驻瑞典大使馆前焚烧伊拉克国旗和《古兰经》。斯德哥尔摩，”莫米卡周四晚告诉瑞典一家报纸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瑞典警方根据言论自由保护向他发放了许可证，但当局后来表示，他们已就针对种族或种族的“煽动”展开调查。瑞典总理乌尔夫·克里斯特森 (Ulf Kristersson) 称焚烧行为“合法但不适当”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一事件可能会给瑞典的北约成员资格申请带来严重问题，因为他们提交了超过一年前，部分原因是过去发生过类似事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚穆斯林走上街头抗议瑞典焚烧古兰经&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;伊斯兰教发源地沙特阿拉伯强烈表示谴责焚烧《古兰经》的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些可恨且屡屡发生的行为，无论有什么理由都不能被接受。他们明确煽动仇恨、排斥和种族主义，”君主国外交部在周四的一份声明中补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊朗召见瑞典临时代办表达愤慨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;焚烧外交部补充说，对伊斯兰教圣书的侮辱尤其令人反感，因为它是在朝觐期间发生的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“穆斯林世界明确谴责对神圣经文和古兰经的侮辱，”伊斯兰共和国外交部长侯赛因Amirabdollahian 发推文。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“瑞典以任何理由允许对《古兰经》的亵渎和侮辱是不可接受的，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“滥用民主和自由进行此类行为只会煽动恐怖主义和极端主义。西方只会烧伤自己的手指。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黎巴嫩亲伊朗真主党运动在一份声明中呼吁伊斯兰政府采取一切措施，促使其他国家“防止这些愚蠢行为在其领土上重演”停止传播仇恨和仇恨文化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;区域组织阿拉伯联盟表示，其主席艾哈迈德·阿布·盖特强烈谴责瑞典当局允许这一行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃及称焚烧《古兰经》是“挑衅世界各地穆斯林感情的可耻行为”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;瑞典将最近的骚乱与针对警察的犯罪团伙联系起来&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在伊拉克，抗议者聚集在瑞典大使馆外据伊拉克官方通讯社 INA 报道，周四在巴格达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该通讯社补充说，在集会上，一些抗议者举起了穆斯林圣书以示崇敬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据说有影响力的什叶派穆斯林神职人员穆克塔达·萨德尔呼吁举行抗议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地媒体报道称，示威者要求驱逐瑞典大使。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊拉克独立网站 Alsumaria News报道称，抗议者短暂袭击了大使馆，然后撤退。据说他们已成功冲破大门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瑞典外交部表示，大使馆工作人员报告说他们很安全。声明称，该部一直与他们保持联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约旦外交部表示，已召见瑞典驻安曼大使，抗议“瑞典政府允许极端分子”焚烧《古兰经》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;外交部谴责这是一种“种族主义和仇恨”行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样，阿拉伯联合酋长国表示已召见瑞典驻这个海湾国家大使并向她递交了抗议信。 ”尽管瑞典长期以来保持中立，但乌克兰的主权仍然受到穆斯林国家土耳其和匈牙利的阻碍。新成员必须得到所有现有北约成员国的一致批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管安卡拉发出警告，反北约抗议活动席卷斯德哥尔摩&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;土耳其总统雷杰普·塔伊普·埃尔多安谴责瑞典允许有人焚烧《古兰经》。埃尔多安在视频信息中表示：“那些以言论自由为借口纵容这些行为并对这种恶行视而不见的人，以及那些犯下这种罪行的人，将无法实现他们的目标。”庆祝穆斯林开斋节，但没有具体说明他的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，周三埃尔多安在与德国总理奥拉夫·肖尔茨的电话中强调，瑞典不应指望土耳其在任何时候都会为其加入北约开绿灯&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据土耳其通讯办公室的一份声明，埃尔多安对肖尔茨表示，尽管斯德哥尔摩一直在朝着正确的方向采取步骤，但仍然存在“不可接受”的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，其中包括授权举行示威活动，在示威活动中传播“恐怖宣传”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来，瑞典的反伊斯兰抗议活动导致斯德哥尔摩和安卡拉之间的关系相当紧张。继二月份禁止类似行动后，瑞典警方批准了在清真寺举行的最新抗议活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;dpa、法新社、路透社和彭博社&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fukushima nuclear plant: South Koreans stockpile salt as Japan set to dump treated radioactive waste water into sea]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3226036/fukushima-nuclear-plant-south-koreans-stockpile-salt-japan-set-dump-treated-radioactive-waste-water?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 11:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/374309eb-eacc-47de-b6b4-3649160a2a28_27a8b33b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由于担心海盐和其他物品的安全，韩国购物者正在抢购海盐和其他物品与日本的合作是由于将超过 100 万吨处理过的放射性水从失事核电站倾倒入海中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些水主要用于冷却东京北部福岛核电站受损的反应堆， 2011 年遭受地震和海啸袭击后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计很快就会将巨大储水罐中的水排入太平洋，但具体日期尚未确定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本已多次保证水是安全的，并称水已经过过滤，去除了大部分同位素，尽管它确实含有微量的氚，这是一种很难从水中分离的氢同位素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是日本和日本的渔民和购物者整个地区都感到害怕。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;关于日本计划将福岛废水排入大海的信息&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我最近买了 5 公斤盐，”李煐民 (Lee Young-min) 说道。一位 38 岁的两个孩子的母亲在韩国首都首尔南部城南市的厨房里煮海带汤时说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说她以前从来没有买过这么多盐，但是觉得她必须尽自己所能来保护家人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为一名抚养两个孩子的母亲，我不能袖手旁观。我想安全地喂养它们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管官员们表示天气和气温较低，但抢购潮导致 6 月份韩国盐价较两个月前上涨近 27%产量也是罪魁祸首。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为回应，渔业部副部长宋桑表示，政府将每天从库存中释放约 50 公吨盐，价格比市场价格折扣 20%，直至 7 月 11 日。 -keun 周三表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国渔业当局表示，他们将密切关注盐场的放射性上升情况。韩国已禁止从日本东海岸福岛附近海域进口海鲜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国也批评日本放水计划，指责其缺乏透明度，并称这对海洋构成威胁environment and the health of people around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan said it has provided detailed and science-backed explanations of its plan to neighbours and the International Atomic Energy Agency&#39;s (IAEA) director general Rafael Grossi will visit the country next week to see the nuclear power plant.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;I would be willing&#39;: South Korean PM offers to drink treated Fukushima water&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Japanese Chief Cabinet Secretary Hirokazu Matsuno said last week Japan was seeing increasing understanding on the issue though that was not so apparent in Seoul shops this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I came to buy salt but there&#39;s none left,” said 73-year-old Kim Myung-ok standing by empty supermarket shelves. “There was none the last time I came too.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The release of water is worrying. We&#39;re old and have lived enough but I worry about the children.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[PLA’s world war Z scenario, Philippines’ new tourism slogan and Hong Kong’s expats — SCMP’s 7 highlights of the week]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3225975/plas-world-war-z-scenario-philippines-new-tourism-slogan-and-hong-kongs-expats-scmps-7-highlights?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/d75c8448-02c6-410c-a309-d3d3427c48b1_dafa7cd1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;We have selected seven stories from this week&#39;s news across Hong Kong, mainland China, the wider Asia region and beyond that resonated with our readers and shed light on topical issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you would like to see more of our reporting, please consider .&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Chinese military has recently added a “total war” scenario when testing and evaluating the performance of new weapons. The Z-war scenario was declassified for the first time in a peer-reviewed paper published in the Chinese Journal of Ship Research this month. The enemy hardware that appeared in the paper, such as the Arleigh Burke-class destroyer, belonged to the US Navy and its allies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;English language tutor Alice Wong moved to Hong Kong last August and was stunned to find the biggest chunk of her pay going towards rent. She said a 245 sq ft flat in Mong Kok cost her and her flatmate HK$11,000 (US$1,400) a month. “One-third, if not more, of my wages was just going on rent, and then with living costs, the rest was gone. I was pretty much always living pay cheque to pay cheque,” Wong recalled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;She has been cancelled, barraged with internet opprobrium and hit by a vague threat to get Interpol on her case, but US-born, Singapore-raised comic Jocelyn Chia is unrepentant over the joke that enraged Malaysia and kicked up a commotion over taste, decency and humour in Asia&#39;s increasingly patrolled online space.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Covid-19 has worsened China&#39;s midlife employment crisis, leading to more older displaced workers seeking re-employment. Mia Fan, who was laid off from her job as an administrator in early May, has applied for over 70 positions across various job portals but only received offers from companies which did not quite meet her requirements. Some even rejected her due to her age, saying that they only want people under 35.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Philippine President Ferdinand Marcos Jnr&#39;s hopes of turbocharging the country&#39;s tourism sector with a new slogan are being met with little enthusiasm from citizens. Marcos said the latest branding campaign, “Love the Philippines”, would act as a “guidepost” for the travel industry as it slowly recovers from the doldrums of Covid. But Filipino social media users said the marketing drive lacks creativity and sounds like a “command”, not an invitation to visit the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A famous financial columnist and commentator in China with late-stage breast cancer has advised young people who do not plan on having children to prepare psychologically and financially in case they become ill later in life. Ye Tan, 50, said: “I was asking myself if I made the wrong decision. I worked so hard in my job, but it seemed that my life was not as good as that of others with a child.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s leader John Lee Ka-chiu has delivered on nearly all 68 goals he vowed his administration would achieve during his first year in office. Of the 194 key performance indicators (KPIs) he set out in his October policy address, 68 were to be met by the middle of this year, another 55 by the end of it and the remainder within two to 10 years. However, observers have warned residents might still not be any better off as a result.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read the full story here.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong ‘should play leading role’ to bring healthcare in mainland China ‘on par’ with city standard, integrate services]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3225984/hong-kong-should-play-leading-role-bring-healthcare-mainland-china-par-city-standard-integrate?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 10:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/5eb125ae-1e2f-476d-aae3-d3c2327fde14_a8899918.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Medical services in mainland China can be on par with those in Hong Kong if the city takes a leading role in training professionals in the region, according to health secretary Lo Chung-mau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Discussions with mainland health authorities were also under way to provide better services for Hongkongers living across the border, including wider coverage under an elderly voucher scheme, and mutual sharing of electronic health records.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong can attract pharmaceutical giants by &#39;having own drug regulatory system&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The Covid-19 pandemic taught us a lesson that it&#39;s crucial to standardise healthcare services [in Hong Kong and on the mainland], to integrate with the Greater Bay Area,” Lo said in an exclusive interview with the Post. “We should achieve a high standard on both sides, but not drag one side down.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Examples cited by Lo of how Hong Kong could take the lead in improving medical standards include specialist training for doctors across the border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bay area refers to Beijing&#39;s scheme to integrate Hong Kong, Macau and nine cities in the Guangdong province into an economic powerhouse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Promoting healthcare integration with the bay area was one of the three goals laid out by the health chief when he took office in July last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lo noted that many elderly Hongkongers living on the mainland had returned to the city regularly for medical appointments until the border was closed during the pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said having to travel back and forth was too demanding for older residents, and not a sustainable solution, adding one of the focuses to address the issue would be expanding the coverage of the elderly healthcare voucher scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;A picture of health: medical struggles for Hongkongers in bay area&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The scheme, which covers all Hong Kong residents aged 65 or above, provides an annual subsidy of HK$2,000 (US$255), which can be used at private health institutions for primary care services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the moment, only The University of Hong Kong–Shenzhen Hospital and a community clinic run by it accept healthcare vouchers on the mainland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government earlier vowed to include more mainland institutions on the schemes&#39; list, with priority given to those with a “Hong Kong management model” and a good understanding of how the vouchers work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lo said local authorities were working with their mainland counterparts to address enforcement challenges when cases of abuse arose.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong adds more mainland, overseas universities to non-local doctors&#39; scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Perhaps [the healthcare service provider] could have a person in charge with a Hong Kong background, so it can be held accountable,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are also exploring if the Health Commission of Guangdong province, or Shenzhen, could help us monitor the usage of the vouchers. They also have a monitoring mechanism for their own public health insurance … and their response has been very positive.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lo said authorities would expand the scheme&#39;s coverage as soon as details were finalised.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That was taxpayers&#39; money, and we can&#39;t afford to roll back the measure … We are taking small but stable steps to prevent this from happening.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that another key step was to establish a mutual-sharing mechanism for health records between Hong Kong and mainland hospitals, but there were challenges related to ensuring patient privacy and compliance with the Personal Information Protection Law across the border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Currently, the HKU-Shenzhen facility is the only mainland hospital that can access patients&#39; health records in Hong Kong with their authorisation, under a special scheme launched in November 2020 to support those stuck across the border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since many residents that received medical support on the mainland have returned to the city, Lo said authorities were also working with HKU-Shenzhen Hospital to transfer their health records back to Hong Kong, so that local healthcare workers could gain a better understanding of patients&#39; conditions and prescriptions over the past three years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The only policy that went beyond the Shenzhen facility was the special permission granted to 19 hospitals to use certain Hong Kong-registered drugs and devices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lo, then chief executive of the HKU-Shenzhen Hospital, recalled the challenges of implementing the policy, which essentially permitted the usage of drugs that were illegal elsewhere on the mainland.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong makes over 130 job offers to doctors based in UK as part of hiring bid&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We had to ensure the drugs would only be used on patients with prescriptions and not be resold, but we can&#39;t always keep an eye on them,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We subsequently developed a mobile app requiring patients to scan the code on the package, register with facial recognition scans, record on video the process of taking the drugs, and upload it … It was truly an innovation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the HKU-Shenzhen hospital served as the starting point for many new policies and the impact of having Hong Kong registered drugs on the mainland could radiate across the bay area and benefit the region&#39;s population of 80 million when the successful model was replicated at other hospitals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the long run, the entire bay area should also seek to improve the training standards of healthcare professionals, with Hong Kong taking a leading role, Lo said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong welcomes more Guangdong healthcare workers under exchange programme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong must not export its talent … instead we should export our quality, management model, medical culture, professionalism, research and training,” Lo said. “We are strong in quality, but not quantity.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong Academy of Medicine set up a specialist training centre at HKU-Shenzhen Hospital in 2019, covering four fields.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On top of the three-year national residency training for mainland doctors, the academy will provide an additional four years of specialist training, matching international standards of specialist training frameworks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “3+4” framework is expected to cover more specialities and expand to more hospitals in Shenzhen, and the bay area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the future, no matter where people go, there is no need to worry about the quality of healthcare services any more, because the training standards for doctors are very similar to that of Hong Kong&#39;s, though not identical.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong can become the biggest contributor to professional healthcare training in the bay area, and we will benefit from that too.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Sammy Heung&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Turkmenistan unveils Arkadag, new ‘smart city’ in honour of former strongman leader]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3226016/turkmenistan-unveils-arkadag-new-smart-city-honour-former-strongman-leader?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 10:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/3fcf7264-1bed-46d3-857a-c565773402d2_9393c717.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;To cries of “Glory to the Protector!”, Turkmenistan on Thursday inaugurated Arkadag, a US$5 billion “smart” city, built in honour of former strongman leader Gurbanguly Berdymukhamedov, cementing one of the most extraordinary personality cults in the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Serdar Berdymukhamedov, his son and current president, unveiled the city around 30km (18 miles) southwest of the capital, Ashgabat, during a grandiose ceremony.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ex-Soviet Central Asian nation is one of the most secretive countries in the world, and access for foreign media is extremely rare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new city – not yet populated – is built in the foothills of the picturesque Kopet-Dag mountains and named after Gurbanguly Berdymukhamedov, who ruled the country between 2006 and 2022 and now carries the title Hero Arkadag (Protector).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Glory to Arkadag and Serdar, glory to the Turkmen leader,” participants dressed in traditional Turkmen clothes chanted during the ceremony, which took place under a scorching sun.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The former president, who turned 66 on Thursday, remains the real decision-maker in the country, observers say.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China, Turkmenistan upgrade ties as Xi urges more cooperation on energy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Rights groups have accused Turkmenistan of channelling money from its gas profits to lavish projects promoting Berdymukhamedov&#39;s personality cult, with little benefit for the wider population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Arkadag, which is in an earthquake zone, will eventually have a population of around 73,000, authorities have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city is dotted with monuments including a sculpture in honour of Berdymukhamedov atop an Akhal-Teke horse, his favourite breed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials have billed Arkadag as a “city of the future”, adding that “green” technologies were used in its construction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All the buildings in Arkadag are white and all residential blocks are seven storeys high, a number considered lucky.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An employee of the construction and architecture ministry said that Berdymukhamedov had closely overseen the project and provided his “valuable recommendations”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thanks to his efforts, a beautiful city has appeared on the land of our valiant ancestors,” the employee said on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only electric vehicles are allowed in the city. The opening ceremony lasted three hours, involving national dances, horse shows and a fireworks show.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the centre of the city is the 43-metre (141-foot) statue of the former dentist, who handed the presidency to his son, Serdar, in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Turkmenistan&#39;s new president inaugurated, pledges to keep father&#39;s course&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The statue is in honour of the “great son of the Turkmen people”, the member of the construction and architecture ministry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The golden statue shows the Turkmen leader on his favourite horse, holding the reins in one hand as the animal stands on its hind legs, while his right arm seems to show the way forward.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statue is reminiscent of those built to imperial kings and emperors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities have said that “the best conditions” have been created for the future residents of Arkadag, the first “smart city” in the desert-covered country that borders the Caspian Sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But despite the pomp in his honour, Berdymukhamedov was not in attendance at the ceremony Thursday, sending his son Serdar instead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The elder Berdymukhamedov was making the haj pilgrimage in Saudi Arabia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This was a truly historic day that will be inscribed in golden letters in the glorious chronicle of the independent and neutral homeland,” the Turkmen news agency assured.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And as the regime opened a new city in honour of the leader, it also announced that a new book had been published by Berdymukhamedov, a sequel to his book entitled The Meaning of Life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was already a “national treasure,” authorities said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Samsung chip executive feels ‘cornered’ after arrest for stealing data to build China factory]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3226012/samsung-chip-executive-feels-cornered-after-arrest-stealing-data-build-china-factory?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 09:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/e752907c-2e2e-4cd4-9466-4e4cb54fea8e_ab1927f7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A South Korean chip executive imprisoned over industrial espionage charges rejected allegations he had sought to build a copycat chip factory in China with sensitive information developed by Samsung Electronics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a handwritten letter to Reuters, his first comments to media since he was detained on May 25, Choi Jinseog elaborated on his defence plan and said the allegations against him regarding the Xian plant were not substantiated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prosecutors earlier this month indicted the former Samsung executive for illegally obtaining secret information to build a semiconductor plant only 1.5km (1 mile) from a Samsung factory in Xian, China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi is in custody at a detention centre in Suwon, a city south of Seoul where Samsung has its headquarters. He previously denied all the charges through his lawyer.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Totally groundless&#39;? South Korea investigates secret Chinese &#39;police stations&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the letter, Choi said the factory was planned for Taiwan&#39;s Foxconn, for early test production of DRAM memory chips, while Samsung&#39;s plant in Xian was designed to manufacture NAND flash memory chips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi said DRAM process technology is more than 30 per cent different from making NAND flash chips because it is more complicated, and some equipment used in manufacturing both chips is also different.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They use different equipment and the layout of [Samsung&#39;s] NAND flash chip equipment is really of no use for us,” Choi said in the letter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several semiconductor industry experts interviewed by Reuters, who aren&#39;t involved in the case, confirmed there are differences in processes and equipment used for NAND and DRAM production, without specifying them precisely.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Samsung declined to comment, citing the ongoing investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neither Foxconn or companies contracted to build the Samsung plant were accused of any wrongdoing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Foxconn, formally called Hon Hai Precision Industry Co Ltd, referred Reuters to earlier comments where it said it was “aware of speculation” around the case but doesn&#39;t comment on ongoing investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We abide by laws and regulations governing jurisdictions we operate in,” Foxconn said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to an unreleased 18-page indictment, prosecutors allege Choi planned to build a DRAM factory in Xian for Foxconn, and illegally used secret data his company&#39;s employees obtained from workers of two Samsung contractors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A NAND flash chip is a storage chip that retains data even when a device is turned off, unlike a DRAM chip which loses data when the power is off. Both are used in smartphones, computers and many other electronic devices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prosecutors claim Choi poached “a large number” of employees from Samsung and its affiliates and pressured several employees to obtain secret information involving management of special semiconductor “clean rooms”, plus factory blueprints and layouts, to shorten construction time for the planned China factory.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi&#39;s lawyer, Kim Pilsung, says this information is non-sensitive data easily accessible to those in the chip supply chain. Prosecutors argue they are “core national technology” protected by law and their theft caused more than US$200 million in damages to Samsung.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Korean chip giants dodge &#39;worst-case scenario&#39; in new US proposal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Choi sent the letter to Reuters via his adviser who recently visited him. The adviser, also a close friend, requested anonymity due to the sensitivity of the matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi confirmed the letter was genuine, according to Roh Hwa-wook, another long-time friend of Choi, who visited him on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his letter, Choi said his plan was to build a research and development chip line and he didn&#39;t need to copy Samsung&#39;s chip facilities designed for mass production.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plant, known as a fab, was never built after Foxconn pulled out, Choi and his lawyer said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What we were planning to build was an R&amp;D fab and there is no R&amp;D fab at [Samsung&#39;s] Xian plant. When there is no R&amp;D fab to copy, there is no reason to copy,” Choi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prosecutors declined to comment on the content of Choi&#39;s letter ahead of his trial scheduled for July 12. They have said the focus of the case is illegal acquisition and use of sensitive information, which Choi denies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi also rejected the claim by prosecutors that it was Xian where he wanted to build the alleged copycat factory, saying the plan was to build a plant in Qingdao after weighing several cities including Xian.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neither the Qingdao or Xian city governments responded to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi&#39;s lawyer Kim said he plans to seek bail, citing Choi&#39;s health condition after he underwent a heart procedure earlier this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi&#39;s adviser said the accused felt “cornered” and “distraught” by the industrial espionage charges, which are viewed by several chip industry experts interviewed by Reuters as part of South Korea&#39;s efforts to slow China&#39;s progress in chip manufacturing.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>