<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Call to adjust compensation policy for Hong Kong homeowners affected by urban renewal projects brushed aside by development chief]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3228908/call-adjust-compensation-policy-hong-kong-homeowners-affected-urban-renewal-projects-brushed-aside?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 23:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/157014eb-dea6-4df6-b681-26a44ffa082 8_9bc030f8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港发展局局长表示，香港当局无意检讨针对受市区重建计划影响的业主的补偿政策，此前一名立法会议员表示，如果工程能够更快完成，居民可以接受更少的资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发展局局长林汉豪周二在立法会会议上表示，政府无法跟随居民调整市区重建局向业主提供的补偿金额&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在现行政策下，补偿由独立机构委任的测量师评估，相当于同区同类七年楼的价格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现阶段，政府无意调整七年楼同等补偿计划。我们不希望看到这个问题妨碍市区重建局进行其项目的能力。因此，我们将通过贷款和放弃地价来支持当局的财务。”Linn 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在立法会议员温迪宏文指出当局在土瓜湾启动其“13 街”计划方面拖延了近十年之后，她发表了此番言论。在该项目下，自2014年起，横跨13条平行街道的数百栋破旧建筑物已被指定用于重建。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港市区重建局录得35亿港元的损失，为9年来的首次&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我问居民是否愿意以区内较旧单位的补偿金来换取早日开始重建，他们告诉我，他们很乐意接受相当于10年或15年旧单位的赔偿金洪说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为这是民众的关键呼声。这意味着作为一个考虑因素，时间比金钱更重要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪还质疑当局为什么没有审查将补偿降低到相当于一套 10 年楼龄公寓的费用会如何影响其财务和项目速度。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;如何了解香港解决住房危机的新公私计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当局董事总经理韦志成上周表示，法定机构已为大型重建项目节省了足够的资金，但必须在避免损失的最佳时机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局尚未提供有关“13街”项目时间表的任何更新，附近的“5街”地区的计划已于去年10月公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wai上周建议审查当局的补偿机制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，Linn周二对现状仍然坚持不懈，认为为了速度，最好不要让重建项目免受争议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;过去五年，香港 1,000 栋受资助建筑物中的十分之一得到了修缮&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Linn 表示：“我们希望推动更多的重建项目，而不是引发争论，因为这会阻碍我们项目的速度。”他补充说，在获得政府援助后，将由当局决定先启动哪些项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局在上一财政年度录得罕见的 35 亿港元（4.479 亿美元）亏损，这是九年来的首次亏损多年来，官员们警告称，由于该市房地产市场低迷，可能会造成更多损失。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 23:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine: nuclear plant is surrounded by landmines, UN watchdog warns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3228909/ukraine-nuclear-plant-surrounded-landmines-un-watchdog-warns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 23:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/6adf3f58-e510-4e83-bfd2-c92e09f63 1b5_39e3a94e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;联合国原子能监督机构表示，俄罗斯占领的扎波罗热核电站的监测人员报告称，乌克兰军队在经过 17 个月的战争后对克里姆林宫的顽固部队发起反攻，在该核电站周围发现了杀伤人员地雷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际原子能机构表示，其小组周日在一个远离外界的禁区观察到了这些地雷。对工厂乌克兰员工的限制。该机构没有直接将这些地雷的埋设归咎于俄罗斯人，但表示其专家被告知“这是一项军事决定，而且是在军方控制的地区。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构总干事拉斐尔·马里亚诺·格罗西(Rafael Mariano Grossi)周一晚间在一份声明中表示，“现场放置此类炸药不符合国际原子能机构的安全标准和核安全指导，会给工厂工作人员造成额外的心理压力。”声明称，该核电站位于其内部和外部边界屏障之间，并且背对核电站，“不应影响该核电站的核安全和安保系统”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际原子能机构多次表示担心，战争可能导致该设施潜在的辐射泄漏，该设施是世界十大核电站之一。该核电站的六座反应堆已关闭数月，但仍需要电力和合格人员来操作关键的冷却系统和其他安全设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;官员称，美国将向乌克兰提供高达 4 亿美元的军事援助&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;乌克兰军事情报机构上个月表示，但没有提供证据表明俄罗斯正在计划对该国东南部的核电站进行“大规模挑衅”，并在屋顶放置了可疑的爆炸物。俄罗斯则在没有提供证据的情况下声称，乌克兰正在策划涉及放射性材料的假旗袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际原子能机构的声明称，俄罗斯占领者仍未允许其进入反应堆顶部及其涡轮机大厅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，乌克兰当局周二表示，防空系统拦截了俄罗斯连夜向基辅发射的伊朗制造的沙希德无人机，这是本月对首都进行的第六次无人机袭击。基辅地区军事管理局局长谢尔希·波普科表示，没有人员伤亡或财产损失的报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯国防部表示，周二早些时候，一艘俄罗斯巡逻舰在黑海摧毁了两架袭击它的乌克兰海上无人机。据称，俄罗斯黑海舰队谢尔盖·科托夫号巡逻舰的船员在克里米亚塞瓦斯托波尔港西南 370 公里处的袭击中没有受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰官员则表示，俄罗斯人在周一晚间对顿涅茨克东部地区科斯蒂安蒂尼夫卡的袭击中使用了集束弹药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;火箭弹击中一个休闲池塘，导致一名 10 岁男孩死亡并受伤顿涅茨克地区军事管理局局长帕夫洛·基里连科(Pavlo Kyrylenko)表示，还有另外四名年龄从5岁到12岁的儿童。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯和乌克兰在整个战争期间都使用了集束弹药，美国最近也向乌克兰提供了集束弹药。西方分析人士周二表示，俄罗斯最近对敖德萨和乌克兰南部其他地区的袭击使用了最初为摧毁航空母舰而开发的导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国国防部在一份评估中表示，每枚导弹重 5.5 吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在短短一周内，俄罗斯已向敖德萨地区发射了数十枚导弹和无人机，周一击中了一座大教堂。自莫斯科一周前中断一项具有里程碑意义的粮食协议以来，罢工就发生了。敖德萨是乌克兰重要的粮食出口枢纽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据评估，袭击损坏了敖德萨以南切尔诺莫斯克港的多个粮仓，俄罗斯无人机袭击了多瑙河上的码头，距离罗马尼亚边境约 200 米。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 23:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese President Xi Jinping sends personal letter to Hong Kong pupils, encourages them to learn country’s history and develop national pride]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3228910/chinese-president-xi-jinping-sends-personal-letter-hong-kong-pupils-encourages-them-learn-countrys?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 23:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/fa1416c6-1ba4-48c5-976e-bb593b64f59 5_7437f59d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国国家主席习近平向香港一所中学的学生发出亲笔信，敦促他们更多地了解国家的历史，培养深厚的民族自豪感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北角培侨中学中四学生上个月的来信的回应也促使香港领导人对习近平周二抽出时间给青少年们回复表示感谢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家最高领导人还写道，他很高兴学生们通过参加爱国活动加深了对身为中国人的自豪感的理解，并肩负着香港年轻一代的使命和责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“爱国主义是中华民族精神的核心。香港同胞有着爱国爱港的光荣传统。” “这是‘一国两制’平稳长远发展的重要基础。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席在周一的信中还写道，希望学生们长大后也了解世界和国家大事，为建设更好的香港、实现民族复兴做出贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李周二表示，习近平的讲话传达了他对香港年轻一代履行使命和责任的殷切期望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该信还李说，这体现了主席对学生的关心和鼓励，将激励当地学校积极举办课外活动，帮助加深对国家历史的了解，让年轻人有归属感和国家认同感。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平强调香港的国家地位和“一国两制”的重要性&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;学生们早些时候写信给习近平，讲述了他们为了解国家所做的各种活动，表达了他们为香港和国家做出贡献的决心&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们在6月20日的信中表示，“每一位香港青年都致力于建设更美好的香港。”“我们已经了解到国家的繁荣昌盛。我们将继续香港的繁荣。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校校长吴焕杰表示，学生的回信是习近平主席在去年纪念香港回归祖国25周年之行期间，提出对香港青年的期望，并强调青年人的发展后向习近平的报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习主席的回信对我们的学生来说是很大的鼓励。” “希望香港青少年好好学习，多了解国家发展，为香港发展、民族复兴贡献力量。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“香港师生要以爱国法案捍卫国家安全”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2018年，习近平回应香港少年警讯祝他新春快乐，鼓励香港青少年“读万卷书”、多出去走走，加深对历史和国家大事的了解。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家第一夫人彭丽媛同年给香港又一村学校的三名学生回信，鼓励他们“画出人生中最美的画”，在寄来一张印有她肖像的手绘贺卡后，“为香港书写更加美好的未来”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平会见了针对小学生的领导力项目“少年警讯”，而彭丽媛则在2017年夫妇俩香港之行期间看望了学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;习近平今年5月还回复了澳门科技大学学生和教职员工的来信，鼓励他们参与大湾区的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湾区是指北京计划将香港、澳门和广东九个城市整合为一个经济和商业中心。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 23:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US on ‘very narrow path’ to avoid recession, IMF chief economist warns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228905/us-very-narrow-path-avoid-recession-imf-chief-economist-warns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 22:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/b23a8483-7afe-4e0f-8748-2533b43ba7 2d_5259695b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;国际货币基金组织首席经济学家表示，美国经济正走在避免衰退的“非常狭窄的道路上”，同时警告中国疫情后的强劲复苏面临风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“经济衰退不在我们的基线之内，”国际货币基金组织华盛顿总部在 2019 年 12 月发布最新的全球增长预测之前，皮埃尔-奥利维尔·古林查斯 (Pierre-Olivier Gourinchas) 在接受采访时表示。周二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们谨慎谨慎地认为，美国经济可以避免衰退，并且可以在未来不会出现衰退的情况下滑向通胀目标”，他说。他警告说，“但这是一条非常非常狭窄的道路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二上午，国际货币基金组织将 2023 年全球经济增长预测上调至 3.0%，比 4 月份的预测提高了 0.2 个百分点，理由是今年第一季度服务业活动富有弹性。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;国际货币基金组织高级官员猛烈抨击美国政府对债务僵局的“焦虑”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国际货币基金组织仍然预计今年和明年的增长将来自新兴和发展中经济体，其中美国、德国和日本等国家的增长速度将远低于中国和印度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但国际货币基金组织的报告也指出，中国经济在疫情后重新开放后面临的风险越来越大，特别是陷入困境的房地产行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际货币基金组织继续预测，中国经济今年将增长5.2%，较去年大幅增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但现在有迹象表明Gourinchas 表示，中国经济从 Covid-19 大流行中快速反弹的速度可能“比预期的更快减弱”，同时指出“对中国经济未来实力的一些担忧”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国经济中可能仍然存在一定程度的闲置现象，这种闲置现象不会消失，从而对物价构成压力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种闲置现象对全球通胀前景产生了积极影响：国际货币基金组织现在预测消费者价格上涨经济增速将从 2022 年的 8.7% 放缓至今年的 6.8%，这主要是由于中国通胀下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古林查斯表示，尽管这对全球经济来说可能是个好消息，但也可能给中国政策制定者带来挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这可能需要中国当局在货币政策方面采取更强有力的政策（也许会采取更具支持性的宽松货币政策），在财政政策方面也可能会采取一些更强有力的政策，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China replaces Qin Gang with Wang Yi but big political questions linger]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228906/china-replaces-qin-gang-wang-yi-big-political-questions-linger?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 23:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/26392a42-2697-4e9c-9331-15e0dd33d 44e_07b8cecc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国用前任王毅取代了外交部长秦刚，此举史无前例，对近年来最引人入胜的政治戏剧之一留下的疑问多于答案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;官方媒体周二援引中国最高立法机构的一项决定，简单地表示，六月从公众视野中消失的秦刚被免职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报道没有详细说明或说明将会发生什么。 ”领导层没有提拔另一位候选人，而是将这一职位交给了王，后者几个月前刚刚晋升为政治局委员，级别比秦还高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这使得王成为几十年来最有权势的外交部长之一，也是继钱其琛之后第一位担任该职务的政治局委员——主要负责政策执行。钱其琛在1992年至1998年间担任中国外交部长和政治局委员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这与党的规矩和先例大相径庭，反映出最高领导层稳定局势的紧迫性，这一局势已成为中国外交事务的巨大尴尬，也是习近平在其前所未有的第三个任期内面临的政治危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;观察人士表示，秦的免职使他成为中国任期最短的外交部长，而且收获了习近平前两届任期内担任外交部长的王毅指出，他的继任者是史无前例的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然关于突然改组的性质的细节仍然很少，但他们指出，这一公告故意含糊其辞，引发了人们对秦的命运的疑问，而秦的命运可能尚未决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去几周秦缺席期间，中央外事委员会办公室主任王一直在代理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“王被选为接替秦出任国家主席这一事实新加坡李光耀公共政策学院副教授吴阿尔弗雷德·吴 (Alfred Wu) 表示，“在大陆政治发生重大人事危机的情况下，中国新任外交部长的任命充分说明了王与最高领导人的密切关系。”吴说，这除了强化了王作为国家最高级别外交官的地位外，还强调了这位资深外交官“仍然是习近平在监督外交事务方面最值得信赖的外交政策助手”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;对中国王毅告诉金砖国家安全官员，“数字铁幕”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;今年 10 月就年满 70 岁的王毅在去年的中共全国代表大会上被晋升为党的最高权力梯队政治局委员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他参加了一系列外交活动，包括在南非举行的金砖国家聚会以及上周在中国与美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格和约翰·克里的会晤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;免去秦总职务的决定是在政治局召开次日举行的全国人大常委会特别会议上作出的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据去年6月更新的规定，全国人大常委会每两个月举行一次会议，但实际上通常在双数月末左右举行。特殊情况可由委员会主席安排召开临时会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;免去秦外交部长职务符合2021年3月生效的《全国人民代表大会组织法》。该规定授权常务委员会而不是全国代表大会任命或罢免国务院的部分成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但官方媒体的简短声明表明，最高立法机关并未决定罢免秦国的国务委员职务，这一职位的级别高于国务院。内阁部长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考虑到全国人大常委会于 2018 年免去了前总理李克强的高级助理杨晶的国务委员兼内阁秘书长职务，分析人士表示，这一举动相当不寻常。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中国外交部称，秦最后一次公开露面是在 6 月 25 日俄罗斯、越南和斯里兰卡高级外交官会议上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，在正式宣布谁将接任总理之前，被问及此事时。关于秦的职责，外交部发言人毛宁表示：“我可以告诉你，中国的外交事务或前线工作正在顺利推进。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但北京方面对这起事件的秘密处理引发了人们对中国政府决策过程不透明的质疑，并加剧了西方的混乱和不信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，英国外交大臣詹姆斯·克莱维利推迟了原定于本月底的北京之行，理由是秦长期缺席公共场合。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秦还计划于本月初会见欧盟外交政策负责人何塞普·博雷尔(Josep Borrell)，但北京突然取消了这次行程，称秦无法出席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于缺乏导致秦被免职的细节，吴表示，这次改组再次凸显了大陆政治缺乏透明度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这一事件对中国来说是一个很大的尴尬，它暴露了中国不透明的本质。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴说，这位圣人的出现对中国来说不是时候，因为中国试图缓和与美国及其盟国的紧张关系，并重振外国企业对中国的信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴克内尔大学国际关系教授朱志群表示，王毅的连任旨在稳定局势，并为中国外交政策的连续性提供保证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秦被认为是新一代外交政策的一部分。中国正在崛起的外交官，他们大多出生于1963年之后，在文革结束后不间断地继续完成正规教育。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于与习近平的密切关系，秦升迁迅速——从外交部发言人、负责礼宾和欧洲事务的外交部副部长到国家二级外交官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秦在担任发言人时被戏称为“战士”，于2021年7月被任命为中国驻美国大使。 17 个月后升任外交部长，3 月升任国务委员。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong and Indonesian leaders focus on deepening economic ties during talks in Jakarta]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3228903/hong-kong-and-indonesian-leaders-focus-deepening-economic-ties-during-talks-jakarta?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 22:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/caf9d600-2ef3-4cd6-bffb-daceb1f72589_accccc6b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong leader John Lee Ka-chiu and Indonesia&#39;s president discussed strengthening ties between the two economies on the second stop of his week-long trip to Southeast Asia on Tuesday, with Joko Widodo stressing the importance of protecting his country&#39;s citizens in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Investment and trade were also among the topics Widodo and the chief executive exchanged views on in the closed-door meeting in Jakarta, a statement issued by the Indonesian cabinet&#39;s secretariat said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said the pair discussed the protection and welfare of the 140,000 Indonesians, mostly migrant workers, in Hong Kong, with Lee quoted as saying the city was grateful for their contribution to the economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The welfare of domestic workers came into focus when a Hong Kong court in February awarded Indonesian former helper Kartika Puspitasari HK$868,607 (US$111,157) in compensation for physical abuse inflicted by her former employers.这是该市针对虐待外籍家庭佣工的最大和解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两位领导人还讨论了基础设施、交通、数字技术和绿色能源方面的投资机会，维多多指出了在东加里曼丹建设印度尼西亚新首都努桑塔拉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统呼吁减少两个经济体之间的贸易壁垒，特别是在向该市出口食品方面。印尼政府声明补充说，行政长官还欢迎有关海关合作的建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;李家耀访问期间，香港与新加坡签订了 7 项双边协议&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;李家耀在香港政府声明中表示，希望香港加强与印尼在贸易、投资、金融、科技和文化旅游方面的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年上半年，香港是印尼第三大外国投资来源地，投资金额约为 35 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;两国领导人去年在亚太经济合作组织峰会期间曾在曼谷会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李显龙于周二上午从新加坡抵达印度尼西亚首都，随后与中国驻印尼最高特使陆康和东南亚国家联盟（东盟）秘书长高金宏举行了会晤，然后举办了商务晚宴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，李显龙预计将参观雅加达的一个高铁站，该站将于下个月开始运营，列车将抵达万隆市西爪哇仅需约 40 分钟，而目前的行程时间约为两小时 40 分钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这条全长 142 公里（88 英里）的线路是中国“一带一路”倡议的一部分，由印尼和中国国有企业组成的财团兴建，但成本超支 12 亿美元，延误了四年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市领导人正在对三个东盟成员国进行为期一周的友好访问，以帮助香港企业抓住新机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;李光耀的另一项使命是巩固东盟国家对香港加入全球最大自由贸易协定“区域全面经济伙伴关系”的支持。他对东盟在与高锟会面时给予的支持表示感谢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李光耀在新加坡结束了他的三国之行的第一站，并签署了七项双边协议，以在贸易、信息技术、研究和金融科技领域进行合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港领导人在东盟之行寻求商业交易，支持贸易协定申办&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新加坡总理李显龙周一与李显龙会面，表示对香港在“一带一路”框架下的持续发展和繁荣充满信心&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李光耀的代表团由五位政府秘书和约30名商界领袖组成，包括亿万富翁李泽楷和香港交易及结算所行政总裁尼古拉斯·阿古津。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李光耀周四前往马来西亚吉隆坡，周六返回香港。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 22:50:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong should not take hard line on ‘soft resistance’, top law professor counsels government]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3228904/hong-kong-should-not-take-hard-line-soft-resistance-top-law-professor-counsels-government?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 22:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/4f39d7a3-b793-4b74-92ea-82e7f58d5 c42_f487044f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位知名法律学者周二表示，如果“软抵抗”仅涉及对中国大陆的反对意见或“错误意见”，香港不应该对政府采取强硬立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学法学教授、前基本法委员会委员陈弘毅周二发表讲话，一天前，保安局局长邓炳强表示，政府必须对中国大陆采取“全面行动”陈在外国记者俱乐部（FCC）的讨论小组上表示：“如此软的抵抗……我自己的观点是，政府应该使用自己的手段来抵消其认为的对历史、中国或其他方面的错误观点，而不是使用法律来这样做。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈承认，他不知道如何定义软抵抗，但他表示，一般的法律原则是，刑法不应仅仅因为当局不同意而被用来监管人们的言论或思想。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在FCC讨论后，他告诉《华盛顿邮报》，政府可以使用替代方法，例如学校教育、政府资助的项目和文化活动，而不是使用国家安全法或《基本法》第23条中的制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但保安局发言人周二表示，政府仍然致力于打击“软抵抗”，在国家安全方面没有妥协的余地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发言人坚称2019年社会责任&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“其中一个原因是，一些人利用媒体、艺术和文化作为软抵抗的手段，煽动他人仇恨中央、香港政府和执法人员，鼓动使用暴力，教唆他人犯罪。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发言人补充说，即使是谣言也可能是一种软抵抗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发言人表示，镇压“软抵抗”并非企图控制民众思想，并强调国家安全法保障权利和自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国联邦通信委员会的专题讨论会是为了纪念北京实施的国家安全法实施三周年而举办的。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港分裂分子采取新的威胁保安局长警告新做法&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2020年立法将分裂国家、颠覆、恐怖主义和勾结外国势力的行为定为刑事犯罪，最高可判处无期徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位发言者、行政会议成员兼高级大律师唐家华表示，唐家璇只是发表政治声明，没有必要反应过度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐说：“将法律与政治混为一谈是非常危险的。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“不存在所谓软抵抗的罪行，[法律中]也没有这样的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只有当您具有违法犯罪意图时，您才会被定罪。这里没有这样的法律。这是政治谈话。他只是说‘别闹’。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京半官方智库中国港澳研究会会长傅建智也同意“软抵抗”没有法律定义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但身为法学教授的傅建智警告说，这并不意味着不能根据国家安全法的规定处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“软抵抗是指非暴力抵抗的总称，例如煽动、煽动等。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会议员谢伟俊呼吁政府采取更宽松的执法方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你根本无法控制人们的思想。 After we have got rid of the major national security threats, perhaps it is time for us to take a more lenient approach,” Tse said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He sparked the debate over “soft resistance” after he said in an interview that the government should guard against “generalising” the concept of national security when tackling social problems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu warned of possible national security threats in the city in a recent interview with the Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that China faced “attacks” for political reasons and there had been “soft resistance” in Hong Kong in a bid to “cause destructions”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee said a recent attempt to disrupt the city&#39;s organ donor register was a form of sabotage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was a large increase in withdrawal applications from the register after the government announced plans to set up a cross-border donation scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 2,900 applications involved people who had never registered as organ donors or who made more than one withdrawal request.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zheng Yanxiong, the director of Beijing&#39;s liaison office in Hong Kong, said in June that there were “different forms of soft resistance” that continued to cause conflict and stoke hatred of the central and city governments through the internet and media.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 22:50:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong taxi driver killed, 4 passengers hurt in crash with crane truck]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3228898/hong-kong-taxi-driver-killed-4-passengers-hurt-crash-crane-truck?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 21:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/27fe9b43-bc81-4964-afde-83bfc13091f3_d1c6c337.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Hong Kong taxi driver was killed and his four passengers injured in a crash in Causeway Bay on Tuesday evening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The taxi ran into the rear of a crane truck on Gloucester Road, near the World Trade Centre, at about 8pm, trapping the cabby and his four passengers in the vehicle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Firefighters freed the cabby but he was declared dead at Ruttonjee Hospital in Wan Chai. The passengers – a man, two women and a three-year-old girl – were taken to Queen Mary, Ruttonjee and Pamela Youde Nethersole Eastern hospitals for treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three adults were left unconscious by the crash. The girl had initially passed out but later regained consciousness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cause of the accident, which resulted in a major traffic jam in the area, was under investigation.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 22:20:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s first US$1 trillion tech firm? Beijing’s top leaders offer fresh backing to country’s Big Tech sector amid uneven economic recovery]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3228870/chinas-first-us1-trillion-tech-firm-beijings-top-leaders-offer-fresh-backing-countrys-big-tech?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/88b98bf4-0122-441c-b679-46ea8d6b30ee_3acdde2d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s top leaders pledged fresh support to the country&#39;s Big Tech sector in Monday&#39;s Politburo meeting chaired by President Xi Jinping, reinforcing efforts to reverse the government&#39;s previous regulatory crackdown that kneecapped the nation&#39;s influential and best-performing technology companies to thwart “the irrational expansion of capital”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese Communist Party&#39;s 24-member Politburo Standing Committee, the country&#39;s highest policymaking body, said the nation will “promote the standardised, healthy and sustainable development of platform enterprises” – referring to internet firms such as South China Morning Post owner Alibaba Group Holding and Tencent Holdings – but did not provide details, according to the official readout that was released after the meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Politburo&#39;s pro-growth message, which followed Beijing&#39;s announcement last week of a 31-point action plan to support the country&#39;s private sector, boosted investor sentiment, with the Hang Seng Tech Index – representing the 30 largest technology companies listed in Hong Kong – surging 6 per cent on Tuesday, with Alibaba up 6.3 per cent, Tencent up 6.2 per cent and Meituan gaining 7.8 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its strong endorsement underscores Beijing&#39;s resolve to enable Big Tech companies to resume their growth trajectory and help boost the country&#39;s post-pandemic economic recovery, which has so far been uneven.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, the National Development and Reform Commission, the country&#39;s top economic planner, endorsed the investment projects of 10 leading internet platform companies, which Beijing see as essential to fuelling growth and creating jobs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China should set a number of objectives to promote the development of the country&#39;s private sector, which includes Big Tech firms, according to Chinese venture capitalist Allen Zhu Xiaohu, a managing director at GSR Ventures – one of the world&#39;s most successful early-stage venture firms, with over US$3.7 billion under management – in his WeChat post that was cited by Chinese media reports last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For instance, China should encourage leading private tech groups to reach a market value of US$1 trillion,” Zhu wrote. “It is particularly important at a time when [the] market value gap is widening between US and Chinese tech companies and US investors are showing little interest in [investing in] Chinese tech firms.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are no Chinese tech companies in that trillion-dollar club, which has remained exclusive to US giants such as Apple, Microsoft, Google parent Alphabet, Amazon.com, Nvidia, Tesla and Facebook owner Meta Platforms.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese premier endorses Big Tech firms in meeting with Alibaba, Meituan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tencent, the world&#39;s biggest video gaming company by revenue and China&#39;s social media giant, once approached that US$1 trillion valuation in early 2021. The Shenzhen-based firm had a market cap of about US$421 billion as of Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s state publications have also followed the lead of Beijing in supporting the country&#39;s Big Tech companies, many of which had been slapped with hefty fines during the government&#39;s 32-month regulatory crackdown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The state-owned Economic Daily, for example, published an opinion piece on Tuesday that described the internet platform economy as having “a brilliant future” and that these enterprises “can play an important role” in the development initiatives of local governments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a recent meeting with outgoing Alibaba chairman and chief executive Daniel Zhang Yong and Xiaomi Corp founder and chief executive Lei Jun, the mayor of Beijing, Yin Yong, assured the tech executives that the “private economy plays an important role in boosting the high-quality development of the capital city”, according to a Beijing Daily report published on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yin expressed hope that Big Tech firms would help Beijing become a “global technology centre” by 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[IMF says China’s economic malaise is holding back global recovery, with ‘cross-border spillovers’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3228876/imf-says-chinas-economic-malaise-holding-back-global-recovery-cross-border-spillovers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/090334a2-535d-4b5a-bfdb-6e57240dd1e7_9e7d73e8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s underperforming reopening is dragging down the global economic recovery, the IMF said on Tuesday, despite keeping its forecast for China&#39;s growth unchanged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Maintaining its forecast of 5.2 per cent economic growth for China this year came in contrast to the International Monetary Fund&#39;s upward revision on both India and the US by 0.2 percentage points, to 6.1 per cent and 1.8 per cent, respectively, in its latest “World Economic Outlook”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s recovery could slow, in part as a result of unresolved real estate problems, with negative cross-border spillovers,” the Washington-based fund said in its flagship publication. “Sovereign debt distress could spread to a wider group of economies.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its growth projection remains only slightly higher than Beijing&#39;s full-year target of “around 5 per cent”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fund, however, noted a change in China&#39;s economic composition, with consumption growth evolving broadly in line with expectations but investment underperforming.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The IMF said earlier this year that China would contribute to more than 30 per cent of global growth this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the country&#39;s gradual loss of economic steam, as indicated by its sequential growth of 0.8 per cent in the past quarter, looks like a long-term challenge to ambitious expectations that China would lead the global economic rebound this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The IMF flagged “negative potential implications for trading partners in the region and beyond”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The principal risks include a deeper-than-expected contraction in the real estate sector in the absence of swift action to restructure property developers, weaker-than-expected consumption in the context of subdued confidence, and unintended fiscal tightening in response to lower tax revenues for local governments,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The IMF revised up its forecast for global growth to 3 per cent for this year, from 2.8 per cent in the previous forecast in April. But that would still be lower than the 3.5 per cent growth in 2022 and “remains weak by historical standards”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The balance of risks to global growth remains tilted to the downside. Inflation could remain high and even rise if further shocks occur, including those from an intensification of the war in Ukraine and extreme weather-related events, triggering more restrictive monetary policy,” it said. “Financial-sector turbulence could resume as markets adjust to further policy tightening by central banks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report added that the rebound in consumption was broadly in line with expectations, but the real estate downturn has dragged down investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;After China&#39;s economic growth disappointed, what&#39;s Beijing got in its toolbox?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Although China&#39;s stronger-than-expected net exports during the first few months of the year helped offset property-induced investment weakness, this contribution to China&#39;s economy has been declining as global demand for China&#39;s goods recedes, the IMF pointed out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the fund lowered its forecast for global headline inflation and global core inflation both by 0.2 per cent, to 6.8 per cent and 6 per cent respectively, “largely on account of subdued inflation in China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leadership said at a Politburo meeting on Monday that China&#39;s economic recovery may fluctuate, as it assessed the economic situation and laid out priorities in lifting demand, adjusting property policies, and addressing local government debt in the second half of the year to prop up economic growth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The moves came after the nation released worrying economic figures, and after investment in the private sector dropped by 0.2 per cent from a year earlier during the January-June period.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[PLA sends 29 planes and ships near Taiwan as island holds annual Han Kuang military drills]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3228890/pla-sends-29-planes-and-ships-near-taiwan-island-holds-annual-military-drills?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.25 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/25/347bdb0d-6b91-43d9-82f8-88a5c6d63b2f_84bdbb36.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The People&#39;s Liberation Army has sent 29 warplanes and warships in missions around Taiwan, with a combat drone entering the island&#39;s southeast air defence identification zone (ADIZ), the Taiwanese military said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PLA sorties came as the self-ruled island started five days of annual war games on Monday. The first day of the Han Kuang Exercise was devoted to testing the Taiwanese military&#39;s ability to maintain air and naval combat strength against a full-scale PLA attack in the eastern part of the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Taiwanese defence ministry reported on Tuesday that 25 PLA aircraft flew towards the island, with 10 entering Taiwan&#39;s southwest and southeast ADIZ.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan to test main airport defence for first time in Han Kuang exercises&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A TB-001 strike and reconnaissance drone was tracked crossing the median line that separates the island from the mainland in the Taiwan Strait, flying into the southeast portion of the Taiwanese ADIZ, the ministry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The nine other aircraft that entered the southwest corner of the air defence zone were four J-16 fighter jets, two J-11 fighter jets, one KJ-500 airborne early warning plane, one Y-8 reconnaissance aircraft and one CH-4 reconnaissance drone, the ministry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Four PLA naval vessels were also tracked operating around Taiwan, the ministry said without elaborating.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since Friday, the ministry has reported 107 PLA warplanes and warships operating around the island, with 38 aircraft crossing the median line and entering Taiwan&#39;s air defence zone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of the 22 sorties that entered Taiwan&#39;s ADIZ on Friday, four flew into the southeastern portion of the zone, while a WZ-7 high-altitude reconnaissance drone went east, raising concerns that the PLA is trying to increase its warplane operations in southeast and eastern Taiwan, where the island&#39;s defences are weaker.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The southeast and eastern side of Taiwan are considered militarily sensitive as it is the location where the military preserves its force and maintains its combat readiness in case western Taiwan is attacked by the Chinese communists,” said Chieh Chung, a security analyst at the National Policy Foundation, a think tank affiliated with the island&#39;s main opposition party, the Kuomintang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Western Taiwan is directly across the strait from the Chinese mainland and more vulnerable to attack from the PLA. If attacked, the island could send some of its warplanes and warships to the east to stage counter-attacks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chieh said that in addition to training, the PLA sorties to eastern and southeastern Taiwan were aimed at gathering intelligence and familiarising the PLA with operations on that side of the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There should be more to come as the PLA is expected to make this a new normal to pave the way for a future blockade of Taiwan should a cross-strait conflict erupt,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing views Taiwan as a breakaway province that must be brought under its control, by force if necessary. Like most countries, the United States – Taiwan&#39;s biggest informal ally and arms supplier – does not recognise Taiwan as an independent state but is opposed to any unilateral change of the cross-strait status quo by force.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Taiwan&#39;s Han Kuang Exercise puts military and public to attack-readiness test&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The 39th edition of the Taiwanese military drills entered their second day on Tuesday, but drills at Fenglien airport in the eastern county of Taitung were cancelled due to a typhoon projected to head to the east of Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The military was originally expected to test the civilian airport&#39;s readiness to serve as an airbase for emergency take-off and landing of warplanes. The rest of the exercises, including air raid and evacuation drills in other parts of Taiwan, continued as planned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen had to cancel her planned inspection of the air raid and evacuation drills in the southern city of Tainan on Tuesday after she tested positive for Covid-19, the island&#39;s Presidential Office said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After ending her morning itinerary, President Tsai felt somewhat uncomfortable and tested positive following a Covid-19 rapid test,” it said, adding that her medical team advised her to cancel her scheduled activities for the rest of the day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsai went to a Taipei hospital in the morning to visit nine soldiers injured in a mortar explosion at an ammunition depot in the northern city of Keelung on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>