<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Beijing to create US$1.4 billion robotics fund as part of plan to become the industry’s ‘international industrial highland’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3231320/beijing-create-us14-billion-robotics-fund-part-plan-become-industrys-international-industrial?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/7756dc20-c73f-4e03-a960-ea6475ab5d4c_a5c85995.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京正在设立一项 100 亿元人民币（14 亿美元）的基金来推广机器人技术北京市政府已承诺启动 20 亿元人民币的初始资金根据该市科技促进机构在其官方网站上发布的通知，该基金将由政府资助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机器人基金将用于帮助孵化最新创新，将这些突破性成果开发成商业产品并为并购提供融资根据北京市经济和信息化局的通知，北京市政府计划对参与该行业的本地企业的并购活动提供丰厚的补贴和奖励。推动在该市创建机器人供应链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括高达3000万元人民币的支持，用于获取半导体和操作系统等关键部件，为企业和研究人员开发原型设备，并制定制造机器人的自动化流程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京的最新技术举措反映了中国致力于利用机器人技术扩大一系列行业自动化程度的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在工信部的支持下工业和信息化部等17个部门将加快机器人技术在制造、农业、物流、能源、医疗、教育、养老等领域的应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目标是实现更多随着中国努力到 2025 年转变为全球机器人强国，超过 100 个创新机器人应用和 200 多个可以应用该技术的模型用例。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国推出新计划，在人口萎缩的情况下使用更多机器人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京市政府表示，将鼓励机器人公司在拟建的京津冀大都市设立工厂，作为在该地区创建机器人供应链计划的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;根据该通知，还鼓励总部位于中国首都的机器人公司将其运营符合国际和国内行业标准，以此作为促进国外业务发展的一种手段。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数月前，市政府宣布了发展机器人产业的三年计划，预计到 2025 年机器人产业规模将超过 300 亿元人民币。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[From obesity to diabetes, China cannot afford to put its epidemic of chronic diseases on the back burner]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231024/obesity-diabetes-china-cannot-afford-put-its-epidemic-chronic-diseases-back-burner?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/4a9942b7-00b9-4660-829e-9812798125b1_85b6593d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;像许多来中国的游客一样，我被中国的美味佳肴所吸引。 “你的体型好像发生了变化。”一位朋友调侃道。回到美国后，我惊讶地发现自己在短短三周内体重增加了 7 磅（3.2 公斤）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我努力在跑步机上减掉这些体重时，我反思了这对健康的影响对于那些面临富含盐、糖和脂肪的丰富饮食诱惑的中国人来说，这些饮食是肥胖、心血管疾病、糖尿病和癌症的主要危险因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二届中国肥胖大会最近发布的一份报告北京强调了我对中国不断升级的肥胖问题的担忧。这项为期五年的研究涵盖了20多个省市的数据，指出从2019年到2021年的三年间，接受减肥和代谢手术的患者数量达到了10,000人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;令人震惊的是，从2021年到2022年，只有一年的时间，才能达到下一个10,000个。这一趋势与国家卫生健康委员会的报告一致，该报告显示，成人肥胖率从 2002 年的 7.1% 增加到 2020 年的 16.4%，增加了一倍多。该报告进一步指出，超过一半的成年人，即超过 5 亿人，毫不奇怪，中国的糖尿病负担正在上升。 2021年，中国有1.41亿成年人患有糖尿病，占全球总数的四分之一，令人震惊，尽管中国人口仅占世界人口的17.7%。值得注意的是，尽管美国成人肥胖率为42.4%，明显高于中国的16.4%，但糖尿病患者仅占美国人口的11.3%，仅略高于中国的10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《柳叶刀》研究预计，从 2020 年到 2030 年，糖尿病负担将大幅增加。根据中国的一份报告，预计到 2030 年，与超重和肥胖相关的医疗支出将占中国医疗总支出的约 22%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;糖尿病发病率的激增只是更广泛问题的一小部分：中国非传染性疾病患病率不断上升。在Covid-19之前，此类疾病就已经是中国的首要死因，占所有死亡人数的88%，占总疾病的70%以上。 2019 年，仅心血管疾病就导致了 47% 的农村死亡和 44% 的城市死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早在 2017 年，政府就已出台计划来减轻非传染性疾病的风险因素到2025年，人口疾病负担大幅减轻。2019年启动健康中国行动，重大非传染性疾病过早死亡率从2015年的18.5%下降到2022年15.9%以下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 然后，Covid-19 大流行来袭，分散了卫生当局的注意力，并加剧了健康问题。鉴于非传染性疾病的高患病率，许多人出现严重 Covid-19 并发症的风险增加。严格和长期封锁的零新冠政策也导致压力、焦虑和体重增加，同时减少体力活动，所有这些都放大了非传染性疾病的风险和影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，诸如此类的措施关闭医院或将其重新用于专门的 Covid-19 治疗意味着非传染性疾病患者得到的护理有限。这与非传染性疾病相关可预防死亡的增加有关；与 2019 年相比，2020-21 年仅城市因脑血管和心血管疾病死亡人数就增加了 70 万人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;零新冠政策非常有效，以至于其他关键的公共卫生干预措施显得不那么紧迫，例如为老年人接种疫苗并推出更有效的疫苗和治疗方法。这使得中国在去年12月取消这一政策时准备不足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，大量非传染性疾病患者，特别是老年人，成为病毒浪潮的受害者。泄露的火葬数据显示，仅今年第一季度就有 150 万人因新冠肺炎死亡。考虑到 12 月，实际数字可能会更高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着 Covid-19 不再是突发公共卫生事件，中国正处于应对日益严重的非传染性疾病危机的关键时刻。据估计，中国有3.3亿人患有某种形式的心血管疾病，其中1300万中风患者、1140万冠心病患者和2.45亿高血压患者。在我度过童年的中国村庄，几乎每个 60 岁以上的人似乎都在与心血管疾病作斗争，其中许多人无法照顾自己。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国 2022 年心血管健康和疾病报告坦率地承认：由于人口迅速老龄化和普遍存在的不健康生活方式，心血管疾病病例和相关死亡预计将继续上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Covid-19 疫情过后，越来越明显的是，非传染性疾病的预防和控制-在中国经济放缓的情况下，传染病已成为附带损害。三年来用于 Covid-19 控制的支出使许多地方当局的预算紧张，而财政收入在不温不火的经济复苏中难以增长。缺乏关于此事的中央政策声明。深陷债务泥潭且主动性有限的地方政府也在努力应对财政紧缩，这阻碍了其应对疫情的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;武汉和大连等财政拮据的地方政府选择了削减医疗保健支出通过削减退休人员的医疗福利津贴来支出。正如这些城市随后发生的抗议活动所表明的那样，中国经济放缓所造成的隐性损失可能不仅仅是另一场健康危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于一个以如此决心应对 Covid-19 的国家来说，将非传染性疾病归咎于次要的代价是它根本无法承受的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange “ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fears over China fuel wish for larger American presence in Indo-Pacific: US ambassador to Japan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231346/fears-over-china-fuel-wish-larger-american-presence-indo-pacific-us-ambassador-japan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 06:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/311968d1-bbde-4660-8a21-aaeae2093912_0a8f174c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印太地区国家“迫切”希望增加美国的存在，因为他们美国驻日本大使周三表示，担心“失去锚定和不受约束的中国”的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉姆·伊曼纽尔的这一说法是在北京方面提出批评之际提出的，当时美国总统乔·拜登及其政府正准备与日本举行三边峰会。日本首相岸田文雄和韩国总统尹锡烈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿表示，在马里兰州戴维营举行的会议旨在巩固三边联盟。这是这三个国家在国际论坛之外举行的首次峰会，也是自 2015 年以来外国领导人首次访问美国总统国家度假胜地，突显了这次会议对华盛顿的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京对日益严重的冲突表示失望。首尔、东京和华盛顿之间的距离很近。中国国有小报《环球时报》将这次峰会描述为朝着“小北约”迈出的一步，并指责美国“破坏了冷战后亚洲的经济一体化进程”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但伊曼纽尔认为，此次会议以及四边安全对话等其他安全倡议以及美国与澳大利亚和英国的奥库斯三边协议反而象征着“重组……以及美国在该地区的联盟和承诺的加强”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国永远不会因睦邻政策而获奖。他们与印度发生土地冲突，”他在华盛顿智库布鲁金斯学会的讲话中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们刚刚向菲律宾海岸警卫队发射了高压水枪。他们在尖阁诸岛的问题上不断发生冲突，”他补充道，他用的是日本对东海群岛的名称，北京声称拥有主权并称之为钓鱼岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊曼纽尔表示，中国军队“向中国发射了导弹”时任美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西去年访问台湾后，“向日本[专属经济区]发射五枚导弹”。 “他们最近在 2017 年对韩国和澳大利亚进行了经济胁迫。我凭记忆做这件事，我可能错过了一半。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登与日本、韩国领导人的峰会希望发出“团结”信息&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;库尔特·坎贝尔白宫印太地区国家安全协调员周三也在布鲁金斯学会发表讲话，称美国对该地区的参与“将继续存在”并且“现在已完全融入美国体系”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;他说，印太国家承受着“巨大的外交和军事压力”，为印太地区带来“非凡繁荣和巨大财富”的国际体系的各个方面现在面临着来自中国的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“他们感受到并亲眼目睹的是中国的行为近年来发生了明显的变化，威胁到了他们的安全，并在国家和地区范围内引起了更大的担忧，”坎贝尔在谈到该地区国家时说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坎贝尔认为，华盛顿的合作伙伴认为美国在“维护和平与稳定”方面发挥着至关重要的作用，维护“建立在法治、航行自由及和平解决基础上”的冲突秩序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，坎贝尔否认峰会以“遏制中国”为中心，而拜登政府一直通过其他官员强调这一说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“高度警惕”：中国密切关注美国、日本、韩国的目标“亚洲北约”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国务院副发言人韦丹特·帕特尔周二表示，“没有理由将这次峰会视为挑衅性的或任何煽动与中国紧张关系的步骤或努力”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在周三单独谈到峰会时，国家安全委员会发言人约翰·柯比 (John Kirby) 多次表示，中国并不是让这三个国家走到一起的主要问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及领导人是否会讨论他们对可能发生的峰会的反应时，针对北京对台湾的军事攻击，柯比表示，三边的一个关键目标是“恢复和重振联盟与伙伴关系……以阻止冲突”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将讨论一系列涵盖经济、外交和安全的主题，但柯比补充道，这次会议“与中华人民共和国无关”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这与该地区的具体挑战无关。这实际上是关于改善我们三边合作的更广泛的挑战。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Hong Kong museum uses simulated hallucinations to build understanding of mental health, raise public awareness]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231323/new-hong-kong-museum-uses-simulated-hallucinations-build-understanding-mental-health-raise-public?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/d3045502-332e-413c-9d7d-bfacdeb95eb2_67b62455.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;失去时间和空间感，听到声音并出现幻视。这些是严重精神疾病的症状，公众现在可以在香港公立精神病医院开办的博物馆中体验到。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;青山医院精神健康研究所联席主席黄爱贤医生执行委员会本周早些时候表示，通过虚拟现实技术再现幻觉的房间是新博物馆的一大亮点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“参与者可以体验精神疾病的症状，进一步了解精神疾病所面临的困难和挑战。患者。我们更邀请康复者分享康复历程，展现接受和支持的力量。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;屯门青山医院开设全市首间体验式心理健康博物馆心灵空间，本月早些时候，旨在教育公众并消除耻辱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去的研究表明，与精神疾病患者互动并体验他们的生活可以帮助消除歧视并为他们建立同情心，从而促进对精神疾病患者的理解黄说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家精神病医院成立于 1961 年，是香港历史最悠久的同类设施。 2002年，医院成立了研究所，以促进该主题的教育。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;永恒的恐惧：为何香港出院的精神病患者如履薄冰&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mind Space设有四个体验室，游客可以在其中体验可以沉浸在患有幻听、幻视、幻触的精神疾病患者的生活中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;模拟场景设置在菜市场、图书馆和客厅等日常生活场景中。参观者在体验过程中佩戴虚拟现实耳机或眼镜观看 3D 动画。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;模拟结束后，康复的精神疾病患者通过分享他们的经历以及他们最终如何寻求帮助来向参观者汇报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该医院表示，2016年开始将其历史博物馆改造成心灵空间，并从汇丰银行150周年慈善计划中获得了3,000万港元。该项目于2020年完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但由于Covid-19大流行，该场馆只能接受学校和组织的导游服务，并已将其正式公开开放推迟到今年，她说。迄今为止，已有约 1,900 名学生参观了该博物馆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名正在接受心理健康问题治疗的男子据称刺伤了两名陌生人，围绕疾病的耻辱和对患者支持的争论成为该市的热门话题六月在钻石山购物中心死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该医院行政总裁萧伟文医生表示：“公众有时可能不了解精神疾病患者的想法和行为，这可能会导致精神疾病患者死亡。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过博物馆的体验，我们希望公众能够进一步了解精神疾病患者的症状和心理，并提高人们对精神健康问题的认识&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;心灵空间还设有“记忆隧道”，游客可以通过观看精神病患者约束服、历史遗迹等文物，了解城市精神科服务的发展情况。文件。还重建了旨在保护患者的配有垫子的房间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;博物馆还将向居民介绍大脑与精神疾病之间的关系，以及使用现代精神病治疗和心理社会疗法进行康复的过程。干预措施。亦提供有关照顾心理健康、应对压力及寻求帮助的资讯。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;建议更多香港精神病患者有条件出院&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;医院将邀请学校及大专院校为学生安排参观，居民可以在博物馆的网站上进行预订。萧先生表示，预计每月接待700名访客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们相信，在青少年价值观形成的关键阶段，参观Mind Space是最有效的影响力方式她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一和周四可以团体预订，周三和周六个人可以参观。所有入场均免费。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2 US House members visit Solomon Islands but prime minister is ‘unavailable’ for meeting]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3231344/2-us-house-members-visit-solomon-islands-prime-minister-unavailable-meeting?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 06:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/9936d101-4ec7-4381-af9b-399729dbc802_77487e45.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国众议院两名共和党议员，其中一名是特别委员会成员中国共产党本周在所罗门群岛会见了反对派领导人，这是印度-太平洋之旅的一部分，其中还包括访问澳大利亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们无法见到所罗门群岛总理玛纳西据众议院委员会的一份新闻稿称，索加瓦雷“无法在日程中抽出时间”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特别委员会和两位官员都没有回应就众议院委员会提供的理由发表评论的请求。所罗门群岛，且无法联系到美国所罗门群岛的代表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佛罗里达州众议员尼尔·邓恩 (Neal Dunn) 和美国众议院无投票权代表、美属萨摩亚人奥穆阿·阿玛塔 (Aumua Amata) 启程就在索加瓦雷在北京会见中国国家主席习近平几周后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月10日，索加瓦雷和习近平承诺建立“全面战略伙伴关系”，并在中国的“一带一路”倡议与群岛之间形成“更大的合力” &#39;2035发展战略。双方还签署了一系列涉及发展、贸易、基础设施和治安方面的协议，允许中国在所罗门群岛再维持三年警察存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国的访问正值华盛顿加强其在所罗门群岛的执法力度之际。参与太平洋岛屿事务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月，美国宣布在缺席 30 年后重新开放驻所罗门群岛大使馆。 5 月，美国在汤加开设了大使馆，国务卿安东尼·布林肯 (Antony Blinken) 于 7 月在汤加举行了落成仪式。据美国国务院称，瓦努阿图和基里巴斯即将设立大使馆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2022 年以来，美国政府还推出了多项举措，包括让和平队重返该地区以及从美国引进中层专业人员。太平洋岛国将于秋季获得约翰霍普金斯大学高级国际研究学院的奖学金。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;当美国国会辩论预算时，太平洋岛国关切地关注&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国会也表现出希望加强接触，在其必须通过的年度国防法案的参众两院版本中都包含了增加美国在该地区外交存在的条款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“就像一条在猎物周围爬行的毒蛇，中共正在盘绕周围所罗门群岛希望加强对印太地区的控制，”邓恩周三表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须维护与所罗门群岛朋友的关系，以确保印太地区保持稳定与和平”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邓恩和阿玛塔会见了反对派人士，包括所罗门群岛民主党的马修·韦尔、民主联盟党的里克·胡尼普韦拉和联合党的小彼得·凯尼洛雷亚。他们的行程包括与卫生和发展人员以及马莱塔省前省长丹尼尔·苏伊达尼 (Daniel Suidani) 的会面。丹尼尔·苏伊达尼曾直言不讳地批评所罗门群岛与中国建立更密切的关系，并在 2 月份的不信任投票中被赶下台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，人们对所罗门群岛与北京的讨好感到担忧。 2019 年，霍尼亚拉将外交承认从台湾转为中国，使其太平洋岛国马绍尔群岛、瑙鲁、帕劳和图瓦卢成为仍承认台北的 13 个剩余国家之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，所罗门群岛美国政府因与中国签署秘密安全协议而受到美国批评。尽管有人猜测这将允许中国在所罗门群岛建立军事基地，但北京和霍尼亚拉否认了这种可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是所罗门群岛最大的贸易伙伴，并成为其第二大官方发展援助据澳大利亚智库洛伊研究所称，2021 年将成为捐助者。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Georgia prosecutor Fani Willis seeks March trial date for Donald Trump – a day before Super Tuesday]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231345/georgia-prosecutor-fani-willis-seeks-march-trial-date-donald-trump-day-super-tuesday?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 06:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/5adb2e9d-c19f-4d42-be7d-da97856ed172_5a0eb7c0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;本周获得针对美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普和特朗普的起诉书的亚特兰大检察官另外 18 人希望在 3 月份审理此案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富尔顿县地方检察官 Fani Willis 在周三向法院提交的拟议日程安排命令中表示，她希望审判于 3 月 4 日开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这将使审判在超级星期二的前一天开始，届时大多数代表都将参与决定下一位共和党总统候选人的初选。从加利福尼亚州和德克萨斯州到马萨诸塞州和缅因州，全国范围内将举行大约 14 场初选。特朗普目前是该党的主要领先者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普和其他 18 人周一被富尔顿县大陪审团起诉。他们被指控犯有各种罪行，作为特朗普在 2020 年大选中输给民主党人乔·拜登后继续掌权计划的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;威利斯还提议在 9 月 5 日这一周对被告进行提审。她已经设定了 8 月 25 日中午为所有被告在富尔顿县监狱自首的最后期限。这似乎表明特朗普和其他人可能会在未来几周内两次前往佐治亚州，首先是自首，然后是接受传讯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普驻佐治亚州的法律团队没有立即回应一条寻求评论的短信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;威利斯提议的相对紧张的日程可能会因被告的审前操纵而变得复杂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，特朗普前幕僚长马克·梅多斯的律师提出了一项快速动议，将案件从州法院移交给联邦法院。他们说，他采取的所有行动都是为了他在白宫的角色，这预示着宪法使他免受起诉的论点。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;用于指控特朗普的佐治亚州反黑手党法 Rico 是什么？ &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;人们普遍猜测特朗普和其他人可能也试图将案件移交给联邦法院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拟议的命令还建议了该案的其他截止日期，包括证据开示和动议的截止日期.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;威利斯的文件称，她选择日期是“考虑到被告唐纳德·特朗普在我们姐妹主权国家法院待决的其他刑事和民事案件”，并表示这个时间表不会与那些时间表冲突其他法院已经安排了听证会和审判日期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普已计划于 3 月份在纽约的另一起案件中接受审判，该案件涉及数十项州指控，涉及伪造商业记录，这些指控与涉嫌向一家公司支付封口费有关。色情演员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他计划于 5 月在特别检察官杰克·史密斯提起的联邦案件中接受审判，指控他在海湖庄园非法囤积机密文件，并阻碍政府归还这些文件的努力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;史密斯的团队正在寻求在 1 月 2 日审理有关特朗普推翻选举的联邦案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乔治亚州的起诉书长达近 100 页，使用了该州的敲诈勒索法指控特朗普和其他人参与阴谋，详细说明了他们据称为让他继续掌权而采取的数十项行动。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China real estate: would-be buyers ask whether it’s a home or a hindrance as they seek to wait out market turmoil]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3231302/china-real-estate-would-be-buyers-ask-whether-its-home-or-hindrance-they-seek-wait-out-market?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/abca9e06-f8e3-40d0-babc-c58b7690d65c_80ceeebc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;这是探讨中国当前消费状况的第三部分，包括看看很多家庭最紧迫的开支。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;何樱在家庭方面可以说别无选择。在经济形势不明朗的情况下，她和丈夫推迟了今年在广州买房的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国房地产市场低迷，加上这位36岁的人力资源经理的家庭收入意外减少，她令人担忧的经济数据凸显了这种明智而审慎的情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我已经存了几年首付，但今年我丈夫的收入非常不稳定，”他的丈夫搬家了。几个月来在当地找不到工作，上个月他远赴 1000 多公里之外的浙江省工作。目前，她和两岁的儿子留在广州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在房地产市场疲软且尚未显示出明显触底迹象的情况下，在一个正在努力应对疫情的国家中，面对前所未有的人口变化，贺建奎和许多其他中国中产阶级一样，不太可能留意北京方面的鼓励言论，因为当局希望将住房和汽车等大预算商品消费成为经济增长的推动力。&lt;/ p>;&lt;h3>;随着经济担忧打击支出，中国表示计划降低商品价格&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“房价正在下跌，越来越多的年轻人选择不结婚、不买房、不生孩子，“ 他说。 “所有这些让我觉得今年不应该买房，而应该保留现金以防万一。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前七个月中国房地产投资下降了 8.5% 2023 年同比出现最大跌幅，一系列疲弱指标给北京今年实现“5%左右”经济增长目标的前景蒙上了阴影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最大的令人担忧的是房地产行业，该行业的低迷势头有增无减，”龙洲经讯周二在一份研究报告中表示。 “销售额同比略有改善，但从 6 月份的 63% 降至 7 月份经季节性调整的 2019 年平均水平的 60%。新开工项目仅为 2019 年水平的 37%；由于有充足的政策支持来完成停滞的住房项目，只有竣工量继续增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“住房市场的下降也将给就业市场和消费带来压力。事实上，重新开放复苏的引擎——导致收入和支出增加的劳动力市场收紧——实际上已经停滞了。”报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2021 年收紧对开发商的压力以来，中国的房地产危机已经减弱其经济和金融市场的健康状况，从恒大 2021 年的离岸债券违约和 2022 年的抵押贷款抵制就可以看出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，随着中国最大的私营房地产开发商碧桂园停止了房地产交易，疫情蔓延的担忧进一步加深。一些在岸债券并难以解决流动性压力。国家支持的远洋集团错过了数百万美元的利息支付。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;网络影响者和经济学家任泽平本月早些时候呼吁提高房地产市场的透明度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我们需要理性准确地认识房地产市场的贡献、问题和现状。”他说。 “作为支柱产业，我们不能承受房地产市场的硬着陆。它对于经济增长、金融风险和创造就业机会都很重要。稳定房地产市场需要加大力度。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自2022年底以来，政策制定者不断放松房地产政策，监管层放宽资金限制，更多城市取消限购。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的首要决策中央政治局7月下旬表示，房地产市场供需状况发生变化，政策需要调整。这被广泛认为是北京发出的最强有力的信号，表明房地产政策将调整，重点不再放在防止市场过热上，而更多地放在避免硬着陆上，同时减轻对中国经济增长的拖累。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着中国预示着房地产复苏，“高风险”房地产还能拉动经济增长吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自7月下旬以来，北京也宣布了一系列振兴私营经济、鼓励消费的措施。 In the 20-point plan to expand consumption, issued on July 31, the government said it would address the housing problems for new urban residents and young people who have increasingly felt priced out of the market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Societe Generale expressed concerns that Beijing&#39;s policies may not be strong enough to fuel a substantial rebound in the housing market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The more material ones are the relaxation of housing-demand restrictions in top-tier cities. However, at this point, any solution short of a bailout of large developers might still fail to stabilise housing any time soon,” the investment bank&#39;s Wei Yao and Michelle Lam said in a research report on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the capital city of Beijing does loosen home-purchasing restrictions, Wang Qiuyue intends on buying a large apartment. The department head at a small, privately owned internet firm said he has not been able to because of family-ownership restrictions that are connected to residency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing is among China&#39;s top-tier cities that have imposed the most rigid restrictions on property and automobile purchases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t have the additional budget nor time to spend on anything but repaying the mortgage and raising my boy,” said Wang, whose son turned one in July. “But I am worried, very much so, about job prospects. If I were unemployed, everything would be ruined.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a second-quarter survey by the People&#39;s Bank of China of 20,000 depositors in 50 cities, fewer households said they were planning to buy flats in the following three months, with the proportion dipping to 16.2 per cent from 17.5 per cent in a first-quarter survey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, more households expected property prices to fall in the next three months, with the proportion up to 16.5 per cent from 14.4 per cent, the survey found.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yu Qian, a 26-year-old freelance English teacher, has moved with her husband and newborn to Zhengzhou, the capital of central China&#39;s Henan province, from Zhumadian, a third-tier city nearby, seeking more lucrative work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The small family will not be buying a home for now. They are currently renting a 90-sq-m (968-sq-ft) flat for 2,100 yuan (US$290) a month. The unit&#39;s sale price is listed at 1.08 million yuan (US$148,000).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are also considering buying an apartment in Zhengzhou, but I think property prices will very possibly drop next year. The liquidity and preservation value of real estate are much worse than before,” Yu said. “All of my friends who bought an apartment over the past couple of years have regretted the decision.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Fang, a senior researcher with the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, flagged risks stemming from insufficient confidence in residential consumption, warning that the situation could turn chronic from even a short-term aversion to buying property, if not timely fixed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Regarding the possible new norm involving residents&#39; economic activities, new ideas are required in macroeconomic policies, with stimulating consumption for starters,” Cai said in an article published by China Finance 40, a leading think tank, on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lin Suzhen, a self-employed man in his mid-forties, is still willing to consume as long as he has options.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I won&#39;t cut my consumption budget. [I have] no plan to buy a big apartment, as it is too expensive. Overseas tourism is not easy, so I travel domestically, and that is it. If Beijing can loosen the auto-plate restrictions and grant me a quota, I would, without hesitation, spend 400,000 yuan to buy a car,” said Liu, who has participated in the city&#39;s car-plate lottery since 2012, a year after Beijing rolled it out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Calling the stimulation of residential consumption the “most pressing” policy target, Cai said the government should take measures “by all means” to increase residential income. The government should, he said, also allow rural migrant workers to become residents with urban household registration – known as hukou – to unleash new demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, China&#39;s central bank said housing accounted for nearly 70 per cent of urban household assets in China – at a time when it was still widely viewed with potential investment value across the country, and as an asset to grow wealth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eli Mai, a sales director with a foreign company in Guangzhou, saw the value of his two flats rise from 3.8 million yuan in 2016 to 6.4 million yuan in 2017. They peaked at 8 million yuan in 2021 and are now worth less than 7 million yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“No one knows how the economy will be in the future. Under such circumstances … you should not invest rashly,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now, most Chinese ordinary people who own housing feel that their wealth is shrinking dramatically. That must be profoundly affecting the economy and the spending,” Mai said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Central bank data showed that outstanding mortgage loans shrank by 0.7 per cent at the end of June to 38.6 trillion yuan, compared with a year earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will cutting China&#39;s mortgage rates ease household burdens, free spending power?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The weak demand also dragged down the new loans issued by banks. In July, the figure stood at 345.9 billion yuan, much less than the market had expected. Medium- to long-term loans to households, which are largely mortgages, fell by 67.2 billion yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Wei, a freelancing copywriter in Shenzhen, has to repay 18,000 yuan each month for three apartments bought in the late 2010s when the property was still booming and buyers were betting on persistent price hikes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The mortgage is now a heavy burden for me,” said the 34-year-old with a two-month-old, as current market prices have fallen below what she paid.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adding to her stress, she has not yet been paid for freelance work done this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Overdue payments are common in the film industry,” she said. “The production company delayed payment to the advertisers, which then delayed payment to us.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore man sets mattress on fire to kill bed bugs, smoke causes death of maid living upstairs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3231325/singapore-man-sets-mattress-fire-kill-bed-bugs-smoke-causes-death-maid-living-upstairs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/36119141-f134-44d4-b4ed-b95a3caa5903_2e9b5c7e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Believing to have seen bed bugs, an elderly man in Singapore sprayed them with insecticide to try to kill them, then set his mattress on fire when this did not work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fire he started soon engulfed the unit and the smoke drifted to the upper floor, causing the death of a domestic worker.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chia Gek Yong, 73, cried as he pleaded guilty on Wednesday to causing death by committing a rash act not amounting to culpable homicide. He is set to return to court on September 11 for sentencing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court heard that on the day of the incident, Chia had suffered a relapse of his bipolar disorder. This resulted in him experiencing symptoms such as increased energy levels and hallucination, causing him to act dangerously.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the early morning of January 29 last year, Chia woke up from his bed in the living room of a 10th floor housing unit that he shared with four other occupants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Claiming that he had to kill the bed bugs he saw on his bed, Chia took several insecticide cans he had on his bed to spray the mattress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite this, Chia claimed that the bed bugs were still not dead and he went on to use several lighters to set his mattress on fire, said Deputy Public Prosecutor R Arvindren.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the fire started spreading, Chia tried to use water to put out the flames but was unsuccessful.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He then left his unit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The other four occupants in the house were awoken by the smoke and quickly evacuated the unit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of them went to a nearby coffee shop and took a fire extinguisher to try to put out the blaze, but he was unsuccessful as the fire started to engulf the entire unit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The police and Singapore Civil Defence Force officers soon arrived and they evacuated the entire block.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The Force Closes: Singapore&#39;s Lucasfilm &#39;Star Wars&#39; studio to shut up shop&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The firefighters faced two stumbling blocks: The unit&#39;s occupants had hoarded various items that contributed to the fire becoming bigger, and there was also a gas leak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chia later admitted to a police officer at the scene that he was the one who started the fire.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was arrested on the same day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As firefighting efforts continued, the smoke from the blaze grew thicker and drifted to the unit above.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Firefighters had to break into a locked 11th floor unit after they were informed of an occupant who was not accounted for.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They found a woman, 48-year-old domestic worker Koimatun Achmad Ali, unconscious in a room next to the kitchen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was taken to the hospital alive, but died hours later at around 10.30pm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An autopsy report by the Health Sciences Authority stated that her cause of death was due to smoke inhalation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Court documents did not state her nationality while the flat&#39;s location was redacted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In light of the findings from a psychiatric report submitted by the defence, the prosecution stated that they would not object to a call for a mandatory treatment order suitability report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A mandatory treatment order is a community sentencing option offered to offenders suffering from mental conditions that contributed to the offence.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;More homes were sold in Singapore last month than at any point since 2021&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The psychiatric report, dated March 10 this year, stated that Chia was suffering from a long term bipolar disorder and had been seeking treatment from the Institute of Mental Health before his offence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also stated that Chia&#39;s behaviour at the time of the incident was also unusual and that his actions were part of his manic episode, which led to impulsive and dangerous behaviour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Agreeing with the prosecution, defence counsel Riko Chua Isaac said that Chia has expressed deep remorse over the incident and deeply regrets the death of Koimatun.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Isaac added that Chia had been suffering from bipolar disorder since a very young age and there is no suggestion that he started the fire to specifically harm the victim.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For causing death by a rash act not amounting to culpable homicide, Chia can be jailed up to five years, fined or both.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This article was first published by &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China snubs Canada as it lifts travel bans, blames ‘hyping up’ of foreign interference claims]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231343/china-snubs-canada-it-lifts-travel-bans-blames-hyping-foreign-interference-claims?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 05:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/17/46786fbd-06b4-4e30-b85f-3783c11a5ff2_4c9043e8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China – a major source of outbound tourists – has left Canada off a list of countries now approved for travel by tour groups, its embassy in Ottawa said on Wednesday, due to anti-Beijing rattling by Ottawa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week Beijing lifted a Covid-era ban on group tours to dozens of countries including the United States, Germany, Japan and Australia, but not Canada.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Travel agents turn to the list of approved destinations when promoting and arranging foreign holidays for Chinese nationals. There are currently 138 countries on the list.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese embassy in Ottawa said in a statement that the reason behind the snub was “the Canadian side has repeatedly hyped up the so-called &#39;Chinese interference&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said “rampant and discriminatory anti-Asian acts and words are rising significantly in Canada” and “the Chinese government attaches great importance to protecting the safety and legitimate rights of overseas Chinese citizens and wishes they can travel in a safe and friendly environment.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United Nations tourism agency (UNWTO) says China grew to be the biggest tourism source market in the world before the pandemic. In 2019, Chinese tourists spent a collective US$255 billion on international travel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Group tours from China to Canada were first approved in 2010.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2018, nearly 700,000 Chinese visitors came to Canada, spending an average of C$2,600 (US$1,922) per visitor, or a total of C$2 billion – out of C$22 billion spent collectively by all foreign travellers, according to a report by the Canada China Business Council.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ralph Lauren investigated in Canada over Uygur forced labour claims&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;That same year, tit-for-tat arrests of a top Huawei Technologies executive in Vancouver on a US warrant and two Canadians living in China, accused of espionage, dealt a serious blow to bilateral relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ottawa accused Beijing of engaging in “hostage diplomacy”. before a deal was eventually reached with US prosecutors that saw all three people released in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China-Canada relations hit a new low this year amid accusations of Chinese meddling in Canadian elections and the attempted intimidation of MPs that led to the expulsion of a Chinese diplomat in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing responded by sending home a Canadian diplomat from Canada&#39;s consulate in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Canadian government officials did not immediately reply to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Janice Thomson, the head of tourism at Niagara Falls – the top tourism destination in Canada – said China&#39;s decision to leave Canada off its approved destinations list was “disappointing”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She expressed hope that Canada would make it onto the list in a future round of country additions.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Zealand jury finds mum guilty of killing her 3 young daughters in a case that shocked the nation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3231285/new-zealand-jury-finds-mum-guilty-killing-her-3-young-daughters-case-shocked-nation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/16/0753e2dd-5e10-4c65-83c6-125284e4b2bb_6418b89c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A New Zealand jury on Wednesday found a mother guilty of murdering her three young daughters in a case that shocked the nation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lauren Dickason, 42, had earlier admitted killing her 2-year-old twin daughters Maya and Karla, and their 6-year-old sister Lianè, at their home in the town of Timaru nearly two years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But she had pleaded not guilty to murder, arguing she was mentally disturbed at the time of the killings and didn&#39;t know that what she was doing was wrong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prosecutors acknowledged Dickason had suffered from depression but said it wasn&#39;t enough to warrant a medical defence. They said she killed her children out of anger and resentment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They pointed to Dickason&#39;s troubling phone messages and online history in the weeks before the killings, including comments about wanting to kill her children and Google searches for “most effective overdose in kids.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dickason and her husband Graham Dickason, both qualified medical professionals, had moved from South Africa to New Zealand just days before the murders, seeking a more stable lifestyle away from the turmoil in their home country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lauren Dickason at first tried to kill her children using zip ties and then suffocated them with pillows. She then placed them in their beds under the covers and tried to kill herself.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Woman in suitcase murder case involving 2 kids was in mental hospital: report&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Graham Dickason, an orthopaedic surgeon returned from a work dinner to find his children dead. He later told police that he knew his wife was struggling with her mental health and with motherhood but had no idea she was capable of killing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The guilty verdict came after a four-week trial.陪审员驳回了迪卡森根据新西兰精神错乱和杀婴法提出的法律辩护。 Jurors were not unanimous, voting 11-1 for conviction, a split allowed under New Zealand laws.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dickason faces a sentence of life imprisonment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Radio New Zealand reported that Dickason was motionless in the dock as the verdict was read out in the Christchurch High Court, and then cried quietly as she left. Jurors could also be heard crying, RNZ reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dickason&#39;s parents issued a statement saying the deaths were the result of their daughter&#39;s debilitating mental illness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We would like to encourage families and individuals around the world to be aware of the symptoms of post-partum depression as early as possible, both for yourselves as well as close family and friends around you,” parents Malcolm and Wendy Fawkes said in the statement, RNZ reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Detective Inspector Scott Anderson said police wanted to express their deepest sympathies to family members who would never get to see Liané, Maya, and Karla grow up and live out their lives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Words cannot begin to express the tragic circumstances of this investigation,” Anderson said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[British Museum sacks employee over ‘missing, stolen or damaged’ items]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3231342/british-museum-sacks-employee-over-missing-stolen-or-damaged-items?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.17 05:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/17/1d183fe3-878b-481a-981a-01deab58fd68_53ee76d4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The British Museum said Wednesday that it had dismissed a staff member and alerted the police after items from its collection were found to be “missing, stolen or damaged”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The items included gold jewellery and gems of semi-precious stones and glass dating from 15th century BC to the 19th century, it said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is a highly unusual incident,” said Hartwig Fischer, director of the museum in central London, which is best known for housing collections that include the Rosetta Stone and the Parthenon Marbles.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We take the safeguarding of all the items in our care extremely seriously,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The museum apologises for what has happened but we have now brought an end to this – and we are determined to put things right.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The museum said legal action would now be taken against the former employee, and an investigation was under way headed by the economic crime unit of London&#39;s Metropolitan Police.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most of the items affected were described by the museum as “small pieces kept in a storeroom belonging to one of the museum&#39;s collections”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;None had been on recent public display and they were kept mainly for academic and research purposes, it added, without elaborating.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese-Canadian translator calls out British Museum over use of her work&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Fischer said security had been tightened and outside experts had been brought in to help compile a “definitive account” of what was missing, damaged or stolen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This will allow us to throw our efforts into the recovery of objects,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;George Osborne, chairman of the British Museum, said its trustees were “extremely concerned when we learned earlier this year that items of the collection had been stolen”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the priority was to recover the items, find out what could have been done to prevent the thefts, and “do whatever it takes, with investment in security and collection records, to make sure this doesn&#39;t happen again”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Founded in 1753, the British Museum is one of the most famous galleries in the world, with a collection of around 8 million objects, including ancient artefacts such as Egyptian mummies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in recent years the museum has faced increasing pressure to address the contested items in its collection, which were acquired during the era of the British Empire.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This includes one of the museum&#39;s prized exhibits, the Parthenon Marbles, also known as the Elgin Marbles, which Greece insists should be returned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sculptures were taken from the Parthenon temple in Athens in the early 19th century by British diplomat Lord Elgin and have been held by the British Museum ever since.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 17 Aug 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>