<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong taxi drivers to get incentives to pick up passengers from Kai Tak cruise ship terminal and bus services to be boosted to cut waiting times]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3230313/taxi-drivers-get-incentives-pick-passengers-kai-tak-cruise-ship-terminal-and-bus-services-be-boosted?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 00:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/c43620e6-52bd-4719-b644-a7f698899667_fd6d66a9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港的士司机将获奖励前往启德邮轮码头接载乘客政府表示，还计划增加巴士服务，以帮助游客尽快到达目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一晚上宣布这一消息是在上周下船的乘客抱怨他们被困在码头上之后。由于出租车排队时间过长，以及公共汽车和小巴的等待时间过长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;皇家加勒比海洋光谱号于 8 月 4 日返回香港，这是自因冠状病毒危机而中断 18 个月以来首次返回香港该公司表示，该船将从明年 12 月起以该市为母港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但《华盛顿邮报》观察到下午 4 点左右约有 60 人在排队等候出租车，乘客不得不等待长达 20 分钟前往观塘的免费穿梭巴士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅游事务专员沈凤光与运输署、香港旅游发展局及码头营运商会面后承认启德有「改进空间」全球邮轮码头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，将向前往码头接载乘客的出租车司机发放隧道折扣券等甜头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sum 补充说，当局和港口运营商还将“加强与出租车运营商的沟通，以提供有关乘客分布的实时信息”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些措施将立即生效，”Sum说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，一条来往游轮码头和尖沙咀的新公共巴士路线正在筹备中，并正在考虑增加额外的非专营巴士路线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sum表示，希望“在实施之前实施这些改进措施”。下一艘大型游轮将抵达香港”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们知道游客使用信用卡支付需要额外的时间，因此我们也在探索更方便的方式让游客支付交通费，”她补充道。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;皇家加勒比游轮在长时间停泊后回归香港，提振香港&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;海洋光谱号定于 8 月 19 日再次停靠香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总和上周六（海洋光谱号在香港的第二天）表示，从早上到下午 1 点，有 1,660 人下了船，其中 80% 选择乘坐巴士或小巴出行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其余的人其中 20% 是由 143 辆出租车组成的车队运送的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sum 表示，当名胜世界游轮运营的名胜世界一号周日停靠启德时，情况“大大改善”，共有 192 辆出租车上午 10 点到中午之间到达航站楼，人们等待“不超过 15 分钟就登上出租车”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她没有回答有关政府是否会采取任何措施吸引零售商重返航站楼的问题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们发现抵达香港的游客渴望游览城市的各个目的地，因此码头的主要目标是为游轮提供空间”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港需要与旅游时代同步，以与区域竞争对手抗衡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这一消息是在杰夫·本特 (Jeff Bent) 之际发布的环球邮轮码头 (Worldwide Cruise Terminals) 董事总经理周一在电台节目中表示，计划 2023 年将有 143 艘船只停靠在香港，占疫情前水平的 80%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但本特表示，这些船只将由于大型船舶的航线普遍较小，因此到达的乘客量仅为冠状病毒爆发前水平的 40%，而且预计情况要到 2026 年才会恢复正常，因为大型船舶的行程是提前几年计划好的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bent补充说，周五在码头附近发生车祸，导致该地区交通中断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，他已要求政府增加来往码头、北角及观塘的渡轮服务，以便乘客可以再乘搭渡轮。交通选择，特别是在陆地服务受到影响的情况下。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why China should tread carefully around French interests in Africa and the Pacific]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3230091/why-china-should-tread-carefully-around-french-interests-africa-and-pacific?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.08 00:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/05/dedbbe22-7117-4e84-9b51-a0c924e0c546_6bb44d64.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;上个月在北京举行的中法对话会上，中国国务院副总理何立峰表示希望法国与欧盟“稳定友好合作基调”。在此之际，法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙(Emmanuel Macron)试图在美国和中国之间的大国竞争中促进欧洲的战略自主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京方面承诺加强经济合作，这表明它希望得到巴黎的帮助，以修复其与法国日益恶化的关系。欧洲联盟。但如果中国跨越了法国认为具有战略意义并目前备受关注的两个地缘政治棋盘——非洲法语国家和南太平洋地区，这一策略可能会失败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国在非洲影响力的增强，法国肯定会监视这两个棋盘。中国对最近发生在曾经是法国殖民地的尼日尔的军事政变的立场。法国政府与欧盟一起谴责了这次政变，并强调支持穆罕默德·巴祖姆总统的民选政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些观察家表示，中国可能会在萨赫勒地区取得进展，从而损害法国的利益。西方，特别是法国，因为北京并不回避与尼日尔将军阿卜杜拉哈曼·蒂亚尼（Abdourahamane Tiani）领导的军政府打交道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，如果政变领导层设法稳定其对权力的控制，中国可以试图承认新统治者以保护其在尼日尔的石油和铀利益。毕竟，近年来北京已经接受了在布基纳法索和马里的军事权力争夺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果中国成功填补法国在尼日尔的空白，那么在与南半球国家的战略竞争日益激烈的情况下，它将在全球南方再得一分。美国。但中国对尼日尔政变领导人的任何可能的示好也会激怒法国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与邻国乍得一样，尼日尔是法国从马里和布基纳法索撤军后在萨赫勒地区的最后一个军事堡垒。分别于 2021 年 5 月和 2022 年 1 月发生政变。去年，尽管马里军事领导人被指控部署俄罗斯瓦格纳集团雇佣军，法国仍被迫从马里领土撤军。今年早些时候，巴黎还正式结束了在布基纳法索领土上的军事行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;失去在尼日尔的地位对巴黎来说将是一个明显的挫折。法国军队已部署在这个内陆国家，以打击萨赫勒地区的伊斯兰叛乱分子。尼日尔还是世界第七大铀生产国，也是法国核电站的重要贡献者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在非洲的地缘政治需要是确保其投资和贸易经营有一个稳定的环境，这意味着北京无意冒惹恼法国的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据其在苏丹内战问题上的立场，中国外交部呼吁尼日尔各派别“通过对话和平解决分歧，尽快恢复秩序”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果北京对尼日尔危机持谨慎态度，那么在南太平洋地缘政治博弈上，北京可能不会对法国那么宽容。 ”，考虑到对中国国防的直接影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在印度-太平洋地区，特别是在大洋洲，新帝国主义正在出现，权力逻辑正在威胁多个国家的主权；马克龙 7 月 27 日在太平洋岛国瓦努阿图发表讲话时表示：“最小的，往往也是最脆弱的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;太平洋岛屿认为西方对福岛计划的支持是虚伪的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;法国由于新喀里多尼亚、法属波利尼西亚以及瓦利斯和富图纳群岛的属地共有约 56 万法国公民，法国将自己视为太平洋参与者。凭借这些领土，它在南太平洋拥有约650万平方公里的专属经济区需要保卫。它在新喀里多尼亚和法属波利尼西亚驻扎着 2,840 名士兵，是唯一在该地区永久驻军的欧洲强国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙在瓦努阿图的长篇大论也针对的是正在与美国发生冲突的美国。对于中国在南太平洋的影响力，他的第一个目标显然是北京。 7月26日访问新喀里多尼亚期间，他宣布将增加法国在新喀里多尼亚的驻军人数，并警告说，法国海外领土的独立可能意味着明天将建立“中国海军基地”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙显然指的是中国去年与所罗门群岛签署的安全协议。该协议的条款基本上是秘密的，但将赋予中国军舰在这个与法属喀里多尼亚拥有共同海上边界的太平洋岛国港口中途停留和加油的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国小报《环球时报》攻击了马克龙关于南太平洋新帝国主义风险的叙述，一些专家称其为“空洞的概念”，并为挽救法国在该地区的边缘地位而拼命努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国希望保留其势力范围其前非洲殖民地的影响力并捍卫其在南太平洋的主权。中国国家主席习近平如果希望与马克龙的协议取得成果，就必须考虑到这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧洲最近的事态发展，例如意大利决定尝试退出中国的“一带一路”该倡议以及欧盟委员会推动的明显针对中国的经济安全战略，应该建议北京在最终可能威胁法国国家利益的领域打好牌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UK begins moving asylum seekers to residential barge on south coast]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230312/uk-begins-moving-asylum-seekers-residential-barge-south-coast?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 23:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/172af34a-c75a-4789-b27a-a8368159ee92_1f458f9c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英国周一开始将一些移民转移到其南部海岸的一艘大型住宅驳船上，作为在处理庇护申请期间使用更便宜的酒店替代方案作为临时住宿计划的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府表示，希望限制吸引寻求庇护者前往英国的“拉动”因素，目前英国有超过 50,000 名寻求庇护者他们乘坐小艇横渡英吉利海峡完成了最后一段旅程，目前住在酒店。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;使用驳船和废弃军事基地的计划引起了当地社区的抗议，一些人抱怨可能的影响并质疑这些地点是否会成为抗议的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人称，为来自伊拉克、伊朗、叙利亚、阿富汗或阿尔巴尼亚等国家的人提供的住房是不人道的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;英国内政部部长莎拉·迪恩斯(Sarah Dines)周一早些时候告诉天空新闻，在酒店费用升至600万英镑后，驳船是增加政府可用于安置移民的地点数量计划的一部分(每天 760 万美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它传达的是一个强有力的信息，即会有适当的住宿，但不豪华，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府表示，毕比斯德哥尔摩驳船将只容纳单身男性，并提供“基本和实用”的住宿，以及医疗服务、餐饮设施和船上保安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，约 50 名移民将搬上船上。一位知情人士称，他们在中午左右开始抵达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们照顾的寻求庇护者的福利是最重要的，”内政部发言人表示。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“（我们）继续与当地警方和我们在当地的合作伙伴密切合作，以确保现场和更广泛社区中任何人的安全。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt; div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong transport sector files 118 applications under scheme to import minibus, coach drivers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3230305/hong-kong-transport-sector-files-118-applications-under-scheme-import-minibus-coach-drivers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 22:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/63e7b8c6-3ba4-4f12-bd4b-eb26e2414d8d_230a2e48.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一项输入工人并支持香港运输业的计划收到了 118 份申请小型巴士和长途汽车司机的第一轮截止日期已于周一截止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些申请是政府最近引进 20,000 名工人以缓解香港建筑、航空和运输行业人员短缺的计划的一部分&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该政策，交通运营商最多可招聘900名小巴司机和800名长途客车司机。预计企业将转向中国大陆引进工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运输署周一表示，从 7 月 17 日第一阶段启动到周一，已收到 118 份小巴和长途客车司机的申请，但没有收到任何申请。详细说明每份提交材料涵盖了多少候选人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“香港应允许输入工人参与小型建筑项目”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作为该计划的一部分招募的任何候选人都必须支付薪水不低于小巴司机的工资中位数，即 14,300 港元（1,830 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港专线小巴持牌人协会成员陈志辉在电台节目中表示，他的公司已代表其申请上周在珠海的一个招聘会上，我们筛选了 20 名候选人，面试了 120 多人，以寻找讲粤语的大陆人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他补充说，根据该计划招聘工人对企业来说成本也很高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“雇用一名新员工将额外花费30,000至40,000港元。我们预计新员工抵达后第一个月、通过驾驶考试和公司培训之前将无法工作。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 还表示，他的企业必须支付住宿费和往返期间的费用。每次驾驶考试费用为港币8,000元至港币9,000元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[该计划]对每个人来说都是新鲜事物，因此业界期望能够处理杂项问题。但到目前为止，这还不是一个大问题。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港下周推出引进 12,000 名建筑工人的计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港的士及公共小巴协会主席周国强亦表示，额外费用阻碍了部分公司申请计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他估计，外地司机的住宿费用包括1万港元，用于为七至八名司机装修一套公寓，其次是另一项费用。该集团的租金每月为10,000港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chau表示，通过驾驶考试的司机将必须在更有经验的员工的指导下接受路线培训。他指出：“这需要额外的人力，每天可能会多花费 1,000 港元。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专线小巴专线巴士营办商总会主席苏世雄表示，额外的费用是“必要的” ”，因为该行业长期面临严重的劳动力短缺问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，该协会由40家运营商组成，涵盖130条小巴路线，大多数成员都已申请该计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“输入外劳是唯一出路，但我们希望这只是暂时的，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港领导人为工会成员罢工后输入劳工的计划辩护&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;So 补充说，当局已承诺设立额外的驾驶考试名额，以便根据该计划引入的司机可以快速接受评估。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在低劳动力数量出现后，政府于 6 月推出了劳动力输入计划。 2018年至2022年间，香港的技术工人减少了16万名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该计划的进口配额，航空业可雇用6,300名机场工人，而建筑业最多可进口12,000名劳工。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为 7 月份结束的第一轮的一部分，政府已收到来自航空业的约 2,900 份申请，而建筑公司必须在 8 月 16 日之前提交申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[German man held in France after wife freed from 12 years captivity in flat: police]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230310/german-man-held-france-after-wife-freed-12-years-captivity-flat-police?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 22:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/29fff63d-32fc-409b-a2f7-c2fafa217d0d_f1e5da63.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;法国警方周一表示，在一名德国公民的妻子被发现后，他们逮捕了他在这对夫妇的家中被囚禁了 12 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方消息人士称，这名女子也是德国人，当他们在公寓的卧室里发现她时，她赤身裸体，剃光头，身上有多处受伤，包括骨折。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消息人士称，她可能受到了酷刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方称，位于法国东部福尔巴赫的住所的卧室被金属丝封闭，该住所靠近德国边境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位警方消息人士称，这名 53 岁的女子设法打电话给德国警方，德国警方又通知了法国同事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消息人士称，这名女子据信她在德国西部威斯巴登发现了一部电话并报了警。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她因双腿和手指骨折而被送往医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名男子，法国广播公司 BFMTV 称，55 岁的男子被指控绑架、严重强奸以及酷刑和野蛮行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该男子被关押在东部城市梅斯，一名警方消息人士告诉法新社，调查人员仍在拼凑事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“几项检查正在进行中，我想保持谨慎，”消息人士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;广播电台 RMC 表示警方发现了一本日记 -公寓里的笔记本上，据信该男子记录了他的行为以及他给妻子食物的时间。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Teenager drowns at natural Hong Kong pool while exploring country park]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3230311/teenager-drowns-natural-hong-kong-pool-while-exploring-country-park?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 22:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/d5f94c8f-b333-42eb-a967-363915894b0e_a94f0913.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周一，一名青少年在美国著名的天然泳池游泳后溺水身亡。香港西贡东郊野公园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该名19岁菲律宾裔持有香港身份证的男子于下午3时25分左右与三名友人分头前往四池畅游。 ，也被称为四联池。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的一个朋友在10分钟后折回后费力寻找该男子，直到潜入池底才发现他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该组织拦住了一名路过的徒步旅行者，一名 40 岁的男子，他联系了紧急服务部门。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港游泳者和渔民在西贡发生两起不同事件溺水身亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府飞行服务队出动直升机，救援人员立即为昏迷少年提供医疗救助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;19岁少年被空运至柴湾东区尤德夫人那打素医院，但抵达后不久即宣告死亡.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方正在调查这起事件，预计当局将进行尸检。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 7 月，一名 37 岁的徒步旅行者在同一地点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三年前，救援人员在四池进行了三个小时的搜寻后救出了一名尼泊尔男子，但这名 25 岁的男子在被空运到医院时死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据信该男子曾与其他人一起帮助拯救一名溺水妇女，但随后消失在水中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四池是位于岩石地形中的一系列中流跌水池，是一口井- 著名的自然景点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最上面的泳池是最深的，12 米高的垂直悬崖隐约可见，使其成为勇敢的悬崖跳水者的热点。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;一名男子乘船游览香港西贡附近海域溺水&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;六名独木舟者被困在岩石区附近，警方呼吁公众不要前往偏远岛屿或水域进行高风险户外活动周六，西贡金岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方发布的一段视频显示，两名救援人员冒着巨浪试图营救被困的人群。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方强调，这些地点构成了对参与高风险活动的个人以及参与其恢复的救援人员构成重大危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China-India border row: will Delhi’s ‘solidified’ stance hinder efforts to ease dispute?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3230304/china-india-border-row-will-delhis-solidified-stance-hinder-efforts-ease-dispute?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 21:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/695de7ef-467e-4108-928a-1ad23d6020c6_f84315b0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国和印度可能在边境一些“非常紧张”的地区取得了进展近年来两国关系恶化，但分析人士表示，新德里更加自信的外交政策可能会成为改善两国关系的绊脚石。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度外交部长苏杰生周一表示，印度在解决问题上已取得进展。 “五个[或]六个非常紧张的地区”，强调缓解前线僵局的谈判“没有停止”，并将“很快举行”另一次会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两者之间的关系2020 年，有争议的克什米尔地区发生了一场致命的小冲突，造成至少 20 名印度士兵和 4 名中国士兵死亡，该地区大国遭受了重大挫折。这是自 1962 年中印战争以来首次在边境发生暴力冲突，这场战争也是因为英国时代边界问题上的历史性分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后，双方举行了多轮军事级别会谈，以防止局势进一步升级，但未能取得任何突破。 2022 年 12 月，数百名印度和中国军队爆发冲突。2 月，苏杰生将边境局势描述为“危险”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月第 18 轮军长级会议后，印度和中国据报道，中国同意维护当地的安全与稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“事实是，中国和印度仍陷入重大军事对峙。而且，尽管谈判正在进行，但这种对峙只会更加严重。”德里智库政策研究中心战略研究教授布拉马·切拉尼 (Brahma Chellaney) 周一表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然印度已经中国外交部长王毅在 7 月与苏杰生会面时重申，持续的边境对峙“不应定义整体关系”，并表示，只有“边境地区实现和平与安宁”，两国关系才能“正常”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;王敦促德里聚焦“共同利益”，与北京“相向而行”以解决边界问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，印度外交部承认印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪和中国国家主席习近平习近平在 2022 年 11 月印度尼西亚 G20 峰会期间讨论了“稳定”双边关系的必要性。当时的交流并未披露。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪已确认出席定于 8 月举行的金砖国家峰会22-24 日在南非约翰内斯堡，揭穿了一份报告，该报告声称他将虚拟参加会议，因为他对“中国在新兴经济体（还包括巴西、俄罗斯和南非）集团中的主导地位感到“不安”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;习近平还将出席9月9日至10日在德里举行的G20峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当双方数万军队在喜马拉雅山上对峙时，这会很奇怪如果习近平访问德里而不寻求化解边境对抗，”切拉尼说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着莫迪和习近平看起来将在峰会上会面，冷冰冰的印中关系会解冻吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;尽管苏杰生评论称有关缓和紧张局势的谈判将继续进行，德里更加自信的外交政策立场可能会削弱正在取得的任何进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国和平研究所的亚历克斯·斯蒂芬森，这是一个无党派联邦机构，旨在促进冲突解决，称德里近年来的行动“是为了对抗北京而不是接触”，因为它加深了与华盛顿和其他印太地区参与者的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近发生的事件表明印度对中国的立场更强硬。上个月，德里就 2016 年仲裁裁决表示支持菲律宾，该裁决驳回了北京在南海的“九段线”主张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪还谈到了“胁迫和对抗的乌云” 6 月在美国国会发表讲话时，他没有公开点名中国，给该地区蒙上一层阴影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度最近与美国签署了协议，以增强国防和技术能力，同时也强化了其作为一个大国的承诺。面对中国的军事和经济野心，印度是四方安全组织的成员，旨在维护基于规则的秩序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苏杰生周一表示，德里还大幅增加了对边境基础设施以及与孟加拉国、尼泊尔和印度的互联互通的投资。不丹。后两国与中国接壤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当涉及到国家安全时，基础设施的质量对于部署的有效性更为重要，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 22:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China takes cautious line on Saudi-led Ukraine talks but Russia still the big bear not in the room: analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3230282/china-takes-cautious-line-saudi-led-ukraine-talks-russia-still-big-bear-not-room-analysts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/07/81d91caa-66c0-4ae3-9800-1f3632c3ec2a_87988f67.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;关于乌克兰的周末和平谈判取得了一些进展，但如果不这样做，战争就不可能结束据中国分析人士称，俄罗斯的参与。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是出席在沙特城市吉达举行的为期两天的会议的 40 多个国家之一，北京直到会议前夕才离开会议，以确认这一点欧亚事务特使李辉将出席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他与会者包括印度、巴西、南非和美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但俄罗斯没有受到邀请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;俄罗斯外交部副部长谢尔盖·里亚布科夫(Sergei Ryabkov)驳斥了这次聚会，称其为“西方试图继续徒劳且注定失败的努力”，目的是让全球南方支持乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉达会议后没有发表联合声明，但据沙特阿拉伯报道，两国一致认为，尊重乌克兰主权和领土完整应成为未来俄乌和谈的核心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是中国首次向此类国家派遣特使。据报道，中国代表重申了北京关于政治解决乌克兰危机的十二点立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们已经路透社援引李克强的话说：“我们有很多分歧，也听到了不同的立场，但重要的是我们有共同的原则。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在会议间隙，李克强会见了白宫国家安全顾问和代表团团长杰克·沙利文以及负责政治事务的副国务卿维多利亚·纽兰。 《华尔街日报》援引华盛顿官员的话说：“中国在这里真是太好了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国热衷于确保乌克兰和谈不会变得“反俄”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;上海华东师范大学国际关系副教授张欣表示，据了解，这次会议为中国提供了一个“相当好的”平台，可以在这个问题上发表立场文件，并与广泛的国家寻求共识。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一个可贵的成果是，与丹麦相比，这次参加的国家特别是发展中国家更多了，”张说，他指的是6月举行的一次会议。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“似乎就下一轮会谈的人员和议程达成了一些共识。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，似乎在核安全、粮食安全和供应链等问题上达成了一些共识。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他警告说，只要莫斯科不参与其中，原则上就很难达成任何协议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国的出席也是对沙特阿拉伯外交地位的认可，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民大学国际关系教授时殷弘对此表示赞同，并表示莫斯科的缺席意味着这次会议并不是和平进程中的里程碑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“双方达成真正和平协议的希望不大，”时说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道俄罗斯不愿意改变对乌克兰的战略，甚至停止了允许乌克兰运输粮食的交易——这是一场长期战争的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;石补充说，北京在会议上传递的信息持谨慎态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我们没有从中国官方媒体那里听到特使在那里做了什么或详细谈论了什么。中国的态度是谨慎的，这是应该的，因为战争还没有结束的迹象。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家通讯社新华社对周一的峰会进行了简短报道，称“所有与会者都强调了实现这一目标的重要性”。通过国际谈判和平解决乌克兰危机”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰总统办公室主任安德里·叶尔马克表示，此次会议就乌克兰十二步和平计划的关键原则和可能采取的步骤进行了富有成效的磋商.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然观点不同，但所有与会者都表明了各自国家对《联合国宪章》原则、国际法以及尊重国家主权和领土完整不可侵犯的承诺，”叶尔马克&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;史指出，这次会议最大的成果是中国支持《联合国宪章》，承认乌克兰主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国提出了解决乌克兰危机的十二点和平主张。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它呼吁停火，但基本上放弃了谴责俄罗斯入侵的联合国决议，并表示不支持将乌克兰冲突描述为“俄罗斯联邦的侵略”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;It did not take part in the June talks in Denmark so its decision to send Li this time attracted much attention.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, Chinese foreign ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin said “China stands ready to work with the international community to continue to play a constructive role in seeking a political settlement of the Ukraine crisis.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba described China&#39;s participation as a “super breakthrough” on Friday, and emphasised that Saudi Arabia had played an important part in pushing China to make that decision. “Saudi Arabia has attracted China, and this is a historic victory.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Jun Mai&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong ex-health secretary appeals for better integration of cross-border medical services]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3230306/hong-kong-ex-health-secretary-appeals-better-integration-cross-border-medical-services?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 22:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/e56eb1df-3281-4724-8f9d-342b5132e219_e5aebba8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Hong Kong ophthalmologist applied for a permanent qualification certificate in mainland China in 2020 so he could practice in the Greater Bay Area, despite a busy schedule in the city, he has said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dr Jeffrey Pong Chiu-fai on Monday added, because of the increasing demand for “Hong Kong style” medical services in the region, he had been in discussions with mainland Chinese hospitals about taking up managerial or leadership roles where he could help them to fit into city standards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some local private hospitals, in order to compete with tertiary hospitals, may need to polish their brand with Hong Kong style medical services,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pong added there was also a lot to learn from mainland hospitals, where the amount of surgery performed was much greater than in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Greater Bay Area is Beijing&#39;s scheme to merge Hong Kong, Macau and nine cities in the Guangdong province into an economic powerhouse, with a population of over 86 million people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Government statistics for 2022 showed there were about 529,500 Hong Kong permanent residents in the bay area at the time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hongkongers across the border were unable to return to the city for medical treatment during the Covid-19 crisis, which sparked discussions on providing quality healthcare services in the bay area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Health secretary Lo Chung-mau in June stressed the importance of standardising healthcare services in Hong Kong and on the mainland and said that the city should take a leading role in training professionals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former health minister Dr Ko Wing-man said about 30 Hong Kong doctors had submitted applications to work across the border at present. Sixteen of them were family medicine and general practitioners and others were specialists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ko, also the honorary president of the Greater Bay Area Medical Professional Development Association, said the group was setting up centres in the region to help Hong Kong doctors to apply for qualification certificates and buy practice liability insurance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said it was also helping mainland hospitals to buy drugs used in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said Hongkongers in the region had admitted they could not get used to the medical system across the border and there was a demand for “Hong Kong-style” healthcare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ko added that proved the need to ensure the quality of mainland healthcare services was on par with Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The integration of healthcare services in Hong Kong and the bay area can bring the medical models in the two places closer, allowing Hongkongers to receive more recognised medical services no matter if they are in Hong Kong or on the mainland,” he explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong should &#39;take lead to bring mainland healthcare on par with city standard&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ko said encouraging city doctors to work in the bay area would not cause a drain on medical manpower as it would only need those with management experience and leaders in clinical specialties to exchange knowledge with mainland counterparts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added doctors who qualified in Hong Kong after 2002 could only obtain a temporary licence on the mainland, which had to be renewed every three years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ko appealed to the government to discuss the relaxation of the regulations with mainland authorities to allow doctors to gain permanent qualification certificates irrespective of when they graduated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was speaking as the association appealed for better integration between health services on both sides of the border with the Greater Bay Area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Special permission is at present granted to 19 hospitals on the mainland to use Hong Kong-registered drugs and devices in emergencies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ko said the rules should be relaxed to allow more drugs and devices to be used for non-emergency purposes and there should be more promotion of the scheme as not many medical professionals or patients were aware of it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pong, also an executive committee member of the Hong Kong Professionals and Senior Executives Association, said he expected that city doctors would prefer to work in mainland hospitals rather than setting up their own clinics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He explained doctors from Hong Kong might not be familiar with medical policies and administration on the mainland, which would make it difficult for them to set up on their own.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In hospitals operating as an enterprise, it is easier for doctors to receive support such as setting up of the system used for consultations, finding customers, securing indemnity insurance for doctors and employees&#39; compensation insurance, and handling taxation,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong nurse exchange with mainland has eased pressure on city hospitals: staff&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Dr Ng Yin-ting, a specialist in psychiatry, said she was interested in working on the mainland and had applied for a qualification certificate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng said she began holding online consultations in 2019 for mainland residents who had said they preferred not to travel to Hong Kong during the anti-government protests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong is a part of the Greater Bay Area. It is only a matter of time for us to practice in the mainland,” she said&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Medical and health services sector lawmaker Dr David Lam Tzit-yuen also suggested an expansion of coverage for the elderly healthcare voucher scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scheme, for Hong Kong residents aged 65 or above, provides an annual subsidy of HK$2,000 (US$255).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It can be used at private health providers for primary care services in the city, as well as The University of Hong Kong–Shenzhen Hospital and a community clinic run by it on the mainland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam said the government could require mainland hospitals covered by the scheme to submit figures to Hong Kong regulatory organisations for a clinical audit, which is also done by every hospital in the city, to ensure quality control.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It will look at the outcome of some patient cases and see whether there is any room for improvement,” he explained.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thai election runners-up agree coalition with government-aligned party]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3230308/thai-election-runners-agree-coalition-government-aligned-party?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 22:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/a23cdcdc-1ca6-47b7-8979-ecb4575ed324_43a2b8b5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Thailand&#39;s election runners-up announced a fresh coalition with a government-aligned party on Monday as lawmakers attempt to overcome resistance from military and pro-royalist senators to break a political deadlock.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The kingdom has been unable to form a government after the reformist Move Forward Party (MFP) fell short of a majority, despite winning the most seats in May&#39;s polls, and was later excluded from a progressive coalition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MFP rode a wave of support from young and urban Thais weary of almost a decade of army-backed rule but spooked Thailand&#39;s powerful conservative establishment with pledges to break up business monopolies and amend strict royal defamation laws.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The party&#39;s closest rival, Pheu Thai, announced the new partnership on Monday with another party, Bhumjaithai, bringing together a total of 212 seats in the Thai parliament&#39;s lower house.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A previous eight-party coalition headed by MFP failed to get leader Pita Limjaroenrat elected prime minister after he was blocked by junta-appointed senators opposed to his determination over the lese-majesty laws.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pheu Thai announced last week the progressive party had been excluded from the coalition, saying support for Pita&#39;s bid had stumbled over MFP&#39;s stance on lese-majesty reform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leader Chonlanan Srikaew announced on Monday a coalition agreement between his party and Bhumjaithai – a member of the army-backed coalition government elected in controversial 2019 polls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We would like to thank Bhumjaithai for accepting the invitation so that we can step over this political deadlock,” he told a news conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chonlanan said Pheu Thai and Bhumjaithai would seek support from other parties in forming a government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We want all parties to support the candidate from Pheu Thai,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Bhumjaithai party, best known for delivering on a 2019 campaign promise to legalise cannabis in Thailand, had previously insisted it would not be part of any coalition containing MFP.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leader Anutin Charnvirakul said his party had partnered with Pheu Thai on three conditions, including dropping the lese-majesty amendment and not forming a minority government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Third, if Pheu Thai leads the government, for Bhumjaithai, the Move Forward Party cannot be part of the government,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The news sparked a small protest outside Pheu Thai&#39;s headquarters. Protesters threw paper fliers with pictures of the Pheu Thai leader emblazoned with: “WANTED: Chonlanan what time will you resign?”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Thailand&#39;s Thaksin plans his return amid rumours of a &#39;super-deal&#39; with ex-foes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Pheu Thai is seen as a vehicle for the Shinawatra political clan, whose members include two former prime ministers ousted by military coups in 2006 and 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week Pheu Thai nominated businessman Srettha Thavisin as the bloc&#39;s candidate for prime minister and Chonlanan confirmed on Monday that was still the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To become prime minister, a candidate must be approved by a majority of both houses of parliament – the 500 elected MPs and the 250 senators appointed under the last junta.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pita managed 324 votes across the two houses in the first vote in parliament, with only 13 senators supporting him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was blocked from running in a second ballot and suspended as an MP by the Constitutional Court over his ownership of media shares, which is prohibited for lawmakers under Thai law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Constitutional Court last week delayed hearing a petition challenging parliament&#39;s decision to deny Pita a second ballot to become prime minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parliament postponed a scheduled vote soon afterwards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MFP has agreed to go into opposition, insisting it can still effect change despite not holding power.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese public fear repeat abuse of flood relief funds after it emerges over US$1 billion in aid for 2021 was misused]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3230301/chinese-public-fear-repeat-abuse-flood-relief-funds-after-it-emerges-over-us1-billion-aid-2021-was?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.07 21:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/07/bd046edf-a982-46ac-bb37-a751b5d78600_f2c4ba24.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Reports that flood relief funds had been siphoned off have sparked anger in China and prompted fears that the same thing may happen again after this month&#39;s devastating floods.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Late last month an audit report by the Henan provincial government documented how about 10 billion yuan (US$1.4 billion) of reconstruction funds earmarked for the 2021 summer flooding in Henan had been misused or siphoned off for other uses by local officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story started spreading quickly online late last week after a commentary on the issue was published by state-run Guangming Daily even as rescue efforts continued in the north and northeast of the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 30 people have been killed after heavy floods hit Beijing and provinces such as Hebei, Jilin and Heilongjiang last week, with the capital recording its heaviest rainfall in 140 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The central government has so far allocated 520 million yuan of relief funds to the worst hit regions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 2021 summer flooding in Henan, which killed almost 400 people, caused a nationwide uproar because of the heavy death toll and a poor emergency response by local officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Candlelit dinner&#39;: restaurant in China flood area treats 200 disaster workers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to a report released in January 2022 by a State Council investigation team, the “historically rare heavy rainfall” that hit the central province had affected nearly 15 million people and resulted in economic losses of over 120 billion yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Henan province has not published how much it has spent on reconstruction but media reports said the figure amounted to at least 20 billion yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November 2021 the authorities pledged, in an article for the official Zhengzhou Daily newspaper, to “seriously enforce financial discipline, strengthen fund management, and urge cities and counties to deliver funds directly to the grass roots and the affected people as soon as possible to ensure that the valuable relief and reconstruction funds are used properly”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the audit report uncovered a series of problems. In one case it found that nine counties and a provincial government-controlled enterprise were allocated a total of 405 million yuan but they had failed to use them in accordance with rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another two counties were discovered to have diverted over 30 million yuan of reconstruction funds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Construction funds are specially issued by the state, so why haven&#39;t they been used for the people?谁这么大胆？有什么规定吗？” the Guangming Daily commentary said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It must be clear that the money belongs to the state and the people, and how it is used must be investigated thoroughly.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hashtags relating to the report were blocked on the social media platform Weibo, but posts on the issue were widely shared with some attracting thousands of comments.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Global warming to drive longer, more extreme weather events: climate scientists&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;One popular comment on the platform said simply: “Hebei will soon be Zhengzhou in 2021.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the most liked responses to a post from the media outlet iFeng.com that was shared or commented on more than 15,000 times read: “What an embarrassing piece of news to happen at this moment.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another reply said: “Let&#39;s not donate money [for relief] now because of this.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 07 Aug 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>