<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Colombian drug lord compared to Pablo Escobar sentenced to 45 years in US prison]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3230461/colombian-drug-lord-compared-pablo-escobar-sentenced-45-years-us-prison?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 11:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/09/e832cac1-39ea-45a8-b5ca-b98ab96fbec0_9643a919.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;承认美国贩毒指控的哥伦比亚一个著名犯罪集团的头目是周二，布鲁克林的一名法官判处他 45 年监禁，称他比已故大佬巴勃罗·埃斯科瓦尔“多产”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在对戴罗·安东尼奥·乌苏加·大卫（Dairo Antonio Usuga David）（更为人所知的名字是奥托尼尔）宣判时，美国地区法官多拉（Dora）伊里扎里 (Irizarry) 称他在领导戈尔福家族 (Clan del Golfo) 贩毒集团期间向美国运往美国的近 100,000 公斤可卡因“非同寻常”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她驳回了辩方的说法，即检察官将 51 岁的奥托尼尔 (Otoniel) 比喻为“夸张”，埃斯科瓦尔 (Escobar)，前麦德林贩毒集团头目，于 1993 年在美国和哥伦比亚的一次联合行动中被杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有很多毒贩比巴勃罗·埃斯科瓦尔 (Pablo Escobar) 更加多产，包括你的客户，”伊里扎里 (Irizarry) 告诉奥托尼尔的律师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布鲁克林美国检察官办公室请求判处 45 年徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥托尼尔于 10 月在这个南美国家与巴拿马边境附近被哥伦比亚武装部队逮捕2021 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡以贩毒罪处决一名男子，这是今年第五次绞刑&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他于 2022 年 5 月被引渡到美国，并于次年 1 月认罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在被判刑之前，奥托尼尔在法庭上向受害者以及美国和哥伦比亚政府道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哥伦比亚几十年来一直卷入左翼叛乱分子、右翼准军事组织、犯罪集团之间的冲突&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于哥伦比亚人民和年轻人，我建议他们并警告他们不要走我走过的路，”奥托尼尔通过西班牙语翻译说道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥托尼尔的律师要求判处不超过 25 年的监禁，理由是他愿意承担责任，而且他童年时被迫作为儿童兵参战，童年十分贫困。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是法官表示，“数十亿”人出生在类似的情况下，但没有成为贩毒集团头目。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方逮捕一名男子，在村屋查获1.1公斤强效可卡因&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; “我是在南布朗克斯的项目中长大的，”她说。 “我太清楚在那种环境中长大的感觉了，那里的人们日复一日地在街上互相开枪，人们在街上死去。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥托尼尔面临着强制性的惩罚最低刑期为 20 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Clan del Golfo 或 Gulf Clan 拥有 1,000 多名武装人员，主要是右翼准军事组织的前成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥托尼尔 (Otoniel) 成为其领导人曾担任左翼游击队员，后来成为准军事人员。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China universities waste millions, fail to make real use of research, audit finds in indictment of tech-sufficiency drive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3230413/china-universities-waste-millions-fail-make-real-use-research-audit-finds-indictment-tech?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/08/c8663b13-9c7f-4308-8d40-0b00dc2e8fae_71f91578.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国南方地区的大学在将学术研究转化为市场应用方面做得还不够，并维持大量闲置资金，调查结果可能会对国家雄心勃勃的科技自给自足计划提出质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据广西壮族自治区 2022 年的新审计报告，九所大学2020年至2022年，该地区的大学将发明推向市场的转化率极低，低于1%。其中，一所大学在实施的862个总资助额为1.31亿元的研究项目中，没有成功的产业化应用（ 1.43 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究结果凸显了中国在加强基础研究方面长期存在的薄弱环节，中国认为基础研究对于在本世纪中叶成为科技超级大国并摆脱束缚至关重要。美国的科技遏制措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“本质上，这反映了一个全国性的问题，”中国人民大学国家发展与战略研究院教授刘瑞明说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的不平等教育体系拖累经济，美国专家组听取了这份15000字的审计报告，两周前在广西审计署网站上短暂出现，随后被删除，但主要内容已在网上流传。审计结果似乎只反映了被提及的九所大学，尚不清楚是否会对其他大学进行审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大学教授的主要考核指标和激励措施往往基于基础理论研究，但这些他说，这些努力通常很难转化为实际应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“研究人员似乎正在进行基础理论研究，但他们常常产生大量无用的研究成果，这些成果主要集中在以论文为中心的评估上，“ 他说。 “这些成果既不纯粹有利于推进基础理论，也不直接转化为实际应用。因此，这是一种闲置、低效的研究状态。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;25位科学家和企业家联合发表文章表示，大学应改革过度以学术论文为依据的研究人才评价体系刘说，过度依赖论文和忽视实际成果是中国科技抱负的核心，并补充说，遵守此类标准的激励机制面临风险浙江省委周二在关于科研成果使用的微信帖子中表示，中国许多大学和研究机构在年度工作评估中优先考虑研究项目的数量&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，在缺乏系统性组织的情况下，研究人员往往各自为政，短期研究成果碎片化，这也增加了研究的难度。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京长期以来一直呼吁加强基础研究，实现科技的高度自力更生，让中国成为全球领先的科技力量。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;随着前景恶化，中国大学誓言打击虚假毕业生就业数据&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据国家统计局的数据，中国的研发总支出位居世界第二，是 2012 年的三倍。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;中国还加大了对科技成果转化为盈利项目的投资，国家资金目标是到 2022 年底达到 624 亿元人民币（87 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，根据广西的审计报告，四所大学总共有 6682 万元人民币（930 万美元）长期闲置。此外，两所大学有22个科研项目的科研项目经费预算与实际需要不符。预算与实际支出差异高达69.24%，造成914万元人民币（130万美元）的闲置资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科技成果转化为实际应用可能是至关重要的刘教授表示，“这被认为至关重要，因为它代表了改革的新杠杆。”刘教授说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，中国现在缺乏刘认为，建立一个全国性和全球统一的科技成果交易市场，企业可以在其中获得这些成果，研究人员可以了解企业的​​需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有一些政策限制需要克服，例如对跨域交易的限制，这阻碍了全国统一市场的建设。” “这是中国当前形势下的一个重大制约因素。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浙江省有关部门微信发文称，提高科研成果转化率并不意味着将其作为中国科技发展的唯一方向。中国的研究机构不应走向另一个极端，而应建立更加多元化、合理的研究评价体系。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Claims of topless ‘body checks’ at Miss Universe Indonesia beauty pageant sparks police probe]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3230456/topless-body-checks-claim-miss-universe-indonesia-beauty-pageant-sparks-police-probe?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 11:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/09/f30903df-4c53-4a6a-b5b2-e9367d7b6fbc_7d904efb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;超过六名参加印尼环球小姐选美比赛的女性向组织者举报在声称自己受到赤裸上身的“身体检查”后，向警方提出性骚扰指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该投诉是在 7 月 29 日至 8 月 3 日在首都雅加达举行的比赛中七名决赛选手被出乎意料的是，在选美加冕仪式前两天，他们被要求脱光衣服进行所谓的身体检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们说，组织者要求其中五人在一个有20多人的房间里脱光衣服进行身体检查，其中包括男人。他们的律师 Mellisa Anggraeni 表示，随后她们被拍到裸照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚环球小姐执照持有者 PT Capella Swastika Karya 的官员坚称，她们必须“检查她们身上的任何疤痕、橘皮组织或纹身”。安格莱尼周二表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“决赛入围者并不知道他们会接受这样的程序，因为最初计划是为了试衣，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;她说，选美比赛的所有 30 名决赛选手都受到了意外的身体检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在印度尼西亚，举报骚扰行为可能会让女性入狱&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;挺身而出投诉的参赛者数量她说，随着更多决赛选手赋予她举报事件的权力，这一数字可能会上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雅加达警方发言人 Trunoyudo Wisnu Andiko 周二告诉记者，参赛者已向警方提交了报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雅加达警方发言人 Trunoyudo Wisnu Andiko 告诉记者，参赛者已向警方提交了报告。 >;&lt;p>;他说，警方对该投诉展开了调查，并将该报告作为“我们进一步调查的基础”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚环球小姐国家总监 Poppy Capella 没有证实或否认这一事件。 Instagram 帖子中的指控，但对那些就该事件与我们分享“他们的观点、感受和观点”的人表示感谢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“您的评论不仅仅是言语：它们是一股强大的力量，”她写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环球小姐组织在周二的一份声明中表示，它已经了解了这些指控，并且正在调查此事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“环球小姐组织接受了以下指控：性虐待和不当行为极其严重。为女性提供一个安全的场所是环球小姐组织的首要任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;广播公司 Kompas TV 的画面显示，这些女性就这些指控举行了新闻发布会，她们在发言时隐藏了自己的身份。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中一名投诉人在新闻发布会上表示，她被要求摆出不恰当的姿势，包括张开双腿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我感觉自己被偷看，我感到非常困惑和不舒服， ”这名身份不明的女子说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度尼西亚作家揭露 1998 年骚乱中中国妇女被强奸的事实：“这是一个新低”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;世界上人口最多的印度尼西亚的宗教团体穆斯林国家过去曾反对选美比赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国名人媒体大亨和变性人权利倡导者 Jakapong“Anne”Jakrajutatip 去年以 2000 万美元收购了环球小姐组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在雅加达举行的比赛是为了选出印度尼西亚选手参加今年年底在萨尔瓦多举行的年度环球小姐比赛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该比赛由唐纳德共同拥有的环球小姐组织主办。特朗普于 1996 年至 2002 年间担任总统，自 1952 年以来一直在竞选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Amazon nations launch alliance to fight deforestation at summit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3230459/amazon-nations-launch-alliance-fight-deforestation-summit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 11:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/09/5829e9dd-81d2-4cab-815e-aac9b3f11add_9625ee2f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;八个南美国家同意成立联盟，誓言对抗亚马逊森林砍伐在巴西举行的峰会上，旨在阻止世界上最大的热带雨林达到“不归路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;受到密切关注的亚马逊合作条约组织 (ACTO) 峰会通过了东道国巴西所称的“新政策”。以及雄心勃勃的共同议程”来拯救雨林，这是应对气候变化的重要缓冲地带，专家警告说，雨林正被推向崩溃的边缘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该组织的成员 - 玻利维亚、巴西、哥伦比亚、厄瓜多尔、圭亚那、秘鲁、苏里南和委内瑞拉——在亚马逊河口的贝伦签署了一份联合声明，制定了一份近万字的路线图，以促进可持续发展、结束森林砍伐并打击助长可持续发展的有组织犯罪。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;但峰会未能满足环保人士和原住民团体最大胆的要求，包括要求所有成员国采纳巴西关于到 2030 年结束非法森林砍伐的承诺以及哥伦比亚关于停止新石油勘探的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是巴西气候观测站联盟负责人马西奥·阿斯特里尼 (Marcio Astrini) 表示：“这是第一步，但没有具体决定，只是一系列承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“地球正在融化，气温记录正在下降。每天都在被破坏……八位亚马逊领导人不可能不以粗体字母声明森林砍伐必须为零，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在卢拉的第一个任期内，巴西亚马逊森林砍伐量下降了 34% 6个月&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦在周二为期两天的峰会开幕致辞中强调，“气候危机的严重恶化”需要“一致行动”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这从未如此紧迫”，就在欧盟气候观测站确认 7 月是有记录以来最热的月份几个小时后，他在讲话中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哥伦比亚总统古斯塔沃·佩特罗同时呼吁采取大规模行动取消发展中国家债务以换取保护气候行动的计划，将该想法与二战后的“马歇尔计划”联系起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们正处于灭绝的边缘，而这个计划是必须做出重大决定的十年……那么，除了发表演讲之外，我们还在做什么？”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了向聚集在一起的国家元首施压，数百名环保人士、活动人士和原住民示威者游行到贝伦的会议地点，敦促采取大胆行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是第一次八国集团 14 年来举行的峰会，由共享亚马逊盆地的南美国家于 1995 年成立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这里拥有估计地球生物多样性的 10%、5000 万人和数百名居民。亚马逊雨林拥有数十亿棵树，是一个重要的碳汇，可以减少全球变暖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但科学家警告说，热带雨林的破坏正在将其推向危险的临界点，超过这个临界点，树木就会死亡并释放&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地区领导人在某些问题上似乎存在分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哥伦比亚石油公司正在敦促其他国家遵守他禁止所有新能源的承诺。石油勘探——对于包括巴西在内的一些成员国来说，这是一个敏感话题，其国有石油公司正在寻求在亚马逊河口勘探新的海上区块，这一争议颇具争议。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;亚马逊河和尼罗河哪个更长？新的探索旨在解决旧的争论&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“实现零森林砍伐甚至不足以吸收我们所有的碳排放，”佩特罗说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“解决方案是停止燃烧煤炭，石油和天然气。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次峰会可以说是贝伦将主办的 2025 年联合国气候谈判的彩排。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢拉、佩特罗、玻利维亚总统路易斯·阿尔塞和秘鲁总统迪娜博卢阿特均出席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;委内瑞拉总统尼古拉斯·马杜罗因耳部感染缺席，派副总统德尔西·罗德里格斯出席，厄瓜多尔、圭亚那和苏里南则派高级官员出席。&lt;/p>;&lt;阿尔塞敦促富裕国家为保护亚马逊地区提供资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“气候危机及其后果的所有责任不应落在我们和我们经济的肩上。我们不是制造这场危机的人。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次峰会对资深左翼卢拉来说是一次关键考验，卢拉曾于 2003 年至 2010 年担任总统，并于 1 月重返办公室，并发誓在其极右前任雅伊尔·博尔索纳罗领导下的四年大规模森林砍伐之后，巴西在应对气候变化的斗争中“回来了”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;土著群体——他们的土地是防止世界森林遭到破坏的重要缓冲区专家表示，敦促南美领导人采取果断行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的斗争不仅仅是为了土著人民，”厄瓜多尔土著联合会 CONFENIAE 主席 Nemo Guiquita 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“这是为了整个世界，以便子孙后代能够在这个星球上生存，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US Navy sailor Jinchao Wei’s mother encouraged him to pass military details to China, prosecutor says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230457/us-navy-sailor-jinchao-weis-mother-encouraged-him-pass-military-details-china-prosecutor-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 10:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/09/12aaefef-9788-4973-b0d9-ce1300f2ae24_e9bba3c2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名被控向中国提供敏感军事信息的美国海军水手的母亲鼓励他检方称，她与一名中国情报官员合作，告诉她的儿子这可能会帮助他有一天在中国政府找到一份工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国助理检察官 Fred Sheppard 在联邦法院的听证会上提出了这一指控。圣地亚哥敦促法官不要释放魏金超，魏金超上周因一项罕见的间谍罪名被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官没有在法庭上透露这名女子的名字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;魏金超就是其中之一。两名驻加利福尼亚水手被指控向中国提供敏感军事信息，包括战时演习、海军行动和关键技术材料的详细信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官尚未透露这两人是否受到同一个中国人的追求或支付报酬情报官员是一个更大计划的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;司法部根据《间谍法》对 22 岁的魏提出指控，该法规定收集或传递信息以援助外国政府属于犯罪行为。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;中国“间谍气球”出现在美国国会有关不明飞行物的听证会上&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;两名水手均不认罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官表示，出生在中国的魏是最先接触的2022 年 2 月，一名中国情报官员在他申请入籍美国公民时向该官员承认，他知道这种安排可能会影响他的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即便如此，检察官表示，他还是向该官员提供了信息有关埃塞克斯号和其他充当小型航空母舰的两栖攻击舰上的武器系统和飞机的详细信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在反对释放他的过程中，谢泼德周二告诉法庭，当魏回家过圣诞节时见到他住在威斯康星州的母亲，她知道儿子的安排。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还鼓励他继续帮助中国情报官员，因为这可能会让他在离开后有一天在中国共产党找到一份工作。谢泼德说，美国海军。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢泼德告诉法庭，情报官员告诉魏，他和中国政府愿意让他和他的母亲飞到中国亲自与他们会面，并且魏搜查了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢泼德说，该官员还让魏购买一台电脑和手机来传递信息，如果魏提供收据，中国政府将报销他的费用.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辩护律师杰森·孔福尔蒂 (Jason Conforti) 告诉法庭，魏对社区不构成危险，并且不再能够获取任何军事信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢泼德反驳说，魏的行为使数千名水手陷入困境。因泄露美国海军舰艇的敏感信息而面临风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官裁定将他拘留，不得保释。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;国家安全部长，中国需要“积极防御”间谍起诉书称，魏提供了多达 50 份手册，其中包含有关美国海军舰艇的技术和机械数据，以及有关即将举行的演习中海军陆战队人数和训练的详细信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢泼德说，魏在过去一年里从这项安排中赚取了10,000美元至15,000美元。如果罪名成立，他可能面临终身监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;司法部还指控驻扎在洛杉矶北部文图拉县海军基地的 26 岁海员赵文恒 (Wenheng Zhu) 合谋在美国境内收取近 15,000 美元。一名中国情报官员行贿，以换取 2021 年 8 月至至少今年 5 月期间涉及美国海军演习、行动和设施的信息、照片和视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些信息包括美国大规模军事演习的计划&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong scouts at world jamboree in South Korea disappointed event cut short by typhoon, as spirits high despite heat and poor conditions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3230449/hong-kong-scouts-world-jamboree-south-korea-disappointed-event-cut-short-typhoon-spirits-high?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/09/4a0f25d3-26bc-4b09-9c4c-cf2d7c656ddc_3c0875a4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;部分参加韩国世界狂欢节的香港星探表示失望尽管天气极其炎热，卫生条件也很差，但活动因即将来临的台风而被迫中断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些青少年是参加世界童子军大露营的 460 名来自该市的代表之一，说现场厕所堵塞，地板泥泞，帐篷内的温度堪比桑拿房。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我单位里几乎所有的侦察兵都不想离开。我们已经度过了最艰难的日子……我们怎么能不挺过营地的其余部分呢？ 15 岁的 Anson Ng 说：“我们香港人生来就是要接受挑战并保持决心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港童军总会宣布，该团体已搬至首尔的一个学习中心，并将于周三返回家中。周一，由于台风卡农即将来临，代表们将在 8 月 9 日或之前离开新万金露营地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一消息是在为期 12 天的活动组织者表示所有参与者都必须离开之前发布的。因为极端的天气。狂欢节原定持续到周六。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，由于气温过高，来自英国、美国和新加坡的队伍已于周末提前离开现场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该活动于 8 月 1 日开始，第一周，数百名青少年报告在酷暑中生病，许多人因发烧和皮疹在现场医院接受治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协会周二表示，八名香港代表身体不适，其中大多数患有轻微的中暑疾病。他们在现场设施接受治疗，并于当天出院。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;460名香港童子军在韩国举行的世界赛事中撤离台风卡农&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;预计水星将在空中盘旋未来几周该地区的气温约为 35 摄氏度（95 华氏度），营地几乎没有阴凉区域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng 表示，营地的安排一开始就“混乱”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“第一天，我们去场外活动看瀑布，结果被送到水上活动课程，巴士司机也不知道该怎么办，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一名代表表示：“大部分厕所要么堵塞，要么人们不冲水，厕所地面总是泥泞不堪。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴还指出，用餐时间推迟了大约两个小时，注意到他从早上 5 点一直排队到早上 7 点左右。他说，有些食物已经腐烂了，因为在炎热的天气里，尽管他发现自己的饭菜还过得去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管存在问题，学生还是认可了组织者所做的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“我深深感谢所有领导和国际服务团队所做的工作，我可以看到他们已经尽力了……只是天气和环境太恶劣了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位洪15 岁的 Kong 星探 Tim Leung 表示，他也对提前离开感到难过，但他认为疏散是必要的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我很遗憾无法参加闭幕式，因为将会有韩国流行音乐表演，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;组织者重新安排了周五在全州世界杯体育场举行的闭幕式。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国努力从残酷的热浪中拯救 40,000 名球探：“真正的混乱” &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;安生表示，香港星探的士气依然很高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然我们互不相识，但我们帮助了所有人，共用电风扇，帮助其他人设置睡觉的地方等等，”他说。 “这种精神，再加上我们做好了准备，让我们度过了一切。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;16岁的香港童子军Tate Yau表示，由于酷热，他有几次感到头晕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“天气真的很热，阳光明媚，尤其是上午 9 点到下午 6 点之间。我感觉就像在帐篷里洗桑拿一样，”他说。 “帐篷里没有风扇。但这周我们收到了一个手持风扇，我在睡觉时使用它。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丘说，大多数活动，包括一些场外活动都因天气原因而取消，他们被迫留下来在露营地与来自不同国家的其他同侪交换童子军徽章。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;童子军韩流演唱会推迟​​，但在受热浪袭击的狂欢会上表演仍在进行&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港民政及青年事务局协会敦促协会采取适当措施，确保所有会员特别是青少年的安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;协会发言人表示，狂欢节主办方取消了部分户外活动，提供充足的水、电解质补充，安排了更多的空气流通。调节地点和公共汽车，并部署更多医务人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国总统尹锡烈早些时候在出现厕所脏乱、食物不足和缺乏服务的报道后要求“立即改善”条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国总统尹锡烈早些时候要求“立即改善”条件。 >;&lt;p>;这次盛会最初接待了来自 158 个国家的 43,000 名童子军，其中大部分年龄在 14 至 17 岁之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;组织者周二晚表示，近 40,000 名参与者已安全离开营地并转移到首尔的多个地点.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Sorry America. Asia wants better wages and won’t be your low-paid workshop for much longer]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/article/3230448/sorry-america-asia-wants-better-wages-and-wont-be-your-low-paid-workshop-much-longer?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 10:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/09/c2cced1c-b709-48c4-9d57-ec188c90e908_c68dde00.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;趁芭比娃娃相对便宜的时候囤积它们。未来几年价格可能会飙升，这不仅仅是因为新大片的炒作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国人已经习惯挥霍的各种产品也是如此，包括衣服、据《华尔街日报》报道，电视、家具和玩具。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是因为亚洲各地传统上生产这些产品的工厂正在努力寻找工人。作为回应，许多制造商正在提高工资并提供其他福利，包括瑜伽课程、更好的自助餐厅食物以及为工人子女提供幼儿园补贴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然这对亚洲工人来说是个好消息，但也可能是个坏消息对于美国消费者来说，当工厂提高价格以抵消不断上涨的劳动力成本时。廉价商品的时代可能即将结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于习惯于在可支配收入中拥有一定且相对稳定部分的商品的美国消费者来说，我认为该基金会将会有伦敦经济学家马诺吉·普拉丹 (Manoj Pradhan) 告诉《华尔街日报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去的二十年里，中国等亚洲国家更便宜的海外制造成本压低了各种商品的价格。但工厂工作并不像以前那么便宜。在中国，制造业工人的工资在过去十年中增加了两倍多，越南、马来西亚和日本的工厂工人的工资也出现了显着上涨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对价格的涓滴效应已经显现开始了。芭比娃娃制造商美泰 (Mattel)、玩具制造商孩之宝 (Hasbro) 和耐克 (Nike) 等公司在亚洲面临劳动力成本上升的问题，从而导致价格上涨。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于美国生活成本上升，越南鞋业制造商耐克 (Nike)、阿迪达斯 (Adidas) 裁员 6,000 人危机&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;专家将亚洲工厂劳动力短缺归因于多种因素。首先是年轻工人，他们中的许多人不太愿意在该行业工作。一些人对工作条件提出了要求，而另一些人则坚持寻找更符合其教育水平的高薪工作。尽管许多工厂都需要工人，但上季度中国16-24岁工人的失业率创下了创纪录的21%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过了一段时间，这项工作就会让你的头脑变得麻木。我无法忍受重复，”前中国工厂工人朱利安·朱 (Julian Zhu) 11 月告诉美国之音新闻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2001 年，耐克典型的亚洲工厂工人年龄为 22 岁。如今，该公司中国和越南员工的平均年龄分别为40岁和31岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;面对这种不断变化的制造环境，美国企业要么选择在亚洲坚持下去，要么将部分制造业务转移到美国或墨西哥等其他国家。除了国家安全和人权问题之外，新冠疫情的供应链问题已经导致许多企业近年来将部分生产线从中国转移。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然搬到美国有一定的优势，例如创造美国就业机会并提高供应链弹性，但不太可能使购物者免受成本上涨的影响。这是因为，由于劳动力成本和其他因素，在美国制造商品的成本通常比在亚洲更高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些公司，如芭比娃娃的美泰公司，看到了“近岸外包”——将供应链转移到美国与美国更接近的国家——这是最好的路径。 2019 年，该公司关闭了两家亚洲工厂，并斥资 5000 万美元扩建了墨西哥的一家现有工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“友好外包”如何帮助美国将供应链从中国转移出去&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;“如果考虑到成本，能够让产品靠近消费者，而不必从亚洲运输，利润会更高，竞争力也更强，”美泰拉丁美洲董事总经理加布里埃尔·加尔万 (Gabriel Galvan) 去年告诉路透社.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然墨西哥可能提供比美国更便宜的劳动力和比亚洲更低的运输成本，但这是否足以控制价格还有待观察。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这可能是最好的现在就买那个芭比娃娃吧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文首发于&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange “ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia state polls: DAP’s Anthony Loke says it’s a battle for stability, as campaigning hits final stretch]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3230377/malaysia-state-polls-daps-anthony-loke-says-its-battle-stability-campaigning-hits-final-stretch?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/08/5fe45e9f-5605-4945-aafa-8872f8777e30_7048946a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;When the chief of Malaysia&#39;s Democratic Action Party (DAP) addressed a campaign stop in the Malay-majority seat of Batang Kali in Selangor on Monday, his message was clear – a vote for Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim&#39;s unity government in no way diminishes the political power of the country&#39;s largest ethnic group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking before a small crowd of Malay armed-forces veterans and locals, Anthony Loke – the secretary general of the Chinese-led DAP – said it would be unreasonable for the six non-Malay ministers in Anwar&#39;s 28-member cabinet to have an outsize say on public policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are five Chinese ministers and one Indian minister, and cabinet decisions are made on consensus.这如何削弱马来人的政治权力？”洛克说。 “The prime minister is Malay, a deputy prime minister is Malay, the home minister is Malay … there is no way that Malay political power will be eroded.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Malaysia&#39;s Selangor polls could drive referendum on Anwar&#39;s unity government&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The opposition Perikatan Nasional (PN) alliance has pushed Malay political power as a key campaign issue ahead of Saturday&#39;s polls in six states, which come nine months after a November general election where the Islamist PAS&#39; “green wave” swept up heartland Malay votes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 9.7 million people are registered to vote in 245 constituencies this weekend in the PN-held states of Kedah, Kelantan and Terengganu in the north of the Malaysian peninsula, as well as in the pro-federal government states of Negeri Sembilan and the two richest states in the country, Selangor and Penang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The outcome of the state polls will have little bearing on federal power, but PN leaders have positioned it as a referendum on Anwar&#39;s administration and its alleged failure to address persistent cost-of-living issues in the wake of the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Loke, who is transport minister, said it was “misleading” for the opposition to claim that the state polls were a referendum on the federal government when they were in fact a limited measure of the performance of the six state governments over the last five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that there was no basis behind claims that giving the DAP a share of federal power would chip away at the interest of the Malays – who account for more than 60 per cent of Malaysia&#39;s 33 million population – especially when it was also a key argument employed in the past by rivals-turned-partners Umno.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have been addressing this issue for a long time.按理来说，马来人在政治权力方面并没有失去任何东西。 It&#39;s just different parties and personalities [assuming power],” Loke told This Week in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is a work in progress.短期内我们看不到。 At the respective ministries where we have DAP leaders, we try to bring a more moderate image for DAP.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are seeing more positive comments on social media, and it looks like we have a higher acceptance level among the Malays,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Loke admitted the threat remains of the “green wave” – so-called to reflect the party colour of the Islamist PAS, a key member of PN that benefited from a shift in Malay votes in November&#39;s general election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PN leaders have claimed they would come within striking distance of taking federal power if they register a strong performance in the state polls, including wresting power from PH in Selangor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Loke said the federal government would remain intact regardless of the outcome of the state polls, but stressed that a bad result for Anwar&#39;s administration would lead to a prolonged period of political instability.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Who is PAS, the single biggest party in Malaysia&#39;s new parliament?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“If there is a change of the [federal] government in a big way, it would be very bad for the economy and the nation. Everyone in the unity government is committed to ensure that this does not happen again,” he said, referring to 2020&#39;s political coup.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To me, maintaining the three states is the minimum target we need to achieve. Anything above that is a bonus and will only strengthen the unity government,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the results are not good for us, it will only empower the destabilising forces to keep going all year round.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Anwar rose to power in November after the king granted him the top job on condition that he form an administration that included friends and foes, to cool temperatures after a racially-charged national election that saw a distinct shift in Malay votes in favour of former leader Muhyiddin Yassin&#39;s PN coalition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The arrangement gave a way back into government for former ruling party Umno, which were left with just 28 of parliament&#39;s 222 seats as their traditional Malay support base abandoned them for PN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Umno had led the country for six decades, spanning Malaysia&#39;s independence from Britain in 1957 to the party being unceremoniously booted out in 2018 in the wake of widespread anger at allegations of rampant corruption, including the multibillion-dollar 1Malaysia Development Berhad scandal linked to disgraced former leader Najib Razak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Najib was jailed in August last year after failing to overturn a conviction for corruption and abuse of power involving 42 million ringgit (US$9.2 million) linked to a former unit of 1MDB. He and his supporters deny any wrongdoing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PH campaigners, including from key coalition member DAP, have said that the partnership with Umno has made for a difficult proposition for supporters from both sides, in light of decades of political enmity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Loke, however, believes that the state polls have helped bring grass-roots members from both sides closer as they worked together to ensure that candidates under their perpaduan (unity) campaign do well.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Any adjustment takes time … but the state elections have helped bring together our [election] machineries,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our grass-roots members are voters as well. If they are not convinced of this unity government, how are we to expect non-members to vote for us?”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong politician Starry Lee to quit as leader of city’s largest party after 8 years, citing workload concerns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3230447/hong-kong-politician-starry-lee-quit-leader-citys-largest-party-after-8-years-citing-workload?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/09/f05cfa64-5fc3-49fe-b0ca-e114c4eb8260_ee8f6f1d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The chairwoman of Hong Kong&#39;s largest political party has announced that she is stepping down, citing concerns about workload.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawmaker Starry Lee Wai-king, who has led the pro-Beijing Democratic Alliance for the Betterment and Progress of Hong Kong (DAB) for eight years, revealed her decision in a Facebook post on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With limited time and limited work capability, I am starting to realise that it may not be conducive to the development of the party [if I continue],” Lee, 49, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After careful consideration, I have decided not to run for election as DAB chairman.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am pleased to see that there is much talent in the party and I am certain that the future chairman will be more successful.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Starry Lee becomes sole Hong Kong member of nation&#39;s top legislative body&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lee succeeded party veteran Tam Yiu-chung as the city&#39;s sole delegate to the National People&#39;s Congress (NPC) Standing Committee, China&#39;s top legislative body, in March, becoming the youngest Hong Kong member yet in the role. Since then, all eyes were on whether she would step down from the party leadership.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The party was expected to decide on a new leadership line-up in September.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Political affairs observer Professor Lau Siu-kai said: “Lee probably would not like to give the public impression that her work and policies at the DAB could be influenced by her role as a NPC standing committee member.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With more than 51,000 members, the DAB is arguably the biggest political party in Hong Kong. It has 19 seats in the Legislative Council and 21 district councillors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Including Lee, the party has seven members on the NPC. Nine DAB members are also delegates to the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference (CPPCC), the country&#39;s top political advisory body.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Changing of the guard as 21 new members elected to Hong Kong&#39;s NPC delegation&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lee said she would like to spend more time on work related to the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In her Facebook message, she said: “In the coming days, I shall certainly make more efforts to work for the country and Hong Kong, and serve countrymen and Hong Kong people.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Legco, Lee represents the Kowloon Central constituency. She is also a Kowloon City district councillor but earlier indicated that she would not seek another term having served on the council for about 20 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DAB vice-chairman Gary Chan Hak-kan, who also sits on the government&#39;s key decision-making Executive Council, is widely tipped to succeed Lee as party chief.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An accountant by profession, Lee became the DAB&#39;s first female leader in 2015, succeeding Tam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She grew up in a low-income family in Choi Hung and started her political career at the age of 25. Lee first stood for election in 1999 as an independent, winning a seat on the Kowloon City district council and becoming the youngest female councillor. She was re-elected in 2003.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The following year, she was among a group recruited by DAB veteran Jasper Tsang Yok-sing as the party pushed to broaden its reach to the middle class and professionals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee then contested a Legco election for the first time in 2004 but was unsuccessful. She tried again in 2008 and won a seat in the Kowloon West constituency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the time, she often used her communication skills to raise her profile. As many DAB lawmakers&#39; command of English was weak, Lee would often speak on the party&#39;s behalf when responding to questions from the English-language media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing appointed her as a CPPCC delegate in 2018 and she was elected as a Hong Kong deputy to the NPC in 2022.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China inflation: consumer prices fall for first time since 2021 amid ‘low inflation trap’ warning]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3230450/china-inflation-consumer-prices-fall-first-time-2021-amid-low-inflation-trap-warning?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 09:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/09/e29482e9-a032-43fd-bcc2-d9c1bec66d9b_fec3a579.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s consumer prices fell for the first time since early 2021, as experts warned against the risk of a “low inflation trap” to weigh on the already underpowered economic recovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The consumer price index (CPI) fell by 0.3 per cent in July from a year earlier, following a flat reading in June, the National Bureau of Statistics said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This was slightly higher than the expected drop of 0.5 per cent by Wind, a Chinese financial data provider. China last reported a drop of its CPI by 0.2 per cent in February 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The low reading highlighted incessant concerns about deflation as persistent sluggish domestic demand has dragged down China&#39;s economic recovery, with private companies reluctant to invest and expand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the producer price index (PPI), which reflects the prices that factories charge wholesalers for products, fell by 4.4 per cent in July, year on year, narrowing from the fall of 5.4 per cent in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This was in line with expectations by Wind.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The China Finance 40 (CF40) Forum, a leading economic think-tank, warned against the vicious circle between slow economic growth and low inflation and said China should avoid stepping into the “low inflation traps”, which might erode company profits and inflate their actual debt levels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Managing low inflation could be more difficult than managing high inflation, full attention should be paid to potential risks resulting from a low inflation environment,” the CF40 Forum said in a report last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities have conceded previously that the CPI was likely to drop in July, as a result from last year&#39;s high base, when the inflation pressures were at a two-year high.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A rebound is expected to start in August, bringing CPI up to close to 1 per cent at the end of the year, it is still far from the “around 3 per cent” official CPI target set for 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts have argued that reforms and more policy support are necessary to turn the economic situation around, including an increase in public spending, interest rate and tax cuts, as well as a more well-rounded social security net to promote consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More to follow …&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 09:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Ugly but comfortable’: Barbie movie kicks off China craze for practical footwear  as many switch to sensible shoes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3230241/ugly-comfortable-barbie-movie-kicks-china-craze-practical-footwear-many-switch-sensible-shoes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.09 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/08/d617040e-7ed4-40c5-85fe-a01cc2eb76ac_52da523e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The film has boosted the profile of Birkenstock shoes in China after the titular character&#39;s shoe choices inspired women to ditch heels in a trend dubbed “ugly but comfy”, according to mainland reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Released globally on July 21, Barbie has reignited discussion about feminism and gender equality after its massive success, earning US$1 billion at the global box office, including 200 million yuan (US$28 million) in China, where women have comprised almost 80 per cent of viewers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, it has been Barbie&#39;s footwear choices that have had the most noticeable impact in China, reported mainland news site Huxiu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In one scene, Barbie chooses a pair of plain-looking but far more comfortable Birkenstock rather than a stereotypical pair of high heels when she decides to go out into the real world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, in the film&#39;s final scene, Barbie is shown wearing a pair of pink Birkenstock sandals during a visit to a gynaecologist.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This has led to a rise in sales of the German brand of footwear, with many women saying they were inspired to buy them after watching the movie.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Are Birkenstock shoes ugly?它们舒适、多功能且易于穿着。 Only those who have worn them know,” said one Barbie filmgoer online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One commenter pointed out the discomfort many experience after wearing high heels: “Please give me a pair of Birkenstock shoes. After wearing high heels for a whole afternoon, my toes swelled up like mosquito bites, and that&#39;s when I had this realisation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A third person said that shoe fashion was constantly evolving: “Fashion and rustic styles keep alternating. Wearing perforated shoes with long socks is surprisingly popular this year.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past, shows like Sex and the City have promoted high heels as the go-to shoe for women by promoting luxury brands like Jimmy Choo, Manolo Blahnik and Christian Dior.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the release of Barbie in China has marked a turning point in consumer footwear choices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Birkenstock&#39;s official online Taobao store in China, the pink pair of Birkenstock sandals worn by Barbie and several other styles, including the more expensive ones, which can cost up to 1,300 yuan (US$180), are in short supply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taobao is owned by Alibaba which is the parent company of the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “ugly but comfy” trend has also helped another brand known for comfort, if not aesthetics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There has been a noticeable rise in the number of people seen in public wearing Crocs, the famously unfashionable brand of perforated foam sandals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There has also been a surge in popularity for “shoe accessories” or “shoe flowers,” with sales on Chinese social media platforms rising significantly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mainland social media platform Xiaohongshu has more than 40,000 posts related to “shoe flowers,” where the tiny floral decorations have become a way for young girls to showcase their creativity and foster social interactions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without decorating, the perforated shoes are like roughcast houses. Only with shoe flowers can they be exquisitely furnished,” remarked one online observer on the platform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rise of the “ugly but comfy” shoe trend coincides with a growing global awareness of gender equality, as more women, especially from younger generations, reject high heels as an outdated form of patriarchal conditioning imposed on women.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 09 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>