<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Never a promise’: did Philippines ever agree to tow away grounded warship in South China Sea?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3231584/never-promise-did-philippines-ever-agree-tow-away-grounded-warship-south-china-sea?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/7237c60c-8c55-493f-9e6d-78fd1c2a7a2d_0cbea833.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;1999 年 11 月，即现在臭名昭著的菲律宾海军舰艇 BRP Sierra Madre 事件发生五个月后故意在有争议的南海仁爱礁搁浅，马尼拉又搁浅了另一艘海军舰艇 BRP Benguet，这次是在黄岩岛搁浅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;时任国防部长奥兰多·梅尔卡多 (Orlando Mercado) 告诉我们本周在亚洲，菲律宾时任海军中将路易斯托·费尔南德斯会见了他，并表示“任务完成”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅尔卡多表示，他随后命令费尔南德斯“再寻找两到三艘登陆舰”坦克”在中国与五个东南亚国家的领土和海洋争端的核心地带的其他浅滩上搁浅。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;一艘生锈的旧菲律宾军舰为何卷入南海争端？&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;从菲律宾的角度来看，这是其阻止中国“悄悄入侵”国际公约规定的马尼拉领海的一种方式。梅尔卡多说，费尔南德斯警告他，中国人没那么容易上当受骗。 “先生，中国人可能不相信我们，”梅尔卡多援引他的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1999 年马德雷山脉搁浅背后的情况在 8 月 5 日事件发生后的最近几周成为人们关注的焦点，当时中国的行动– 包括发射高压水枪 – 迫使为船上人员补给的两艘菲律宾船只中的一艘返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾和包括美国在内的几个西方国家谴责中国的行为是“危险的” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国则表示，其在距离最近的陆地海南岛 1,000 公里处作业的海岸警卫队是“专业且克制的”，并敦促菲律宾移走该船。报告称，马尼拉（称该浅滩为阿云金）数十年来多次违背了这样做的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前的争论焦点在于菲律宾是否确实在 1999 年及其后做出了承诺，在总统约瑟夫·埃斯特拉达 (Joseph Estrada) 的领导下，放弃了浅滩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前参议员、马尼拉第一位常驻东盟代表梅尔卡多 (Mercado) 以及爱德华多·玛丽亚·桑托斯 (Eduardo Maria Santos) 等其他人的观点和评论当 BRP 塞雷马德雷搁浅时，他是海军参谋长 - 已被仔细解析。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然 86 岁的埃斯特拉达尚未发表评论，但他的儿子、参议院国防委员会主席金戈伊本周发布了一份声明声明强调，梅尔卡多已确认“没有协议或承诺”移除该船。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们普遍认为，菲律宾确实故意搁浅这两艘船，作为其对第二托马斯号主权主张的一部分浅滩和黄岩岛均位于其专属经济区 (EEZ) 内。 BRP Benguet 在 1999 年 11 月搁浅后立即被拖走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;驻扎在二战时期摇摇欲坠的 BRP Sierra Madre 上的部队依靠补给任务来维护菲律宾的南中国海主权主张 - 这马尼拉表示，北京经常试图扰乱 - 为了在他们的远程驻地中生存。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾海岸警卫队担心，如果军事分遣队离开，中国将寻求占领仁爱礁。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;菲律宾参议院的背后是什么？两党支持更加强硬的对华政策？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;许多观察家担心南海争端是一个火药桶，任何误判或意外都可能引发军事冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从马尼拉的角度来看事实上，BRP Sierra Madre 驻有其唯一的军事分队，保卫着石油和天然气资源丰富的礼乐滩，免遭中国的进一步入侵。 “阿云金岛距中国占领的美济礁仅 22 海里，”退役海军参谋长桑托斯告诉《亚洲周刊》。 “晚上，你可以[从马德雷山脉]看到庞加尼班的灯光，”现在已军事化并戒备森严。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，中国大使馆副团长周志勇在马尼拉的一个论坛上表示：“这是已经24年了，菲律宾方面仍未兑现承诺。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，中国已要求现任总统小费迪南德·马科斯的政府“立即……拖走该船”，并进一步敦促马尼拉“周坚称，菲律宾政府早在1999年就同意撤走该船。“菲律宾方面也明确承诺这样做，”他说。 “这些陈述已被记录在案并有据可查。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，梅尔卡多向《亚洲周刊》断然否认任何此类协议的存在：“我们从未承诺过。没有这样的承诺。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管南海局势紧张，但菲律宾并未与北京处于“战备状态”&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;通过采访和对事件的审查据报道，《亚洲本周》能够拼凑出到底发生了什么，导致中国相信马尼拉承诺撤走这艘军舰，但也给了梅尔卡多否认曾经做出过这样的承诺的回旋余地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;对于梅尔卡多来说，问题不是食言，而是针锋相对的反应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他解释说，两艘船搁浅应该在中国突然扣押和扣押的背景下理解。 1995 年，菲德尔·拉莫斯 (Fidel Ramos) 担任总统期间，占领了庞加尼班礁 (Panganiban Reef)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅尔卡多表示，尽管存在外交抗议，中国也不会让步，并坚称其只是在庞加尼班礁 (Panganiban Reef) 上修建渔民小屋，以便在风暴期间避难，中国称其为“明治”角。 “但很快他们就用水泥结构加固了它。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Binobola naman tayo, e de bolahan tayo”，直言不讳的梅尔卡多说，大致可以翻译为：“因为他们在欺骗或欺骗玩我们，那就让我们互相玩吧”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须保护我们的利益。我们不能允许他们占领我们的地区，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅尔卡多说，他当时可能发表的任何誓言都应该在这种背景下考虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论是否他和其他官员做出的移除这些船只的承诺——无论是明确的还是其他的——仍存在争议。虽然梅尔卡多否认曾这样做，但他当时的言论表明了一定程度的文字游戏 — — 大概是为了让中国人陷入困境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，在 1999 年 11 月的新闻发布会上，梅尔卡多被引述说： “我们正在尽最大努力修复搁浅的两艘船。此举将符合我们在该地区[不会建造]新建筑的政策”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅尔卡多还表示，他向北京保证“已采取适当措施来评估船只受损程度[并且]将立即努力将船只从浅滩中解救出来”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时可能有梅尔卡多所属的埃斯特拉达政府的原因，暗示两艘船将立即被拖走。埃斯特拉达是当年东南亚国家联盟峰会的东道主，日本、韩国和中国的高级领导人（以时任总理朱镕基为代表）出席了此次峰会。拟议的南海行为准则是​​会谈的首要议题，而围绕船只的对峙可能会在会议上造成尴尬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谈判几乎没有取得任何进展。据当时的媒体报道，BRP Benguet 于 11 月 29 日，即峰会结束后的第二天被拖走。 BRP Sierra Madre 仍然留在原地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾大学法律中心海洋事务和海洋法研究所所长 Jay Batongbacal 表示，废弃的 BRP Sierra Madre 至今仍继续存在。仁爱礁“是为了主张和保护专属经济区和大陆架，这需要在中国声称拥有主权的海域中存在”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，1999 年，马尼拉搁浅是“唯一可行的手段”在缺乏其他方法所需的海上能力和资源的情况下，可以尝试监视和阻止对菲律宾水域的进一步入侵。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;立法者敦促菲律宾需要新的贸易协议以远离中国&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;前参议员安东尼奥·特里兰尼斯四世（当时是菲律宾海军中尉）表示，“据我所知，从未有过将 BRP Sierra Madre 号从阿云金撤走的命令”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;如果有的话，现任总统小马科斯上周表示他将废除该法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅尔卡多最近建议搁浅更多船只以监视浅滩。他还指出，由于 BRP Sierra Madre 仍然是一艘服役舰，“任何对其的攻击都会触发与美国的共同防御条约”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但特里兰尼斯对这一策略是否仍然有效表示怀疑，因为“2023 年的中国（比 1999 年）更具侵略性和敌对性。因此，任何此类举动都应被视为对中国类似侵略行为的回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href= “https://feedx.best” style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[11 West Africa nations commit to a military deployment to restore ousted president of Niger: ‘ready to go anytime’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3231627/11-west-africa-nations-commit-military-deployment-restore-ousted-president-niger-ready-go-anytime?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 09:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/19/5c5bb5e6-a482-461d-a9f5-517c09654e1d_ce2a6716.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;十一个西非国家已同意派遣部队进行军事部署，旨在恢复尼日尔的经济周五，该地区集团的一名官员在国防部长会议后表示，西非经共体集团是在上个月政变后民主选举产生的总统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西非经共体集团此前宣布，打算部署一支部队，以恢复总统穆罕默德·巴祖姆的职务。自 7 月 26 日被总统卫队成员推翻以来，他一直被软禁。但这个由 15 名成员组成的集团没有详细说明哪些国家将加入，也没有说明部队何时可能进入尼日尔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五西非经共体和平与安全事务专员阿卜杜勒-法托·穆萨赫 (Abdel-Fatau Musah) 表示，11 个国家已承诺部署。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只要下达命令，我们就准备出发，”穆萨赫在加纳首都表示，阿克拉，在在那里举行了两天的会议之后。 “我们的军队已准备好响应该地区的使命召唤。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这 11 个国家不包括尼日尔本身以及该集团其他三个政变后处于军事统治下的国家：几内亚、马里和布基纳法索法索。后两人警告说，他们将把对尼日尔的任何干预视为战争行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;穆萨表示，西非经共体尚未放弃与尼日尔政变领导人接触，他们已经无视恢复巴祖姆和不接受有关恢复其统治的谈判。穆萨表示，西非经共体代表团可能于周六访问尼日尔，试图与尼日尔军政府进行进一步对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们可以放弃军事选择；这不是我们的首选。但我们有义务这样做，因为该政权顽固不化，而且他们为谈判解决设置了障碍。”穆萨说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，巴祖姆的一名高级成员该政党在接受美联社采访时警告称，如果推翻巴祖姆的叛乱士兵成功，将威胁整个地区和非洲大陆的民主与安全，&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尼日尔正在发生的事情，如果成功，是非洲民主的终结。结束了。 ……如果我们今天战斗，就是为了防止此类事情发生，并确保我们大陆的未来，”萨博周四表示。萨博是巴祖姆领导的尼日尔民主与社会主义党副秘书长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一个政变频发的地区，尼日尔被视为西方国家最后可以合作击退日益壮大的圣战组织的民主国家之一。与基地组织和伊斯兰国组织有关的叛乱活动。近一个月前总统被推翻，对美国、法国和其他欧洲国家来说是一个沉重打击，这些国家已投入数亿美元的军事援助来训练尼日尔军队，并在法国进行军事训练。联合军事行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士和当地人表示，政变是由巴祖姆和总统卫队负责人阿卜杜拉赫马内·奇亚尼将军之间的内部斗争引发的，后者自称现在由他负责。从那时起，军政府一直在巩固民众的支持，利用对尼日尔前殖民统治者法国的不满，压制反对者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尼日尔政变和新军事领导人对西非稳定意味着什么？&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;萨博是少数仍在该国公开直言不讳地批评军政府而不是躲藏起来的人之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几位部长和高级政界人士被拘留，人权组织称他们他说，他们无法访问它们，而其他人则受到威胁。萨博称，首都对政权的支持浪潮具有欺骗性，因为军政府花钱请人集会支持其。他说，尼亚美也从来不是巴祖姆的据点，军政府一直在投机取巧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;支持军政府的集会几乎每天都会举行，数百甚至有时数千人在街道上游行，按喇叭，挥舞着尼日利亚人和俄罗斯人的手。旗帜高呼“打倒法国”。军政府已经断绝了与法国的军事协议，并向瓦格纳集团的俄罗斯雇佣兵寻求帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，尽管政党和民间社会组织对巴祖姆的政党确实感到沮丧，包括对其与法国的军事联盟存在分歧。萨赫勒专家表示，法国目前尚不清楚军政府在首都和全国各地有多少真正的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果军政府无法在经济上安抚当地民众，其在全国各地的支持基础可能会面临挑战。拜罗伊特大学博士后研究员亚当·桑德尔 (Adam Sandor) 表示，如果军队继续因不断增长的圣战暴力而遭受损失，那么圣战分子的袭击就会增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自政变以来，圣战分子的袭击不断增加，至少有 17 名士兵死亡，20 名士兵死亡本周早些时候，他在圣战分子的伏击中受伤。这是六个月来针对尼日尔军队的首次重大袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;武装分子正在利用法国和美国的支持缺口，两国都暂停了在该国的军事行动，以及尼日尔的军队冲突专家表示，安全部队的注意力集中在首都，担心该地区国家可能入侵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，在尼亚美和全国各地，预计周六将开展志愿者招募活动，人们可以在那里招募志愿者。登记参加战斗并帮助满足其他需求，以便军政府有一份名单，以备需要时向人们寻求帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尼日尔政变对中国在萨赫勒地区的存在意味着什么&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; “我们知道，我们的军队在数量上可能比[即将到来的]军队少，”组织者之一阿姆萨鲁·巴科(Amsarou Bako)说。 “那些即将到来的人，他们掌握了有关我们军队的信息，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首都居民正在努力应对政变造成的经济影响。严重的经济和旅行制裁不仅使人们难以获得资金和店主进口食品，危机还迫使数百名外国人离开，这对当地企业造成了影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我以前这里有各种各样的顾客，美国人、法国人、意大利人，”餐厅老板马穆杜·伊德里萨 (Mamoudou Idrissa) 说。但现在很多外国人都离开了，留下来的人也不敢出去，他说。 “现在只有尼日尔公民来这里吃饭。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong developers whipsawed by 16-year high inventories, lofty interest rates and China slowdown]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3231571/hong-kong-developers-whipsawed-16-year-high-inventories-lofty-interest-rates-and-china-slowdown?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/2542ee5b-9fe1-4d0f-975b-29ed864e55d7_9b09a7f4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;内地房地产危机加剧，香港开发商乌云密布当该市的建筑商已经在努力应对利率上升、经济放缓和新办公空间大量涌现的致命组合时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来住宅交易量的疲软已经浇灭了持续复苏的希望由于中国的重新开放未能产生预期的资金流入，资金流入已从疫情期间的低点回升。令该行业雪上加霜的是抵押贷款利率上升，与一年前相比至少贵了三分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港房地产公司短期内缺乏乐观情绪，盈利可能会下降让人失望。香港私募股权投资公司开元资本首席投资官布洛克·西尔弗斯(Brock Silvers)表示，内地经济低迷还远未结束，当局仍不愿接受房地产盈利模式已经改变的事实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港多年来，房地产业受益于美国的低利率和中国的强劲增长，但现在情况却发生了逆转。过去一年，香港商业银行将抵押贷款利率提高了近五分之一，而中国的经济困难导致大量研究机构降低了增长预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年第二季度，未售出的存量根据中原地产的数据，住宅单位数量增至 19,085 套，为 2003 年以来的最高水平，当时住宅单位数量达到 22,000 套。此后，随着香港金融管理局上个月宣布的最新一轮加息，抵押贷款利率进一步上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“较低的平均售价和较高的利率可能会侵蚀开发商的利润，并会影响开发商的利润。”对未来一到两年的预订产生持久影响，”美国投资银行 Jefferies 股票分析师 Sam Wong 告诉《华盛顿邮报》。在最近的一份报告中，他全面下调了香港开发商的盈利预期，理由是利润率、利息支出上升以及人民币贬值，这些因素都考虑到其中一些公司在内地的风险敞口相当大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人民币对于那些在中国风险敞口相对较大的香港房地产品牌来说，贬值可能会成为一个阻力。” “历史上新世界发展、长实集团、恒隆地产和香港置地在人民币贬值周期中往往表现较弱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，在宏观经济状况改善的背景下，需求回升得到满足Jefferies 表示，去年下半年积压的供应充足，有 12,000 套已获得预售批准但尚未推出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;库存过剩意味着平均价格追踪香港新建住宅物业的数据提供商 Dataelements 的数据显示，今年 6 月新房售价为每平方英尺 19,600 港元（2,508 美元），是自 2022 年 9 月每平方英尺 18,800 港元以来的最低水平。 6 月份的价格也比一年前低了 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年上半年的总体售出率（指已售出的房屋百分比）接近 80%杰富瑞 (Jefferies) 表示，但黄表示，尽管销量不错，但购房者的需求受到利率上升的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，香港商业银行今年第二次提高了最优惠利率，此前，香港金融管理局与美联储同步将香港基准利率上调了四分之一个百分点。中国银行（香港）、汇丰银行和恒生银行将最佳客户贷款利率上调12.5个基点至5.875%。一年前，最好的利率约为 5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在此期间，开发商可能会优先考虑去库存，而不是激进的定价，”杰富瑞 (Jefferies) 分析师 Wong 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港的库存根据物业服务公司 JLL 的数据，已竣工项目中的未售出单位数量达到 2007 年以来的最高水平，目前共有 83,000 套住房可供出售，预计 2023 年将有约 25,000 套住房投入市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;可以肯定的是，在开发商利用需求复苏的机会匆忙推出房产、寻求先发制人的过程中，库存卸载已经开始认真进行。本月早些时候，香港亿万富翁李嘉诚的旗舰开发商长实集团降价并售空其海岸线的全部626个标准单位后，Villa Garda III住宅项目的开发商纷纷涌向市场，以折扣价发布第一份价单。 II 九龙发展。价格比该地区的市场价格低约 16%，目前人们正在关注将于 8 月 20 日星期日开始出售的 Coast Line I 和 Villa Garda III 项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们预计兴趣会增加穆迪投资者服务公司在本周的一份报告中表示，利率和资本市场波动将限制未来几个季度的购房者情绪。 “我们预计这些情况将导致未来 6 至 12 个月内价格出现中高个位数下跌，很大程度上回吐 2023 年上半年积累的涨幅。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港住宅杰富瑞 (Jefferies) 分析师表示，鉴于利率正常化、供应恢复到更正常的水平以及人口流入支持住房需求，价格更有可能在 2024 年出现实质性复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但情况在改善之前可能会恶化。&lt;中原地产表示，第三季度新房销量将回落至3,000套左右，环比减少约500套。随着近期市场放缓，下半年新房销售将出现下滑。中原地产将2023年新屋销售预估下调至13,000套，较上季预估减少2,000套。 2023年一手案件数量将是近10年来第二低水平，仅次于2013年的9,753起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年第二季度新屋销售数量为2,753套，下降据美联物业统计，较第一季的3,468套减少约20.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于大型豪宅新屋销售放缓，新屋销售价值暴跌26.2%至293.6亿港元美联地产称，第二季度将出现这种情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“短期内利率将继续困扰投资市场，”美联地产香港和澳门住宅部门首席执行官 Sammy Po 表示。 “房价已显示出疲软的迹象。由于加息周期何时结束尚难以确定，第三季度香港楼市将继续承压。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;开发商积极进取，新房对购房者更具吸引力定价策略。 Po 预计第三季度新屋销售量将仅环比增长 2%，达到 2,800 套。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲地产控股有限公司董事长 Raymond Tsoi 拥有 38 年房地产行业经验，现任 Hong Kong 总裁拥有 3,000 多名会员的香港专业房地产顾问商会认为，情况正在缓慢恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“房价将继续下降，”Tsoi 告诉《华盛顿邮报》。 “不会是急剧暴跌，而是逐渐下降。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsoi预计下半年下降5%至7%，全年下降2%至3% ，随后明年将下跌 10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市场预测未来几年私人住宅市场将充斥着新的供应，这也印证了悲观的前景。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;根据彭博资讯 (Bloomberg Intelligence) 引用的团结香港基金会的预测，今年和 2024 年平均将有约 20,200 个私人住宅单位竣工，到 2025 年将增至 20,900 个单位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中原地产表示，与上半年售出的6,310套相比，开发商的表现不佳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“开发商为了利益，会以低价销售来抢夺和竞争。”许多开发项目都需要启动，”蔡说。 “开发商必须推出。否则他们就没有结果。如果市场疲软，他们是否必须降价？几家卖得好的大开发商不得不通过回扣、高贷贷比、高佣金和低价来[刺激销售]。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内地开发商开发的鸭脷洲滨海路根据截至 7 月底的交易登记册显示，合景泰富集团控股公司和龙光集团自 1 月份首次投标以来，仅售出了 295 套公寓中的 3 套。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前的交易量为创历史新低，”蔡说。 “亏损交易也不少。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上半年，全市亏损住宅交易1,964笔，占总数的14.6%，创降温以来最高水平据利嘉阁地产称，这些措施于 2010 年下半年推出。地产代理机构将其归咎于去年房价下跌15%和移民潮。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中原地产称，7月份房产交易总数创八个月新低，为4,426套。对于那些急于出售的人来说，损失不断增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsoi 还指出，土地价格暴跌是市场情绪疲软的一个迹象。政府于 7 月初进行的本财政年度首次土地招标，取得了自 2002 年 6 月以来港岛区最低价格，比 11 月份上一次招标的价格低了 25% 以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时经济低迷提供了整理资产负债表的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港房地产公司应通过减少债务、提高效率和专注于国内市场来渡过难关。一旦中国开始重组境内房地产行业，或许香港终于能看到几缕阳光。”西尔弗斯说道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A Hong Kong relaunch must create space for youth art and culture]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231250/hong-kong-relaunch-must-create-space-youth-art-and-culture?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/7cbe34d5-10dd-43dd-8ab5-ba21ea8db5a8_4e2594b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;作为一座综合中国文化遗产、英国历史影响以及与华人侨民的联系的城市香港位于东南亚，对国际友人和来自四面八方的旅客基本开放，拥有 750 万人以千种声音说话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我们寻求踏上新方向时，在过去几年的困难时期，艺术和文化在确定这次重新启动的基调方面发挥着至关重要的作用，我们需要做大量的工作来促进这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;幸运的是，香港长期以来一直以其当地的创意艺术和文化多元化而闻名。插画家 Don Mak 升华了屯门和元朗等拥挤街区的喧嚣。我们拥有摄影师梁威廉 (William Leung) 拍摄的住宅区图像的几何精度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后是香港灵魂令人惊叹的当代表演艺术，它在爱丁堡边缘艺术节上演了三个节目，以及宽阔、生动的壁画香港岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城市超现代性覆盖着香港街道原有的工业风貌，是创意艺术的有机加速器。这座城市不断壮大的创意人才群体借鉴了新旧亚洲和西方传统的健康组合以及各个演变阶段的有机趋势，通常使用我们的后工业城市景观作为画布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当谈到香港年轻人的艺术时，我们必须鼓励和帮助更多的人在任何媒介的创意表达中找到满足感。特别是，我们应该通过露天展览、街头节日和精选的工作室空间，为年轻人提供不受约束的平台，而不是消除使艺术如此自发地强大的不和谐音。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们为什么要这样做？最明显的原因是，年轻的创意表达是香港重新吸引未来人才和领导者的最有力手段之一，将个人和创意的实现放在首位。这也是振兴我们城市美学的最佳方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在设计复杂的城市更新方案上投入了大量的精力和资金。与真正对社区充满热情的年轻人互动可以找到更有效的解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鼓励崭露头角的艺术家与过去进行斗争，同时展望未来，这正是街道所要解决的问题。艺术可以为城市更新做贡献。新街、拉斯卡阁和艺术巷只是艺术家留下印记的几个地点，为香港成为适合步行的城市的愿景增添了艺术色彩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;变革性的亚文化，例如污垢在英国的嘻哈音乐和美国的嘻哈音乐在贫穷的工人阶级社区（东伦敦和纽约的布朗克斯）出现，作为一种青年表达形式。&lt;​​/p>;&lt;p>;在香港，波西米亚风格深水埗大南街的咖啡馆和屯门充满活力的 HANDS 篮球场使社区焕发活力并改善人流量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在社区共同创造青年友好文化也具有声誉层面的意义。当今最伟大的城市是那些能够利用年轻人主导的创意表达生态系统的城市——比如北京、伦敦、纽约或东京。在马德里，楚埃卡 (Chueca) 社区因庆祝多元化性取向和性别认同而闻名，帮助这座城市吸引了 LGBTQ 旅行者和进步人才。香港刺激的街头文化也可以发挥类似的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港变装团体保持原始状态——忘记鲁保罗的变装比赛&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;街头文化不仅仅是街头艺术；它也是一种艺术。它还包括借鉴城市景观的摄影、写作和音乐，以及对此类创作中所蕴含的价值观的庆祝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论是壁画的细微差别，每个人都能从中找到一些东西painted by those who integrate nature into their repertoire, the unapologetically confrontational graffiti that interrogates everyday assumptions, or the photographs of densely packed housing blocks, such as the buildings on King&#39;s Road in Quarry Bay that found their way into Hollywood blockbusters Transformers: Age of Extinction and Ghost in the Shell.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Street art is an important conduit for teenagers and young adults to play a positive role in civic life and have a constructive dialogue with their peers and beyond. From the queer art challenging rigid norms on sexual orientation and gender identity to graffiti skewering the inequalities justified by a neoliberal logic, such as Banksy&#39;s work, there is much wisdom to be found in the radical, avant-garde displays on the street.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For far too long there has been a disconnect, between the youth and the elderly, between the bulk of Hong Kong&#39;s population and its elite. While supporting, appreciating and offering a platform for cathartic street art creation will not fix the problem altogether, it would at least contribute to its resolution.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Much as the future belongs to the youth, this city belongs to all of us. And it&#39;s our collective responsibility to make it more liveable, appealing and accommodating for all.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall to fill 2,000 new job openings for fresh graduates as Chinese Big Tech firms seek new growth]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3231590/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-fill-2000-new-job-openings-fresh-graduates-chinese-big-tech-firms-seek-new?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/52a880ab-9929-476d-bcc2-6cd1c9ae626e_87ad81d4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Alibaba Group Holding&#39;s domestic e-commerce unit Taobao and Tmall is hiring for more than 2,000 entry-level positions, in a new sign that Big Tech firms in China are gearing up for growth after years of downsizing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unit, one of six major business groups under Alibaba, is looking for fresh graduates to fill roles ranging from engineering to algorithms and data in places including its hometown Hangzhou, as well as Beijing, Shanghai, Nanjing and Guangzhou, the company said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The recruitment effort forms part of an overall plan by Alibaba, owner of the South China Morning Post, to add 15,000 employees – including 3,000 fresh graduates – across the company this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tech giant&#39;s return to active hiring follows noticeable cuts in its payroll. Alibaba had 228,675 employees as of the end of June, down 6,541 from the end of March, according to its latest earnings report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Social media and video gaming giant Tencent Holdings, which announced on Thursday it would be offering a large number of openings at home and abroad, covering artificial intelligence, cloud computing, robotics and industrial internet, had also been slashing jobs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shenzhen-based firm had 104,500 employees at the end of June, a decline of 6,200 from a year ago, its financial statements showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s youth unemployment hit a new high in June, raising pressure for authorities to boost hiring of young people. The National Bureau of Statistics, which was expected to publish July figures on Tuesday, suspended the release of youth unemployment data, sparking public concerns that the situation could be worsening.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese tech giants, which had been under intense regulatory scrutiny over the past few years as Beijing moved to curb the “irrational expansion of capital” and pursue “common prosperity”, now plays an important role in absorbing some of the estimated 11.5 million university graduates who left school this summer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government&#39;s crackdown on the internet industry had seen trillions of dollars wiped off company valuations and thousands of jobs eliminated. But as economic headwinds mounted, Beijing&#39;s attitude took a big turn in late 2022, as it began to highlight the positive value that internet platforms can bring to the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The National Development and Reform Commission, China&#39;s top economic planning agency, in July praised internet companies for “advancing high-level scientific and technological self-reliance efforts” and “contributing to the promotion of high-quality development”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That high-profile endorsement was followed by a friendly meeting between Chinese Premier Li Qiang and representatives from major tech companies, including Alibaba Cloud founder Wang Jian and Xiaohongshu founder Qu Fang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With Beijing easing its control over Big Tech, several other tech firms have also expanded recruitment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Late last month, on-demand local services giant Meituan, which runs the country&#39;s leading food delivery platform, announced 6,000 new positions that were open to fresh graduates – up from 5,000 similar vacancies last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kuaishou Technology, operator of China&#39;s No 2 short-video app, unveiled more than 200 new job openings that month.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japanese wear clothes with built-in fans to beat the heat as temperatures soar to record high]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3231597/japanese-wear-clothes-built-fans-beat-heat-temperatures-soar-record-high?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/f20e4630-e273-4d39-b05e-b2241ac3fa06_42e29dd2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Selling jackets with built-in fans, neck coolers and T-shirts that feel cold, Japanese firms are tapping into a growing market for products to help people handle the summer heat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan – like other countries – is seeing ever-hotter summers. This July was the warmest in 100 years, with at least 53 people dying of heatstroke and almost 50,000 needing emergency medical attention.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Workman, which makes clothes for construction workers, launched a version of their fan-fitted jackets adapted for the high street in 2020 as demand grew.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mechanism is simple – two electric, palm-sized fans powered by a rechargeable battery are fitted into the back of the jacket.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They draw in air to then deliver a breeze – at variable speeds – onto the wearer&#39;s body.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The jackets retail for 12,000 to 24,000 yen (US$82-US$164).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As the weather gets hotter, people who have never worn fan-equipped clothing before want to find ways to cool down … so more people are interested in buying it,” Workman spokesman Yuya Suzuki said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Just like you feel cool when you are at home with a fan, you feel cool just by wearing [the jacket] because the wind is blowing through your body all the time,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan bakes as residents warned of once-in-a-decade, life-threatening heat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Japanese summers are known to be hot and humid, but this July, Tokyo really sweated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average temperature was 28.7 degrees Celsius (83.7 degrees Fahrenheit), the highest on record since 1875.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heatstroke is particularly deadly in Japan, which has the second-oldest population in the world after Monaco.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 80 per cent of heat-related deaths in the past five years have been among senior citizens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some people die from heatstroke,” said Nozomi Takai of MI Creations, a company selling neck-cooling tubes mainly to factory and warehouse workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Individuals as well as companies are putting more and more effort into measures against it every year,” Takai said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gel inside his firm&#39;s brightly coloured tubes – priced at 2,500 yen – is cool enough to use after 20 minutes in the fridge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wearing it on the neck will “considerably cool the whole body” for about an hour, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Takai&#39;s company joined an expo this year on “measures against extreme heat” in Tokyo to showcase new products that help users stay cool in the scorching heat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At another booth, Tokyo-based company Liberta had a series of clothing including T-shirts and arm sleeves using prints that make users feel cool – especially when they sweat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prints use materials such as xylitol that feel cool when reacting with water and sweat, they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chikuma, an Osaka-based company, has even created office jackets and dresses equipped with electric fans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We developed them with the idea that it could be proposed in places where casual wear is not allowed,” Yosuke Yamanaka of Chikuma said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regular fan-fitted clothes can make the wearer look puffy, as they need to be zipped up, and cuffs are tight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But jackets developed jointly by Chikuma, power tool maker Makita and textile giant Teijin do not need to be buttoned up, thanks to a special structure that sandwiches the fans in two layers and keeps the cool air in, Yamanaka said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parasols, which are commonly associated in Japan with skin-tone-conscious women protecting against a summer tan, are now proving more popular with men too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Komiyama Shoten, a small, luxury umbrella maker in Tokyo, began making parasols for men around 2019 after the environment ministry encouraged people to use them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before, many male customers thought parasols “were for women and they were embarrassed”, the owner Hiroyuki Komiya said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Once you use it, you can&#39;t let go,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Heatwaves to hit China every 5 years as extreme weather events multiply: study&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On the busy streets of popular tourist destination Asakusa, Kiyoshi Miya, 42, said he decided to “use his umbrella as a parasol”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s like I&#39;m always in the shade and the wind feels cool,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another visitor, Shoma Kawashima, wore a wearable fan around his neck to stay cool under the blazing sun.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s so hot I want to be naked,” the 21-year-old said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gadgets are helpful, but “not a solution” to rising temperatures, he added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mpox cases rise in China, but response is affected by anti-LGBTQ bias and ‘technology nationalism’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3231470/mpox-cases-rise-china-response-affected-anti-lgbtq-bias-and-technology-nationalism?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 07:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/3f9ccc66-8fdd-42b2-8317-3d20a8cce063_564b5a5e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hazmat suits, PCR tests, quarantines and contact tracing – it was hard not to feel a sense of déjà vu a few weeks ago when the Chinese Centre for Disease Control and Prevention published new guidelines on containing a disease outbreak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But what was happening was not another Covid-19 wave. Rather, the Chinese government was addressing a potentially significant new public health concern: mpox.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The World Health Organization (WHO) reports that China is currently experiencing the world&#39;s fastest increase in cases of mpox (formerly known as monkeypox), and the country needs to act quickly to contain the spread.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the Americas and Europe have mostly contained the mpox outbreak that started in mid-2022, Asia has emerged as the disease&#39;s new hotspot.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan, South Korea and Thailand, which all saw sporadic imported cases last year, have reported weekly new case numbers in the double digits in 2023, meaning the virus has been spreading in the domestic population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But according to the latest data reported to the WHO, China has surpassed all other countries in the world, with 315 confirmed cases in the past three months – although irregular case reporting from Beijing makes it impossible to know the true scale of the disease at this point.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;No need to panic&#39; over Hong Kong&#39;s spike in mpox cases, as vaccination centre opens&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mpox is less contagious than Covid-19, but since 2022 more than 88,000 people have contracted the disease, which can be painful, and debilitating for some. More than 150 people have died.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some countries have been more successful than others at containing domestic mpox outbreaks – and much of their success is arguably a result of proactive measures such as vaccination campaigns. But the Chinese government has barely started to take action.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Compared with the response to Covid-19 […] the [Chinese] response is certainly dramatically different,” says Yanzhong Huang, a senior fellow for global health at the Council on Foreign Relations in the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even though [mpox] is less likely to develop into a large outbreak in the country, the Pollyanna attitude may encourage the spread of the disease among the at-risk population – unless they take a more active campaign against the disease.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, the WHO declared that mpox was no longer a public health emergency of international concern (PHEIC), because cases had gone down significantly in countries that had seen large outbreaks last year, mostly in the Americas and Europe. (Mpox has been endemic in West and Central Africa for decades and remains so.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Overall, compared to where we were last year, we&#39;re definitely in a different place,” says Krutika Kuppalli, an infectious-disease doctor and chair of the Infectious Diseases Society of America&#39;s Global Health Committee. “We have much fewer cases, but we are seeing sporadic outbreaks in different parts of the world.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indeed, by the time the WHO rescinded the PHEIC declaration, many Asian countries were already starting to see an uptick. Japan was the first Asian country to report a significant increase in mpox cases, in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, a report by researchers in the country warned that the disease could surge across Asia, owing to the connection between Japan and other Asian countries, and the low mpox vaccination rate in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the outbreak grows to the level it did in the West, the researchers noted, more than 10,000 cases might be expected in Japan alone before mpox is successfully contained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is less clear what exactly is happening in China. According to data collected by the WHO, China reported 315 new mpox cases from May to July. A case count this high suggests that not all cases were travel-related.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But – in another situation reminiscent of its Covid-19 response – China isn&#39;t as forthcoming as other countries with its disease data; it doesn&#39;t publish weekly reports of new cases. Rather, it has released a one-time report of the number of mpox cases recorded in June: 106.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong to open dedicated mpox vaccination centre on Thursday&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Chinese government didn&#39;t release data from May and, at the time of writing, hasn&#39;t released any data about July cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The WHO, though, includes case counts from Taiwan, which has its own government and Centres for Disease Control, and Hong Kong in its China numbers. And there is no way for the public to separate the data. So the 315 number includes the 106 cases Beijing says it identified in June, plus the number of infections in Taiwan and Hong Kong over May, June and July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This all further obscures the true number of mpox cases in mainland China – even though it is critical during an infectious-disease outbreak to be on top of things as soon as possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We also need to understand more about the people that have been infected,” Kuppalli says, “such as […] the demographics, the clinical presentation, their immune status and about how they&#39;ve been presenting to care. I think that type of information is important.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lack of clarity on how the disease has spread has caused some people in China to panic. The news that mpox cases have started to appear in the country has been circulating for weeks. But not until July 26 did China&#39;s CDC and health ministry co-publish new guidance on how to prevent its spread, and even that left questions unanswered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The directive asked that all confirmed mpox patients transfer to a medical facility for quarantine unless they have only mild symptoms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said contact tracing going back three weeks would be conducted for every patient, and their close contacts would be asked to self-quarantine for three weeks. It also recommended that local authorities monitor the mpox virus level in waste water in certain areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What makes monitoring the outbreak more difficult in China is that, as in the West, the current mpox spread has been seen mostly among communities of men who have sex with men (MSM).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And similar to what happened in the US and Europe, that association is consistently misinterpreted in China to suggest that mpox is only an STD spread by gay men through sexual activity – a particularly dangerous connection, as the LGBTQ community is increasingly targeted in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many Chinese social media users who have spotted men with skin lesions in public have been posting their photos to ask whether it is an mpox symptom. And the Chinese name for mpox – houdou – has also been thrown around casually as a slur against gay men.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To stop the spread of mpox, public health officials need to strike a delicate balance between destigmatising the disease by dispelling the idea that it affects only gay men and prioritising the MSM communities that are most vulnerable to it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Working with the people that are affected, helping to have non-stigmatising language and communication, has been hugely effective in helping to curb the outbreak” in the West, Kuppalli says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So far, some LGBTQ communities in China feel they are on their own. M, who works for a queer rights organisation in Guangzhou and asked to be identified only by his first initial given the sensitivity of his work, points out that the CDC recommended waste-water monitoring specifically near venues that MSM communities frequent, including bars, clubs and saunas.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Anti-LGBTQ China mouthpieces and &#39;Christian&#39; bigots don&#39;t speak for Hong Kong&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He says this has become controversial within the Chinese LGBTQ community, and that some organisers feel this puts a target on their backs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another LGBTQ organiser, Suihou, in Hubei province, who asked to be identified by a pseudonym, says that even though contact tracing information is supposed to be strictly confidential, he has seen one example in which an mpox patient&#39;s private information, including phone number, national ID, address and HIV status, was leaked and passed around on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Organisers such as M and Suihou are doing their own work to mobilise a disease response. To spread information about mpox prevention, M has recently sent text messages to 700 people and hosted in-person lectures that reached more than 900 people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suihou has worked with one mpox patient closely, helping him get testing and treatment. Not all the medical workers they have encountered have been trained on how to handle the sensitivity of these cases, he says; during the contact tracing process, the doctor told the patient that this disease is a problem for “your kind of people”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suihou warns that some people may avoid seeking medical help altogether, particularly given the lack of state support for mandatory quarantine and contact tracing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From the individual cases that I have heard of, everyone who has a confirmed case is being asked to go to a quarantine facility,” Suihou says. But, he explains, since the government has not provided a budget to help cover the quarantine, as it did with Covid-19, patients have no choice but to pay for the hospital stay and all medical tests out of their own pockets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many marginalised individuals, who are also more vulnerable in an infectious-disease outbreak, may not be able to afford that.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With the slowdown of the [Chinese] economy, local governments don&#39;t have the physical capacity or even the willingness to invest more in public health,” Huang says. Even the WHO doesn&#39;t have funding specifically earmarked for mpox prevention; it has been using its emergency fund to cover mpox-related work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A lot of the financial burden will again fall on local organisers. M says his organisation is using funds intended for HIV prevention to conduct mpox outreach work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All of this could further discourage people who get infected from seeking medical tests and treatment. This in turn would make the community spread of mpox even harder to track – and could undermine prevention efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As with Covid-19, vaccination is one of the best ways to get mpox under control. Worldwide, three vaccines are currently being used for mpox prevention: ACAM2000, MVA-BN (also known as JYNNEOS in the US) and LC16m8.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All these vaccines were originally designed for protection against smallpox but have been found effective against mpox.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Monkeypox to be renamed mpox by WHO&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US has administered more than 1.2 million MVA-BN and ACAM2000 shots. And in Asia, South Korea imported 10,000 MVA-BN shots last year and is planning to procure another 20,000 this year, while Taiwan, despite its small size, has procured and administered more than 72,000 MVA-BN shots so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan, meanwhile, has relied on a Japanese company to produce its own LC16m8 while also donating doses of the vaccine to countries including Colombia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But none of these vaccines has been approved for use in China. The situation recalls China&#39;s refusal to import any mRNA Covid-19 vaccines, instead relying on a few home-grown vaccines that were shown to be less effective.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this case, though, the country doesn&#39;t currently produce any of its own smallpox vaccines; production was terminated after smallpox was eradicated globally in 1980.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bavarian Nordic, the Danish company that produces the MVA-BN vaccine, says it can&#39;t disclose client information unless requested by the government and can&#39;t confirm whether China has procured any MVA-BN shots. But it says the company is not in the process of applying to register the vaccine in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The WHO also has a sharing mechanism in place that allows member states to receive vaccines if needed. But it is unclear whether China has applied for mpox vaccines. The organisation did not immediately respond to an inquiry about whether there are plans to send vaccines to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new Chinese CDC guidance on mpox made no mention of any vaccine as part of its outbreak response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s quite unlikely that China will focus on procuring vaccines at this moment, since there&#39;s no precedent and [no] emergency approval of the vaccines. Rather, there seems to be a focus on surveillance, monitoring, quarantine, contact tracing, etc,” says Zoe Leung, a senior associate at Bridge Consulting, a Beijing-based communication consultancy specialising in public health.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It may not be this way forever: Sinopharm, a Chinese state-owned pharmaceutical company, announced in November 2022 that it had developed the world&#39;s first mRNA vaccine against mpox, and it has been found to be effective in preclinical studies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On July 13, Sinopharm officially applied for clinical trial approval for a “replication-defective mpox vaccine”, though it is unclear whether these are the same products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sinopharm did not immediately reply to questions about its mpox vaccine development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is domestic research [into an mpox vaccine], but we don&#39;t know when it can be commercially available. It will take a long time,” says M. “I have some friends who have already travelled to Hong Kong or Macau to get vaccinated against mpox.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for Chinese people to get vaccinations outside mainland China, there is often a high cost, a long wait and layers of bureaucracy to wade through. It&#39;s again similar to trends seen earlier in the pandemic, when Chinese people with means travelled to Hong Kong to get mRNA Covid-19 vaccines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It doesn&#39;t necessarily mean [Beijing is] not interested in vaccines,” says Huang, “but there&#39;s this technology nationalism that discouraged them from rapid approval of the use of foreign vaccines.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And that, he warns, “certainly contributed to the rapid increase in Covid-related mortalities”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Wildfires threaten western Canada’s Kelowna as far north evacuated: ‘100 years of firefighting in one night’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231625/wildfires-threaten-western-canadas-kelowna-far-north-evacuated-100-years-firefighting-one-night?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 06:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/19/86ffa928-e7e4-4551-b258-5ca8bf693808_6935f281.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Wildfires on Friday bore down on Kelowna in western Canada – a city of 150,000 – while efforts to clear Yellowknife in the far north turned it into a ghost town as scorching flames burned ever closer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two fronts in British Columbia and the Northwest Territories are just the latest in a summer of devastating wildfires across the country that have forced tens of thousands from their homes and left millions of acres scorched.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Kelowna, officials described “a hard night” beating back flames, at times forcing crews to pull back and some firefighters to become trapped behind lines while making “heroic efforts” to rescue residents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We fought hard last night to protect our community,” West Kelowna fire chief Jason Brolund told a briefing on Friday. “A significant number of structures were lost,” he said, but no injuries or fatalities were reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was like 100 years of firefighting all at once, in one night,” he said, adding that he expects “another scary night tonight” under an eerie glow of the fires.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 2,500 homes and businesses on Kelowna&#39;s west side were ordered evacuated late Thursday, while another 4,800 were advised to be ready to leave at a moment&#39;s notice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city is nestled in the Okanagan Valley that is home to some of the country&#39;s top wineries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The emptying of Yellowknife continued in the far north, meanwhile, with cars snaking along the lone highway connecting the remote capital of the Northwest Territories to southern Alberta province ahead of a 12pm deadline.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese scientists calculate mammoth emissions from Canadian wildfires&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The exodus has also continued by air, with thousands of residents flying out and an increased number of flights scheduled Friday to evacuate the regional capital&#39;s more than 20,000 inhabitants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The nearest evacuation centre is 1,150km (700 miles) away, in Alberta, where several sites have been set up. Prime Minister Justin Trudeau will meet refugees in the provincial capital Edmonton in the afternoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Air Canada pilot Chad Blewett, who flew one of the first relief flights out of Yellowknife, told public broadcaster CBC that the lakeside city was “pretty empty already.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The stragglers, he said, were mostly essential workers “building fire breaks and working with airlines [to facilitate evacuations].”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Crews have scrambled to erect defences as the flames approached Yellowknife, while water bombers have been seen flying low over the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strong winds over the next two days will send the fire, already within just a few kilometres of the city&#39;s perimeter, “in directions we don&#39;t want”, Northwest Territories&#39; fire information officer Mike Westwick said late on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several military aircraft have already been dispatched, along with more than 120 soldiers to help beat back the flames.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Defence Minister Bill Blair told reporters “conditions remain very difficult” in the north, and warned that the highway out of the city was open “for now”. As the evacuation winds down, he said, “the priority [will now be] to make sure that Yellowknife and all its property are safe”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s scary&#39;: New York has world&#39;s worst air as Canada fire smoke drifts south&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The flight from Yellowknife means half the population of the near-Arctic territory has been displaced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several towns and Indigenous communities were also already under evacuation orders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Canada is experiencing a record-setting wildfire season, with official estimates of over 13.7 million hectares (33.9 million acres) already scorched. Four people have died so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, the fires have also emitted an unprecedented amount of carbon dioxide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scientists say human-caused global warming is exacerbating natural hazards, making them both more frequent and more deadly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It shows how quickly our climate is changing if a place like Yellowknife, so close to the Arctic Circle, is on fire,” Adria McPherson told the CBC while fleeing the fires in the north by car.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The evacuation of Yellowknife is the second time an entire Canadian city has been cleared due to wildfires since 100,000 residents of Fort McMurray in Alberta&#39;s oil and gas producing heartland were forced out in 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, suburbs of Halifax on the Atlantic coast were also evacuated.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 06:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Brics summit: African countries wait in the wings for expansion of economic bloc]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231482/brics-summit-african-countries-wait-wings-expansion-economic-bloc?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/4d5b7012-973f-4589-89d6-f69a666830bc_1b398a70.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese President Xi Jinping&#39;s visit to South Africa for the Brics summit next week will be a stage for Beijing to promote its post-Covid charm offensive, including agenda items like membership expansion and de-dollarisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the Johannesburg summit is not expected to yield any concrete results, it will be watched closely by developing countries looking to the Brics group – Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa – as a major counterweight to Western influence in global governance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South African President Cyril Ramaphosa, as Brics chairman for 2023, will also host Brazilian President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva and Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi for the summit. Russia will be represented by Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, with President Vladimir Putin to participate virtually.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, Xi and Ramaphosa will hold talks to strengthen ties and will witness the signing of various agreements, according to the South African president&#39;s office.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why African nations are keen to join the expanding BRICS club&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On August 10, ahead of Xi&#39;s visit, Chinese companies signed 20 deals to buy products worth US$2.2 billion from South Africa. South African Trade Minister Ebrahim Patel and Chinese Minister of Commerce Wang Wentao witnessed the signing at a meeting of a joint economic and trade committee aimed at boosting South African manufacturing exports to China. Anglo American Platinum, Glencore, Sappi and Pioneer Fishing were among South African companies involved in the agreements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi will also co-chair a China-Africa Leaders&#39; Dialogue on the sidelines of the summit, according to China&#39;s foreign ministry – welcome news for African countries such as Algeria, Egypt, Ethiopia, Nigeria and Senegal, which are eager to move another step closer to joining the bloc.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yun Sun, head of the Stimson Centre&#39;s China programme in Washington, said China had been focused on its post-Covid diplomatic charm offensive for some time now, and developing countries and emerging markets were a big part of it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The] Brics summit this year covers both. I am sure issues such as African debt sustainability, post-Covid economic recovery and the war in Ukraine, as well as the expanded membership of Brics, will be high on the agenda,” Sun said. “China needs to show that it is still firmly committed to the future of Africa, provide reassurance and offer assistance. Africa needs the commitment from China as well.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Across Africa, Brics members are seen as important trade partners, sources of foreign investment and champions of the concerns of so-called developing countries, according to Tim Zajontz, a research fellow in the Centre for International and Comparative Politics at Stellenbosch University, South Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We can expect President Xi to stress at the summit that China and the Brics are at the centre of South-South cooperation and ready to boost economic development across Africa,” Zajontz said, referring to collaboration among countries in the Global South.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is little surprise that countries like Burundi, Egypt and Ethiopia want to join the grouping,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While their immediate accession appears unlikely, the fact that President Ramaphosa has invited other African leaders to attend the Johannesburg summit shows that there is keen interest to increase the Brics&#39; footprint on the continent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Expansion of the bloc as well as trade in local currencies as an alternative to the US dollar are likely to be the two main topics discussed – even if they do not end up leading to any firm outcomes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is among the supporters of Brics expansion among the five countries, but we are unsure if any country will be able to fully join Brics at this summit, as the criteria for new admissions has yet to be finalised,” said Steven Gruzd, head of the Africa-Russia Project at the South African Institute of International Affairs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the debate turns to currencies, it is likely the summit will push for reforms of the international economic governance system, including political discussion about the dominance of the US dollar and the euro in trade and financial transactions. But Carlos Lopes, a professor at the University of Cape Town&#39;s Nelson Mandela School of Public Governance, said not to expect any major decision on this.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neither is it expected – whether hoped or feared – that the Brics&#39; New Development Bank (NDB), led by former Brazilian president Dilma Rousseff, is ready to compete with Western-centred international financial institutions at this stage, according to Lopes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zajontz, who is also a lecturer in international relations at Dresden University of Technology, said the future of the NDB would be high up on the agenda at the summit as its lending had decreased lately and the bank had faced challenges to raise capital following sanctions against Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the medium to long term, the NDB wants to further de-dollarise its capital base by increasing local currency lending and by increasing NDB membership,” he said. Egypt joined the NDB in 2021, and Algeria and Zimbabwe have expressed interest to join as well.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But [it is] not just the question of possible new African NDB members but also whether the NDB might soften its current policy to only lend to member countries,” Zajontz said, adding the many African states “are keen to diversify their creditors in times of tight development finance”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Brics meeting comes as tension between the West and the East is growing. Many African political actors, including recent army putschists in Mali, Burkina Faso, Sudan and Niger, are trying to take advantage of this discord to either protect their acquired power or contest established authority, according to Lopes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The summit will be an opportunity for Brics, and countries invited, to demonstrate independence in relation to the West while reserving endorsement of their nemesis, Russia, and their competitor, China,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cameron Hudson, a senior associate at the Centre for Strategic and International Studies&#39; Africa programme, said that as well as trying to diversify their external partnerships, African countries were looking to have a greater voice on the world stage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said African leaders would want to explore how Brics could be used as a forum where policies that benefited developing countries were created and coordinated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Africans are not interested in the illusion of coordination. They want to see real change and real impact in tangible ways that benefit them and their societies,” Hudson said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Stop posing for naked photos in our sunflower field, UK farm owners beg visitors]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3231624/stop-posing-naked-photos-our-sunflower-field-uk-farm-owners-beg-visitors?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 04:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/19/0b1ba70a-289a-4c7b-918b-c8faace90530_1b2781da.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The owners of an English farm are begging visitors to quit posing for naked pictures in its sunflower field.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a Facebook post earlier this month, Stoke Fruit Farm – which is located off the southern coast of England on Hayling Island – made the request that visitors stay fully clothed when in their sunflower field.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Reminder to all we are a family area and please keep your clothes on in the sunflowers!” the farm wrote on Facebook.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are having a increase of reports of naked photography taking place and this must not happen during our public sessions please!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The farm then promptly erected signs in its field that say “no public nudity,” according to photos obtained by CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNN spoke to the owners of Stoke Fruit Farm, Sam Wilson and his sister Nette Petley.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wilson said there have been at least six instances of public nudity among the flowers since the end of July when the field opened for visitors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ve always had people take risqué pictures but this is the first year it&#39;s been a problem, which is why we&#39;ve put signs up,” Wilson told CNN. The farm staff had to put up the signs after some kids caught a peek of what was going on in the field, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russian woman &#39;lay naked to cool down&#39; while scaling Malaysia&#39;s tallest tower&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We are a really free and happy farm but we just can&#39;t have nudity in public view,” Wilson said, according to CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Petley echoed Wilson&#39;s sentiment that the farm is a “really happy and fun place” that gives “you that empowering feeling”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But it&#39;s about the people around and being respectful of that,” Petley told CNN. “The site is huge and there are so many places that you can hide away without anyone finding you for over an hour, but these incidents were blatantly public.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stoke Fruit Farm has 350 acres of land and produces wheat, peas, potatoes, pumpkins, squash, sweetcorn, hay, and sunflowers, according to CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wilson first planted the sunflowers with his then fiancée behind the church where they married six years ago, intending to have their wedding surrounded by the sunflowers, but they did not bloom in time, according to CNN. Instead, they sprang up while the couple was away on their honeymoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While they were gone, Wilson told CNN that Petley called him and said: “People want to pick your flowers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNN reported at that point, Wilson and Petley set up an “honesty box for visitors”, but the sunflowers have since gained massive popularity over the years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now, paying visitors, who travel far and wide to see the field, can walk among 2 million sunflowers in the massive 50-acre field, Wilson told CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump to skip Republican primary debate, do interview with Tucker Carlson instead, report says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231622/donald-trump-skip-republican-primary-debate-do-interview-tucker-carlson-instead-report-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 03:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/19/ec266b11-b634-45e8-ac24-44e2fc8fe3df_f7cff0a0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普计划跳过下周的第一次共和党初选辩论，转而进行据《纽约时报》援引知情人士的话报道，特朗普参加了前福克斯新闻主持人塔克·卡尔森的在线采访。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普几个月来一直暗示他可能会在周三晚上密尔沃基的辩论中通过，威斯康星州认为，鉴于他在全国民意调查中在共和党人中遥遥领先，给其他人攻击他的机会是没有意义的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普还批评了主持这场辩论的福克斯公司最近的报道&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普的缺席可能意味着佛罗里达州州长罗恩·德桑蒂斯（在民意调查中排名第二）将成为其他候选人攻击的焦点，这些候选人希望将自己定位为前总统的主要替代者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;特朗普竞选发言人史蒂文·张表示，候选人的辩论计划尚未得到证实，但没有详细说明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候与卡尔森分道扬镳的福克斯代表和共和党全国委员会可以未能立即联系到置评。卡尔森现在正在创办自己的媒体公司，也无法联系到他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在本月发布的最新路透社/益普索民意调查中，特朗普在全国范围内获得了 47% 的共和党选票，德桑蒂斯的支持率下降比 7 月份下降了 6 个百分点，仅为 13%。 None of the other candidates due to attend the debate have broken out of single digits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s rivals for the Republican presidential nomination ahead of the 2024 election will gather at the debate to tout their candidacies, but so far only a few have aggressively criticised Trump despite his mounting legal troubles.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;22 years in jail for Canadian woman who sent poison-laced letter to Trump&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Trump has an August 25 deadline to voluntarily surrender in Fulton County, Georgia, after being charged this week in a fourth criminal indictment, for an alleged scheme intended to reverse his 2020 election loss to Democrat Joe Biden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most self-identified Republicans polled in June said they saw politics behind the indictments of Trump up to that point.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump also faces two federal indictments over his handling of classified documents after leaving office in January 2021 and over his alleged role in efforts to overturn his election loss.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also faces charges in New York over alleged hush money payments to a pornographic film star ahead of the 2016 election.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>