<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Lewis Capaldi cancels Singapore, Philippines, South Korea tour dates amid struggles with Tourette’s syndrome]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225688/lewis-capaldi-cancels-singapore-philippines-south-korea-tour-dates-amid-struggles-tourettes-syndrome?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 13:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/3334e6c6-f796-48fd-bc5e-37d1884607da_f820c0eb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;苏格兰创作型歌手刘易斯·卡帕尔迪 (Lewis Capaldi) 表示，在可预见的未来，他将暂停巡演他正在努力适应抽动秽语综合症的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的声明是在他周六在英国格拉斯顿伯里音乐节上表演之后宣布的，当时他似乎失去了声音，人群陪着他演唱了他的歌曲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“首先，感谢格拉斯顿伯里邀请我，在我需要的时候一起唱歌，以及之后所有令人惊叹的信息，”他在周二的一份声明中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“事实这可能不会让人感到意外，但这并不会让写作变得更容易，但我很遗憾地告诉你，在可预见的未来我将暂停巡演。”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;图雷特氏综合症是一种神经系统疾病，会导致个体不自觉地发出声音和动作，通常称为抽动。卡帕尔迪去年 9 月透露，他已被诊断出患有这种疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;26 岁的卡帕尔迪将于周三在瑞士苏黎世演出。他目前的巡演地点包括新加坡、菲律宾、韩国、澳大利亚和新西兰等地，定于 10 月 7 日在阿拉伯联合酋长国达到高潮。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“披头士乐队最终唱片” ” 得益于人工智能：麦卡特尼，今年将出版&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;卡帕尔迪在声明中表示，他“仍在学习适应抽动秽语症的影响，周六，很明显我需要花更多的钱”是时候让我的身心健康恢复正常，这样我就可以在未来很长一段时间内继续做我喜欢的事情”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Netflix 一部关于格莱美提名的纪录片上映后接受采访时明星卡帕尔迪说，他很高兴自己的症状得到诊断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时，他说他试图“不要了解太多”有关图雷特氏症的信息，因为这往往会让他的病情感觉更糟。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这部题为《我现在的感受如何》的纪录片展示了卡帕尔迪回到苏格兰家乡并在大流行期间尝试写新歌曲时困扰他的恐惧和焦虑。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[6 out of 7 Hong Kong universities in global survey drop down the rankings; HKUST plummets 20 places to 60th spot]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3225687/6-out-7-hong-kong-universities-global-survey-drop-down-rankings-hkust-plummets-20-places-60th-spot?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 13:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/a3595dc4-0187-463d-9a32-515c7d384ba8_ddeac076.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;参与全球评级调查的七所公帑资助的香港大学中有六所下降排名下降的原因包括国际研究和学生毕业后的就业能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港科技大学 (HKUST) 周三宣布，排名下降 20 位，至第 60 位。这是 Quacquarelli Symonds 世界大学排名 12 年前推出以来最差的表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也是西贡大学首次跌出前 50 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学 (HKU) 全球排名较去年下降 5 位，至第 26 位；中国大学排名下降 9 位，排名第 47 位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有理工大学较去年保持第 65 位。这也是该校首次超过城市大学，城市大学从第54位跌至第70位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浸会大学从第281位下滑至第295位，岭南大学则从第601位至650位跌至第641位至650位。 ，这是十多年来最差的排名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;七所大学的国际研究网络指标得分与去年相比下降了 24% 至 95%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该指标衡量机构通过与海外大学合作实现研究网络多元化的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;QS 表示，虽然香港因其在高影响力期刊上发表的世界级研究而获得认可，但该城市在&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港4所大学在亚洲顶尖学校排名中上升&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“在国际研究网络中，没有香港大学跻身世界前300名，”说，并补充说，即使是香港顶尖大学香港大学也仅排名第 355 位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前，世界上约 20% 的研究是通过国际合作完成的。虽然香港 74% 的研究是与国际合作伙伴一起进行的，但其中不到四分之三是与中国合作进行的，这凸显了多元化和全球化研究议程的重要性。”它补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国总部位于香港的教育信息公司还表示，香港应该感到欣慰的是，继早些时候由于“社会政治摩擦”而导致香港高等教育机构的声誉下降之后，全球学术界现在再次高度评价其高等教育界。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;与去年相比，所有大学的“雇主声誉”指标均有所下降，根据对全球数千名雇主收集的调查结果，下降幅度从 1% 到近 40% 不等。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“香港似乎在将其卓越的学术优势转化为就业市场方面遇到了困难。在雇主声誉方面，表现最好的是香港大学，排名第 159 位。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科大发言人表示，排名因多种因素而上下波动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“科大将采取“它们是了解我们和其他大学的表现并确定需要改进的领域的有用参考。”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国大学的一位女发言人表示，全球高等教育行业仍在从新冠疫情的影响中恢复过来。 -19大流行，影响了一系列因素，包括外地学生的流动和学者的国际招聘。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港大学全球排名下降归咎于缺乏合作&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;但她补充道：“中文大学现正经历非本地学生需求的强劲复苏，并加大力度招收来自世界各地的优秀学者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学发言人表示该大学坚定不移地致力于为学生提供卓越的教育，并在教学、研究和知识交流方面不懈追求卓越。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港教育大学未参与调查。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Quacquarelli Symonds 公布了 2024 年结果，该机构对全球 1,500 所高等教育机构进行了评级。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港教育大学校长预计将进一步削减教师培训名额&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该评级部分基于对约1750万篇学术论文的分析以及超过24万名学者和雇主的意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共评估了九个方面，包括学术声誉、雇主声誉、学术人员学生比例、教师引用次数、国际教师比例、国际学生比例、可持续性、就业数据和国际研究网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后三个指标是今年新增的，每个指标占权重的 5%。去年它们仅作为参考。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;招聘机构 ACTS Consulting 董事总经理 Alexa Chow Yee-ping 表示，近年来大学教育受到 2019 年社会动荡和 Covid-19 大流行的打击&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些雇主甚至问我毕业生毕业前是否认真学习过，因为他们觉得新毕业生与往年毕业生相比表现很差”，她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麻省理工学院连续 12 年保持排名第一的大学地位，紧随其后的是剑桥大学，后者自去年以来一直保持第二名的位置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;牛津大学和哈佛大学分别上升一位至第三和第四。斯坦福大学从第三位下降至第五位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡国立大学是亚洲顶尖学府，从第十一位上升至第八位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国大陆，北京大学下降排名上升 5 位至第 17 位，清华大学则从第 14 位下滑至第 25 位。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Belarus leader Lukashenko says he told Wagner chief to stop Russian mutiny or be ‘crushed like a bug’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225678/belarus-leader-lukashenko-says-he-told-wagner-chief-stop-russian-mutiny-or-be-crushed-bug?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 12:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/0e1d111c-4f81-438f-8587-4a7c0613a377_94fd3c73.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;白俄罗斯总统亚历山大·卢卡申科表示，他亲自与弗拉基米尔·普京和瓦格纳创始人进行了交涉雇佣军组织，以防止俄罗斯周末兵变期间发生流血事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在国有通讯社贝尔塔周二发布的卢卡申科对事件的版本中，他说服俄罗斯总统让他与瓦格纳的团队联系叶夫根尼·普里戈任的雇佣兵畅通无阻地行进到距莫斯科近 200 公里（124 英里）的地方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢卡申科表示，他敦促普京不要杀死普里戈任，并在前往莫斯科的途中警告瓦格纳首领“你只会这样做”像虫子一样被压碎”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在白俄罗斯总统斡旋的协议中，普京承诺结束针对普里戈任的刑事诉讼，并让他的部队加入俄罗斯军队，返回家人身边或前往白俄罗斯，卢卡申科表示，普里戈任对这一呼吁感到愤怒，并要求莫斯科领导人伸张正义。 “我们在第一轮的 30 分钟里说了脏话。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着乌克兰战争进入第 17 个月，普里戈任在大量充满粗俗内容的视频和音频中指责普京的军事官员无能，试图通过将其私人军队置于他们的指挥下来摧毁它。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;被监禁的克里姆林宫评论家阿列克谢·纳瓦尔尼认为瓦格纳叛乱是一个“笑话”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;卢卡申科表示，他曾向瓦格纳雇佣兵提供援助，这些雇佣兵来到白俄罗斯，并在一个废弃的基地停留，但表示他们必须支付费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还提出了他们成为白俄罗斯军队的一个单位的前景，但表示他不会&#39;卢卡申科表示，不要让瓦格纳看守俄罗斯向白俄罗斯运送的核武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白俄罗斯也不会允许任何瓦格纳招聘办公室，并警告说，任何加入私营军事公司的人都应该做好准备去每天晚上睡觉时“拥抱死亡”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京在兵变被取消后首次向俄罗斯发表讲话，他在周一晚上感谢卢卡申科“为和平解决局势所做的努力和贡献”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;备受瞩目的俄罗斯国家电视台主持人弗拉基米尔·索洛维约夫表示，卢卡申科值得被授予俄罗斯英雄称号，普京的发言人德米特里·佩斯科夫周二对这位白俄罗斯领导人大肆赞扬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢卡申科“佩斯科夫表示，“普京是一位非常经验丰富、明智的政治家”，长期以来与普京保持着良好的工作和友好关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际社会对卢卡申科政权在卢卡申科声称 2020 年连任后残酷镇压抗议者的制裁已经解除他在经济和政治上越来越依赖普京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位长期领导人允许俄罗斯利用他的国家作为去年入侵乌克兰的集结地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;流亡反对派领导人斯维亚特兰娜齐哈努斯卡娅表示，她将于周二前往布鲁塞尔，参加与欧洲领导人就防止白俄罗斯沦为俄罗斯殖民地的讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们白俄罗斯人既不需要普里戈任的暴徒，也不需要俄罗斯的核导弹，也不需要强手。” ”，Tsikhanouskaya 在 Telegram 上说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong expands scheme for non-locally trained doctors to include more mainland Chinese medical schools, overseas programmes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3225680/hong-kong-expands-scheme-non-locally-trained-doctors-include-more-mainland-chinese-medical-schools?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 12:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/28cf929d-0d53-4add-aa49-fdee826c30e0_3aa51463.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;更多中国内地医学院和海外大学的课程获得特别计划的认可为非本地培训的医生，毕业生无需参加执业资格考试即可在香港执业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卫生局周三公布了当局认可的最新一批资格，其中包括六所新的医学院，认可院校总数增至80所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新增的三所医学院来自内地大学，包括清华大学、中山大学和浙江大学，使内地院校数量增加名单上接近六所。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的外国培训医生计划收到了数十份申请&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;另外三所是美国杜克大学和科罗拉多大学，以及西澳大利亚大学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该名单还包括前三轮中添加的更多大学的医学资格，例如剑桥大学和牛津大学的四年制课程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划根据2021年修订的《医生注册条例》推出，旨在解决公共医疗保健领域严重的劳动力短缺问题，预计这一问题在未来几年将进一步恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自74所医学院的三批认可课程自2022年4月起公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划允许指定名单中具有认可医疗资格的非本地培训医生无需参加执照考试即可在本市获得正式注册。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;只有65名海外医生申请特别计划来港工作&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但须符合一定条件。其中包括在毕业地点持有医疗注册证、获得专科资格后在香港公共部门全职工作至少五年，以及被视为在五年期间“令人满意且称职”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自认可医疗课程的应届毕业生，如果是香港永久性居民，但尚未在接受培训的国家完成实习，也将有资格参加执业资格考试并在香港实习。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此前，非本地培训的医生即使已在其他地方完成实习，仍须参加执业资格考试。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India starts to gag on its Russian oil binge as refiners reach limits of what they can process]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3225677/india-starts-gag-its-russian-oil-binge-refiners-reach-limits-what-they-can-process?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 12:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/cc8b333f-f731-42dd-a551-8b37f1887736_644c8f1a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;从历史悠久的孟买市中心外的一座岛屿堡垒上，游客可以看到巨型油轮在该市东南海岸的两家炼油厂卸货。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到一年前，这些船几乎肯定是从十几个主要供应国之一运输原油——中东、美国和西非（非洲西部。如今，石油更有可能来自俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据分析公司 Kpler 的数据，上个月莫斯科占印度石油进口的 46%，比之前的不到 2% 有了惊人的飞跃入侵乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从绝对值来看，5 月份创下了新高。诚然，中国在过去一年中进口了更多的俄罗斯原油，进口量创下历史新高，但真正挺身而出支撑俄罗斯经济的却是美国的战略伙伴印度。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;今天的问题是，随着印度的折扣缩小，但克里姆林宫的财务压力增加，采购热潮能否继续下去，而克里姆林宫比以往任何时候都更迫切需要资金来消除对弗拉基米尔·普京总统统治的国内威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 迄今为止的转变适合克里姆林宫，在西方买家和老牌石油贸易商撤出之际寻找新市场。这对印度也有效，印度急于抢购更便宜的燃料以控制通货膨胀。 4 月份，运送到印度海岸的俄罗斯原油平均成本为每桶 68.21 美元，而沙特石油价格为每桶 86.96 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“印度炼油商的价格远远超出了我们的想象。 Petro-Logistics 战略与分析董事总经理贾迈勒·库雷希 (Jamal Qureshi) 表示： “他们很快就取代了与乌拉尔类似的牌号，这正是我们所期望的，但他们也放弃了除此之外的其他牌号。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至少象岛一日游者可以看到的炼油厂表明，产量激增已经到来&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;莫迪在谈到新德里对俄罗斯的立场时表示，“印度的首要任务是和平”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;首先是基础设施。虽然用于决定炼油厂最佳原料的分析主要针对俄罗斯乌拉尔混合物，但这两家工厂都不是为使用俄罗斯桶而设计的。巴拉特石油公司 (BPCL) 的工厂旨在加工印度国内原油，其含硫量低于俄罗斯石油。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更多的俄罗斯石油桶意味着生产更多的燃料油，这是一种通常以折扣价出售的泥状石油价格。或者成本高昂的重新利用——接受本文采访的高管表示，他们不愿意进行这种做法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现阶段炼油厂并不寻求对配置进行任何改变，”印度工程师有限公司技术总监拉吉夫·阿加瓦尔 (Rajiv Agarwal) 表示。 ，一家为此类项目提供咨询服务的国有公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，孟买的 BPCL 炼油厂没有焦化装置（可加工像俄罗斯那样的重质含硫原油的装置），因此一位因无权向媒体发言而要求不透露姓名的高管表示，大约十分之一的加工原油来自俄罗斯。这个数字低于一些新工厂的比例，后者的比例高达 40%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，炼油厂配置是最大的限制因素，此外还有担心过度依赖炼油厂。如果制裁收紧，供应来源可能会面临中断。这将使潜在的涨幅保持在 2% 或 3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“乌拉尔原油过去从来都不是首选原油，”BPCL 炼油厂前总监 R. Ramachandran 表示。 “如果定价合适，并且炼油厂需要将乌拉尔原油作为主要原油进行加工，那么工厂就需要资本投资，这可能需要三到四年的时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有人回复发送给 BPCL 媒体部门寻求帮助的电子邮件。评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与俄罗斯的一些其他客户不同，与中国等国家相比，印度还相对缺乏混合所需的商用储罐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度没有远离俄罗斯。通过在储罐中混合不同类型的石油，一些俄罗斯原油供应可能会变得更适合那些难以获取更多原油的工厂。这可能会导致产量增加，一些高管估计每天产量可能在 200,000 至 400,000 桶之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有其他供应商的问题。几位炼油厂官员表示，他们担心长期转变（而不是机会主义购买）会损害与​​现有合作伙伴的关系，特别是中东生产商的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迄今为止，买家主要关注俄罗斯现货采购，这种安排在供应充足时有效。最近，印度炼油商也一直在进行谈判，以确保来自俄罗斯的流量更加稳定，但讨论进展缓慢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但进一步的激增将需要政府重新燃起热情来指导炼油商。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;“毫无疑问”：拜登-莫迪会谈中讨论了中国的共同挑战&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“展望未来，问题是是否可以促使国有炼油厂购买比目前更多的俄罗斯石油。 Petro-Logistics 的 Qureshi 补充道：“这就是公众方面最大的潜在空间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当然，这一切的背后都存在进一步购买的政治因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;虽然俄罗斯的经济影响力比以前有所下降，但两国在安全问题上的密切关系可以追溯到几十年前。莫斯科是印度最大的武器供应商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪上周在华盛顿受到款待，白宫担心的只是印度购买的武器价格低廉，从而最大限度地减少了克里姆林宫的收入同时保持油轮移动。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese military conjures world war Z scenario of all-out conflict to test and evaluate new navy weapons]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3225529/chinese-military-conjures-world-war-z-scenario-all-out-conflict-test-and-evaluate-new-navy-weapons?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 12:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/27/4ef0e6d0-9c38-4397-974f-dda6059ec4a6_ee534c2c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国军方最近在测试和评估参与该项目的科学家表示，随着中美之间发生军事冲突的风险达到数十年来的最高水平，新武器的性能将受到影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全面战争意味着一个国家所有可用的资源和努力都被动员起来赢得战争。它不仅涉及军事，还涉及平民和经济，就像一战和二战时发生的那样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最新的军舰评估中，中国海军科学家将世界末日场景定为Z。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在中国大陆，常规武器的性能评估包括基于计算机的兵棋推演和实地测试。它主要侧重于评估武器在地区冲突中的作战能力，例如台湾周围或南中国海的两个或多个外国航母编队的直接军事干预。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在 Z 中，“存在战略意志力的冲突。中国人民解放军91404部队研究员方灿新领导的团队表示，“地区冲突升级为全面战争”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;方灿新所在的部队负责中国一些最新、最强大的舰艇的海上试验。根据公开信息，海军武器。本月在《中国船舶研究杂志》上发表的同行评审论文中，Z-war场景首次被解密。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;方和他的同事没有点名任何国家，只点名出现的敌方硬件。论文中的阿利·伯克级驱逐舰等属于美国海军及其盟国。他们被标记为“蓝色联盟”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国开发者表示，人工智能像人类一样玩专业战争游戏&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;人们越来越担心中国和美国之间发生军事冲突的风险美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾前总统罗德里戈·杜特尔特 (Rodrigo Duterte) 表示，“如果我将即将发生的战争的规模划分为 1 到 10，那么我会将当前局势划分为 7”。在周末的广播节目中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在特朗普担任总统期间，美国国务院的一些高级官员将两国之间的争端定义为“文明冲突”，并在 2019 年将中国称为“第一个非白人的大国竞争对手”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;种族分裂言论，加上最近对中国高科技公司和美国在中国海岸线附近的军事行动的制裁，被中国社会广泛认为是故意的努力遏制中国未来的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更多中国军事研究人员提出，如果无法避免，就将战争带到美国本土。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些尖端武器，例如高超音速导弹根据公开信息，可以穿透美国防御网络的核动力鱼雷已经部署或正在开发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但准备全面战争的想法并不是中国政府的标准思维一些舆论领袖表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民族主义报纸《环球时报》前总编辑、中国社交媒体知名人士胡锡进表示，中国政府的大多数官员都相信中国应该保持冷静，不要被怂恿与美国进行“歼灭战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果中美爆发战争，双方战略利益平等” 6月18日，在美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯访问北京之际，胡锦涛在微博上表示：“一旦危急关头，美国就可以轻松调动力量，与中国进行你死我活的斗争。” >;&lt;p>;“在这种情况下，我认为中国没有获胜的机会，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平敦促中国海军采取“坚定而灵活”的态度&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;去年美国众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台湾时，胡锦涛曾提议击落她乘坐的飞机。他的言论突然软化，在中国社交媒体上引发了一些激烈的反弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;微博上另一位著名的民族主义人物司马南对胡锦涛关于中国将在全面战争中被美国击败的估计提出了挑战。 “这不是基于战争游戏或其他严格的评估，”司马在一段短视频中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两个核超级大国之间爆发全面战争将对世界各地的人类文明造成灾难性后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;在他们的论文中，中国科学家关注的是一艘船的命运。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Z-war模式假设中国军队受到假设的蓝色联盟的全面攻击。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，中国海军目前拥有近50艘驱逐舰。据方的团队称，每艘船都受到了超过 11 枚导弹和超过 3 枚鱼雷的攻击。&lt;​​/p>;&lt;p>;这些武器以多种方式从各个方向袭击，这使得保卫这艘船具有挑战性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;蓝色联盟产生的干扰噪音比中国军舰用于通信的信号强30倍以上。中国雷达的探测距离远低于正常距离的 60%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;方的团队表示，这些极端条件严重限制了中国军舰的作战能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，驱逐舰几乎三分之一的防空能力将在袭击后立即丧失。只有一半的地对空导弹能够击中来袭目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;方的团队表示，中国海军专家对试验评估结果进行了独立评估，并“相信这些数字是现实的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;对于一场全面战争的总体成本来说，军舰的命运可以忽略不计，这场战争可能包括数百万人甚至数十亿人的生命损失，以及对城市、交通系统、通信网络和工业设施等基础设施的广泛破坏。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;如果使用核武器，战争还可能对生态系统、农业和整体环境造成持久和有害的影响，从而可能导致粮食短缺、基因突变以及癌症和其他疾病的高发病率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;但是，一位帮助开发商业兵棋软件的北京计算机科学家表示，详细的技术评估仍然是必要的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;军事研究人员考虑最坏情况的情况并不少见——该研究人员表示，这可以帮助军队更好地了解自己的优势、劣势和局限性。由于问题敏感，该研究人员要求不透露姓名。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国专家参与审查台湾最新的模拟解放军攻击的兵棋&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;方的团队在水面舰艇可能面临的潜在威胁的背景下，对全面战争进行了认真的讨论他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过评估世界末日场景中武器的作战能力，军队可以展示其战备状态，并阻止潜在对手卷入可能导致此类灾难性后果的冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“这篇论文不太可能是一部恐怖电影，”研究人员说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange “ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden unveils 2024 election battle plan: ‘Bidenomics’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225670/joe-biden-unveils-2024-election-battle-plan-bidenomics?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 11:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/f455d927-cd3d-4481-a0ba-b017f9b950c4_837ca9d6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登对美国经济下了很大的赌注，这将推动他重新崛起- 明年大选，本周将向选民推出“拜登经济学”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在继承了遭受新冠大流行蹂躏的经济，然后又受到挥之不去的通货膨胀和供应链困境的困扰后，拜登经历了一段艰难的时期是时候让美国人相信他做得很好了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国广播公司新闻/华盛顿邮报 5 月份的一项民意调查甚至发现，拜登丑闻缠身的共和党前任 — — 以及可能在 2024 年复赛的对手 — — 唐纳德·特朗普在支持率上领先 18 个百分点谁能更好地管理经济的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着本周以拜登周三在芝加哥的演讲为基础的品牌重塑启动，白宫认为它可以扭转局面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首席副新闻秘书奥利维亚·道尔顿 (Olivia Dalton) 告诉记者，“拜登经济学”就是这个词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它是“每日一词、每周一词、每月一词、年度一词”。白宫，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国将斥资 420 亿美元，到 2030 年普及互联网&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这句口号是对著名的“里根经济学”的故意运用和斥责。 ” 罗纳德·里根 (Ronald Reagan) 1980 年代的总统任期，当时“涓滴经济学”的理念被一些人认为点燃了美国的繁荣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫称拜登已经来埋葬“里根经济学”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫称拜登已经来埋葬“里根经济学”。国家经济委员会主任莱尔·布雷纳德 (Lael Brainard) 告诉记者：“他拒绝接受滴流经济学，即顶层减税会向下层层扩散的理论，我们所需要的只是政府让路。” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，道尔顿说，拜登将专注于“当我们发展中产阶级时我们就会发展经济”的信念。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登的主要主张是制定庞大的政府支出计划在他的第一个任期内将刺激长期扩张，从而重建美国的制造业实力并提升该国较不富裕的人口的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这不仅仅是一个经济论据，而且如果有效的话，这将是一个潜在的政治路线图在这场选举中，民主党和共和党将争夺少数摇摆州选民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登最引人注目的是他在过去两年中取得的一系列令人印象深刻的立法胜利。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;国会通过的主要法案向绿色能源技术、半导体投入了历史性的巨额资金，并投入不少于 5500 亿美元用于改造国家的道路、桥梁和其他基础设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布雷纳德说，里根时代trickle-down theory led to the hollowing out of US industrial cities with offshoring and abandonment of ambitious infrastructure upgrades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By contrast, Biden&#39;s tax-money-heavy industrial policy, she said, is using government funding as a catalyst for a “boom in private sector spending in manufacturing construction”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Joe Biden vows to fight Republicans&#39; &#39;extreme&#39; anti-abortion agenda&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;She touted funding for expansion of broadband internet to every corner of the United States as an echo of Franklin Roosevelt&#39;s epic electrification programme to modernise the nation in the 1930s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The problem so far is that voters are not buying what Biden has to sell.&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Polls show him getting little credit for the low unemployment and generally upbeat economy. Inflation, despite falling slowly for 11 months in a row from post-pandemic highs, remains a key worry for voters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dalton said that Americans are about to see things differently as projects funded by Biden&#39;s programmes finally kick in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re seeing shovels in grounds, we&#39;re seeing private investment come back to our country, we&#39;re seeing millions of jobs created. So now is the time, with all of those accomplishments, (when) the president can take this message to the American people and say this is what Bidenomics is,” Dalton said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re just starting to feel the impact.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Not that great’: Brazil President Lula complains about palace food he got in Italy, France]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3225661/not-great-brazil-president-lula-complains-about-palace-food-he-got-italy-france?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 10:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/da714893-f65a-4b6c-8c04-9e8a04a04811_895a776f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Brazil President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva complained about the food he was served by his counterparts in Italy and France last week, criticising the quality and size of the portions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I had lunch with [Emmanuel] Macron and with [Sergio] Mattarella,” Lula said Tuesday, referring to recent meetings with his French and Italian counterparts in Paris and Rome. “Two palace foods that were not that great.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The former union leader added that, when travelling, he always misses having a big tray from which one can grab as much food as they want. “In any case, we&#39;ve survived,” he said during a webcast from his official residence in Brasilia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The French and the Italian government didn&#39;t respond to requests for comment and didn&#39;t give details on the menu served to Lula.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His comments – whether serious or lightheartedly said in jest – will never land well in two culinary capitals of the world that take an inordinate amount of pride in their cuisine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The remarks also add to the controversial rhetoric the leftist leader has employed since returning to the global stage, including his assertion that Joe Biden and Volodymyr Zelensky share part of the blame for Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese, Indonesians, Malaysians among 2,700 victims rescued in Philippines cyber scam raid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225649/chinese-indonesians-malaysians-among-2700-victims-rescued-philippines-cyber-scam-raid?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 11:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/431f4aca-9ed3-42bc-bf11-c7f0338e2fa9_1a170f89.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Philippine police backed by commandos say they have rescued more than 2,700 workers from China, the Philippines, Vietnam, Indonesia – and more than a dozen other countries – who were swindled into working for fraudulent online gaming sites and other cybercrime groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of human trafficking victims rescued from seven buildings in Las Pinas city, metropolitan Manila, on Tuesday and the scale of the massive nighttime raid were the largest so far this year and indicate how the Philippines has become a key base of operations for cybercrime syndicates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cybercrime scams have become a major issue in Asia with reports of people from the region and beyond being lured into taking jobs in countries like strife-torn Myanmar and Cambodia. However, many of these workers find themselves trapped in virtual slavery and forced to participate in scams targeting people over the internet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, leaders from the Association of Southeast Asian Nations agreed in a summit in Indonesia to tighten border controls and law enforcement and broaden public education to fight criminal syndicates that traffic workers to other nations, where they are made to participate in online fraud.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brigadier General Sydney Hernia, who heads the national Philippine police&#39;s anti-cybercrime unit, said police armed with warrants raided and searched the buildings around midnight in Las Pinas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They rescued 1,534 Filipinos and 1,190 foreigners from at least 17 other countries, including 604 Chinese, 183 Vietnamese, 137 Indonesians, 134 Malaysians and 81 Thais.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were also a few people from Myanmar, Pakistan, Yemen, Somalia, Sudan, Nigeria and Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was not immediately clear how many suspected leaders of the syndicate were arrested.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US urges softer touch towards Asian nationals tricked into becoming scammers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Police raided another suspected cybercrime base at the Clark free port in Mabalacat city in Pampanga province north of Manila in May where they took custody of nearly 1,400 Filipino and foreign workers who were allegedly forced to carry out cryptocurrency scams, police said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some of the workers told investigators that when they tried to quit they were forced to pay a hefty amount for unclear reasons or they feared they would be sold to other syndicates, police said, adding that workers were also forced to pay fines for perceived infractions at work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Workers were lured with high salary offers and ideal working conditions in Facebook advertisements but later found out the promises were a ruse, officials said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesian Minister Muhammad Mahfud, who deals with political, legal and security issues, told reporters in May that Indonesia and other countries in the region have found it difficult to work with Myanmar on cybercrime and its victims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said Asean needs to make progress on a long-proposed regional extradition treaty that would help authorities prosecute offenders more rapidly and prevent a further escalation in cybercrime.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UK braces for new waves of Channel asylum seekers with barge and barracks plan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225652/uk-braces-new-waves-channel-asylum-seekers-barge-and-barracks-plan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 10:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/c4cdb8f1-1e4d-4aa9-86b7-4f97aa3a08fe_898fe52b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The UK is expecting the arrival of thousands more asylum seekers in small boats, and has announced numerous plans to move undocumented migrants to unused military bases and large accommodation barges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UK Home Office figures showed that more than 11,000 people have made the Channel crossing so far in 2023, including about 3,300 this month amid warm weather.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sunday, June 11 saw the highest number of crossings on a single day this year, with 549 people making the risky Channel journey on dinghies and old fishing boats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asylum seekers seem undeterred by a UK Conservative government pledge to “stop the boats” and send some illegal arrivals to Rwanda. Last year, an unprecedented 45,755 people were recorded making the Channel crossing from France. That is up from 28,000 in 2021 and 8,500 people in 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around half of those seeking to come to the UK are from conflict zones, with Afghanistan topping the list. While a surge in Albanians last year has since declined, Indians are among recent arrivals, according to the Home Office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The European Union is the other favoured destination for asylum seekers crossing the Mediterranean, the most dangerous migrant sea route in the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Protesters denounce UK plan to halt migrants&#39; Channel crossings&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the UK, tens of thousands of asylum seekers are staying in temporary accommodation while awaiting a decision on their claims, which can take years. Accommodation includes hotels, which costs British taxpayers almost £6 million (US$7.5 million) a day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With stopping the small boats a flagship policy, the government of Prime Minister Rishi Sunak wants to end its reliance on hotels to save money and deter more asylum seekers from coming. By the end of this year, Channel arrivals since 2020 would total more than 125,000, if 2023 figures match last year&#39;s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the plans face resistance from both human rights groups and local authorities. A proposal to dock a cruise ship for asylum seekers near Liverpool was scrapped due to objections from local authorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An idea to place a vessel at London&#39;s Royal Docks was pulled after it was opposed by the Royal Docks management authority and the mayor of London&#39;s office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;London&#39;s Labour Mayor Sadiq Khan said this month: “Vulnerable people fleeing appalling circumstances would not have access to the support they need”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A plan announced in April to dock the Bibby Stockholm barge for at least 18 months at Dorset port in the south coast of England is running weeks behind schedule as the vessel is refitted. Anti-terrorist police have carried out unexplained exercises where it is to be docked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The barge has 222 bedrooms and would accommodate 500 single male asylum seekers. The plan has been met with opposition by the Conservative-run Dorset Council and local Conservative MP Richard Drax.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When they leave the port – if indeed they can get out, because this barge will be nothing more than a quasi-prison – when they go into Weymouth (the nearest town), what will they do? Who will monitor them?” Drax said of asylum seekers on LBC radio this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asylum seekers are not allowed to work in the UK or choose where they live. Human rights groups have said barges were not appropriate for people fleeing conflict or hardship.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There has also been opposition to plans to move thousands of migrants to barracks at old Royal Air Force (RAF) bases.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UK aims to deter Albanian refugees with &#39;make clear the perils&#39; ad campaign&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“It is clear that the government&#39;s use of disused barracks and airbases is driven by the need to pander to the lowest common denominator in society – to those who see asylum seekers not as fellow human beings, but as somehow &#39;the other&#39;,” said Steve Smith, chief executive of the UK-based refugee charity Care4Calais.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest Home Office proposal is to house asylum seekers in huge marquees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Liberal Democrat-led council is trying to block proposals for facilities at RAF Scampton, in Lincolnshire.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some asylum seekers are already staying at the RAF base in Wethersfield, Essex, where there has been demonstrations from angry locals bolstered by far-right groups. The area&#39;s Conservative MP, Britain&#39;s immigration minister Robert Jenrick, has found himself at odds with local party members who are threatening to sue the government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While the abandoned military facilities once housed British troops, they have long been left vacant and fallen into disrepair, verging on dereliction,” Smith said. “The combination of visible security measures, shared living quarters and isolation from the wider community results in accommodation that is wholly unsuitable for survivors of war, conflict, torture, trafficking and persecution.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of asylum applicants increased from 40,830 in 2020 to 133,607 as of March 31 this year, according to government figures. The opposition Labour Party blames staff cuts and recruitment problems at the Home Office as the main reasons for the backlog.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A fundamental problem not being adequately addressed is the asylum backlog where we have a situation where the number of people waiting for asylum to be granted or refused has spiralled,” said Robert McNeil, deputy director at Oxford University&#39;s Migration Observatory.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Immigration was a major issue leading up to Brexit in 2016, which resulted in the UK ending the free movement of people from the EU.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UK plans curbs on foreign students amid immigration furore&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Still, net migration hit a record 606,000 in 2022, as student numbers surged and the UK granted visas for people fleeing the war in Ukraine and British National (Overseas) passport holders from Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;London&#39;s fast-track residency scheme, launched two years ago, has seen at least 105,200 Hongkongers arrive in the UK, according to the British government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To stem the flow of what it deems illegal arrivals, Sunak&#39;s Conservative government has proposed sending some migrants who arrive in the UK in small boats to Rwanda, where their asylum claims would be processed. Those granted asylum would stay in the African country rather than return to Britain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Illegal Migration Bill is currently in the House of Lords. It has been labelled “cruel and nasty” by the Refugee Council, and become mired in legal challenges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The British government has argued that its deportation policy will deter people-smuggling gangs who ferry migrants across the Channel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Policymakers promising solutions to these problems are being slightly disingenuous because they do not have the tools to solve them. These are intractable scenarios that cannot be solved by national policy alone,” McNeil said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The passage to the UK is often the last leg of long and dangerous journeys highlighted by the tragic sinking of a migrant vessel off the coast of Greece on June 14. Hundreds of people are thought to have been on board when the boat went down after departing Libya.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eight days later, a migrant boat that sailed from Tunisia capsized off the Italian island of Lampedusa, leaving more than 40 people missing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United Nations has recorded more than 21,000 deaths and disappearances in the central Mediterranean since 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brussels has put the blame on people-smuggling gangs, but many NGOs and rights groups blame “Fortress Europe” policies that have highlighted the lack of legal pathways refugees faced in seeking protection in Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the UK the issue of “small boats” has become the bugbear of the right-wing of the Conservative Party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But there were 21 countries in Europe that took in more asylum seekers than the UK in 2022. The UK (74,751) trailed Germany (296,555), France (170,705), and Spain (128,015), according to the Home Office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The UK government cannot continue to use the country&#39;s island status to avoid its international responsibility to protect refugees,” Smith said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[First US M&A reforms in 45 years will crack down on illegal mergers but also delay deals by months]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3225650/first-us-ma-reforms-45-years-will-crack-down-illegal-mergers-also-delay-deals-months?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 10:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/967d8934-dc86-4325-810f-484bbffb3af7_13aff7b2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The US antitrust agencies are requiring firms to turn over much more information about their transactions than before in an overhaul to merger rules that could delay deals by months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The revamp of the so-called Hart-Scott-Rodino filing process, a move by the Justice Department and the Federal Trade Commission to crack down on illegal mergers, could add as much as two to three months to the timetable for deals, according to one estimate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agencies say the overhaul, the first in 45 years, will allow them to “more effectively and efficiently screen transactions” for antitrust concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The proposed changes, released on Tuesday for publication in the Federal Register later this week, require details about acquisitions during the previous 10 years, information on company officers, directors and board observers, in addition to data on the firms&#39; workforce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agencies will take public comments on the proposed changes for 60 days. The new rules will not go into effect until after the FTC and DOJ publish a final version, which is expected to take several months to complete.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new filings also would require disclosure of subsidies such as grants and loans by certain foreign governments including North Korea, China, Russia, and Iran. Congress passed a law in December requiring the agencies to begin collecting information on foreign government subsidies amid concerns that countries like China could distort competition by offering financial support to some firms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The FTC estimated the new requirements laid out in the 126-page document would add more than 100 hours to the time it takes for firms to prepare their filings, which they said currently takes about 37 hours to complete.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Bloomberg Intelligence senior analyst Jennifer Rie said companies are likely to need much longer than that to compile all the information and analysis the agencies will now be seeking. Today, a law firm can complete paperwork for companies seeking antitrust approval to merge in seven to 10 days, said Rie. The proposed changes could add months to that process, bringing the US merger filing regime more in line with Europe&#39;s, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re looking at changing something from a 10-day process to a two-to-three month process,” said Rie, who practised antitrust law for 10 years before joining Bloomberg Intelligence.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;CK Hutchison, Vodafone to merge units to form UK&#39;s biggest mobile provider&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Antitrust advocates praised the changes as a much-needed update that will help enforcers better investigate deals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The merger and acquisition landscape has shifted dramatically in the past 45 years, and the HSR filing process – a key part of merger review – should reflect that,” said Krista Brown of the antimonopoly group American Economic Liberties Project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under US law, deals valued at more than US$111.4 million must notify the FTC and DOJ and wait 30 days before closing. The vast majority of mergers raise no concerns and are finalised after the initial waiting period expires. But the agencies can ask for additional information, triggering an in-depth investigation of the deal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of the 3,520 transactions reported in fiscal 2021, the last year for which the agencies have published data, the FTC and DOJ asked for more information in 65 of them, or about 1.9 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What next for HSBC after stopping Ping An from carving up top Hong Kong lender?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Today&#39;s filings mostly require one- and two-word responses, said Bloomberg&#39;s Rie, whereas the new proposal would ask companies to provide narrative summaries of the transaction and outline business areas where the firms compete.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It creates a lot more likelihood that deals aren&#39;t going to fly under the radar,” she said. “You are laying out competitive overlaps for them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An FTC official said the revamp is intended to help preserve agency resources and cut down on the need to ask for more documents or information during the first 30 days. The US agencies consulted with other jurisdictions, including the European Union, the UK and Canada, to see what information they require about deals up front, said the person, who was not authorised to speak on the record.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US agencies do not believe that the new form will change the number of deals that draw in-depth probes, said the official. But they anticipate the beefed-up form may lead to fewer so-called pull-and-refiles, the person said, referring to a commonly used technique where companies withdraw their paperwork and submit a second time to give the FTC or DOJ an additional 30 days to decide whether to pursue a longer review.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, the agencies moved to a graduated fee system with the smallest deals paying US$30,000 for their merger reviews while the largest ones must pay US$2.25 million.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>