<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Virgin Galactic takes its first paying customers to space]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3226000/virgin-galactic-takes-its-first-paying-customers-space?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 01:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/d5199881-bdfd-4df7-915f-73b6c8664f5e_5ea24b0c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;维珍银河周四成功将其第一批付费客户飞往最后的边境，这是一个长期的边境期待已久的成就，使其在新兴的私人太空飞行领域重回正轨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意大利空军军官展开国家国旗，向窗外凝视地球的曲率，同时在 85 公里（52 英里）的高度享受几分钟的失重状态。英里）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“欢迎来到太空，宇航员，”维珍银河的 Sirisha Bandla 在直播中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被称为“银河 01”的任务开始于一个巨大的双胞胎 -当地时间上午8.30左右，机身“母舰”飞机从新墨西哥州美国太空港的跑道起飞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运载机升到高空，大约40分钟后释放了一架火箭动力飞机，称为 VSS Unity，以近 3 马赫的速度飞入太空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国宇航局和美国空军将 80 公里（50 英里）视为太空边界，尽管国际公认的边界称为“太空边界”。卡门线，高 100 公里（约 60 英里）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;航天飞机机舱内有意大利空军的 Walter Villadei 上校和 Angelo Landolfi 中校、意大利国家研究委员会的 Pantaleone Carlucci 和 Colin维珍银河的贝内特。太空飞机上还有两名飞行员，舰载机上还有两名飞行员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直播显示 Unity 随后安全滑翔回地球。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;维珍银河的理查德·布兰森 (Richard Branson) 进行了历史性的太空飞行&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;这次飞行是在维珍银河创始人理查德布兰森进行太空试飞近两年后进行的，旨在开启利润丰厚的太空旅游新时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但该公司随后面临挫折，包括美国联邦航空管理局 (FAA) 短暂停飞，该管理局发现布兰森航班偏离了指定空域，而维珍银河没有按照要求通报这一“事故”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来，实验室测试表明某些情况其飞行器中使用的材料已低于所需的强度裕度，因此需要对机队进行升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司通过 5 月份的一次成功测试结束了太空飞行暂停，为周四的任务铺平了道路。在周四的商业飞行之前，它总共进行了五次试飞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;银河 01 机组人员的任务是进行 13 项监督和自主实验，并收集其套装和机舱内传感器的数据。实验包括测量未充分研究的中间层的辐射水平，以及某些液体和固体在微重力下如何混合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;维珍银河成立于 2004 年，已售出约 800 张未来商业航班座位的机票 - 2005 年期间售出 600 张2014 年，票价为 20 万美元至 25 万美元，此后又增加了 200 个，每人票价为 45 万美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;电影明星和名人是最先抢购座位的人，但该公司的计划在 2014 年遭遇了灾难，当时一架太空飞机在一次试飞中，飞机在空中解体，导致副驾驶死亡，飞行员重伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司现在正在展望未来。下一个任务“银河 02”计划于 8 月进行，之后它希望每月进行一次太空跳跃。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;维珍银河重新开始太空票销售，新价格为 45 万美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;维珍银河在“亚轨道”太空旅游领域与亿万富翁杰夫·贝佐斯的公司蓝色起源展开竞争，该公司已使用垂直升空火箭将 32 人送入太空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但自 2022 年 9 月发生事故以来在一次无人驾驶飞行中，蓝色起源的火箭已停飞。该公司在 3 月份承诺很快恢复太空飞行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 的 SpaceX 已与合作伙伴公司合作，将付费客户送入更高的轨道、地球轨道或国际空间站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但是租用 SpaceX 火箭的成本要高得多。据报道，SpaceX-Axiom Space 联合任务中国际空间站的门票价格高达数千万美元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Wagner mutiny shows China’s ‘no limits’ partnership with Russia is a risky bet]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3225795/wagner-mutiny-shows-chinas-no-limits-partnership-russia-risky-bet?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 00:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/77b626fe-1a02-43f8-909f-1a2eb4e96133_0cdeb780.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;由其首领和金融家叶夫根尼·普里戈任向中国国家主席习近平发出了明确信号：中国与弗拉基米尔·普京领导下的修正主义俄罗斯建立“无限制”伙伴关系，双方旨在制衡美国及其西方盟友，这是一个冒险的赌注。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰战争一直在削弱俄罗斯的地缘政治、军事和经济潜力。正如许多观察家所预料的那样，普京军事冒险的影响也在俄罗斯国内感受到。普里戈任率私人部队发起武装攻势，逼近莫斯科200公里，这表明俄罗斯在乌克兰的军事屡屡受挫而引发的俄罗斯内战不再令人难以置信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被西方边缘化由于对乌克兰的侵略，受内部不稳定和政治内斗影响的俄罗斯无法发挥重要的国际作用。莫斯科与西方的对抗尤其如此，这是中国与克里姆林宫接触的主要焦点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，俄罗斯国际影响力减弱的初步迹象正在显现。上周，哈萨克斯坦表示将停止主持俄罗斯、叙利亚、土耳其和伊朗之间旨在解决叙利亚冲突的讨论，据报道此举令克里姆林宫感到惊讶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这表明，即使是俄罗斯的传统合作伙伴，例如叙利亚，后苏联时代的中亚国家对继续卷入俄罗斯地缘政治动态的前景越来越感到不安。中亚领导人从一开始就对普京对乌克兰的军事行动持怀疑态度，并且越来越倾向于与中国建立政治和经济关系，他们避免公开评论俄罗斯局势并非偶然。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;如果俄罗斯继续对内衰弱，它将无法向海外投射力量，甚至在其传统后院也将失去影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了中亚之外，莫斯科正在让步土耳其、以色列、印度、欧盟和美国等国家在南高加索地区的战略地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，亚美尼亚和阿塞拜疆之间持续的领土紧张局势自普京袭击乌克兰以来不断加剧，有可能破坏俄罗斯与伊朗的伙伴关系。德黑兰传统上支持亚美尼亚遏制阿塞拜疆的军事扩张，而因乌克兰战争而分心的俄罗斯可能无法遏制阿塞拜疆试图确保通往土耳其领土的陆地走廊的安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可能还有更多的事情要做。来。普里戈任和他的瓦格纳集团的不确定命运可能会危及普京在非洲施加影响的计划，他的前盟友的私人军事公司在非洲拥有重大利益。在非洲大陆，中国可能会看到其在那里的经济利益受到威胁，更不用说北京将不得不向其非洲伙伴解释为什么它会继续下去。支持俄罗斯总统这样的破坏稳定的行为者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国通常对其他国家的国内危机采取谨慎立场。 6月25日，俄罗斯副外长鲁登科在北京会见中国外交部长秦刚后，中国外交部发表简短声明，称瓦格纳叛乱是内部问题，“中方支持俄罗斯维护国家稳定”。声明中没有明确提及普京，可以解读为反映了中国领导层对俄罗斯总统处理国内发生的事件以及与乌克兰冲突的方式感到失望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是在北京的声明中克里姆林宫最高领导层能够确保俄罗斯国家的顺利运转、领土完整以及相应的核武器库的控制，这符合根本利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯内战将世界经济进一步不稳定，对正在应对国内经济挑战的中国来说前景黯淡。例如，如果内部混乱蔓延到东西伯利亚和俄罗斯远东地区，也将危及通过西伯利亚力量天然气管道和东西伯利亚-太平洋石油管道向中国供应化石燃料。俄罗斯热衷于推进第二条西伯利亚力量管道向中国输送天然气，但不稳定可能会威胁到该项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果中国政府只是被怀疑在重新调整与中国的特殊关系方面犹豫不决在克里姆林宫，一些中国企业已经在对冲俄罗斯市场的风险。周六瓦格纳集团叛乱的消息开始流传后，据报道中国南方的几家公司停止了向俄罗斯运送货物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着俄罗斯入侵乌克兰，美国已将部分注意力和资源从乌克兰转移。台湾海峡和中国海域到东欧，这是北京不想失去的战术优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对中国来说最好的情况是普京牢牢掌权。由于这种情况并不确定，北京需要制定 B 计划，至少试图遏制普京政权可能崩溃的溢出效应。对于中国领导层来说，与“一带一路”倡议和上海合作组织的合作伙伴，特别是土耳其、伊朗和中亚共和国合作，在俄罗斯边境建立某种警戒线似乎是一个更可行的选择。 p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s yuan to remain under pressure amid stalling economic recovery, as central bank weighs moves to stem weakness]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3225974/chinas-yuan-remain-under-pressure-amid-stalling-economic-recovery-central-bank-weighs-moves-stem?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/25ca2000-f0ed-4c00-832b-f6bcd853ef98_0a5f421c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国的人民币在未来几周可能面临更大的压力，引发人们的疑问央行是否会进行干预以支持人民币，自今年年初以来，人民币兑美元汇率已贬值4.7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人民币兑美元汇率在周四再次下跌，此前人民币兑美元汇率已跌至周三触及七个月低点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，中国人民银行 (PBOC) 将每日中间价设定为强于预期，市场参与者将其视为遏制疲软的官方尝试。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;交易员密切关注央行的每日中间价设定，他们普遍将官方利率与其预测之间的偏差视为央行对外汇市场立场的标志。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们东北证券周四表示：“我们认为，尽管未来一段时间内人民币汇率可能会维持波动，但贬值势头将逐渐减弱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国经济复苏慢于预期分析师表示，人民币兑美元走软以及两国利差的关键驱动因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这只是反映了一个基本的经济事实，即中国的经济连续增长央行全球首席经济学家管涛表示：“今年一季度增速见顶，但现在正处于环比下滑的过程中，市场难免会感到复苏陷入停滞。”中国国际的董事、前中国外汇官员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民银行迄今为止没有直接干预外汇市场以稳定人民币汇率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;管相信央行会采取“有针对性的方式”稳定预期，甚至“一些模糊的利好消息”也可能给市场信心带来更大的提振。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东北证券分析师表示，如果人民币贬值“太快”，中央银行可能会将其所谓的反周期因子纳入每日定价中，这实际上给利率带来了偏差。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民银行还可以提高银行的外汇风险准备金率，以及发行人民币票据东北证券补充称，“央行态度的改变可以扭转汇率市场的贬值预期”。总部位于金融服务公司的人士表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;人民币升值的贸易用途都是空谈。俄罗斯将给予美元右臂&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，随着中国推动人民币在国际上的使用，海外出口商也纷纷抛售人民币，以换取更多可兑换货币，例如美元和人民币。观察人士称，欧元走强，人民币进一步贬值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯央行及其财政部自今年年初以来一直在抛售人民币，以弥补西方国家造成的收入缺口。入侵乌克兰后的制裁对重要的石油和天然气出口造成了打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，俄罗斯财政部表示将每天出售价值 36 亿卢布（4200 万美元）的外币。 6 月 7 日和 7 月 6 日，日常业务量较上月有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科已表示将出售人民币，而不是所谓的“不友好”西方货币，突显了人民币日益增长的重要性尽管受到制裁，人民币仍能确保俄罗斯的经济稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柬埔寨合作与和平研究所高级客座研究员陈亨利表示，北京有能力稳定人民币汇率，因为中国有能力世界上最大的外汇储备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果中国不能支持其货币，所有货币都会失败，”他说。 “所以，如果中国想要支持，它肯定可以。但如果不支持，别人就会继续抛售[人民币]。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国现在最缺的可能就是对经济的信心，这个很难处理。”&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Putin seeks to project business-as-usual image as Wagner mutiny questions linger]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3225998/putin-seeks-project-business-usual-image-wagner-mutiny-questions-linger?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 23:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/2f9ea318-f646-4a49-80c1-60849b628c6c_54f2eef9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;弗拉基米尔·普京总统继续努力重申其权威，并表现出一切如常的感觉瓦格纳雇佣兵的叛变威胁到了他在俄罗斯近四分之一个世纪的统治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京定于周四在莫斯科举行的一个名为“新时代的强创意”的论坛上发表讲话，该论坛是一年一度的活动，其在瓦格纳领导人叶夫根尼·普里戈任的军队在距首都 200 公里（124 英里）范围内发动叛乱后，这个头衔具有了意想不到的象征意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的评论将受到密切关注，以了解是否涉及最近发生的事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;总统连夜从俄罗斯南部达吉斯坦共和国返回莫斯科，在那里他与地区官员就促进旅游业发展进行了会谈。尽管一名官员感谢普京“在如此困难的时刻”到访，但并未提及周六的叛变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不同寻常的是，国家电视台显示普京与欢呼的当地居民混在一起，甚至亲吻了一名年轻女孩的头部并摆出姿势与她合影。这与克里姆林宫长期以来对任何与普京会面的人实行严格的Covid-19隔离制度形成鲜明对比，以避免这位70岁的领导人可能受到感染。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管努力描绘叛变危机截至最后，关于军队和安全部门内部人员在多大程度上了解普里戈任计划进军莫斯科推翻国防部高级官员的问题仍然悬而未决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦格纳的全副武装的部队首先控制了俄罗斯南部城市顿河畔罗斯托夫，然后跨越780公里领土迅速向莫斯科进军，沿途封锁了军队部队，没有遇到重大抵抗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任只是叫停了前进在接受白俄罗斯总统亚历山大·卢卡申科斡旋的一项协议后，在对瓦格纳创始人或其战士的刑事指控被撤销后，他可以前往邻国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;令人眼花缭乱的一系列事件已经离开了美国、欧洲中国对一场叛乱造成的政治后果感到困惑，这场叛乱粉碎了普京作为俄罗斯领导人的不可战胜的形象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这场危机凸显了俄罗斯内部因乌克兰战争而存在的激烈分歧，乌克兰战争是二战以来欧洲最大的冲突，乌克兰的反攻继续试图将普京的军队赶出被占领土。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US Supreme Court curbs affirmative action in university admissions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225996/us-supreme-court-ends-affirmative-action-university-admissions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 22:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/7912c8bb-5ee9-489a-b92f-f09949a1fe1e_f0dbb69b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国最高法院周四驳回了哈佛大学具有种族意识的学生招生计划和北卡罗来纳大学的平权行动政策遭受了严重挫折，这些政策通常用于增加校园中黑人、西班牙裔和其他代表性不足的少数群体的数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官做出了有利于一个名为“由反平权行动活动家爱德华·布鲁姆 (Edward Blum) 创立的“学生公平招生”组织，对下级法院维持两所著名学校为培养多元化学生群体而使用的项目的裁决提出上诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该决定由法院的保守派法官与持不同意见的自由派法官，以 6 比 3 战胜北卡罗来纳大学，以 6 比 2 战胜哈佛大学。自由派法官 Ketanji Brown Jackson 没有参与哈佛案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在去年同样由保守派法官牵头的重大裁决中，法院推翻了 1973 年罗伊诉韦德案的裁决，该裁决使堕胎在全国范围内合法化并扩大了枪支范围两项具有里程碑意义的裁决中的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首席大法官约翰·罗伯茨（John Roberts）代表多数派撰文表示，“哈佛和北卡罗来纳大学的招生计划无法与平等保护条款的保证相一致”，他指的是美国宪法的承诺法律下的平等保护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与此同时，”罗伯茨说，“正如各方都同意的那样，本意见中的任何内容均不应被解释为禁止大学考虑申请人关于种族如何影响的讨论布鲁姆的团队在 2014 年提起的诉讼中指控北卡罗来纳大学歧视白人和亚裔美国申请者，以及哈佛大学对亚裔美国申请者存在偏见。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学生公平招生组织声称，公立大学北卡罗来纳大学采取的非种族中立的招生政策违反了宪法第十四修正案对法律平等保护的保证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;该组织认为哈佛大学是一所私立大学，违反了具有里程碑意义的联邦法律《1964 年民权法案》第六章，该法案禁止在接受联邦财政援助的任何计划或活动中基于种族、肤色或国籍的歧视。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;许多高等教育机构、企业和军队领导人长期以来一直支持校园平权行动，不仅是为了纠正美国生活中的种族不平等和排斥现象，也是为了确保人才库能够为工作场所带来多种观点和美国武装部队军衔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据哈佛大学的数据，大约 40% 的美国学院和大学以某种方式考虑种族问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈佛大学和北卡罗来纳大学表示，他们仅将种族问题视为一个因素考虑到对无配额录取的一系列个性化评估（最高法院之前的判例是允许的），并且限制其考虑将导致代表性不足群体的学生入学率大幅下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国的平权行动大学不公平，尤其是对亚裔美国人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;几十年来一直试图推翻这些政策的批评者认为，这些政策本身就是歧视性的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多美国保守派和共和党民选官员认为无论动机或情况如何，给予某一种族优势都是违宪的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些人提出了不再需要补救性优惠的论点，因为美国已经超越了过去的种族主义政策，例如种族隔离和变得越来越多样化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这场纠纷为最高法院的保守派多数派提供了推翻其先前允许种族意识招生政策的裁决的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下级法院驳回了该组织的主张，引发了上诉向美国最高法院要求法官推翻一个重要先例，即大学可以将种族作为招生过程中的一个因素，因为创建多元化的学生群体具有迫切的兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“没有解决这个问题问题：马来西亚的土著政策，五十年来&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;平权行动几十年来经受住了最高法院的审查，最近一次是在 2016 年一项涉及一名白人学生的裁决中，该裁决得到了布鲁姆的支持，布鲁姆在被起诉后起诉了德克萨斯大学&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最高法院自 2016 年以来向右转，现在包括对德克萨斯大学案件持异议的三名法官以及前共和党总统唐纳德·特朗普任命的三名新法官。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 23:20:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU leaders debate Russia mutiny, pledge support for Ukraine]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225995/eu-leaders-debate-russia-mutiny-pledge-support-ukraine?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 22:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/2ec92234-ecbd-47f6-bd3e-64c53e263ac3_52cff515.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧盟领导人周四齐聚一堂，讨论俄罗斯流产的兵变，并讨论其角色欧盟可以履行西方加强乌克兰安全的长期承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领导人在抵达布鲁塞尔参加峰会时表示，他们仍然致力于支持乌克兰应对去年 2 月俄罗斯入侵其邻国引发的战争德国总理奥拉夫·肖尔茨 (Olaf Scholz) 对记者表示：“我们必须做好准备，这种情况会持续很长时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“重要的是，我们要进行磋商并表示我们正在准备长期坚持下去，提供乌克兰所必需的财政和人道主义支持，而且在武器方面也是如此。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北约秘书长延斯·斯托尔滕贝格与领导人共进工作午餐并预计乌克兰总统泽连斯基也将通过视频连线在峰会上发表讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为期两天的峰会是欧盟 27 国领导人的定期聚会，议题包括移民、经济安全和关系等一系列议题与中国的一切都提上了议程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但主要话题是乌克兰战争，领导人还讨论了上周末瓦格纳雇佣军组织流产的叛变可能如何影响俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;领导人表示，他们将密切关注瓦格纳领导人叶夫根尼·普里戈任被流放的白俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些人还表示，兵变削弱了普京的实力，但这并不意味着西方可以放松。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“普京的削弱是一个更大的危险，”欧盟外交政策负责人何塞普·博雷尔表示。 “不稳定的俄罗斯也会成为一种风险。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多领导人强调，叛乱是俄罗斯内部事务，无论如何，欧盟都应该继续支持乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着西方国家制定一揽子长期保证措施，向基辅提供武器、装备、弹药、训练和其他军事援助，这种援助也在布鲁塞尔的谈判桌上提出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;峰会结论草案表示欧盟及其成员国已准备好为未来对乌克兰的安全承诺做出贡献，“帮助乌克兰长期保卫自己，威慑侵略行为并抵制破坏稳定的努力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交官们表示，法国 –欧盟发挥更大安全作用的拥护者提出了该文本，称其想法是建立在欧盟举措的基础上，例如为基辅提供军事援助的基金和乌克兰士兵的培训任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但该案文引起了奥地利、爱尔兰、马耳他和塞浦路斯等军事上不结盟的欧盟成员国以及波罗的海国家等跨大西洋合作坚定支持者的担忧，这些国家坚称欧洲安全主要是北约的事务。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯的高级将领在哪里？瓦格纳叛变后谣言四起&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“对于我们作为中立国来说，很明显我们不能提供这样的安全保证。奥地利、爱尔兰、马耳他和塞浦路斯已明确表示反对，”奥地利总理卡尔·内哈默在参加峰会的路上说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们肯定会讨论这个问题，我们会找到可以接受的方案对我们来说也是如此。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括美国、英国、法国和德国在内的国家正在讨论下个月在立陶宛维尔纽斯举行的北约峰会之前为乌克兰提供的可能的安全保证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;荷兰首相马克·吕特表示，欧盟的任何角色仍有待讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须讨论它能走多远，以及是致命还是非致命支持。我们必须考虑到一些欧盟国家不是北约成员国。”吕特说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰：基辅指控当地男子指挥导弹袭击，造成 10 人死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;同时，在有报道称俄罗斯瓦格纳雇佣兵计划转移到邻国白俄罗斯后，波兰计划加强其东部边境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;波兰副总理雅罗斯瓦夫·卡钦斯基周三晚间表示，将增加军装部队和“保护防御工事” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卡钦斯基是在政府安全与国防问题委员会特别会议后发表上述评论的。他援引波兰情报称，多达 8,000 名瓦格纳战士可以在白俄罗斯寻求庇护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;波兰是欧盟和北约成员国，与白俄罗斯有 418 公里（260 英里）的边界。 2021 年夏末和秋季，边境局势升级，数千人试图非法进入欧盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟指责白俄罗斯领导人亚历山大·卢卡申科将移民从危机地区带到欧盟有组织地对外边界向西方施压。此后，波兰在边境陆地部分安装了 5.5 米高的围栏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任周六暂时占领了俄罗斯南部城市顿河畔罗斯托夫，然后率领他的战士前往莫斯科，瓦格纳首领与莫斯科军事领导层之间长期酝酿的权力斗争升级。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;距离俄罗斯首都约200公里，武装起义突然中止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢卡申科据称，普里戈任调解了这次叛变，据报道，普里戈任和他的雇佣兵承诺免受俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京的起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据卢卡申科称，普里戈任现在在白俄罗斯。白俄罗斯强人还允许雇佣军战士进入他的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德新社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Global recruitment effort by Hong Kong to ease hospital staffing problems shows healthy results with 20 veteran specialists already signed up]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3225994/global-recruitment-effort-hong-kong-ease-hospital-staffing-problems-shows-healthy-results-20-veteran?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/29/eca151da-056f-433b-919b-4ce931426a9c_efdc2d8a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;20名专家获批到香港公立医院进行短期交流卫生主管表示，这是一项新的全球人才计划的一部分，旨在帮助缓解城市医生的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次招聘活动是在该市公立医院的医疗保健专业人员继续保持高流动性的情况下进行的。过去一年，超过 450 名护士流失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但医院管理局周四表示，将继续加大全球招聘力度，以解决人员短缺问题，其中包括一项新的全球医疗保健人才计划，该计划已经吸引了20位来自欧洲、东南亚和中国内地的资深专家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构主席范鸿龄解释说，这些专家预计将在城市医院工作一到两年，以加强&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所有来港工作的医生都必须获得医务委员会的有限注册，这将确保”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范补充说，退伍军人不会占用城市医务人员的专科培训名额或晋升机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，医生将获得与同等资质的城市工作人员薪资待遇相同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范透露，截至4月下旬，过去12个月内已有超过2,450名护士加入公立医院，但约有2,900人离开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同期，医生的人员配置情况稍好一些，新增528人，留下449人，增加了79人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;护士的流失率为10.9%，医生的流失率为7.1%，范表示。补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“情况并不理想。虽然我们竭尽全力招募更多医生，但如果失去这么多护士，我们就无法保持平衡。”他承认&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们欢迎政府提出限制护士注册的建议，并会走向海外一旦法案在立法会获得通过，就会立即招募人才。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;作为招聘竞标的一部分，香港向英国医生提供了超过 130 个工作机会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据该提案，未在香港接受过培训的护士无需通过执照考试即可在香港工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们可以进行有限注册工作，这将允许他们在香港担任职位nursing schools or care homes, or with a special registration, which would clear them for jobs in public healthcare settings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities earlier flew to the United Kingdom and Australia to recruit doctors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Fan revealed a total of 59 doctors from the UK had been selected, and would join city hospitals in the second half of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He earlier said that more than 100 conditional offers were made on their previous trip to London.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fan added there were also 45 conditional offers given to Australian doctors and the authorities would start the selection process soon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hospital Authority also introduced a low-interest home loan scheme late last year to help retain qualified staff and had already received more than 1,100 applications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Successful applicants were given in-principle approval this month, which meant they could start house hunting.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; Hong Kong nursing body to decide eligibility criteria for new scheme: health chief&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“More than half of the applications came from positions with a high turnover rate, and the average age of the applicants ranged from 37 to 42 – the prime years,” Fan said. “This showed that the measure is effective in retaining talent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Employees who have worked with the authority for three years or more can borrow up to HK$6 million (US$766,026), or four times their annual salary, with a maximum repayment period of 20 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fan said the extension of the retirement age from 60 to 65 was well-received and 65 doctors and 241 nurses who would have retired next year had opted to stay on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They accounted for 84 per cent of doctors scheduled to retire and 51 per cent of nurses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While we strive to recruit talent globally, the local staff remain the core of the system as the number of people we recruited overseas could never compare to that of local workers,” Fan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The staff morale will not be affected either, as they are here to help, to relieve the workload, not to interrupt them.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Don’t ‘act blindly’ on Taiwan: Beijing should resist US pressure and stay own course, policy influencer says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3225969/dont-act-blindly-taiwan-beijing-should-resist-us-pressure-and-stay-own-course-policy-influencer-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/b3efd15f-261d-4c80-96d7-5fa9c1789bd1_77b7e943.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing should avoid acting blindly on Taiwan in the face of increasing pressure from the US, according to Sun Yafu, a former mainland official and influential figure for Beijing&#39;s Taiwan policy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun said mainland China was “facing more severe and complex challenges and risks” in cross-strait ties, and “high winds” and “even turbulent waves” were “still highly possible” – an apparent reference to the possibility of a military conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He made the speech during a forum on Taiwan issues in eastern Zhejiang province on Wednesday, with the speech published on the social media account of a cross-strait studies journal on the same day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun is deputy head of the Association for Relations Across the Taiwan Strait, Beijing&#39;s semi-official group for handling cross-strait matters.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Shoot them down&#39;: Taiwan vows to destroy &#39;risky&#39; mainland Chinese balloons&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The body was created in 1991 as an unofficial representative of the mainland Chinese government in its dealings with Taipei, which has a similar group for dealing with Beijing. The groups were established so the island and the mainland could interact without the official endorsement of the other side&#39;s government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun served as deputy head of the mainland&#39;s Taiwan Affairs Office from 2004 to 2013 and remains deeply involved in Beijing&#39;s policymaking.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the current situation where opponents are surrounded and pressure is increasing, we should neither be anxious nor act blindly … We should not be shaken by increased pressure,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[We should] adhere to the direction and efforts of peaceful reunification, and at the same time strengthen preparations for military struggle.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun&#39;s remarks offered a rare look into Beijing&#39;s strategic and tactical thinking when it comes to handling its strained ties with Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Military tensions have grown since Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen of the independence-leaning Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) came to power in 2016. Sun said the situation became “more severe” in 2021, after the US used the Taiwan issue to suppress China and “create a war atmosphere” in the strait.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing sees the self-ruled island as a breakaway province that must be reunited with the mainland – by force if necessary. Most countries, including the United States, do not recognise Taiwan as an independent state, but Washington opposes any use of force to change the status quo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington has accused Beijing in recent years of ratcheting up military pressure on Taiwan and speeding up its reunification plan, with some US officials speculating that the People&#39;s Liberation Army (PLA) could have the capacity to take the island by 2027.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Taiwan Strait situation has undergone the biggest change since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and the United States in 1979,” Sun said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He blamed a shift in Washington&#39;s stance towards Beijing – from “a force that it could rely on” to its “biggest strategic competitor” – as the root of the present tensions and why the US “had to beat China down”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Beijing and Washington have clashed over a wide range of issues, with Taiwan among the most sensitive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his speech, Sun followed Beijing&#39;s official line, saying the US was mobilising its allies in the Asia-Pacific region, engaging in “military coercion” against the mainland and supporting the DPP in “speeding up war preparations”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Support for Taiwan&#39;s Tsai at 4-year low as #MeToo scandals rock ruling party&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Sun said frequent visits by US officials to the island aimed to “inflame war sentiment”, adding that Washington had upgraded its military support for the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since August, when then US House speaker Nancy Pelosi visited Taiwan, Beijing has conducted two major rounds of military exercises near the island and its warplanes have frequently crossed into Taiwan&#39;s air defence identification zone (ADIZ).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun said the mainland insisted that peaceful reunification was best and that “the use of force is the last resort when no alternative has been left”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing introduced its Anti-Secession Law in 2005 to create a legal framework for it to use non-peaceful means to guard against pro-independence forces in Taiwan and the island&#39;s possible separation from mainland China. But Beijing has remained vague about when and under what circumstances the law would be invoked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun called on Beijing to take the initiative in opposing foreign interference, noting that the US and its allies “have challenged the rule that resolving the Taiwan issue is China&#39;s internal affair to create an excuse for its armed intervention”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said Beijing should maintain “strategic confidence, strategic composure and strategic initiative” over the Taiwan issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We stand firmly on the moral high ground when it comes to national reunification,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Striving for peaceful reunification is not only to serve the needs of the overall national development strategy, but also our moral duty for national stability and the unity of compatriots.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech War: US chip restrictions dominate debate among Chinese semiconductor veterans at Semicon industry conference]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3225986/tech-war-us-chip-restrictions-dominate-debate-among-chinese-semiconductor-veterans-semicon-industry?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/076f9a77-8986-48a3-9bf8-1780b0ce0314_08d31115.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The looming possibility of greater US chip restrictions, and the worsening of semiconductor supply chain disruptions, has become the dominant topic among Chinese chip experts at an industry forum in Shanghai, where some experts declared “globalisation is dead”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Industry insiders shared their concerns at the Semicon China conference in Shanghai on Thursday about interruptions to the semiconductor supply chain as Washington reportedly considers further tightening its export controls to slow the flow of AI chips to China. New rules would apply to chips like the Nvidia A800 graphics processing unit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wei Shaojun, director of Tsinghua University&#39;s Institute of Microelectronics and an official of the China Semiconductor Industry Association, said China is the biggest victim of deglobalisation in the semiconductor industry because the country expected to be able to tap global resources. “When globalisation is destroyed, [the industry] model has great shortcomings, as China cannot realise the global allocation of resources,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese chip maker YMTC sees &#39;turbulence and disorder&#39; in semiconductor industry&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A ban of the Nvidia A800, which The Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday Washington is considering, would present both new challenges and opportunities for China, according to Wei. “If the US bans the sale of A800 chips, they are blocking their own way,” he said, adding that the new ban could be a chance for China to accelerate the sourcing and development of alternatives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han Di, senior vice-president of Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp (SMIC), China&#39;s largest wafer foundry, said the country must find new ways to embed itself in the cross-border supply chain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The traditional industrial cooperation mode is facing new challenges and opportunities,” Han said. He suggested that China focus on chip materials and components, as well as develop the capability to manufacture advanced chips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As the leading integrated circuit company in mainland China, SMIC has always adhered to the attitude of compliant operation, open innovation, and win-win cooperation,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US escalated its technology export controls on China last October, further restricting its access to advanced chips and equipment. Under the updated rules, tools that enable Chinese foundries to make chips at the 14-nanometre node level and more advanced are barred from sale to China without US government approval.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lung Chu, president of Semi China, said the slump in the chip industry has spread to the whole supply chain amid geopolitical tension and an industrial downturn.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Li, executive vice-president and secretary general for China Semiconductor Industry Association, said China&#39;s chip industry has continued to be affected by the industrial downturn and “unstable trade environment”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Ning, president of the China Electronics Chamber of Commerce, said at the event that “there&#39;s still a large gap between the technical level of the domestic semiconductor manufacturing industry and that of foreign countries”. He called this a big concern as 5G technology and ChatGPT-like generative artificial intelligence services increase demand for advanced chips.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Nvidia sees permanent loss of opportunities from China export curbs&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China lags the US in both technology and production capacity in advanced chips, according to Tsinghua&#39;s Wei, and the problem cannot be solved in the short term despite the country&#39;s willingness to spend lavishly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must aim for the mass production of much-needed high-end chips, which have been banned or restricted by the West,” Wei said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China sees critical grains cut into copious cotton yields, including in boycotted Xinjiang region]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3225965/china-sees-critical-grains-cut-copious-cotton-yields-including-boycotted-xinjiang-region?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/626ff5ef-2641-48c7-915a-142378f3e71f_6f4c6506.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Cotton planting acreage in China, the world&#39;s top grower of the plant, has dropped significantly in the span of a year, amid a US-led boycott and Beijing&#39;s aggressive push to boost national grain production.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Farmers had grown about 41.4 million mu of cotton (2.76 million hectares) as of the end of May, 10.3 per cent less than a year prior, a market-monitoring platform under the country&#39;s operator of state cotton reserves said on Wednesday, using a common Chinese unit of measurement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decline was mainly driven by a shift to grain sowing, as Beijing has ramped up efforts in recent years to increase grain production amid concerns over food security, the China National Cotton Information Centre said in a post, citing a nationwide survey last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was also a result of the global apparel industry&#39;s boycott of cotton from the Xinjiang Uygur autonomous region, China&#39;s top producer, for alleged forced labour, according to a professor of agriculture.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Already ravaged by extreme weather, China agriculture braces for early El Nino&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China provides more than 20 per cent of the world&#39;s cotton, and Xinjiang accounted for 90 per cent of the country&#39;s total production last year, according to official figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The area has been ordered to allocate an additional 4.8 million mu of cropland for grains this year, with much of that supplanting cotton, as the government encourages farmers to switch to plants for food, according to the centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decline also came after the central government lowered subsidies for cotton farmers in Xinjiang in April, as well as several impactful bouts with bad weather, including low temperatures, sandstorms and heavy rain during the sowing season, it said. Many farmers had to shift to other crops such as corn after cotton seedlings were destroyed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other cotton-growing areas of the country have also shown diminishing interest as costs rise and profits drop, with an estimated decrease in sowing area of up to one-fourth, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, the average profit for growing each mu of cotton was merely 58.4 yuan (US$8) for Chinese farmers, without taking subsidies into consideration, and that was a 97 per cent plunge from the previous year, according to the China Cotton Association.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zheng Fengtian, an agriculture professor at Renmin University, said that ensuring self-reliance in food is higher on Beijing&#39;s agenda, to the point of being deemed a national security issue, and any unmet cotton demand may be filled by increased imports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese government has intentionally moved cotton planting to Xinjiang in the past years for intensive production, but it may need to reconsider the approach after the boycott from Western countries,” Zheng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It would be nonsense if we say there&#39;s no impact on China&#39;s textile exports after the boycott launched by the United States. Under such circumstances, we may need to put our eggs in different baskets,” said Zheng, referring to diversifying planting areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US&#39; Uygur Forced Labour Prevention Act, which went into effect last June, has effectively blocked American imports of all products wholly or partially sourced from Xinjiang. The Communist Party has been accused of committing rights abuses such as forced labour against Uygur Muslims and other minorities in the region, but Beijing has consistently denied the allegations.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thai passenger has leg amputated at Bangkok airport after getting trapped by moving walkway]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225988/thai-woman-has-leg-amputated-bangkok-airport-after-getting-trapped-moving-walkway?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.29 20:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/29/49ad16a6-6589-4217-92ec-8351a8654a0c_08fc24bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A woman&#39;s leg had to be amputated in a Thai airport after it was trapped by a moving walkway on Thursday, officials said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 57-year-old Thai passenger was due to board a morning flight from Bangkok&#39;s Don Mueang Airport to the southern Nakhon Si Thammarat province when she was caught by the walkway in the airport&#39;s Terminal 2.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A medical team eventually had to cut her left leg off from above the knee, according to airport officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On behalf of the Don Mueang International Airport, I&#39;d like to express my deepest condolences regarding the accident,” Don Mueang Airport Director Karun Thanakuljeerapat said during a press conference. “I&#39;d like to insist that we will ensure that no such accident will happen again.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the airport will be fully responsible for the woman&#39;s medical costs and will be open to negotiations on other compensation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The medical team at the hospital she was initially sent to informed Karun that they could not reattach her leg, but the woman requested to be transferred to another hospital to assess the possibility, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Images shared online showed the lower part of the woman&#39;s leg trapped beneath the belt at the end of the walkway as she was being assisted by airport staff.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A suitcase lying near her was missing two wheels, and yellow comb-like plates were seen broken off from where they typically cover the edge of the belt where the moving walkway ends.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Karun said the suitcase wheels were found underneath the belt, but it was unclear how it might relate to the accident.他说，机场的走道每天都会检查，每月还会进行一次检查。 He said the walkway has been closed and a team of engineers was inspecting it to determine the cause of the accident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The walkway was manufactured by Japanese company Hitachi and was installed in 1996, the airport director said, adding that there is a plan to request for a budget to change to a newer model in 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, a passenger&#39;s shoe was damaged after it was caught in the airport&#39;s moving walkway in Terminal 1. The airport released a statement after that saying the faulty walkway was repaired and reopened in about an hour.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 29 Jun 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>