<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China’s Wang Yi calls on Global South to make voice heard in changing world order]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3229000/chinas-wang-yi-calls-global-south-make-voice-heard-changing-world-order?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 17:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/5ae9a2c7-b942-4951-9ac0-664ef81ff79a_a957f94e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国最高外交官、新任外交部长王毅呼吁全球南方国家在不断变化的世界秩序中“扩大发言权”，“在共同核心利益和重大关切问题上相互支持”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[南半球]需要团结合作，倡导原则王毅周二在约翰内斯堡举行的金砖国家集团会议上表示，“共同目标和共同责任……[并]支持联合国在国际事务中发挥积极作用”，他使用的是发展中国家和新兴经济体的统称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王毅是中国共产党外事委员会主任，他的电话是在北京任命他接替秦刚担任外交部长之际发出的。秦刚于 12 月上任，但已在公开场合露面了更多。不到一个月。秦接替了自 2013 年起担任该职务的王。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王在周二的会议上表示，“[我们]应该反对霸权主义和强权政治”。来自巴西、俄罗斯、印度、中国和南非是新兴经济体，非正式的金砖国家集团就是以它们的名字命名的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是南半球国家的“天然成员”，并且“将永远是发展中国家大家庭的成员”王说，这明确指的是美国为将世界第二大经济体列入发展中国家名单而做出的不懈努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王和其他金砖国家官员正在南非金融首都举行一系列会议下个月举行领导人峰会之前。预计中国国家主席习近平将率领一个大型商业代表团参加自冠状病毒大流行以来首次面对面的金砖国家峰会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅发表此番言论之际，金砖国家成员面临更加分裂的全球安全局势，史无前例的美中竞争以及俄罗斯在乌克兰持续的军事行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发展中经济体俱乐部的另一个主要大国印度也在与美国长期存在领土争端的情况下加大了与美国建立更密切合作的力度。中国和印太地缘政治紧张局势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王敦促金砖国家“消除冲突，共建和平”，推动“平衡、有效、可持续的安全结构”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;他表示，“抵制外部干涉”、“维护政治和政权安全”是南方国家的使命，并呼吁深化“南南合作”，实现团结和自力更生。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;除了安全担忧之外，王还强调了全球南方关注经济发展的重要性，同时敦促发达国家履行援助承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么非洲国家热衷于加入不断扩大的金砖国家俱乐部&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;“我们应该坚持把发展置于国际议程的中心……维护发展中国家的合法发展权利，”王说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为世界上最大的经济强国中国为金砖国家提供了强有力的经济支持，并推动更多国家加入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非洲、南美、中东、东欧等一些发展中国家热衷于加入金砖国家俱乐部。即将成为成员，其中包括阿根廷、沙特阿拉伯、土耳其和伊朗等一些地区强国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;副部长表示，今年金砖国家峰会的东道主南非已向北京寻求更多帮助，以改善其基础设施贸易和工业部 Fikile Majola 本月早些时候表示。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 17:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s Modi faces no-confidence vote over deadly clashes where women were paraded naked through the streets]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3228993/indias-modi-faces-no-confidence-vote-over-violent-clashes-where-women-were-paraded-naked-through?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 17:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/8e897b99-cd83-40ec-8115-46bfb21752e2_c8d2790d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;印度议会周三授权联盟对纳伦德拉·莫迪政府进行不信任投票反对党的意见，迫使总理详细解决对东北部邦种族冲突的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪领导的印度人民党 (BJP) 在下议院 542 个席位中拥有 301 名议员的绝对多数席位因此，不信任投票不会影响其稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对派反而想引发一场关于印度人民党统治的偏远曼尼普尔邦暴力事件的辩论，该州已有 130 多人被杀害。自 5 月初开始以来，已造成 6 万人死亡和 6 万人流离失所。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;裸体游行视频后，愤怒的印度妇女烧毁了两名嫌疑人的房屋&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;下议院议长 Om Birla 表示，他批准了反对派动议很快就会决定何时进行辩论和投票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪政府将这个拥有 320 万人口的小邦的种族紧张局势视为罕见的安全和政治失败，该政府将于2024 年 5 月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到上周，莫迪才公开评论暴力事件，当时显示两名妇女在曼尼普尔邦赤身裸体游街并遭到暴徒猥亵的视频浮出水面，引发了全国愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;莫迪谴责大规模袭击事件“可耻”，并承诺对肇事者采取严厉行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，反对党扰乱了上周开始的议会季风会议，要求莫迪就这一事件发表详细声明。曼尼普尔邦进入议会，随后进行辩论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为政府首脑，他必须在不信任动议付诸表决之前对其做出回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府已提供了内政部长阿米特·沙阿的一份声明，称内部安全是他的部门的责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法院命令州政府考虑扩大特殊经济福利以及政府工作和教育配额后，暴力事件于 5 月 3 日开始主要反对党国大党领导人沙希·塔鲁尔表示，政府必须投入时间来回答有关曼尼普尔邦的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“每个人都知道曼尼普尔邦在暴力、性侵犯和流离失所中目睹了可怕的生命损失。这怎么可能不是主要议程呢？”塔鲁尔说道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 17:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ignoring the potential of women and older workers hurts Hong Kong’s efforts to replenish its talent pool]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3228882/ignoring-potential-women-and-older-workers-hurts-hong-kongs-efforts-replenish-its-talent-pool?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 16:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/25/b6dc342c-7f23-4f1b-adac-b2d8dbef7f24_4d1f09e0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;为了补充不断萎缩的人才库，香港去年 12 月推出了一项计划，以吸引来自世界各地的多元化工人队伍，帮助香港重新成为行政长官李家超所设想的全球商业中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划成功吸引了来自内地的申请者。现在，除了加大力度吸引其他地方的人才外，香港还应该确保留住本地人才，特别是女性和老年工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港政府报告称，已收到超过 10 万份申请截至6月底，支持率超过60%。大多数申请者来自内地，部分原因可能是内地大学毕业生的青年失业率较高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个消息令人鼓舞，但与吸引世界各国人才的初衷相去甚远。到大陆。例如，鉴于美国、英国或澳大利亚与中国之间的紧张关系不断加剧，香港将很难吸引来自这些国家的年轻人才。面对这些挑战，香港该如何吸引更多人才来港工作？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;留住本地人才有两个容易实现的目标。首先，我们必须记住，香港在20世纪80年代经历了强劲的增长，这得益于中国的经济改革以及许多香港本地专业人士的贡献。这些专业人士中的许多人现已退休，但他们的技能和经验本来可以帮助加强该市的经济。因此，为了维持稳定、高效的劳动力队伍，政府应将法定退休年龄延长至65岁以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，雇主应承认并纠正各种偏见，包括年龄歧视和认为老年工人成本高昂的观念，从而拥抱老年工人。适应性和创造力较多，而较少。公司可以采取积极主动的措施来消除这些误解，例如为老年人提供替代头衔和角色，而无需支付更高的工资，也不会让他们感觉自己被降职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过不同的头衔和角色，雇主可以避免在不同年龄层之间进行薪资比较。年长和年轻的工人。在美国，公司经常以短期合同的形式为高级专业人士设立咨询职位，大学为退休专业人士提供兼职教职，通过分享他们的学术或工业知识来教学或为学生提供建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一般来说，老年员工更喜欢更大的灵活性，这样他们就有更多的时间留给自己和照顾亲人。在包容性的环境中，老年工人可以利用多年的专业知识或任期来创造价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其次，让女性加入劳动力队伍是刺激经济增长的有效途径。例如，较高的女性劳动参与率是帮助国家减轻贫困的因素之一。 2022年，香港女性劳动力参与率为54%，落后于内地同年的61%。因此，香港有机会寻找更多女性加入劳动力市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;工作中的性别平等：香港、新加坡和其他国家相比如何？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与许多国家一样然而，与全球女性相比，香港女性面临着工作场所的歧视和偏见等障碍。平等机会委员会 2018 年的一项研究发现，超过一半的香港雇主不愿意雇用有孩子的女性，即使她们与其他申请人一样有能力。这种情绪不仅是公然的歧视，还可能暗中鼓励女性不要生孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使女性有报酬，政府数据也表明她们的工资低于男性。除了工作机会较少和工资较低之外，女性还比男性面临更大的照顾孩子和父母的压力，这种压力在 Covid-19 大流行期间只会变得更糟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吸引和留住女性对于香港的人才来说，企业必须解决这些歧视性做法。已经取得了进展，但还可以做更多的事情。例如，进行例行工资审计并使工资水平更加透明有助于缩小性别工资差距。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近的研究基于1997年至2017年在美国公立大学工作的约10,000名学者的工资数据研究表明，当大学公开员工工资时，性别工资差距就会缩小。此外，一旦薪资信息变得更加透明，高薪学者发表的研究文章就会多出 7%。因此，公平薪酬可以激励工人提高生产力，这也可以使雇主受益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;缩小性别薪酬差距至关重要，但提供灵活的工作时间表也至关重要，特别是对于那些需要的人照顾他们的亲人。在美国，许多公司提供灵活的工作时间和在家工作的安排。这样做可以帮助减轻工人的压力水平，从而提高他们的忠诚度和生产力，特别是对于那些经常觉得自己因家庭责任而需要辞职的女性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港是一个领先者-思考国际商业中心。为了在城市人口老龄化和萎缩的情况下吸引和留住外国和本地人才，政府必须带头鼓励私营部门认识到年长工人和女性加入劳动力队伍的价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港Kong需要在国内外招募更多人才。有志者事竟成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 16:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s fight against corruption to zero in on bribers with severe penalties]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3228970/chinas-fight-against-corruption-zero-bribers-severe-penalties?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 16:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/e861e43c-2229-466e-979e-33f67906a843_4fdfcdbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国正在采取措施堵住一个漏洞，该漏洞被指允许公司或实体负责人&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最高立法机关提出的刑法修正案将加大对私营企业内部腐败的打击力度，对此类人员处以更严厉的处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;拟议的修正案是北京试图实施更全面的反腐败方法的一部分——将重点从受贿者转移到行贿者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法律的修正案草案已提交给国家主席习近平全国人大常委会法制工作委员会主任沉春耀表示，这些变化旨在解决案件数量“严重失衡”的问题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“行贿者不追究刑事责任的比例过高，而对行贿者的处罚相对较轻，不利于切断贿赂链条。”官方《法制日报》援引沉先生的话说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沉先生表示，实践中，一些个人以单位或公司的名义行贿，以避免更严厉的处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据官方媒体报道，提交的草案一读修改了七项条款，修改了与行贿人员和私营企业内部腐败有关的规定。修正案草案通常要经过立法者三读。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拟议的修改是中国持续反腐败斗争中为消除腐败所做的最新努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 9 月，中央纪律检查委员会 (中纪委) 与其他党和国家机构发布了一份联合文件，概述了建立行贿人员黑名单的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2022 年 2 月发布的一份报告中，共产党的最高纪检部门称，2021年，反腐败机构以受贿罪拘留5,006人，移送检察机关处理2,822起案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国国家主席习近平的反腐败斗争中，刑法修正案（九） 2015年通过的《刑事诉讼法》，加大了对贿赂行为的处罚力度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国人大常委会法工委刑法办公室主任王爱丽表示，最新的修正案草案是打击行贿犯罪的“又一次重大修改” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王向新华社表示，“行贿者对党员干部肆无忌惮的‘猎杀’”是腐败的一个重要根源，行贿者是“政治生态的污染源”。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“靠金融吃饭”的中国前央行副行长因违法行为被开除&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;法律专家表示，如果提供反腐败信息，对行贿者的处罚会较轻&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;修正案草案将对累犯、向多人行贿以及向公共机构工作人员行贿的人进行严厉处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法律修改将加大对重大建设项目、人事职务、执法司法、环保、金融、食品医药、抢险救灾、养老社会保障、教育医疗等领域行贿人员的处罚力度。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;被判犯有行贿罪的公司或实体的代表将面临最高 10 年的监禁，而目前的最高刑期为 5 年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次修订还将最高刑期提高到 7 年&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;上海新闻门户网站澎湃新闻董事长因腐败接受调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;草案还扩大了该法对三项腐败的规定范围相关收费涵盖私营企业和企业家，而不仅仅是国有企业。私营企业员工故意损害公司利益，造成严重损失的，将被追究刑事责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沉说，扩大范围旨在“为私营企业有效预防和惩治内部腐败提供法律手段，积极回应企业家关切。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 16:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Cargo ship carrying nearly 3,000 cars on fire in North Sea, 1 dead and several hurt]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3228987/cargo-ship-carrying-nearly-3000-cars-fire-north-sea-1-dead-and-several-hurt?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 16:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/b6d73255-4ba7-4eb4-af02-3744bc1d0cf6_6df4d023.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三，一艘载有近 3,000 辆汽车的货轮发生火灾，失控。荷兰海岸警卫队表示，一名船员死亡，其他人受伤，正在努力挽救船只免于沉没。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;船只和直升机被用来将 23 名船员从船上救出。海岸警卫队在一份声明中表示，在他们试图扑灭大火失败后，他们已将船只救出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前有很多船只在现场监视情况并查看如何控制火势” ，”海岸警卫队发言人 Lea Versteeg 在电话中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但这完全取决于天气和船只的损坏情况。因此，我们目前正在研究如何确保……最不糟糕的情况会发生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及船是否有可能沉没时，Versteeg 说，“这是一种情况我们正在考虑并为所有情况做好准备。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗里曼特尔高速公路从德国不来梅港驶往埃及塞得港时，在以北约 27 公里（17 英里）处起火。荷兰阿默兰岛的岛屿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其位置靠近瓦登海浅海中深受游客欢迎的一系列荷兰和德国岛屿，瓦登海是一个被列入世界遗产名录的地区，被联合国教科文组织描述为“最大的完整系统”世界上最大的潮间带沙地和泥滩”和“世界上最重要的候鸟栖息地之一”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;火灾原因尚不清楚，也不清楚是如何发生的。船员死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“船上载有汽车2857辆，其中25辆是电动汽车，这使得火灾变得更加困难。”控制住这种火并不容易，即使在这样的船上也不容易，”Versteeg 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从岸边拍摄的图像显示，受灾的地方冒着长长的灰色烟雾，飘过海面。一艘拖船设法与货轮建立了连接，将其固定到位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望火势能够得到控制或熄灭，我们希望火势能够得到控制或熄灭。”可以让船只到达安全地点，”Versteeg 说。 “但现在会发生什么都不确定。”海岸警卫队在一份声明中表示，打捞公司和水务部门正在“寻找尽可能限制损失的最佳方法。”&lt;据德新社报道，德国当局也处于戒备状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北部城市库克斯港的德国海上灾难指挥部发言人表示，“我们正在监测局势”并补充说它已向荷兰当局提供了支持。他表示，救援船只和特遣部队已准备好在需要时提供帮助，但尚未决定是否派遣它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 16:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong and Indonesia sign 15 deals as city leader John Lee touts Asean ties to buffer against economic headwinds]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3228979/hong-kong-and-indonesia-sign-15-deals-city-leader-john-lee-touts-asean-ties-buffer-against-economic?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 16:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/e43ee09b-b6ae-44b2-aef0-99e61649ba3f_ab571e02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港与印尼周三访问期间签署15份谅解备忘录行政长官李家超向全国表示，与东盟国家建立更紧密的关系将在经济逆风中创造额外机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些不具约束力的协议涵盖环境、社会和治理领域（ESG） ）以及绿色金融、海事服务、气象和航空航天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我非常感谢印度尼西亚总统与我分享他的愿景，”李在签署协议的商务午餐会后说道，指的是早些时候与印度尼西亚总统佐科·维多多的会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们对两国可以合作并努力的各个领域的潜力和可能性有着一致的看法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;李家耀访问期间，香港与新加坡签署 7 项双边协议&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;李家耀认识到香港近几个月进出口疲弱，表示消费者支出和旅游业出现积极迹象，而当局正在努力扩大香港的经济影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“重点将我们的网络扩展到东盟国家，就像我和我的代表团所做的那样，这意味着我们正在为香港创造额外的机会，”他说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据香港领导人称，谅解备忘录将有助于为企业打开大门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在午餐会上，李光耀向约 300 名政商领袖介绍了香港的营商优势和连通性，并补充说，正在努力使该市的金融市场多元化，以更有利于伊斯兰金融。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三早些时候，李与该公司所有者、香港大亨李泽楷一起参观了富卫保险公司在雅加达的办事处。查凯和集团主席马时亨。他还参观了在香港拥有强大影响力的印尼力宝集团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李还透露，一名来自印尼的工人在提交申请仅两个月后，就根据香港的顶尖人才通行证计划获得了签证.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位城市领导人早些时候在周二与维多多的会面中讨论了贸易、投资和保护在香港的印度尼西亚公民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李周三告诉记者，这是很自然的事情国家主席就此话题表达关切，并重申在香港的印尼家政工人与当地雇员受到“相同标准”的保护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他再次对印尼家政工人做出的贡献表示感谢”周三下午的高铁站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为“一带一路”倡议的一部分，连接西爪哇雅加达和万隆的 142 公里（88 英里）铁路由印度尼西亚和中国国有企业财团建造，中国发展全球贸易的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个期待已久的铁路项目在成本超支 12 亿美元并拖延了四年之后将于下个月开通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李正在谈论他将前往东南亚国家联盟（东盟）的三个国家进行为期一周的访问，以加强联系并帮助香港企业抓住新机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他将于周四上午离开印度尼西亚前往瓜拉马来西亚吉隆坡，这是他此行的最后一站。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 16:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Cambodia’s Hun Sen resigns as prime minister after 38 years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3228972/cambodias-hun-sen-resigns-prime-minister-after-nearly-four-decades?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 15:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/8699292a-b30f-432e-b38e-4833ecdb8e6a_54f73eef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;世界上任职时间最长的总理之一柬埔寨洪森周三表示在经历了近四十年的强硬统治后，他将辞职并将权力交给他的长子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我宣布我将不再担任总理时，我想请求人民的理解。”他在国家电视台的特别广播中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[我的儿子]洪马内......将在未来几周内成为总理，”他说，并补充说新领导人将于 8 月 10 日任命.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前红色高棉领导人自 1985 年以来一直统治着这个王国，消除了所有反对他权力的人，禁止反对党，挑战者被迫逃离，言论自由受到压制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的柬埔寨人民党 (CPP) 在周日的大选中大获全胜，没有任何有意义的反对派，获得了 82% 的选票，为他的长子的王朝继承铺平了道路，一些批评者将其与朝鲜进行了比较。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;政府称赞 84.6% 的投票率是该国“民主成熟”的证据，但包括美国和欧盟在内的西方大国谴责这次投票既不自由也不公平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪森落后于将权力移交给儿子一年半后，这位 45 岁的老人在争取周日投票的活动中发挥了主导作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他已明确表示，他仍然打算发挥影响力，即使在他下台后，放弃了国家可能改变方向的想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;柬埔寨总理洪森的政党声称选举胜利，称儿子赢得席位&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我将继续担任柬埔寨首相执政党和国民议会议员”，他周三表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在洪森的领导下，柬埔寨与北京关系密切，受益于中国的巨额投资和基础设施项目，包括重建海军基地，引起了华盛顿的警觉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国对周日的选举表示欢迎，国家主席习近平向洪森发出了个人祝贺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但中国资金的大量涌入也带来了问题，包括大量的资金流入。赌场和在线诈骗机构的员工都是被贩运的工人，条件极其恶劣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;批评者称，他的统治还以环境破坏和根深蒂固的腐败为标志。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柬埔寨在透明度方面在 180 个国家中排名第 150 位国际腐败感知指数。在亚洲，只有缅甸和朝鲜排名较低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人权组织指责洪森利用法律制度镇压任何反对其统治的人，包括活动人士、麻烦的工会领导人以及政客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;许多反对派政客在他执政期间被定罪和监禁，并且在周日选举前修改了法律，规定呼吁选民破坏选票为非法行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;洪森的美国会不会- 受过教育的儿子为亲中国的柬埔寨改变？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;距离投票日前五天，当局禁止流亡反对派领袖桑兰西竞选公职 25 年，因为他敦促人们作废选票。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;反对党领袖根速卡 (Kem Sokha) 于 3 月份因涉嫌密谋推翻洪森政府而被判叛国罪并被判处 27 年监禁。他目前正在软禁中服刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪森表示，新选出的议会将于8月21日召开，新内阁将于8月22日宣誓就职。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 15:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Over 1 in 25 Tokyo residents are now foreign as Japan population tumbles for 14th year in a row]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3228955/over-1-25-tokyo-residents-are-now-foreign-japan-population-tumbles-14th-year-row?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 15:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/f2c3e3f3-f632-4745-95c5-64ded00e5f66_a63fae41.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在日本的日本人数量以有史以来最快的速度减少周三政府数据显示，外国居民数量已增至创纪录的近 300 万。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，日本社会在全国范围内正在老龄化，并表明外国人在创造就业机会方面发挥着越来越大的作用。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据日本国务省公布的截至 2023 年 1 月 1 日的住民登记数据，日本国民数量连续 14 年减少，减少约 80 万人，至 1.2242 亿人。总务省。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，所有 47 个都道府县的日本居民人数首次出现下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;居住在日本的外国人数量创历史新高299万，比上年增长10.7%，这是自该部十年前开始跟踪数据以来的最大同比增幅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至2020年1月1日，即新冠疫情爆发之前-19疫情在全球蔓延，有287万外国人居住在日本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新数据显示，日本总人口降至1.2542亿，减少约51.1万人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于出生率低，自 2008 年达到顶峰以来，人口逐年下降，去年创下历史新低。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;首相助手表示，如果人们不生育更多孩子，日本“将会消失”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; h3>;&lt;p>;政府的目标是通过各种方式解决这个问题，包括雇用更多的女性，政府最高发言人表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了确保劳动力稳定，政府将推动劳动力市场改革，以最大限度地提高劳动力市场的竞争力。”内阁官房长官松野博和表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首相岸田文雄已将扭转出生率下滑的趋势作为首要任务，他的政府尽管债务水平很高，但仍计划每年拨出 3.5 万亿日元（250 亿美元）用于儿童保育和其他支持父母的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东京的一个公共智囊团去年表示，日本需要的外国人数量约为四倍到 2040 年，劳动力数量将达到政府的经济增长预测。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东京拥有最多的外国居民，其中有 581,112 人，占首都人口的 4.2%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 15:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Crisis over Netanyahu’s judiciary overhaul is hitting Israel’s once-flourishing economy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3228966/crisis-over-netanyahus-judiciary-overhaul-hitting-israels-once-flourishing-economy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 14:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/26/9a349702-97e5-4b9b-b9a3-b37e0bd28630_7fc117ec.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二，以色列主要报纸的封面上覆盖着纯黑色的整版广告。医生罢工罢工，以色列货币和股市下跌，因为该国正准备应对政府削弱法院的努力所带来的危险经济后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治动荡导致数万名抗议者走上街头抗议。投资者和专家表示，过去六个月也拖累了以色列经济。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡的极右翼联合政府通过的一项法律剥夺了最高法院的权力，招致了批评者的警告，称以色列将陷入困境。专制——以及国际信用机构和该国高科技产业对以色列经济未来的看法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自六个月前司法改革危机开始以来，以色列货币谢克尔的价值已跌至三分之二。 -year low and the stock market has fallen by 10 per cent, according to Reuters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent days, the TA-35 Index, the top 35 companies with the highest market value on the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange , dropped 4 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The last few months have literally broken the spirit of a lot of people who now don&#39;t believe their future is in Israel,” said Eynat Guez, co-founder of an international payroll company called Papaya Global and a leader in the Democratech movement. “The government is sending a clear message: you&#39;re not welcome here. We don&#39;t care about your future.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Israel MPs pass Netanyahu&#39;s contested reform clause, amid protests, US criticism&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The law passed Monday, the first of three proposed judicial overhauls, strips the Supreme Court&#39;s ability to nullify government decisions it finds “unreasonable in the extreme”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Opponents believe it will gut Israel&#39;s judiciary and destroy a central pillar of its democracy. Supporters want to limit the power of liberal judges to overturn laws created by an increasingly extremist and ultranationalist legislature.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The efforts by Netanyahu, who is on trial on corruption charges, brought a rebuke from Israel&#39;s most loyal ally, the United States, where President Joe Biden and major US Jewish organisations urged the prime minister to reconsider the law and seek more consensus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netanyahu ignored those entreaties, although the Israeli Knesset, or parliament, is entering a long recess and won&#39;t be able to take further action until returning in October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Knesset&#39;s moves also threaten to jeopardise Israel&#39;s attempts at rapprochement with Arab nations, especially Saudi Arabia, and further erode chances of peace with the Palestinians living under Israeli occupation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reverberations prompted a warning Tuesday from the credit agency Moody&#39;s about a “significant risk” likely to cause “negative consequences for Israel&#39;s economy and security situation”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Morgan Stanley also predicted “increased uncertainty about the economic outlook,” though neither agency downgraded Israel&#39;s credit rating, which helps guide international investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netanyahu and Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich dismissed the economic concerns raised by Moody and others. “This is a temporary response, and when the dust settles it will be clear that Israel&#39;s economy is very strong,” they said in a joint statement Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Especially hard-hit, analysts warn, is the hi-tech industry, a roaring engine of Israel&#39;s modern economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hundreds of thousands march on Israeli cities in attempt to block legislation overhaul&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The news-stands awash in black Tuesday morning were the work of the Democratech movement, a coalition of hi-tech workers opposed to the judicial overhaul. It paid for ads – with the words, “A dark day for Israel&#39;s democracy” – in five of the country&#39;s largest papers, including the pro-Netanyahu Israel Hayom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is killing the hi-tech scene in Israel,” said tech investor Itzik Fried, who has attended the chanting, flag-waving demonstrations weekly. “Money is like water, it flows where it&#39;s easy. And it&#39;s about to stop coming here.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tech sector has been leading the way in Israel&#39;s economic decline as more workers and companies relocate, although the country is not yet in recession and unemployment has not soared, said Yannay Spitzer, associate professor of economics at Hebrew University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Almost 70 per cent of local Israeli start-up companies have taken legal or financial steps toward relocation, including withdrawing cash reserves, moving headquarters outside Israel, and relocating employees or conducting lay-offs, according to a report this week from Start-Up Nation Central, an independent non-profit focusing on the tech sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It took years to build a hi-tech sector in Israel, and hi-tech has two fundamental pillars,” said Spitzer. “One is the institutional make up, that it&#39;s sound to make business here and safe to invest in Israel, and the other is the human capital. And the judicial overhaul is about to destroy both of them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The hi-tech sector has been an influential part of the protest movement over the last six months, including joining general strikes on several occasions. In March, widespread strikes from the tech sector, the country&#39;s largest trade unions and airport workers forced Netanyahu to temporarily shelf the judicial overhaul for a number of months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Spitzer estimates that the Israeli economy has lost some US$81 billion, or 15 per cent of the country&#39;s GDP, because of the judicial reforms and the impact on the economy. Israel&#39;s stock exchange had been a close mirror of the S&amp;P 500 index. But in the last year, the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange has dropped 26.5 per cent lower than the S&amp;P.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the masses of demonstrators who formed an opposition movement unprecedented in Israel&#39;s 75-year history, there was a sense of defeat and dismay after Monday&#39;s vote. Many were returning home Tuesday, and streets here and in Jerusalem were largely back to normal routines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, leaders of the movement, which grew to encompass mostly secular students, progressive academics, business entrepreneurs and the elite of Israel&#39;s security establishment, vowed not to surrender.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netanyahu&#39;s allies have vowed that the law passed Monday is only the beginning. They plan to exert Cabinet control over judicial appointees and take steps to ensure legal advisers throughout the government are partisan loyalists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Without the protest movement, writer Noa Landau said, “all state systems would have long since been completely recruited in service of a prime minister who is on trial for corruption” and his “ultranationalist and theocratic” cronies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The greatest struggle is still ahead,” Landau, an editor at the liberal Haaretz newspaper, wrote Tuesday. “The appetite of the victory-drunk coalition will only increase in the Knesset&#39;s fall session. The civil protest is therefore more important than ever.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Critics of the judicial overhaul have begun to file petitions challenging it at the Supreme Court. But since the law specifically targets the Supreme Court, it is unclear how these challenges would play out, setting Israel on an uncharted institutional clash.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And many in Israel worry that the instability at home weakens their country in the face of its enemies, such as Iran, raising alarms over security.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong police arrest 9 alleged gang members over HK$7 million watch shop robbery, recover 3 of 88 stolen timepieces]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3228968/hong-kong-police-arrest-9-alleged-gang-members-over-hk7-million-watch-shop-robbery-recover-3-88?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 15:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/26/52e95d3b-fa83-4f2c-a8c1-c1648c2003ec_e7039c7c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong police have arrested nine alleged members of a smash-and-grab gang suspected of stealing 88 timepieces worth HK$7 million (US$896,077) from a watch shop in the New Territories two months ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The force on Wednesday said the six men and three women were detained a day earlier in a series of raids that also led officers to recover three of the stolen watches and HK$130,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police also seized five other luxury watches that were not linked to the robbery. Officers are investigating whether they were bought with crime proceeds or linked to other cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chief Inspector Chang Ka-chun of the New Territories North traffic unit said an investigation suggested the nine suspects were alleged members of a robbery syndicate who stole HK$7 million worth of watches from a Tuen Mun outlet during a daylight hold-up on May 14.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The suspects, aged 24 to 56, have been accused of scouting, carrying out the robbery and handling stolen watches.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chang revealed that officers were able to identity the suspects after poring over a large quantity of surveillance camera footage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that police were still hunting other members of the syndicate and trying to track down the remaining 85 watches.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police hunt gang who netted HK$3.8 million haul from watch store&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Police have appealed to witnesses and anyone with information on the case to contact officers at 3661 3340.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of Wednesday afternoon, the suspects, who were arrested on suspicion of robbery and handling stolen property, were still in police custody.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Robbery is punishable by up to life in jail and handling stolen property carries a maximum penalty of 14 years in prison.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the hold-up in May, three men carrying a sledgehammer and knives raided the Kai Fat Path shop and fled with 88 watches. They escaped in a silver car driven by an accomplice. The vehicle was later found abandoned in Yuen Long on the same day.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong man, 79, robbed of Rolex and ring after woman promises massage&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Police adopt a zero-tolerance attitude towards any form of violent crime and take resolute actions to bring criminals to justice,” Chang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Between January and March this year, the force handled 26 reports of robbery across the city, up from 23 cases logged in the same period in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, a watch shop in Tsim Sha Tsui was ransacked by four robbers dressed as construction workers, who stole 46 watches worth more than HK$10 million in three minutes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police said the robbers had threatened a 37-year-old man in charge of the shop with two 30cm (11.8 inches) butcher knives and fled the scene in a private car.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 15:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thailand’s Thaksin will return from exile on August 10, says daughter Paetongtarn Shinawatra]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3228963/thailands-thaksin-will-return-exile-august-10-says-daughter-paetongtarn-shinawatra?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.26 14:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/26/79220b97-550c-42c7-99a2-dec8b726c9fe_2cc8de36.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Thailand&#39;s billionaire former prime minister Thaksin Shinawatra will return to the kingdom on August 10 after 15 years in self-exile, his daughter said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 74-year-old tycoon, twice elected prime minister but ousted by a military coup in 2006, has long spoken of his wish to come home, but faces multiple criminal charges – which he says are politically motivated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thaksin is a bogeyman for Thailand&#39;s pro-military and royalist establishment and his return could inflame an already tense political situation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The kingdom is in political deadlock after the military-dominated Senate blocked the head of the Move Forward Party from becoming prime minister after the reformist party won May&#39;s elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I can&#39;t believe what I am about to write. Dad is coming back on Aug 10 at Don Meung airport,” his daughter Paetongtarn Shinawatra wrote on her official Facebook page on Wednesday – Thaksin&#39;s birthday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Paetongtarn was a prime ministerial candidate for the Pheu Thai party, which came second in the election and is now trying to form a government after the Move Forward Party was blocked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My heart and everyone in our family feel overwhelmed, happy and worried, but we respect dad&#39;s decision,” she wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Days before the May election, Thaksin said on social media that he would return to Thailand “before my birthday” because he was getting old and wanted to spend time with his grandchildren.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Approve Pita as PM or &#39;get out&#39;, Bangkok protesters tell Thai senators&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Thaksin was convicted in absentia on corruption charges in 2008 – and has since faced numerous other cases – but said in May he was ready to face the courts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parties linked to Thaksin have dominated Thai politics since 2001, but lost two prime ministers to military coups and another to a court ruling.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 26 Jul 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>