<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Maui locals slam tourists holidaying in aftermath of deadly wildfires]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231209/maui-locals-slam-tourists-holidaying-aftermath-deadly-wildfires?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 03:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/c62e7670-7adb-4f0c-b353-b6a1fa3f997c_e35bbca1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;夏威夷毛伊岛的当地人正在努力应对创纪录的野火房屋、生计和整个社区都遭到破坏，有人说，游客到访该岛使恢复工作变得更加痛苦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，拉海纳这座历史悠久的城镇曾经居住着约 12,000 人，居民被迫被迫撤离。据美国有线电视新闻网 (CNN) 报道，官员称，多拉飓风横扫毛伊岛，引发的狂风助长了野火，跳入大海以躲避野火。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据美国有线电视新闻网 (CNN) 报道，官员称，大火夷平了该镇大部分地区，造成近 100 人死亡。据报道仍有数千人失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管当地官员甚至夏威夷演员杰森·莫玛都警告游客取消前往毛伊岛的非必要旅行计划，但社交媒体上分享的视频似乎显示游客在岛上度假。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TikToker @kayafromhawaii 周末在她的帐户上重新分享了夏威夷旅行者的视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，在这段视频中，观看次数已超过 263,000 次：“想象一下，近 100 人死亡，而且还在增加。数千名当地人和夏威夷人失去了一切，还有 1000 人失踪。法律当局不允许当地人和夏威夷人带着人们需要的物资和东西回来，因为这很危险。但随后，你就会看到这个。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该视频显示了另一位用户分享的 Instagram 视频，画面中似乎是 8 月 11 日游客在游船周围浮潜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毛伊岛浮潜，视频开始在社交媒体上流传后，一家旅游公司随后在其网站上发表了道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;夏威夷山火造成 36 人死亡，“末日”袭击毛伊岛度假城市&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然尚未确认毛伊岛浮潜公司是否拥有视频中的这艘船，该公司也没有回应置评请求，该公司对举办这次旅行表示歉意，称这次旅行距离拉海纳“不近”17.7 公里（11 英里） 8 月 11 日上午。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司还表示，举办此次探险活动是为了为毛伊岛食品银行筹集资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不想给那些已经失去了那么多。因此，我们将暂时暂停运营。”Maui snorkelling 分享的声明补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TikTok 用户@kayafromhawaii 稍后还在视频中表示，游客正在使用运送物资的人员需要通行的道路。 ，呼应毛伊岛当地人 Courtney Keakahulilani 在夏威夷新闻报道 Instagram 页面上分享的观点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“看到游客试图进入拉海纳，试图进入我们的车队以绕过交通，真是令人厌恶，”Keakahulilani 说周日分享的视频已获得超过 22,000 个赞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当你们还有尸体漂浮在水中时，你们会让游客进入拉海纳并享受我们的海滩吗？”&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;“游客，”她补充道。 “你们内心深处的什么想法让你们认为这可以？对于所有直接受到这场悲剧影响的人来说，这简直是一记耳光。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Insider 无法联系到 Keakahulilani 寻求进一步评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; “这太疯狂了”：随着对夏威夷野火反应的愤怒加剧，启动了调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Keakahulilani 的批评也针对地方当局，她说地方当局允许游客进入拉海纳，尽管这可能会对提供援助产生影响夏威夷州州长乔什·格林 (Josh Green) 在一份关于野火的公告中发布了旅行指南，“强烈劝阻”非必要的旅行，并表示需要“酒店和其他住宿”流离失所的居民和应急工作人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，灾难紧急救援期将持续整个八月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，Keakahulilani 表示，一些旅行者仍在访问毛伊岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“每个人都受伤了，他们都很悲伤，现在情绪高涨，你们甚至在提供足够的资源来帮助社区之前就让游客进来，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在拉海纳有一些心情不好的人，他们只是觉得自己很失望。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mother of six-year-old boy who shot US teacher pleads guilty to child neglect]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231211/mother-six-year-old-boy-who-shot-us-teacher-pleads-guilty-child-neglect?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 03:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/bd6c7e6f-5787-4eb7-86c1-37989b2f7158_9519242e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名六岁弗吉尼亚男孩的母亲开枪打伤了他的弟弟据多家媒体报道，1 月份的一名学校教师周二承认了一项忽视儿童重罪的州指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德贾·泰勒 (Deja Taylor) 此前已认罪，他的儿子在纽波特纽斯 Richneck 小学枪杀了老师艾比·兹维尔纳 (Abby Zwerner)在另一起联邦案件中对枪支指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据弗吉尼亚法院网站称，泰勒将于 10 月 27 日被判刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在州检察官撤诉后，她将面临最高六个月的监禁据《华盛顿邮报》和 NBC 新闻报道，泰勒因鲁莽地留下已上膛的枪支而危及儿童的另一项轻罪罪名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰勒因联邦指控将面临最高两年的监禁，并将在该案中被判刑10 月 18 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《华盛顿邮报》报道，纽波特纽斯联邦的一名律师在周二的法庭听证会上表示，男孩从梳妆台上母亲的钱包里拿走了一把未上锁的枪。泰勒的律师詹姆斯·埃伦森 (James Ellenson) 此前曾表示，这把枪是用扳机锁固定在卧室衣柜里的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周二的听证会上，我们无法立即联系到埃伦森置评。据哥伦比亚广播公司当地附属机构 WTKR 报道，在法院外，埃伦森质疑为什么男孩的父亲没有受到指控，并引用了“家庭虐待问题”，但没有提供更多细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽波特新闻办公室代表也无法立即联系到联邦检察官。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国教师在课堂上被 6 岁儿童枪杀，被誉为英雄&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方表示，这名男孩从家里拿走了手枪。他们说，一名学校员工冲进去制止了男孩，而茨维尔纳则将其他学生带到了安全地带。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗吉尼亚州检察官尚未证实这一点。指控该男孩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该老师已对学校管理人员提起 4000 万美元的诉讼，称他们已被警告 3 次，称该男孩携带武器。 《华盛顿邮报》四月援引两名知情人士的话称，州当局正在调查该校一名前助理校长。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[From China’s property-investment slowdown to its scrubbed youth-jobless rate: 7 takeaways from July’s economic data]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3231183/chinas-property-investment-slowdown-its-scrubbed-youth-jobless-rate-7-takeaways-julys-economic-data?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/ef2d9d3f-8647-4d66-b6ba-ccdfa31ff49e_1cfecf63.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;如果您想查看我们的更多报告，请考虑 。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;1-7月房地产投资同比下降8.5%，上半年下降7.9%，创房地产投资增速最低今年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;房地产投资占中国固定资产投资的五分之一以上，对经济增长的贡献率约为14%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家统计局新闻发言人付凌辉表示，中国的房地产市场“正在经历一个调整期”，“短期内[房地产业务]的运营将面临挑战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但傅表示，一旦房地产市场恢复正常，风险就会化解。政策调整。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着信心的流失，房地产市场受到了巨大的拖累，房地产投资减少，交易量减少，这表明许多旨在[创造]软着陆的政策措施新加坡穆迪分析经济学家 Heron Lim 表示：“房地产市场的信心尚未恢复。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;前 7 个月固定资产投资总额全年增长3.4%，但低于中国数据服务提供商Wind预期的3.9%的增长，也低于上半年3.8%的增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;中国高科技产业在美国科技战中“断崖式下滑”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;今年前七个月民间投资也下降了0.5%，而同期则增长了7.6%见于国有企业。今年上半年，私人投资下降了0.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“房地产投资收缩加剧，但被其他部门支出的回升所抵消。制造业和基础设施投资持平。”凯投宏观表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;7 月份零售额同比增长 2.5%，低于 2019 年 5.3% 的预期增幅Wind，较 6 月份 3.1% 的增幅有所回落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凯投宏观表示，在考虑基数效应和季节性因素后，零售销售环比仍停滞不前，细目显示：上个月所有行业均持平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“也许最糟糕的……是零售额同比增长 2.5%。由于经济重新开放短暂导致零售额激增，4 月份的同比增长率明显因基数效应而大幅上涨 18.4%，这已大幅下降。” ING。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在，以消费者支出为主导的复苏的想法看起来非常脆弱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;7 月份工业生产增长了 3.7%与去年同期相比，该数据低于 Wind 预测的 4.6% 的增幅，该数据在 6 月份上涨了 4.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月份，中国出口出现自以来最快的跌幅。 2020 年 2 月，上个月同比下降 14.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国生产者价格指数（反映工厂向批发商收取的产品价格）7 月份同比下降 4.4%，跌幅较 6 月份的 5.4% 有所收窄。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“工厂不仅要应对国内复苏乏力的情况，还要应对国外需求的回落，”凯投宏观补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;不可否认，数据显示 7 月份工业企业的出口销售略有上升。但更大的情况是，外部需求继续明显下滑，这一点尚未在海关数据中得到充分反映。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;总体调查城镇失业人员7 月失业率从 6 月的 5.2% 升至 5.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但国家统计局突然停止发布月度失业率明细，包括 16-24 岁和 25-59 岁年龄段的失业率，理由是“需要改进统计计算和标准方面的工作”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来，16-24岁年龄段的失业率屡创新高，从5月份的20.8%升至6月份的21.3% 4月份为20.4%，首次超过五分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“近年来，年轻人中的学生人数不断增加……他们的主要职责是国家统计局新闻发言人傅补充道，“虽然城镇失业率与城镇失业率相比仍然较低，凯投宏观 (Capital Economics) 表示，在过去几年的大部分时间里，失业率在 7 月持续上升，表明劳动力市场再次疲软。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创历史新高并不能激发信心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国人民银行（PBOC）下调一年期中期借贷便利（MLF）利率下调15个基点，从2.65%降至2.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;央行还将7天逆回购利率下调10个基点至1.8%，这表明北京政策制定者愿意采取更多行动&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从宏观角度来看，这些政策决定是有一定帮助的。它们将有助于提高现金短缺的地方政府和房地产公司的偿债能力。”荷兰国际集团的卡内尔补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但这并不是一个改变游戏规则的结果，因此我们对市场的前景表示怀疑。正是这一点，情绪将大幅改善。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凯投宏观预计，在中国人民银行将MLF和7天逆回购利率降至新低后，周一贷款优惠利率将下调。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“但货币刺激在当前环境下作用有限，至少其本身不足以为经济增长奠定基础，”他们补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;观点：美中关系科技战争取决于谁能获得半导体主导地位&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;凯投宏观表示，周二公布的数据表明，第三季度初经济仍举步维艰，而且迹象表明经济在第三季度初仍举步维艰。 -频率数据并未表明 8 月上半月出现好转。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们列举了房地产开发商碧桂园和国有远洋集团的麻烦，这些问题削弱了购房者和债权人的信心，并补充道房地产前景更加黯淡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“7 月份所有主要活动指标均低于共识预期，其中大多数指标环比停滞或几乎没有增长，”凯投宏观表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“由于碧桂园等开发商的财务问题可能会在短期内给房地产市场带来压力，除非尽快加大政策支持力度，否则经济确实存在陷入衰退的风险——降息不会削减利率。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;荷兰国际集团的卡内尔表示，需要采取更多政策措施，而且肯定会采取更多措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国人民银行尚未结束利率-降息周期尚未结束，政策降息将会按照我们所看到的方式进一步迭代。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国新的投资限制对中国目标科技行业的影响有限&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;他预计政府的刺激政策将与北京已经实施的许多供给侧增强措施相一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“提高私营部门的效率也将发挥关键作用，不过这以及所有供应方措施都需要相当长的时间才能发挥作用，”卡内尔说。 “与此同时，要求采取更多刺激措施的令人厌烦的合唱不太可能停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在可预见的未来，我们将继续看到疲软的宏观数据。这是调整的必要组成部分，比恢复之前推动增长的债务驱动的房地产模式要好得多。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How South China Sea rows thwart Philippine hopes to improve ties with China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231009/how-south-china-sea-rows-thwart-philippine-hopes-improve-ties-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 01:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/92444b01-2ab1-4f56-acf8-f495491b7eb4_842fca83.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;“停止欺负我们……仅仅因为我们是一个小国家，你就认为你可以对我们这样做。我们需要相互尊重，”菲律宾参议员 Christopher “Bong” Go 上周在中国和菲律宾在南海的紧张局势加剧之际表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾海岸警卫队指责中国船只使用高压水枪阻止对仁爱礁的补给任务，这是一个有争议的地区，由一艘搁浅的船只上的菲律宾海军陆战队分遣队占领。就中国而言，要求菲律宾撤离其声称拥有“无可争议主权”的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该事件在马尼拉引发轩然大波，许多知名人士和政府高层盟友都向费迪南德总统发出呼吁小马科斯将对中国采取更加果断的行动。吴参议员的强硬言论显然是针对国内受众，这是近几个月来菲中关系迅速恶化的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为前总统罗德里戈·杜特尔特的特别助理，吴参议员在多年来努力与北京建立特殊关系的中心。他甚至帮助安排了杜特尔特最近的中国之行，以帮助缓解紧张局势。 “在杜特尔特担任总统的六年里，我们给予您极大的尊重。我们的政府对你们很好，”吴说，并对北京缺乏互惠表示遗憾。海上争端的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果缺乏有意义的外交突破，马科斯可能会被迫进一步与华盛顿结盟，允许五角大楼最大限度地进入菲律宾的各种重要设施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;历史上，菲律宾总统一直试图与中国建立更温暖的关系。部分原因是北京作为最大贸易伙伴的经济重要性日益增强，以及菲律宾领导人日益渴望使菲律宾外交政策多样化，超越传统的西方盟友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;厌倦了专横的乔治·W·布什政府时任菲律宾总统格洛丽亚·马卡帕加尔·阿罗约追求与中国双边关系的“黄金时代”。但她与北京的接触最终因席卷中国支持的项目的腐败丑闻以及有争议的南海联合能源勘探协议而被破坏，菲律宾最高法院最近裁定该协议违宪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的所有继任者试图使与中国的双边关系保持稳定，至少在最初是这样。改革派贝尼尼奥·阿基诺 (Benigno Aquino) 缺席了中国异见人士刘晓波的诺贝尔和平奖颁奖典礼，以避免外交紧张局势恶化。但不到两年后，因黄岩岛危机与中国的海军对峙迫使阿基诺采取更具对抗性的立场，最终导致与美国新的防务合作以及针对中国的国际仲裁案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的继任者罗德里戈·杜特尔特 (Rodrigo Duterte) 更加坚定地追求与中国的友好关系。他不仅与针对中国的仲裁案保持距离，还试图降级与美国的军事合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，这又是一起海上事件，即中国民兵船击沉菲律宾渔船的事件。在礼乐滩，这激起了公众对杜特尔特亲北京外交政策的反对。该事件发生后，中国的净信任度跌至-24%，迫使杜特尔特在南海问题上采取越来越强硬的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与他的前任类似，马科斯试图将与中国的关系“转变为一种更加开放的关系”。更高档次”，推动双边关系“新黄金时代”。但由于今年早些时候对北京进行国事访问期间未能取得任何重大让步，他开始加倍加强与传统盟友的战略关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可能是为了回应马科斯决定扩大与美国的防务关系根据《加强防务合作协议》，中国开始收紧南海的绞索。近几个月来，菲律宾当局指责中国船只向菲律宾海岸警卫队船员发射军用级激光，“蜂拥而至”菲律宾控制的南沙群岛易洛魁礁，最近还向菲律宾的补给任务发射高压水枪。仁爱礁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，马科斯面临着越来越大的压力，要求他采取更具对抗性的政策，大多数菲律宾人要求与盟友进行更密切的防务合作，以阻止中国。在菲律宾参议院，有人呼吁将南海争端提交给国际机构，包括游说联合国大会通过一项决议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在提出数百次外交抗议后，马尼拉最终甚至可能考虑收回其主权。驻北京大使或暂停双边对话机制以表达不满。马科斯还可以选择采取更积极的做法，包括寻求美国的援助，以加强菲律宾在仁爱礁等地的设施。毕竟，华盛顿已经明确表示，对菲律宾军队的任何攻击都可能启动共同防御条约义务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;简而言之，持续的边缘政策最终可能将双边关系推向无可挽回的地步，使菲律宾进一步陷入困境陷入中美博弈的漩涡。为了避免局势恶化，马尼拉和北京应积极缓解紧张局势，防止两国船只发生碰撞，并寻求双方都能接受的妥协方案，以阻止任何一方单方面改变现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阻止菲律宾的补给任务和基本维护这些活动只会加剧菲律宾对中国在有争议地区大规模建岛活动的愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马尼拉可以尝试向北京保证，与美国的防务合作不会对中国构成威胁，反而会增强中国的防御能力。菲律宾自身的防御能力。寻求双方都能接受的妥协将是一场艰苦的斗争，但除了强有力的外交之外，没有更好的选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 02:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong tourists in Japan face flight and rail disruption caused by Typhoon Lan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3231207/hong-kong-tourists-japan-face-flight-and-rail-disruption-caused-typhoon-lan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.16 00:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/16/3fac583d-e4f6-4a81-9dca-47ff1dfc5c7c_d43809ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台风兰周二袭击日本西部后，香港人的旅游计划陷入混乱，从大阪起飞的航班仅在晚上恢复，通往该市关西机场的交通早些时候已停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当兰于周二早上抵达大阪南部时，所有通往关西的铁路服务都停止了&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;52岁的托尼·吴(Tony Ng)在建筑行业工作，原计划从关西乘坐香港快运航空的航班回国。在日本西部度过了六天的家庭假期后的下午。但廉价航空公司告诉他，航班推迟到晚上 11 点 30 分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为以防万一，吴一行三人于周一提前一晚搬出位于大阪的宾馆，并在酒店预订了两晚。距关西机场一个火车站。他们还额外预订了一晚作为备用，以防进一步延误。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但当他周一晚上入住酒店时，他被迫再次改变计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“酒店接待员告诉我，如果我们现在不前往机场，我们可能会错过周二的航班。”Ng 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，他的团队抓起行李，取消了酒店预订，然后就冲了出去。前往机场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们一无所知，因为我们没有看到日本当局的消息。我们只知道航班时间改变了。”吴说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本媒体报道，周二约有 650 名乘客在机场过夜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴说，他在机场发现了其他香港人。机场餐厅和便利店全天库存充足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，在航站楼露营的乘客也得到了毯子和水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“感觉很奇怪，吴说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;旅行混乱：日本为应对台风“兰”而取消火车和航班&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港快运航空派出两架飞机周二有两班飞往大阪的航班，分别于晚上 9 时 20 分及晚上 10 时 40 分抵达，两班往香港的航班预计于周三晚上 11 时 30 分及凌晨 1 时起飞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港航空改期 3 趟大阪航班周二晚上 9.30 至午夜期间飞往关西机场的航班。该航空公司运营了两趟航班，预计在午夜后离开日本城市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自韩国、台湾和澳大利亚的一系列国际航班也在当地时间晚上 9 点后降落在关西机场。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;香港快运航空的母公司国泰航空和日本廉价航空公司乐桃取消或推迟了周二至周三飞往大阪的航班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关西机场的道路连接于当地时间周二下午 6 点左右重新开放，但火车当天余下时间，除一条线路在晚上 9 点后恢复运营约三个小时外，服务仍然暂停。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Peko Wong 在香港快运航空 Facebook 页面上报道称，她在大阪的酒店设法安排了一辆出租车&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是叶永佑说，他的酒店坚称乘出租车到达机场可能会遇到困难，尽管他最终到达了机场。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国在 2019 年搜寻 16 名失踪人员。西安东北部将迎来更多降雨&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港快运航空表示，建议乘客在出发前查看航空公司和机场网站的最新信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港航空向《华盛顿邮报》推荐了《华盛顿邮报》大阪运营的旅行警报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，日本各地至少有 900 趟国内航班被取消，周三取消的航班更多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本预计将在福冈和东京之间开通新干线子弹头列车从周三早上开始恢复正常服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年 9 月，日本西部遭受台风飞燕袭击时，关西机场出现混乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数千名旅客被困在人工岛上一艘重达 2,591 吨的油轮拖锚并撞上了机场的道路连接线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机场停机坪的一大片区域也被风暴潮淹没。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Afghanistan’s Taliban government marks 2 years since return to power]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3231204/afghanistans-taliban-government-marks-2-years-return-power?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 23:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/fe9112af-8285-4b74-93ad-8efeb99769e7_69fa400b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二，阿富汗塔利班政府与支持者一起庆祝其重新掌权两周年批评者谴责对妇女权利日益收紧的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿富汗伊斯兰酋长国（塔利班对该国的正式名称）的旗帜在首都喀布尔飘扬，2021 年 8 月 15 日，喀布尔坠落，美国支持的政府垮台，其领导人流亡国外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后的两年里，塔利班当局对伊斯兰教实行了严格的解释，妇女首当其冲地受到联合国称为“性别”的法律的影响。种族隔离”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局发表声明称赞这场胜利能够“为阿富汗建立伊斯兰制度铺平道路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“征服喀布尔证明了这一点声明称，“没有人可以再次控制阿富汗这个令人自豪的国家”，并且“不会允许任何入侵者威胁该国的独立和自由”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数百名塔利班支持者，其中包括老年男性聚集在废弃的美国使馆大楼附近的年轻男孩们，这是目前空置的众多使馆之一 - 塔利班政府仍未得到任何其他国家的正式承认。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国制造的军用车辆，由美国制造新的塔利班统治者在经历了长达一周的混乱撤退后被国际部队抛在身后，滚过坚固的使馆围墙半开的大门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在西部的赫拉特市，一群塔利班分子支持者高呼：“欧洲人去死，西方人去死，阿富汗伊斯兰酋长国万岁，美国人去死。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坎大哈是塔利班运动的摇篮，也是隐居的最高领袖的发源地。官员告诉记者，希巴图拉·阿洪扎达 (Hibatullah Akhundzada) 根据法令进行统治，阅兵被取消，然后转移到军事大院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坎大哈居民 Agha Sahib 赞扬了阿洪扎达的领导能力，称他统一了国家。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“当他从（坎大哈）发布一项法令时，阿富汗 34 个省份都会接受该法令，”这位 24 岁的内政部工作人员说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些法令已被阿富汗 34 个省份所接受。然而，这并没有受到所有阿富汗人的平等欢迎，也没有受到国际社会的欢迎，国际社会在是否与塔利班当局接触的问题上存在分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对妇女权利的限制——被挤出公共空间、就业和教育– 一直是获得承认和援助的主要障碍，由于外国对与喀布尔的新统治者打交道持谨慎态度，承认和援助被削减。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国的经济和人道主义危机是许多阿富汗人的一个严重担忧，即使，赫拉特人力车司机阿卜杜勒瓦斯·卡德里（Abdulwase Qadri）表示，战斗结束后他们松了口气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这两年已经提供了安全保障，”35 岁的他说。 “但工作环境对年轻人不利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女性的工作途径尤其被关闭，最近全国数千家美容院被关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;非政府组织再次谴责塔利班当局对待妇女的方式来纪念这一周年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们强烈谴责塔利班持续不断且不断升级的严重侵犯人权行为，特别是针对妇女和女童的行为，以及缺乏足够的保护包括人权观察组织和国际特赦组织在内的 10 个人权组织发表的联合声明表示：“这是国际社会的有效回应。”塔利班在周年纪念前统治，敦促国际社会采取更多行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国敦促加大对阿富汗的支持，但提醒塔利班“期望”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“阿富汗已陷入深渊” ”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，在邻国巴基斯坦的首都，100 多名阿富汗妇女举着一张海报进行抗议，上面写着：“8 月 15 日黑色日&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于根据新法律不得不放弃医学研究的喀布尔居民法拉赫来说，这个周年纪念日也是一个严峻的提醒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我面临着未知的未来，被剥夺了受教育的权利，同时我看到塔利班今天庆祝他们的胜利，”她说。 “我看到自己的黑暗未来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;研究人员表示，英国士兵在从阿富汗撤军后感到内疚&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但对于她 21 岁的男性同伴来说，这是光明的一天仍在学习医学的莫尔塔扎·凯里 (Mortaza Khairi) 周二参加了喀布尔大学由高等教育部主办的庆祝活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们今天需要庆祝，”他说。 “今天标志着我们国家占领的结束。”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong construction industry issues revised guidelines on heat stress alerts in bid to fix ‘confusing and impractical’ system]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231205/hong-kong-construction-industry-issues-revised-guidelines-heat-stress-alerts-bid-fix-confusing-and?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 23:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/15/c781628b-6b27-463f-b808-3768f5422d8c_f0121ae0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港建造业人士已达成共识，至少给予工地工人每当政府发布热应激警报时，无论工作类型如何，两次最多 30 分钟的休息时间和更长的午休时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行业领导者表示，他们希望周二生效的新指导方针能够得到落实。 a step forward in better protecting employees in scorching weather, three months after authorities introduced a three-tier warning system for heat stress at work.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;All hot and bothered about Hong Kong&#39;s new heat warning system? The Post has answers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The industry measures were jointly drafted by the Hong Kong Construction Association, trade unions and subcontractors, and endorsed by the Labour Department.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The association represents more than 300 companies, which account for over 70 per cent of turnover across construction projects in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Godfrey Leung King-kwok, executive director of the association, on Tuesday said it was hoped the measures would resolve ambiguities in the government&#39;s current anti-heatstroke guidelines, which unionists had called “confusing and impractical”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the department&#39;s guidelines recommend employees stop work for between 15 and 45 minutes every hour whenever a heat alert is issued, those released by the industry on Tuesday suggested staff take a 15-minute break at 10am, and a 30-minute one at 3.15pm.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong construction and cleaning sectors abandon confusing anti-heatstroke rules&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;When an amber alert is issued, the lunch break will be extended to an hour and 15 minutes compared with an hour previously.当出现红色警报时，每次休息时间将额外增加 15 分钟。 All employees are required to stop work when a black warning is issued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We hope the guidelines … help the industry practically implement breaks for workers. The recommended rest time is the minimum hours workers should have,” Leung said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The revisions cover all construction jobs, without dividing them into light, medium or heavy work as the government had set out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The guidelines also recommend heat relief measures for workers including providing shelters and cooling equipment on site.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung advised site safety officers to conduct a risk assessment every morning and set out flexible rest periods for workers depending on their needs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several major companies are members of the association, including Chevalier, China State Construction Engineering and Gammon Construction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung said he was confident association members and subcontractors would follow through with the guidelines.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s heat stress warnings &#39;fail to consider varying temperatures across city&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He also stressed the latest guidelines would be “in compliance” with the government&#39;s framework and the three-tier warning system. The government&#39;s system is based on the Hong Kong Heat Index co-developed by the Observatory and Chinese University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong Ping, chairman of the Hong Kong Construction Industry Employees General Union, welcomed the new guidelines, saying they would give workers “legitimacy” to take breaks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Longer rest periods will inevitably cause delays to some construction projects, but workers&#39; health should come first,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Association vice-president Conrad Fung Kwok-keung said having breaks with a fixed time would be more “manageable” for employers and would further improve the government&#39;s guidelines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Previously, the construction sector had said employees were not made aware of the warning notification when they focused on work.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How to improve heat stress warnings for workers and avoid flip-flops&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Some workers and unionists noted that employers were left confused by the government guidelines when alerts were raised and cancelled within intervals as short as 10 to 20 minutes on some days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Labour Department spokesman said officers conducted 8,500 site inspections from May 15 to July 31, and 530 warnings were issued to urge responsible parties to conduct heat stress risk assessments and control measures. He said no employers were prosecuted.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China watching closely as US, Japan, South Korea aim for ‘de facto Asian Nato’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231201/china-watching-closely-us-japan-south-korea-aim-de-facto-asian-nato?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 23:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/a95330b2-a5b0-4b5a-9802-c79288b26919_6d9876f6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China is said to be on “high alert” as US President Joe Biden hosts the leaders of Japan and South Korea at Camp David this week to deepen technological and defence ties – building what some observers have called a “de facto Asian Nato” on China&#39;s doorstep.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korean President Yoon Suk-yeol and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida will be joining Biden on Friday at the US presidential retreat in rural Maryland for the first three-way summit of its kind. They are expected to announce plans for expanded cooperation on ballistic missile defence systems and technology development, senior US officials told Reuters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They are likely to also agree to set up a new three-way crisis hotline and gather annually in the future, Reuters quoted the officials as saying.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China urged to boost defence talks as US, Japan, South Korea join hands&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Beijing, foreign ministry spokesman Wang Wenbin said China was opposed to “the cobbling together of various small circles by the countries concerned”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[China] also opposes practices that exacerbate confrontation and jeopardise the strategic security of other countries,” Wang said. “The countries concerned should follow the trend of the times and do more that is conducive to regional peace, stability and prosperity.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lu Chao, dean of the Institute of American and East Asian Studies at Liaoning University in northeastern China, said Friday&#39;s meeting could lead to a trilateral military alliance that would hit a nerve in Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The [likely] mechanism of regular meetings among heads of state and the fixed mechanism of cooperation in the military aspect amount to the de facto formation of a three-way military alliance,” Lu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While North Korea is expected to top the agenda, Beijing will be watching for specific references to Taiwan in the joint statement expected to be issued at the end of the summit, observers in mainland China said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing considers Taiwan a breakaway province to be eventually reunited, by force if needs be. While most countries, including the US, Japan and South Korea, do not recognise self-ruled Taiwan as an independent state, but oppose any attempt to take the island by force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is on high alert for the summit, especially if the Taiwan issue is to be mentioned,” Lu said. “If they raise the Taiwan issue publicly at the summit, it would be seen as a strong provocation to China and will be a dangerous move for stability in the Asia-Pacific.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statement would also contain general observations on maintaining peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait, though the exact wording was expected to be negotiated up until the last minute, an anonymous US official told Reuters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Friday&#39;s summit comes after months of diplomacy by the Biden administration, which has tried to bring together Washington&#39;s treaty allies Japan and South Korea as part of a campaign to strengthen Asian military alliances to counter China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US signed the Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security with Japan in 1951. In 1953, following the Korean war armistice, it signed a Mutual Defence Treaty with South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tokyo and Seoul have a troubled history, especially over Japan&#39;s wartime excesses as well as territorial issues, but a rising China, Russia&#39;s militarism and a nuclear-armed North Korea are factors bringing the two neighbours closer to each other and the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tensions had peaked from time to time, until a major thaw in recent months as Yoon, who took office in May last year, has sought to repair ties with Japan and launched a strategic pivot to the US, to tackle growing military challenges from North Korea and souring ties with China and Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;North Korea test-fired around 90 missiles last year, nearly four times its peak of 25 in 2017. Last month, it tested its latest Hwasong-18 intercontinental ballistic missile, saying it was a warning to the US and other adversaries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During an inspection tour of a military factory last week, North Korean leader Kim Jong-un called for an increase in missile production to help secure “overwhelming military power” and be ready for war, state news agency KCNA reported. This came days before annual joint US-South Korean military exercises due to begin on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the principle of collective defence in Article 5 of the Nato treaty, an attack against one ally is considered as an attack against all Nato members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Liu Jiangyong, an expert on regional affairs at Beijing&#39;s Tsinghua University, voiced scepticism about a trilateral alliance comparable to Nato.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The three countries do not have the security commitments that Nato countries have with each other, and Japan and South Korea are security partners, not allies,” Liu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The strategic goals of the three countries were also different, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US may consider [its goals] from a global perspective, while Japan is largely targeting China … South Korea, meanwhile, is trying to strengthen security cooperation with the US and Japan to build a greater military deterrent against North Korea.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, he expected “joint military exercises and trilateral consultations against China” to continue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a speech on Tuesday marking the 78th anniversary of South Korea&#39;s liberation from Japanese colonial rule, Yoon said his country would step up security cooperation with the US and Japan in addressing the nuclear threat from North Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Kishida renews peace pledge as Japan marks 78th anniversary of WWII defeat&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Kim Jae-chun, an international relations professor at Sogang University in Seoul, also said any trilateral military technology cooperation would largely focus on North Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While previously the discussion remained on sharing the alert on North Korean missiles, now it will focus on the drills to intercept North Korean ballistic missiles using their radar and missile weapons systems,” Kim said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think it has a great meaning in deterring North Korean nuclear development. However, China will criticise South Korea&#39;s incorporation into the US missile defence system.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kim said while the joint statement after the trilateral summit was not likely to point at China as a threat, the US-China rivalry had already turned into a strategic competition, regardless of the aims of the trilateral summit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The current trend shows that China-Russia-North Korea cooperation is strengthening in northeast Asia and US-South Korea-Japan ties are also increasing in response … it appears that the two sides are containing each other.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Number of childless Hong Kong couples doubles in 5 years as average births drop below 1 per family for first time]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3231195/childless-hong-kong-couples-double-5-years-average-births-drop-below-1-family-first-time?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 21:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/03881c67-4fa8-4612-9654-81ff0753962f_5a03c996.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The number of childless couples in Hong Kong has reached an “alarming” level, the Family Planning Association has warned, with a survey finding that the proportion of respondents without offspring has more than doubled in five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The survey released on Tuesday also found the average number of children among the city&#39;s couples dropped to a new low of 0.9, smashing the previous record of 1.2 in 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In Hong Kong, we have an ageing [population] situation because we do not have enough young people,” said the association&#39;s honorary adviser and research subcommittee chairman Professor Paul Yip Siu-fai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city faced emigration challenges, suffered from a low fertility rate and life expectancy was increasing, he noted, adding: “The ageing [population] will just become more and more acute in the years to come.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yip, a population expert at the University of Hong Kong, was commenting on the findings of the association&#39;s Family Planning Knowledge, Attitude and Practice in Hong Kong Survey, which polled 1,502 women and their male partners between September to December 2022. Among the women, 1,104 were married and 398 were not.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The study, conducted every five years, found childless couples had more than doubled from 20.6 per cent of respondents in 2017 to 43.2 per cent, replacing those with one child – which stood at 27.4 per cent – as the city&#39;s average. About a quarter of those surveyed (25.2 per cent) had two children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2017, 38.3 per cent of couples had one child and 33.8 per cent of them had two.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong population hits 7.5 million, helped by border reopening, entry schemes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to Yip, the increase in the number of childless couples was “quite alarming”, especially with the city&#39;s latest fertility rate at 772, with predictions that it could go even lower in the next two to five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fertility rate refers to the average number of babies born alive to 1,000 women during their lifetime, with the figure excluding domestic helpers. According to the Census and Statistics Department, the figure has steadily decreased from 1,205 in 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yip said small families had become the norm of high-income societies, not only in Hong Kong but also in Singapore, Tokyo and London.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said in Hong Kong, in particular, fewer people were tying the knot, accounting for 70 per cent of the drop in the fertility rate, while the other 30 per cent was because of a decrease in the number of married couples having children.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Tax breaks for hiring domestic helpers may boost Hong Kong&#39;s birth rate: study&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Because of the delay of the marriage, the window to conceive the baby becomes smaller,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Responding to questions about how authorities would increase the average number of children couples have, the association&#39;s executive director Dr Mona Lam Wai-cheung said there was no single solution to the issue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The solution would be a holistic approach … just [having] financial support may not solve the whole problem. We have to [use] an integrated approach in different sectors to help young couples,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam pointed out that obstacles which financial support could not solve might include a lack of time off work or a shortage of childcare services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The survey also recorded a slight increase in the proportion of women wanting to have children, rising to 22 per cent in 2022 from 15.3 per cent five years ago, while those who did not want any children or any additional ones accounted for 55.2 per cent, down from 67.4 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Women who had not made up their minds accounted for 22.8 per cent, slightly higher than 17.3 per cent in 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yip said the increase in the number of women wanting to become mothers was due to the younger age of respondents included in the latest survey and residents waiting until later in life to marry. The average marriage age rose to 30 from 27 or 28 five years ago, he noted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The later women get married, the window for conceiving the baby becomes shorter,” he said. “Late marriage has increased women&#39;s desire to have children.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong schools cut over 40 Form One classes amid student population drop&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The trend was good for the city, he noted, while calling for more policies to support it, including enhanced childcare services and more parental leave to encourage more women, especially those undecided about starting families, to have children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Specialist gynaecologist Chan Yik-si from Hong Kong Reproductive Medicine Centre said it had seen a 20 per cent surge in the number of women who had sought help in the past five years, and most were over 40, well past the ideal age for pregnancies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For 43-year-old Ken Chan Hiu-kwong the desire to have children became “very strong” three years ago when he realised that should he or his wife die, the other one would have no one to to rely on for emotional support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The couple&#39;s first child, conceived through in vitro fertilisation, was born 18 months ago and they expect the second one this December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If anyone asks me whether or not to have children, my answer is affirmative even though the children mean a financial burden,” Chan said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Finless porpoise found dead on Hong Kong beach in 20th stranding case reported this year]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231200/finless-porpoise-found-dead-hong-kong-beach-20th-stranding-case-reported-year?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 22:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/bdbb7234-a745-4018-a0b0-f70759d9548f_919a4ba2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A finless porpoise has been found dead on a beach in Sai Kung, marking the 20th stranding case involving marine mammals reported in Hong Kong this year, according to the Ocean Park Conservation Foundation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The group said the adult porpoise&#39;s carcass, which was severely decomposed, was brought to Ocean Park on Tuesday to find out the cause of death, a day after it was discovered on a beach near Joss House Bay, or Tai Miu Wan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The porpoise measured about 1.7 metres (5.6 feet) in length, with its sex yet to be confirmed. The species is commonly seen in local waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spokesman of the foundation, which helps the government investigate all cases of stranded cetaceans, said fishing nets, a common threat to the species, were not seen on the carcass.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The foundation previously said human activity was the main reason for cetacean fatalities among stranding cases where the cause of death could be determined.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fishing nets or gear entanglement was one of the major reasons for the animals stranding in local waters, while trauma caused by boats and lung infections were among common causes of death, the foundation said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Viena Mak Hei-man, vice-chairwoman of the Hong Kong Dolphin Conservation Society, said the resumption of high-speed ferries between Macau and Hong Kong following the full reopening of the border earlier this year would intensify the risks to the finless porpoise.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Whale carcass found in Hong Kong waters sparks anger against sightseers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ferries travel through the waters off southern Lantau Island, an area in which the species breeds and nurses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She urged the government to consider adopting the group&#39;s proposal to relocate the ferry route away from these waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A male juvenile Bryde&#39;s whale measuring more than eight metres in length was found dead late last month off Shelter Island in Sai Kung, two weeks after it was first spotted in nearby waters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The death of the mammal, which had wounds suspected to have been caused by vessels, has sparked heated discussions about the city&#39;s conservation policies.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong buries dead whale earlier spotted alive in city&#39;s waters&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The foundation reiterated a call to the public to play an active role in reporting any cetacean, shark or ray stranding.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It encouraged residents to contact it at 1823, providing crucial information such as the date and time of the discovery, precise location, and any accompanying visual evidence, such as photos or videos, so immediate action could be taken.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also advised boaters to avoid using shampoo and shower gel while on board, as untreated chemicals from these products could directly pollute the sea.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Plastic not fantastic as Hong Kong consumer watchdog finds online stores breach mandatory HK$1 charge for throwaway bags]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231202/plastic-not-fantastic-hong-kong-consumer-watchdog-finds-online-stores-breach-mandatory-hk1-charge?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.15 22:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/15/440a4ead-8921-4d01-a712-18977058e5a4_df48b1ed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong online grocery stores may have broken environmental protection laws by not charging a mandatory HK$1 (13 US cents) fee per plastic bag or by giving too many of them to customers, the city&#39;s consumer watchdog has found.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The discovery that almost half of the retailers checked failed to stick to the plastic bag rules sparked an appeal to retailers from the Consumer Council for simpler packaging and “no bag” options to cut down on waste.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The watchdog added the government should also provide clearer guidelines for traders to reduce the city&#39;s use of disposable plastics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Professor Nora Tam Fung-yee, the council&#39;s research and testing committee chairwoman, highlighted consumers in bricks-and-mortar stores could choose not to take a plastic bag.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Consumers have the right to information and choice. We could choose to not use a plastic bag when visiting a physical store,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Why couldn&#39;t we have such an option when shopping online?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tam was speaking after a council report said five of the 11 online grocery stores and e-commerce platforms it had inspected did not levy the plastic bag charge, designed to protect the environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The council explained that stores and platforms used a variety of terms for extra charges, with some using “packaging fee” and “packaging handling fee” to cover paper bags or cartons, which made it tough to check whether the charge of at least HK$1 per plastic bag rule was applied correctly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also suggested that online stores and e-commerce platforms should be advised to make their charging policies and calculation rules for plastic bags and packaging clearer.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong wet markets hand out plastic bags freely despite HK$1 levy, checks show&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“To safeguard consumers&#39; rights to make environmentally friendly choices, the council also recommends the Environmental Protection Department should provide clearer guidelines,” Tam said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These include stating the scope and quantity of additional plastic bags and insulated bags to be used by the traders in the course of transportation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Retailers, including online ones, are required to charge a minimum of HK$1 for each plastic bag, except where food items are unpackaged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;APITA UNY and DCH Foods gave out plastic bags without charging the levies for all food.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HKTVmall, PARKNSHOP and YATA did the same in some trial orders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The online stores were checked by council staff, who posed as consumers and carried out 69 trial orders for different types of food between June and early July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The watchdog also found that 10 of the trial orders provided more plastic bags than the fees charged.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong marks Earth Day by recycling plastic waste, saving food for the poor&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;HKTVmall charged HK$2, but used six plastic bags for nine food items.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three packs of frozen meat were packed in individual flat-top plastic bags, two T-shirt plastic bags were used for canned food, a cup noodle and a bag of crisps and a head of broccoli was packed in its own insulated bag.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HKTVmall told the council that plastic bags and packaging were used to ensure accurate identification of products and delivery as part of its logistics and transport process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The firm added its collaboration with 5,800 partner shops and suppliers resulted in the use of multiple plastic bags.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DCH Foods said the packaging materials were provided by Foodpanda, which handled its deliveries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The council received 39 complaints related to plastic bag use between January and July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post has contacted the Environmental Protection Department for comment.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 15 Aug 2023 22:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>