<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong marks threefold increase in number of visitors arrested in first quarter, part of post-Covid trend]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3222027/hong-kong-marks-threefold-increase-number-visitors-arrested-first-quarter-part-post-covid-trend?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/27/0ef13db3-84d7-41d7-b3da-a7d549d02495_7525aa2e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;据记录，香港因各种罪行被捕的游客人数增加了三倍该市今年前三个月与 2022 年同期相比，在放松对 Covid-19 的限制后重新向世界开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方数据显示，有 499 名旅客因涉嫌犯罪而被拘留1 月至 3 月期间，该市发生了各种违法行为，是去年第一季度被抓获的 165 名游客的三倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被逮捕的 499 名游客中有一半以上（即 266 名）来自中国大陆，标志着比去年同期的 37 人增加了六倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地方当局在整个 2022 年逮捕了 266 名大陆游客，2021 年逮捕了 251 名，2020 年逮捕了 392 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数量今年前三个月因各种犯罪而被捕的其他国家访客人数也从 2022 年同期的 128 人增加了 82% 至 233 人。该部队没有提供这些访客来源的任何细分。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名警队内部人士表示，这些罪行包括扒窃、盗窃商店和盗窃无人看管的贵重物品，并补充说，一些来自大陆的女访客也因违反在扫黄行动中的逗留条件而被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;据警方称，今年 1 月至 3 月期间，盗窃报告从去年同期的 3,678 起上升了 45%，达到 5,340 起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;盗窃案数量激增早些时候的案件引发了该市日本领事馆的警告，提醒其国民保持警惕，注意自己的财物，避免在街上行走时使用智能手机或听音乐。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方逮捕了一名女子， 53、盗窃价值950万港元的玉器&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方消息称，随着旅游恢复正常，入境人数逐渐增加，预计因各种违法行为被捕的游客人数将激增。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，在 2018 年和 2019 年的每个季度，平均约有 400 名大陆游客因各种违法行为被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方发言人表示，因犯下以下罪行而被捕的游客人数今年第一季的罪案有所增加，但仍低于 2019 年同期的大流行前水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“警方会密切留意趋势，适时采取适当行动，包括加强巡逻所有地区，开展有针对性的以情报为主导的行动，并促进预防犯罪，”发言人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港和大陆之间的所有过境点都已重新开放，同时对旅客实施配额制度和 Covid-19 测试2月初也有所下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;全面重开首日19万人次过港&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;入境事务处统计显示，共有335万内地旅客过境1 月和 3 月，来自其他国家或台湾的游客有 105 万人次进入香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个数字与 2022 年同期形成鲜明对比，当时 2022 年同期实施了与冠状病毒相关的限制措施，只有 7,807 人次大陆游客和 2,082 名来自海外或台湾的游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港于 2022 年 12 月 14 日取消了对国际入境者的强制隔离，使其成为世界上最后一个取消严格的 Covid-19 控制的地方之一&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年第一季度，发生了多起盗窃案，讲普通话的女性以按摩或性服务为由引诱老年男性窃取名表和黄金等贵重物品&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二月份，至少有九起此类案件，其中大多数受害者是老年男性。据报道，三起事件发生在深水埗，其他事件发生在新界地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港“黄金周”中国内地游客涌入打击犯罪&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2月22日，警方逮捕了一对来自内地的夫妇，他们涉嫌从一名老人以性承诺引诱他到深水埗的一间房后盗窃 3,000 港元（383 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了盗窃&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方于 2 月 21 日逮捕了两名来自大陆的老年游客，他们涉嫌拉二胡，并收集铜锣湾路人的钱。这名66岁男子和73岁女子后来被控在公共场所乞讨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在那一周内，两名年龄分别为38岁和51岁的内地残疾男子也被因涉嫌乞讨而被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自该市取消旅行限制以来，当局还注意到贩毒集团利用快递员混入航空旅客以逃避海关检查的情况有所增加&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 8 日至 14 日期间，海关在香港国际机场查获价值超过 1000 万港元的可卡因，并逮捕了五名来自巴西的旅客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在今年前四个月，九名入境旅客在机场被拘留，并在机场查获 5.8 公斤（12.8 磅）违禁药物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oscar Liu 补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As Asia grapples with declining birth rates, Catholic-majority Philippines wants fewer babies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222788/asia-grapples-declining-birth-rates-catholic-majority-philippines-wants-fewer-babies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/c01d9ca4-20b2-4381-9247-ea7fecd04b63_7d3d31be.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;随着亚洲及其他地区的出生率直线下降，菲律宾脱颖而出&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，这个东南亚国家一直在努力应对在日本和韩国等国家令人羡慕的困境，这些国家的政府为有孩子的夫妇提供现金奖励。由于许多国家记录的死亡人数多于出生人数，对于那些认为年轻劳动力预示着更高生产力的人来说，菲律宾是一颗璀璨的明星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但拥有 1.13 亿人口的菲律宾官员对此问题有不同的看法.由小费迪南德·马科斯总统领导的政府警告说，如果不解决人口挑战，该国就无法取得广泛的经济成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管菲律宾在过去十年的大部分时间里都保持着强劲的增长率，但它仍然是最贫穷的国家之一降低生育率（是韩国的两倍多）是发展指标的关键战略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实证明，在这个天主教徒占多数的国家，改变人们对计划生育的态度是一项艰巨的任务。生育率升高与宗教和文化期望交织在一起，也凸显了避孕药具和医疗保健服务的可及性薄弱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾与其富裕的亚洲国家之间三分之一的产出差距可以“归因于国家经济和发展局秘书阿塞尼奥·巴利萨坎 (Arsenio Balisacan) 说，这很容易导致我们还没有进入人口红利这一事实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴利萨坎说，尽管劳动力较少可能是富裕国家的一个问题那些地方的官员有钱投资技术和发展。在菲律宾，越来越多的人对有限的资源造成了巨大压力。政府已将计划生育作为今年最大的预算优先事项之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最基本、最根本的问题是让我们的穷人摆脱困境并改善获得服务的机会，以便每个人都能得到提升，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;‘我们想要自由’：随着态度的转变，菲律宾人争取离婚权&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;关于人口下降对世界意味着什么，结论不一。随着收入的增加和避孕药具的普及，生育率正在下降，此外，女性对晚生育或根本不生育的态度也在改变。联合国现在预计，到 2100 年，人口数量将达到 104 亿的峰值，比早前超过 110 亿的估计有所下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使人口减少有利于环境可持续性等方面，但人口老龄化带来了挑战，包括不断上涨的医疗保健和退休成本。这一论点在亚洲最经得起考验，那里的生育率下降幅度最为严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在日本，出生率多年来一直在下降，政府宣布了新的措施来提高生育率，为未来的发展铺平了道路。将用于儿童的预算增加一倍的方法。在中国，去年人口出现了自 1960 年代以来的首次减少，官员们正在努力改变几十年来对家庭规模的态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本有婴儿危机，因为年轻人是坏情人，政治家说&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在韩国，这个数字甚至更加严峻，韩国拥有世界上最低的生育率，每位妇女生育 0.78 个孩子。官员们正在转向机器人和无人机，以填补征兵方面的空白。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据联合国的数据，到 2050 年，菲律宾是少数几个将占全球人口预计增长一半以上的国家之一&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾著名经济学家巴利萨坎 (Balisacan) 表示，菲律宾必须利用人口增长低于劳动力增长率的“人口甜蜜点”。除非创造足够的优质就业机会，否则该国无法推高国内生产总值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从这个有利的角度来看，Balisacan 表示，对于日本等富裕国家的政策制定者来说，解决出生率下降的问题相对容易。 “放宽你的移民政策，”他说。 “我宁愿有那个问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有一些进步的迹象。根据政府的初步数据，菲律宾的生育率在 2022 年降至每名妇女生育 1.9 个孩子，但很难衡量与流行病相关的限制措施的影响。这比五年前的 2.7 有所下降，也低于通常被视为一代又一代人口更替水平的 2.1。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着菲律宾渴望获得人口红利，它必须付出代价该国人口与发展委员会执行主任 Lisa Grace Bersales 说，关注劳动力素质、妇女和其他少数群体的参与以及其他容易滋生不平等的因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人口据 Bersales 称，委员会正在制定一项旨在于本季度或下一季度发布的五年行动计划。她说，除了解决生殖健康需求外，该行动计划还将以人口统计学的整体方法解决教育、就业、移民和气候变化等问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;批评者认为，菲律宾工人需要工作，而不是另一个移民机构说&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 2012 年具有里程碑意义的生殖健康法获得通过后，计划生育也得到了推动。该立法扩大了菲律宾获得避孕药具、生育控制、性教育和孕产妇护理的机会。&lt;/p>; p>;在该国首都马尼拉，Junice Melgar 表示，现在有更多贫困社区的女性向她的组织寻求建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们发现这种需求很大，”Likhaan Center 的执行董事 Melgar 说为成立于 1995 年的非营利组织 Women&#39;s Health Inc 工作。她说，自大流行以来，人们一直在“公开呼吁”获取有关避孕药具的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公众意识的提高带来了红利。据统计机构称，如今约有一半的已婚菲律宾妇女不想要额外的孩子。农村地区的妇女——那里通常难以获得避孕药具——去年的生育率更高，为每名妇女生育 2.2 个孩子，而城市地区为 1.7 个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马科斯政府“高度重视”其政策预算局局长 Amenah Pangandaman 表示，通过分配资金雇用毕业生进行实习并帮助他们寻找工作，来帮助青年劳动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 9 月于纽约证券交易所向投资者发表的演讲中，Marcos 强调说推动和吹捧年轻人准备工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我相信，我们是亚洲最年轻的国家，”他说。 “随着该地区其他国家的老龄化，这给了我们一个优势。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How exit bans are harming China’s push to welcome foreign business]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3222691/how-exit-bans-are-harming-chinas-push-welcome-foreign-business?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/03d81f12-05e3-4def-a1a9-3de4ea2fde51_31c3df32.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国领导人为知名海外高管铺开红地毯，并反复向他们保证该国自去年 12 月开始营业，当时北京解除了对 Covid-19 的严格限制，该限制关闭了世界第二大经济体近三年。最新的例子是官方媒体对特斯拉首席执行官埃隆马斯克的访问给予了摇滚明星般的待遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们访问的新闻报道无疑会鼓励其他企业家和投资者恢复到大陆旅行在中美紧张局势加剧的情况下，他们试图弄清楚该国充满政治色彩的投资环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，在过去几个月与驻香港的高管交谈时，我发现有些人已经开始对几年前听起来很荒谬的事情表示担忧：去大陆旅行安全吗？他们会被禁止出境吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;听起来不祥的中文短语，或退出禁令，现在经常进入高管之间的餐桌谈话，尤其是在一些酒放松他们的舌头之后。该短语指的是当局越来越多地使用一种政策工具，以防止人们因怀疑或被指控有不当行为而离开该国，或者仅仅因为他们在商业纠纷中站在错误的一方或为错误的人工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着我深入研究这个问题，几乎所有与我交谈过的高管都有关于离职禁令的故事，要么是关于他们自己的不愉快经历，要么是关于他们的商业朋友被禁止离职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这里是一个真实的故事，它将把出境禁令的影响置于背景中，因为它表明该政策是任意实施的，并且违反了国际法和人权。此外，这也成为北京和华盛顿之间谈判的一个症结所在，因为一些美国护照持有人以及其他外国高管已被出境禁令所困。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;对于中国知识分子来说，限制早在pandemic&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这个故事涉及一位业务联系人，我称他为 X 先生，以保护他的身份和安全。 X 先生是一名高级管理人员，供职于最终由段伟红控制的北京众多公司之一，这位亿万富翁因与中国前总理温家宝的近亲有着密切的业务往来而闻名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;X 先生2017 年 10 月，当他试图飞往加拿大探亲时，他意识到事情严重不对，但在北京首都国际机场被边防警察拦下。他们告诉他，他涉嫌经济犯罪，不被允许离开，但他们拒绝出示任何文件或提供进一步的细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他很快意识到，拒绝让他离开可能已经尽管段六年前离开了她的公司，但他仍因腐败指控被秘密拘留的谣言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在接下来的几天里，他疯狂地打电话给同样在公司工作的前同事和其他商业伙伴段某透露，他们中至少有十几人有过类似的经历，在前往香港的机场或轮渡码头的检查站被拒之门外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;X先生最终在北京滞留五年多，直到今年1月，在此期间，他与妻子和儿子保持分离，错过了重要的家庭活动。虽然他可以自由去中国大陆的任何地方，但心理压力对他的身心健康造成了损害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在滞留的五年多时间里，当局没有联系过他一次。他没有途径对出境禁令提出上诉，因为他不知道是谁实施了禁令，也不知道为什么。在此期间，他随后两次尝试离开该国，同样遭到拒绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到今年年初，当有人猜测段已获保释时，他的希望才升起。再次碰碰运气，他订了飞往香港的航班，轻而易举地通过了北京机场的边境检查站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;X 先生的创伤经历符合近年来的一种模式，即一旦一名商界人士被拘留如果怀疑有不当行为，几乎所有此人的家庭成员、高级同事和商业伙伴都将面临离境禁令。在该人被释放或被正式定罪之前，他们将被禁止离开该国数月甚至数年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在全国范围内，权利组织 Safeguard 的详细分析最近揭示了出境禁令的规模捍卫者。它估计至少有“数万人”在任何时候都被禁止离开该国。虽然其中大多数是中国公民，但旅行禁令影响了越来越多的海外公民以及来自香港和台湾的公民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据报告，至少有 14 项法律和数十项法规，涵盖当今中国大陆出境禁令的法律解释和文件。此外，将于下个月生效的中国新反间谍法允许对任何被调查人员实施出境禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据我的调查，在少数例外情况下，一些商人面临出差出境禁令可能会无限期地让他们陷入困境，因为为调查这些人而成立的工作组在出境禁令取消之前就已经解散。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这解释了为什么一些海外投资者和商人越来越担心。虽然交易在开展正常业务时可能会失败，但应以适当和透明的方式解决争端。在中国领导层努力表明其对海外业务开放之际，任意和广泛实施出境禁令只会损害中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Zealand’s ex-PM Jacinda Ardern given top royal honour for service during shooting and pandemic]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3222932/new-zealands-ex-pm-jacinda-ardern-given-top-royal-honour-service-during-shooting-and-pandemic?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 07:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/05/73dd1297-cdd1-4dea-ac81-79335b047ff3_bb5cf875.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周一，前总理 Jacinda Ardern 因其服务获得了新西兰最高荣誉之一领导该国度过大规模枪击事件和冠状病毒大流行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿德恩被授予女爵勋章，这是新西兰第二高的荣誉，是查尔斯国王生日荣誉的一部分。这意味着人们现在会称她为 Dame Jacinda。在新西兰，皇家获奖者通常每年两次由总理选出，并由英国国王查理斯签署，查理斯也被公认为新西兰国王。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿德恩在 2017 年成为总理时年仅 37 岁2017 年，并被视为左翼的全球偶像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在 1 月份表示她将在五年多后辞去领导人职务，因为她不再“油箱里有足够的东西”，这震惊了新西兰人” 以公正对待。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在国内面临越来越大的政治压力，包括她对 Covid-19 的处理方式，这最初受到广泛称赞，但后来遭到反对强制和规则的人的批评。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;接替 Ardern 的总理克里斯·希普金斯 (Chris Hipkins) 表示，她在“我们国家在现代面临的一些最大挑战”中的贡献得到认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“领导新西兰应对疫情2019 年的恐怖袭击和 Covid-19 大流行代表了我们第 40 任总理面临的严峻挑战时期，在此期间，我亲眼看到她对新西兰的承诺仍然是绝对的，”希普金斯在一份声明中说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019 年，一名白人至上主义枪手在基督城的两座清真寺发动袭击，导致 51 名穆斯林礼拜者在周五的祈祷中丧生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿德恩表示，她对是否接受该奖项持两种看法，因为大部分她之所以获得认可，是因为所有新西兰人都有共同的经历。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所以对我来说，这是关于我的家人、我的同事和所有支持我去做这份令人难以置信的有价值工作的人，”她告诉 1 News。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ardern 将在今年晚些时候临时加入哈佛大学，此前她被任命为哈佛大学肯尼迪学院的双重奖学金。她还承担了一项与网络极端主义作斗争的无偿工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;橄榄球教练韦恩·史密斯 (Wayne Smith) 也获得了国王诞辰纪念奖，他帮助带领男女橄榄球队代表新西兰夺得了世界杯冠军。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;按照传统，英国女王卡米拉被任命为新西兰勋章，获得了最高奖项。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How a former Google scientist is trying to ride the wave of China’s ChatGPT-led AI boom]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3222904/how-former-google-scientist-trying-ride-wave-chinas-chatgpt-led-ai-boom?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/ce869284-cbe4-4fd7-af68-abce3d8bf125_a5e77afd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;前谷歌计算机科学家李志飞过去常常在工作日早上8点起床，但经常熬夜在床上多睡一会儿。不再。 “现在我马上起床开始工作，”出门问问的首席执行官兼创始人李先生说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是什么让李先生这些天早点起床？在以 ChatGPT 为首的生成式 AI 技术大受欢迎之后，中国的人工智能 (AI) 初创企业获得了一剂强心针。没有时间可以浪费，李是试图乘风破浪的本土科技企业家的典型代表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他十年的创业之路并非一帆风顺，但生成式人工智能的普及开辟了新的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“事实上，过去五个月我一直很努力，”李在最近接受南华早报采访时说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;中国的类似 Quora 的平台知乎在问答服务中嵌入了生成式人工智能功能&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;李毕业于约翰霍普金斯大学，获得计算机科学博士学位，之后于 2010 年 5 月加入谷歌担任研究科学家。离开谷歌后，他创立了出门问问，一家专注于高级语音交互和软硬件集成的人工智能公司，吸引了红杉资本和真格基金等知名投资者的投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我觉得我连一个谷歌都呆不下去了更多的日子是因为我感受到了一种非常强烈的使命感。我觉得[人与设备之间]的交互非常重要，这是我擅长的[并且具有]强大的市场潜力。如果我晚一个星期进入这个领域，市场情况可能会大不相同，”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于北京的出门问问是众多赶上大语言潮流的中国初创企业之一模型 (LLM)，利用围绕 ChatGPT 的市场狂热，与百度等中国大型科技公司争夺中国市场的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据本周发布的一份报告中国科学技术信息研究所是政府研究机构，中国至少有 79 个大型 AI 模型，参数超过 10 亿个，主要集中在语言和视觉识别领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mobvoi 的模型被称为须列猴子，大致翻译为“测序猴”。据该公司称，它拥有数百亿个参数，与 Open AI 开发的 GPT-3 的 1750 亿个参数相比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国 ChatGPT 竞争对手提交了其首次公开募股计划到香港股票上周交换。根据其招股说明书，收入从 2020 年的 2.645 亿元人民币（3730 万美元）增长到 2021 年的 3.979 亿元人民币，去年达到 5.002 亿元人民币。然而，该公司 2022 年的亏损达到 6.7 亿元，而 2020 年的利润为 5600 万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出门问问正与中国国际金融公司和招商银行国际合作筹集高达 3 亿美元的资金在 IPO 中，彭博社上个月报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了法学硕士，出门问问还推出了消费产品，包括出门问问移动应用程序、TicWatch 系列智能手表和 TicPods 系列无线智能耳机，目标是成为人工智能可穿戴品牌。该公司还为内容生成器开发了 AI 语音配音助手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2012 年开始时，我们主要从事软件开发，很快就获得了资金，但 [大约] 2014 年和 2015 年我在对如何将技术货币化感到迷茫……然后我们转向了硬件，”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在过去的 10 年里，我们尝试了很多方法，它们成为了我们今天的基石，”他补充道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的大型科技公司都在攻读法学硕士学位。总部位于北京的搜索引擎巨头百度于 3 月推出了 Ernie Bot，而邮政所有者阿里巴巴集团控股公司正计划将其统一千文聊天机器人整合到其所有产品中。 4 月，AI 公司 SenseTime 推出了最新的大型 AI 模型集 SenseNova。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li 将 GPT 模型比作 2010 年对互联网的感觉，当时中国人认为它是下一件大事. “在 2010 年，你已经知道智能手机硬件不再是问题......现在，如果你能生成像 GPT-3.5 一样好的模型，我认为下一步就是找到一个好的场景 [in which to apply it]， ”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然会有过滤的过程。现在是大型语言模型的爆发期，一些玩家会掉队。重要的是，每个 [player] 都有其优势和局限性，我们所有人都需要找到自己的定位，”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京最高互联网监管机构发布了指导方针草案，要求进行安全审查随着世界各国政府采取行动控制这些工具的快速发展，生成式人工智能服务的数量也在增加。根据中国国家互联网信息办公室 4 月份发布的拟议法规，在中国提供生成人工智能服务的公司必须采取措施防止歧视性内容、虚假信息以及损害个人隐私或知识产权的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;李说，中国球员在发展法学硕士方面处于不同的阶段。 “美国做大模型的公司不多，但他们有生态系统，有做大模型的，有做中间层的，有做应用的，”李说。 . “然而，中国仍处于第一阶段……所以我们在这个领域比美国落后大约一两年。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于出门问问来说，下一步是通过连接使其 LLM “有用”它与应用程序。 “当模型为我们的用户提供更好的体验时，我们将拥有更多的用户、更多的商业化，我们的模型也会获得更多的数据，”李说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Defying Beijing set Hong Kong’s Civic Party on road to political irrelevance]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3222726/defying-beijing-set-hong-kongs-civic-party-road-political-irrelevance?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 06:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/adbea76a-dfb9-4f2e-a0b2-dafdbb246364_8df9e34b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;我必须承认，当我读到思域的新闻时，我感到一阵遗憾党已经折叠。主席兼联合创始人 Alan Leong Kah-kit 在剩余成员在一次特别股东大会上几乎一致投票开始结束程序后宣布了这一消息，因为没有人准备在这个拥有 17 年历史的组织中任职。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;我立刻想起党在几年前邀请我参加“公民党已成为历史”议案的辩论。我要提出议案，梁会反对，而大部分由议员组成的听众会就所提出的论点的是非曲直进行投票。主持人是一位著名的当地记者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我很高兴接受邀请，原因有很多：我认识许多党的领导人，我特别喜欢他们愿意向外界敞开心扉批评;聚会的工作语言是英语，这将消除沟通中的任何尴尬；将我的技能与受过良好教育的专业人士进行较量将是一种乐趣和挑战，他们中的许多人都是律师界的高级成员，并以复杂的法律案件为生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要说我输了压倒性的轻描淡写。我记得，我从在场的少数几个非成员之一那里得到了一张选票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时的公民党是彩虹色联盟的成员，这个联盟可以粗略地描述为亲民主党派。每个人都有东西：劳动人民的劳动，较不富裕的民主民生协会，政治觉悟者的原始民主党，更激进和各种分裂团体的社会民主党联盟，每个由一个有魅力的人物领导。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我认为公民党处于中间位置，有点高调，带有学术和法律偏见，但有点适度。我预计它会主要吸引中间路线的中产阶级人士，就像它的成员一样，他们倾向于民主，但不热衷于任何过于激进的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我的评估是错误的。一个直接的警告信号是一名党员领导对私人体育和社交俱乐部特权的攻击，暗示这些东西是殖民时代的遗物，是时候将这些设施交到公众手中了。在我看来，这完全是对形势的误读。诚然，这些俱乐部中有许多在刚成立时，其成员主要是外籍人士，而且他们的业务相当排外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，近几十年来的发展改变了这种情况。许多有问题的俱乐部都有大量当地会员，他们必须允许非会员使用他们的设施一定时间。还应考虑会员向俱乐部支付的巨额费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;温和政党的重点肯定应该是确保类似的设施可供较不富裕的人使用。换句话说，它应该支持升级而不是破解。 As for the membership of the private clubs, it seemed to me that both locals and expats should have been people the Civic Party would want to count among its supporters. Where was the logic in attacking institutions which many of their prospective members and voters had paid for and enjoyed?&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why Hong Kong needed clubs before it needed a hospital&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On the political front, the party joined hands with the League of Social Democrats in 2009 to organise the “five districts referendum”. The idea was that one legislator from each of Hong Kong&#39;s five geographical constituencies would resign their seat and then stand for re-election. According to their plan, the resulting by-elections would constitute a de facto referendum on the pace of democratisation desired by local people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The resignations went ahead in January 2010 and the by-elections were held in May. All five members of the pan-democratic camp were duly re-elected, but turnout for the by-election was just 17 per cent whereas the original hope of the organisers had been at least 50 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around the same time the party opposed the reform package, its rival, the Democratic Party, negotiated with the city administration. That package provided for the five additional “functional constituency” seats to be elected on a quasi-democratic basis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, Civic Party members went to the US to discuss democracy and the rule of law in Hong Kong. I must confess this practice has always puzzled me. The capital city we should be focused on is the one in China. The dialogue we must improve is with Beijing. Washington and London are nice places to visit, but they have no part to play in Hong Kong&#39;s political development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Party members also took a role in the procedural tussle that delayed enactment of the law dealing with the national anthem for many months. One does not need to be a political genius to work out how that would have been interpreted by central government leaders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All this said, I will miss the Civic Party. It had admirable aims, and many of its leaders were good people on an individual basis. Even so, it slipped into the posture of attempting to defy Beijing, which is a road to political irrelevance. The inability to live with the reality of Chinese sovereignty meant its time was up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Veteran DJ Paul Oakenfold accused of sexual harassment by former assistant]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222931/veteran-dj-paul-oakenfold-accused-sexual-harassment-former-assistant?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 06:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/05/7787ce59-03fb-4c93-aaf8-9e2f21b7e397_4277cd3b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Veteran trance DJ Paul Oakenfold is facing allegations that he repeatedly exposed himself and masturbated near his young personal assistant, according to a new lawsuit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A woman identified as Jane Roe filed a sexual harassment claim in Los Angeles Superior Court on Friday. She is suing Oakenfold and the companies that managed him, Paul Stepanek Management and New Frequency Management, accusing them of turning a blind eye to Oakenfold masturbating in full view of her and then terminating her when she complained about the alleged abuse, according to court papers obtained by Business Insider.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roe is seeking damages of more than US$25,000. Entertainment news site Deadline was the first to report the news.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plaintiff says the sexual harassment began on her first day working for the Grammy-nominated Briton Oakenfold, 59, who has remixed songs for U2, Britney Spears, Michael Jackson and the Rolling Stones.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roe said she was 23 when Paul Stepanek&#39;s management company hired her last October to be Oakenfold&#39;s personal assistant for US$20 an hour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On four separate occasions, each on different dates, where Oakenfold had plaintiff alone at his house, Oakenfold touched his genitals and then masturbated in front of plaintiff when Oakenfold was aware plaintiff could not escape,” Roe&#39;s complaint states. “In each instance of masturbation, as described herein, Oakenfold stimulated his genitals with his hand, in close proximity to the plaintiff, for plaintiff to see.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roe alleged that Oakenfold escalated the behaviour, masturbating in her presence for longer periods.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In one instance in November 2022, Oakenfold masturbated in front of the woman four times during the work day, the complaint alleges. And in another instance, Oakenfold “surprised” Roe by “opening his legs wide” and masturbating in the passenger seat of her car as she drove him home from the post office.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Plaintiff froze in fear and shock while being in such close proximity to Oakenfold,” the court papers state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roe said in her complaint that she reported Oakenfold&#39;s alleged behaviour to Stepanek, and he responded by pressuring her to sign a non-disclosure agreement. When she hesitated, Roe alleged Stepanek would not let her return to work until she signed it, which she eventually did “under duress,” the complaint states.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Roe did return to work, she said the management company reassigned her to other clients and cut her hours before eventually laying her off in March 2023. However, Roe alleged in the complaint she was let go because she spoke up about the alleged sexual harassment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Actor Danny Masterson segregated in prison for &#39;own safety&#39; ahead of rape sentencing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Our client has shown tremendous courage in coming forward about Mr Oakenfold&#39;s sexual harassment,” Roe&#39;s lawyer Jonathan M Genish told Insider.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our legal team is fully committed to holding him and the other defendants accountable for their egregious actions. We hope that this case will continue to shed light on the prevalence of such misconduct and encourage others who have experienced similar acts to reach out and seek justice.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oakenfold has not publicly commented on the lawsuit. Business Insider has contacted Oakenfold, Stepanek, Paul Stepanek Management, and New Frequency Management for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oakenfold is the latest veteran DJ to be accused of sexual impropriety. In 2020, a woman accused DJ Erick Morillo of raping her after a party where they were both DJing. Morillo, best known for co-writing the hit song I Like to Move It, was found dead in his home a few months later from an accidental overdose, according to the Miami New Times newspaper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawsuit does not seem to have affected Oakenfold&#39;s touring schedule. He is set to perform on June 10 at the Gathering Festival in Cleethorpes, UK.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Business Insider&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 06:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[British PM Rishi Sunak moves to curb migration, citing strain on UK services]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222930/british-pm-rishi-sunak-moves-curb-migration-citing-strain-uk-services?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 05:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/05/4db52764-4c79-4f2b-93f0-645763d783f4_bd9768ba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak this week will move to cut the flow of migrants, saying the UK government is struggling to cope with the number of arrivals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Immigration Minister Robert Jenrick said the government will deploy barges and unused army bases to house people seeking asylum and tell young men four people will have to share one room.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The measures are aimed at making Britain a less-attractive destination to people arriving through informal routes, especially on small boats across the English Channel. Ministers are concerned a record 606,000 more people moved to Britain than departed last year despite a promise to reduce immigration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We also can&#39;t allow the UK to be perceived to be a soft touch,” Jenrick said on BBC television&#39;s Sunday With Laura Kuenssberg show. “It&#39;s placing serious pressure on public services and our ability to successfully integrate people into the country.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Immigration has become a lightning rod for the right-wing of the ruling Conservative Party after a wave of migrants arrived in small boats this spring and inflows hit a record. Sunak has backed away from a manifesto promise to cut migration, but ministers are working on measures to deport 3,000 people a month deemed to have entered the UK illegally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Labour opposition has promised to cut immigration levels and says the Conservatives are to blame for letting numbers get out of control. The issue has added to friction with business lobby groups, which are urging a relaxing of the rules to allow in workers needed to fill vacant jobs and alleviate upwards pressures on wages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We want businesses to be in the first instance investing in British workers and technology and automation that drives productivity, not just reaching for the easy lever of foreign labour,” Jenrick told the BBC.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;UK migration hits record high despite bid to &#39;take back control&#39; of borders&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Jenrick said the asylum system needs “fundamental” reform because it is “riddled with abuse,” notably the government paying too much money to hotel operators for housing people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Illegal Migration Bill, due before the House of Lords on Wednesday, will let officials detain migrants who arrive through informal channels. The government wants to return many of them home – or to Rwanda.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That will create the deterrent we desperately need,” Jenrick said. “It will break the business model of the people smuggling gangs, and it will stop the system from coming under intolerable pressure like it is today.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The House of Commons on Wednesday is set to approve a bill that will confirm how and when immigrants are considered settled in the UK for citizenship purposes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jenrick said it&#39;s reasonable to ask asylum seekers to share rooms, brushing aside concerns of a group that refused to enter a hotel in Pimlico, where the Home Office had asked them to sleep “four people per room.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The leader of Westminster City Council expressed “deep concern” that some 40 refugees were placed in the borough last week “without appropriate accommodation or support available,” the Press Association reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We had offered them a safe bed with board and lodgings in a good-quality hotel in central London,” Jenrick said on the BBC. “Yes, some of them had to share with other people. These are single adult males, I don&#39;t think that&#39;s unreasonable.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the government wants to reduce the cost to taxpayers of housing asylum seekers, saying that putting them in hotels drains “valuable assets for the local business community.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can China’s yuan stake a bigger claim for global prominence following US debt ceiling crisis?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3222866/can-chinas-yuan-stake-bigger-claim-global-prominence-following-us-debt-ceiling-crisis?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/e7bdc369-9eef-4bd7-af05-e5ad122e9cc9_e9a74592.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As investors around the world held their breath last month pending a political compromise on the United States&#39; US$31.4 trillion debt ceiling, International Monetary Fund (IMF) managing director Kristalina Georgieva was among those hoping for a good outcome as the clock ticked closer to the deadline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Monday was the date when the US government could have run out of cash to pay its debts, a scenario that would have significantly weakened America&#39;s sovereign credit rating and global trust in the US dollar, opening up more opportunities for China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The world is watching,” Georgieva said on May 26 after the IMF&#39;s annual assessment of the US economy and financial system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We think of the US Treasury market as an anchor for the global financial system; and this anchor needs to hold something solid.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 190-member fund, a key part of the US-led global financial system, has increasingly looked east. In March, Georgieva applauded China for potentially contributing 30 per cent of global economic growth this year, something it has done consistently since the 2007-08 global financial crisis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Similar to that crisis, which prompted the start of Beijing&#39;s yuan internationalisation efforts in 2009, analysts said the months-long US debt ceiling stand-off, together with US decoupling threats and a succession of US interest rate increases, could be a defining moment for the Chinese currency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“International financial stability is in China&#39;s advantage, but does it have to be US led?” said Professor Liang Yan, an economist at Willamette University in the US state of Oregon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It has been proven that the US is not a great leader in this system.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aggressive interest rate increases by the US Federal Reserve – totalling 500 basis points in the past 14 months – have been a sword hanging over many emerging markets, and they have had to scramble to reinforce their foreign exchange reserves and economic foundations to ride out Washington&#39;s onslaught on high inflation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As China recovers from the economic impact of the Covid-19 pandemic, analysts said the country had several tools – including yuan investment in Belt and Road Initiative projects, yuan settlement with major trading partners, promotion of the digital yuan and non-dollar reserve diversification – that could chip away at the US dollar-driven world financial order.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese economy, the world&#39;s second largest, is moving away from an export-reliant model to one more focused on domestic consumption and a hefty dependence on imports of goods such as oil and food.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That would entail a shift from a US-centric financial mechanism that saw China attract US dollar investment in export-oriented factories and then use the US dollars it earned to invest in low-yield US Treasury bills.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China believes the US-led system, especially the hegemony of the US dollar, includes rules that play against China&#39;s interests,” said Sun Yun, director of the Washington-based Stimson Centre&#39;s China programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Therefore, to gradually undermine US credibility and revise that system is in China&#39;s long-term interest.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Sun said, the yuan could not replace the US dollar “in the foreseeable future”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The step-by-step approach suggested by many analysts largely reflects their concerns over Beijing&#39;s capital account controls, which limit the convertibility of the yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The biggest single obstacle to that goal is not just the entrenched role of the US dollar, but also key is Beijing&#39;s unwillingness to take its hand off its financial system and loosen the capital account,” said Dexter Roberts, director of China affairs at the Mansfield Centre at the University of Montana.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Until it does that – a move which by definition means lessening party control over the economy and allowing for example, independent banks to decide where to lend, and that could lead to capital flight – other countries will not be willing to hold substantial yuan reserves.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Which 8 nations are using China&#39;s yuan more, and how will it affect US dollar?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Analysts at Ping An Securities said the Chinese government was taking a conservative stance in reforming its monetary regime – one that could give the yuan more flexibility in international use.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Regarding the yuan, the Chinese government has always emphasised the orderly promotion of yuan internationalisation, and will not actively seek to replace the US dollar in the short term, and will be more cautious about the risks brought about by rapidly opening up its financial market,” they said at the end of last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has not released a road map or timetable for its yuan ambitions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A more realistic objective than replacing the US dollar, and one that is frequently cited by Chinese scholars and policy advisers, is for international use of the yuan to reflect China&#39;s 18 per cent share of global gross domestic product.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Jobs, the yuan and beyond: 4 things to look out for in China&#39;s economy in June&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Among the major parameters measuring whether the yuan is an international currency, its 12.28 per cent weighting in the IMF&#39;s special drawing rights basket is the closest to that mark, compared with 2.29 per cent for international payments, 4.72 per cent of trade finance and 2.69 per cent of central bank reserves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China might now find wider support for its ambitions to counterbalance the US-led financial system. Analysts said they expected frustration outside the US with recurring debt ceiling issues and perceptions of US protectionism would steer global finance away from the US currency – but not fully or right away.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Progress has been seen in trade settlements between China and its developing partners, an area where Beijing has been able to leverage its trade advantage to quickly increase the use of the Chinese currency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eight countries, including Russia, Brazil, Argentina, Saudi Arabia and Thailand, have accepted yuan as payment for oil, gas and a nuclear power plant, and that momentum is set to grow thanks to major trade agreements and China&#39;s involvement in the BRICS – a bloc that also comprises Brazil, Russia, India and South Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Rare opportunity&#39; for China to accelerate yuan use, but &#39;scope limited&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;That increased internationalisation of the yuan would simultaneously reduce China&#39;s accumulation of US dollar reserves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has also spearheaded overseas projects such as roads, railways and airports under the 10-year-old Belt and Road Initiative as a way to smooth trade and investment, accelerating flows of yuan to more than 60 countries in Asia, Africa, eastern and central Europe and South America.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China definitely wants to diversify and that&#39;s been in the making,” Liang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It might consider increasing the proportion of assets denominated in euros or the Japanese yen in its foreign exchange holdings, while auction rate bonds – debt securities with adjustable interest rates – could offset US Treasury bonds, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Late last week, both houses of the US Congress passed a deal between US President Joe Biden and Kevin McCarthy, the Republican speaker of the House of Representatives, that featured a suspension of the debt ceiling until January 2025 in return for cuts to non-defence discretionary spending next year and growth of just 1 per cent in 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite widespread criticism of US dollar hegemony, Wang Jinbin, deputy dean of Renmin University&#39;s school of economics, said there was currently no strong alternative to US treasuries for international investors despite concerns over recurring US debt crises.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The demand for US debt will change with the changes in geopolitics and economic and trade patterns,” Wang said in a university blog post last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[It] depends on the emergence of other government bonds that can effectively replace US debt in the international financial market.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Still early days&#39;, but Bangladesh-Russia deal in yuan opens doors for Beijing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China is the second-largest holder of US government debt, behind Japan. China held US$869.3 billion worth of such debt in March, up from US$848.8 billion in February, with US government bonds accounting for about 27 per cent of China&#39;s foreign exchange reserves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;March marked the first time China had raised its holdings of US debt following seven months of reductions that saw its exposure drop to the lowest level in nearly 13 years. Its investment in US treasuries peaked in 2014 and has been declining slowly ever since.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We expect a more multipolar currency system to emerge over the next few decades, but it will be led by the [US dollar] because its challengers will struggle to replicate its scale, safety and convertibility in full,” Moody&#39;s Investors Service macro research assistant vice-president Gabriel Agostini said at the end of last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our view could change, however, if confidence in US institutions wanes, economic sanctions multiply [and] protectionism rises.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India rescue work ends as focus turns to cause of worst train crash in decades]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3222929/india-rescue-work-ends-focus-turns-cause-worst-train-crash-decades?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 05:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/05/f0dc026a-bf6f-4b75-88e6-360250061e41_5ed7006c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Indian rescuers completed operations on Sunday after the country&#39;s deadliest rail crash in more than two decades, with signal failure emerging as the likely cause of an accident that killed at least 275 people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The death toll from Friday&#39;s crash was revised down from 288 after it was found that some bodies had been counted twice, said Pradeep Jena, chief secretary of the eastern state of Odisha.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tally was unlikely to rise, he told reporters. “Now the rescue operation is complete.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 1,200 people were injured when a passenger train hit a stationary goods train, jumped the tracks and hit another passenger train passing in the opposite direction near the district of Balasore on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 900 people had been discharged from hospital while 260 were still being treated, with one patient in critical condition, the Odisha state government said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;State-run Indian Railways, which says it transports more than 13 million people every day, has been working to improve its patchy safety record, blamed on ageing infrastructure, and is conducting an initial inquiry to determine the cause of the crash.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s Railway Board, the top executive body, has recommended that the case be handed over to the Central Bureau of Investigation, Railway Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prime Minister Narendra Modi visited the scene on Saturday to talk to rescuers, inspect the wreckage and meet some of the injured.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Those found guilty will be punished stringently,” Modi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Preliminary investigations indicated the Coromandel Express, heading to Chennai from Kolkata, moved out of the main track and entered a loop track – a side track used to park trains – at 128kph (80mph), crashing into the goods train parked on the loop track, said Railway Board member Jaya Varma Sinha.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That crash caused the engine and first four or five coaches of the Coromandel Express to jump the tracks, topple and hit the last two coaches of the Yeshwantpur-Howrah train heading in the opposite direction at 126kph (78mph) on the second main track, she told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This caused those two coaches to jump the tracks and result in the massive pile-up, Sinha said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The drivers of both passenger trains were injured but survived, she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Indian railways minister says signalling system error led to deadly train crash&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The investigation is now focused on the computer-controlled track management system, called the “interlocking system”, which directs a train to an empty track at the point where two tracks meet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The system is suspected to have malfunctioned and should not have allowed the Coromandel Express to take the loop track, Sinha said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Workers with heavy machinery were clearing the damaged track, wrecked trains and electric cables, as distraught relatives looked on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 1,000 people were involved in the rescue, the Railway Ministry said on Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The target is by Wednesday morning the entire restoration work is complete and tracks should be working,” Vaishnaw said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a business centre where bodies were being taken for identification, dozens of relatives waited, many weeping and clutching identification cards and pictures of missing loved ones.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kanchan Choudhury, 49, was searching for her husband.她所在村庄的五人在火车上，其中四人受伤正在接受治疗。 Her husband was found dead, she said, weeping as she waited to claim compensation, carrying her and her husband&#39;s identity cards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Families of the dead will get 1 million rupees (US$12,000) in compensation, while the seriously injured will get 200,000 rupees (US$2,426), with 50,000 rupees (US$606) for minor injuries, Vaishnaw said on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hundreds of thousands march in Poland anti-government protests in support of democracy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222928/hundreds-thousands-march-poland-anti-government-protests-support-democracy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.05 04:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/05/f37d77ad-9515-4043-97e7-82924a26de46_78061eb0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hundreds of thousands of people marched in an anti-government protest in Poland&#39;s capital on Sunday, with citizens travelling from across the country to voice their anger at officials who they say have eroded democratic norms and created fears that the nation is following Hungary and Turkey down the path to autocracy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Warsaw Mayor Rafal Trzaskowski, who belongs to the opposition party that led the march, estimated that 500,000 people took part. The Onet news portal estimated there were at least 300,000 at the march&#39;s culmination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Large crowds also gathered in Krakow and other cities across the nation of 38 million people, showing frustration with a government that critics accuse of violating the constitution and eroding fundamental rights in Poland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former President Lech Walesa, the leader of the Solidarity movement that played a historic role in toppling communism in Poland, marched alongside the leader of the opposition Civic Platform party, ex-Prime Minister Donald Tusk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walesa and Tusk are reviled by the ruling Law and Justice party led by Jaroslaw Kaczynski, and the Warsaw crowd chanted “Democracy!” and “Constitution!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rally started at Prime Minister Mateusz Morawiecki&#39;s office and ended up at the Royal Castle, where Tusk hailed the turnout and pledged to fight to win an autumn election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are going to these elections to win and to right human wrongs. I promise you victory, a settlement of evil, compensation for human wrongs and reconciliation among Poles,” Tusk told the crowd.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government spokesman, Piotr Mueller, accused Tusk and Walesa of “trying to overthrow the government.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Poland renames Russia&#39;s Kaliningrad, drawing Moscow&#39;s ire&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tusk had called on Poles to march with him for the sake of the nation&#39;s future – a message that resonated for Radek Tuskinski, 49, who arrived with his wife and two children. A handmade sign reading “I cannot give up freedom” was attached to their baby stroller.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tuskinski said that he worries about the creeping return of an authoritarian system similar to what he remembers from his childhood.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We want a free country for our children,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Supporters of the march have warned that the election might be the nation&#39;s last chance to stop the erosion of democracy under Law and Justice amid growing fears that the fall election might not be fair.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In power since 2015, Law and Justice has found a popular formula, combining higher social spending with socially conservative policies and support for the church in the mostly Catholic nation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, critics have warned for years that the party is reversing many of the achievements made since Poland emerged from communist rule in 1989.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US government has intervened at times when it felt the government was eroding media liberties and academic freedom in the area of Holocaust research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Critics point mainly to the party&#39;s step-by-step takeover of the judiciary and media, and fear that Law and Justice could eventually force Poland to leave the 27-member European Union.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A clampdown on abortion rights has triggered mass protests. Some also voiced anger at double-digit inflation in the country. Poland&#39;s government blames Russia&#39;s war in Ukraine and the Covid-19 pandemic, but economists say its spending policies have accelerated spiralling prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Barbara Dec, 26, and her grandmother left their hometown of Zielona Gora at 4:30am local time and travelled seven hours on a bus organised by Civic Platform to protest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dec held up a cardboard sign that read, “I am afraid to have children in Poland.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Women have lost the right to have an abortion even when the fetus is terminally ill, and some women have died,” she explained. “And I am also afraid I couldn&#39;t manage financially.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Polish EU patrol plane narrowly avoids collision with Russian fighter jet&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The march was held on the 34th anniversary of Poland&#39;s first partly free election. The protest was seen as a test for Tusk&#39;s Civic Platform, a centrist and pro-European party which has trailed behind Law and Justice in polls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the passage of a contentious law last month seems to have mobilised greater support for Tusk. Poland is expected to hold a general election in October, though a date has not been set.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The law allows for the creation of a commission to investigate Russian influence in Poland. Critics argue that it would have unconstitutional powers, including the capacity to exclude officials from public life for a decade. They fear it will be used by the ruling party to remove Tusk and other opponents from public life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Andrzej Duda, who signed the law on May 29, proposed amendments to it on Friday. In the meantime, the law will take effect with no guarantees that lawmakers in parliament will weaken the commission&#39;s powers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some Poles say it could come to resemble the investigations of Joseph McCarthy, the US senator whose anti-communist campaign in the early 1950s led to hysteria and political persecution.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That fear was underlined last weekend when Kaczynski was asked by a reporter if he still had trust in the defence minister in connection with a Russian missile that fell in Poland in November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am forced … to view you as a representative of the Kremlin,” Kaczynski replied. “Because only the Kremlin wants this man to stop being the minister of national defence.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Poland says ties with US &#39;absolute foundation&#39; of Europe&#39;s security&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The media freedom group Reporters Without Borders expressed concerns that the commission “could serve as a new weapon for this type of attack, in which doubt is cast on journalists&#39; probity in an attempt to smear their reputation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tusk, who once served as European Council president, had called for the march weeks ago, urging people to demonstrate “against high prices, theft and lies, for free elections and a democratic, European Poland.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Law and Justice sought to discourage participation in the rally with a video spot using Auschwitz as a theme – drawing criticism from the state museum that preserves the site of the Nazi German death camp.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 05 Jun 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>