<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[After a pause, US Federal Reserve likely to hike interest rates to 22-year high]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228633/after-pause-us-federal-reserve-likely-hike-interest-rates-22-year-high?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 13:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/23/27f310ca-f217-4620-bf48-297cb6a63 ed7_69bbe2bd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在 6 月份暂停加息之后，人们普遍预计美联储将在周三再次加息，尽管近期出现通胀放缓的迹象，但仍将采取 22 年来最严格的货币立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一年多的时间里连续 10 次加息后，美联储上个月停止了激进的货币紧缩行动，以便让政策制定者有更多时间评估美国经济的健康状况以及近期银行业压力对贷款的影响&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后几周，经济增长的积极升级和通胀数据的降温，增强了美联储利率制定委员会在 7 月 25 日至 26 日投票支持加息 25 个百分点的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这会将联邦基金利率提高至 5.25% 至 5.5% 之间的区间，这是 2001 年以来的最高水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我必须打赌，我打赌他们会将联邦基金利率提高 25%彼得森国际经济研究所 (PIIE) 高级研究员约瑟夫·加格农 (Joseph Gagnon) 表示：“经济正在缓慢降温，”美国银行首席美国经济学家迈克尔·加彭 (Michael Gapen) 在最近的一份投资者报告中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们认为大多数委员会成员认为，需要进一步重新平衡供需，以确保通货紧缩继续下去，”他补充道，并解释了为什么他预计周三会再次加息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在的期货交易员根据 CME 集团的数据，美联储在下一次会议上加息 25 个基点的可能性超过 99%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然现在普遍预期 7 月加息，但美联储今年需要加息多少才能将通胀率回落至 2% 的长期目标仍然存在疑问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自美联储决定在 6 月份暂停加息以来，其青睐的通胀指标已同比放缓至 4% 以下，而失业率仍接近历史低点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于消费者支出强于预期，第一季度经济增长也大幅上调。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美联储在连续十次加息后暂停加息&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;积极的经济消息增加了所谓软着陆的可能性，即美联储通过加息成功降低了通胀，同时避免了经济衰退和失业率飙升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德意志银行经济学家在最近给客户的一份报告中写道：“我们认为温和衰退和软着陆之间的界限越来越清晰，并且无可否认地认为后一种结果的可能性正在上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高盛最近将美国经济在未来 12 个月内陷入衰退的可能性从 25% 下调至 20%，尽管仍略高于战后平均水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最近的数据增强了我们的信心，将通胀降至可接受的水平。该银行首席经济学家 Jan Hatzius 在给投资者的一份报告中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 6 月份的会议上，美联储官员表示，他们预计今年需要再加息两次 25 个百分点，以应对通胀问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于普遍预期周三将首次加息，分析师已将注意力转向美联储下一步的行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些经济学家预测，美联储将在 9 月份的下一次利率会议上再次加息，而另一些经济学家则认为，一旦美联储下次加息，美联储可能会保持利率稳定。 PIIE 的约瑟夫·加格农 (Joseph Gagnon) 表示：“我的感觉是，虽然他们会缓慢采取行动，每次会议甚至每次会议都会加息 25 个基点，但我认为他们不会停止。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于 9 月份的不确定性，美联储主席杰罗姆·鲍威尔在利率决定后的新闻发布会将受到密切关注，以获取有关美国央行下一步可能采取行动的暗示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在新闻发布会上，我们关注摩根士丹利经济学家在最近给客户的一份报告中写道，请鲍威尔主席更明确地说明委员会需要看到哪些指标才能放心地延长持有期限。</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 13:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia’s attack on Ukraine’s Odesa kills 1, damages city’s largest cathedral]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3228629/russias-attack-ukraines-odesa-kills-one-damages-citys-largest-cathedral?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 13:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/23/5fe81d92-880b-40d4-930f-5122e390b 96e_8ff0ab02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周日早些时候，俄罗斯对乌克兰敖德萨市发动空袭，造成 1 人死亡、近 20 人受伤，一座与俄罗斯有联系的东正教大教堂严重受损，官员称他们从废墟下找到了这座港口城市守护神的圣像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“敖德萨：又一次怪物夜间袭击，”乌克兰南部敖德萨地区州长 Oleh Kiper 表示&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;导弹袭击造成 1 人死亡、19 人受伤，其中包括 4 名儿童，还摧毁了六栋房屋和公寓楼。他说，有 14 人住院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯退出联合国斡旋的允许安全运输乌克兰粮食的海上走廊协议后，过去一周几乎每天都在袭击敖德萨和其他乌克兰粮食出口设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;敖德萨军方表示，与莫斯科有联系的乌克兰东正教教堂 (UOC) 的斯帕索-普列奥布拉任斯基大教堂遭到严重破坏。政府在 Telegram 频道上表示：“敖德萨的守护神上帝之母的卡斯佩罗夫斯卡圣像已从废墟下被找到。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯帕索-普列奥布拉任斯基大教堂（又称主显圣容大教堂）是敖德萨最大的东正教教堂建筑。它于 1809 年举行祝圣仪式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;敖德萨官员和警方发布的照片​​和视频显示，该建筑部分被毁，内部一片瓦砾，地上排列着几个圣像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UOC 是乌克兰第二大教堂，尽管大多数乌克兰东正教信徒属于该信仰的一个独立分支，该分支四年前由独立于俄罗斯当局的分支联合而成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰指责 UOC 与乌克兰保持联系。支持入侵的俄罗斯东正教教堂，该教堂曾经是其母教堂，但 UOC 表示去年 5 月与该教堂断绝了联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社无法立即独立核实该视频或有关损坏的报告。俄罗斯没有立即发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰空军周日早些时候在其 Telegram 消息应用程序上表示，俄罗斯在敖德萨发射了高精度 Onyx 导弹和海对岸 Kalibr 巡航导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市军事管理部门表示，防空系统摧毁了导弹的“重要部分”，他们说其中包括伊斯坎德尔弹道导弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯将这次袭击描述为对乌克兰人的报复。俄罗斯建造的一座通往克里米亚的桥梁遭到袭击，克里米亚是俄罗斯于 2014 年占领的乌克兰黑海半岛。俄罗斯指责乌克兰利用海上走廊发动“恐怖袭击”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社交媒体视频显示，一名痛苦的男子在黑暗的大教堂内行走，不断重复着“教堂不再……主啊，怜悯。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Smooth transition to HKeToll system at Hong Kong’s Cross-Harbour Tunnel, but ‘real test’ will come Monday, authorities say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3228631/smooth-transition-hketoll-system-hong-kongs-cross-harbour-tunnel-real-test-will-come-monday?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 13:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/23/0013413f-457a-4c46-a466-9506e84c 1af0_64708651.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周日早些时候，香港海底隧道顺利过渡到新的电子收费系统，但当局警告说，对其性能的真正考验将在周一早上到来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该项目从昨晚到今天早上的进展情况良好。运输署署长罗淑佩在社交媒体上提及新的自动付款系统时表示，“香港收费站从早上5点开始通车大致顺利，道路标记在早上6点后得到改善。”当局不会放松警惕。”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港狮子山隧道全新电子收费系统顺利启用&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;红磡海底隧道是香港最繁忙的过境通道，每天处理 11 万辆车辆。这是香港收费通系统下的第四条隧道，旨在缓解香港长期的交通挤塞问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东区海底隧道及西区海底隧道将于下个月采用新系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;青沙管制区、城门隧道及狮子山隧道均已于五月实施自动缴费系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日早上五时，香港缴费易在红磡口岸开始实施，也是为了减少车辆在入口处切道的事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至周日，车道数量也从八条减少到四条。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邮政局在上午9.45左右检查发现，离开港岛的车辆最初缓慢地通过隧道，但很快在九龙一侧的收费站附近畅通无阻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上午10点左右，前往香港岛的交通比相反方向更繁忙，通过收费站的速度也较慢， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法律表示，早上 6 点左右，负责监督实施的当局注意到九龙一侧入口处的道路标记有改进的空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为避免司机争夺收费站位置而造成事故，路政署承包商开始更改标记，并于早上 6 点 40 分完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的新电子收费系统在推出惨败、延迟两个月后“准备就绪” &lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;红磡海底隧道实施香港易通行前，每天约有20万辆车辆使用支付系统，并发出80万个车辆标签用于扫描车费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;使用香港隧道收费易时，司机需要申请一个标签，进出隧道时扫描标签，并从网上账户扣除费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8月2日起，通过红磡隧道的车辆将不再需要支付费用。司机的费用为 30 港元（3.84 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年晚些时候，私家车将推出按时间调整的通行费，高峰时段和正常时段收费在 20 至 40 港元之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feed x.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Bad for business and leisure? Why Hong Kong’s visa rules are sending Vietnamese visitors to Asean nations]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3228622/bad-business-and-leisure-why-hong-kongs-visa-rules-are-sending-vietnamese-visitors-asean-nations?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 12:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/23/7483c22b-144a-4787-a715-684623b2 4eb0_944eb39c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;今年六月，胡志明市居民Tracy Ly Kiet Oanh想要与母亲一起来香港，办理旅游签证的手续花了一个月的时间，但这只是获得许可证的麻烦的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政经理表示，香港入境处要求她提供过去十年到过的每一个海外地点的记录，以及她的出生证明作为证明文件&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“说实话，我忘记了自己去过哪里，尤其是10年前，所以我浏览社交媒体并检索食物和地点的照片作为证据，尽管其中很多都没有露出我的脸，”她说。 “I also don&#39;t have any [original] birth certificate, but lucky that my mother keeps my copy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ly and her mother were given tourist visas to enter Hong Kong, but the permits were valid for only seven days and cost HK$230 (US$30) each, while the maximum period of stay for business executives is two weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Travelling elsewhere in the region is far easier for Vietnamese, as they do not need a visa to enter Singapore, Malaysia, Thailand, Laos or other countries that belong to the 10-member Association of Southeast Asian Nations (Asean) trade bloc.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Ly said she enjoyed Hong Kong and hoped to visit more often, the visa requirement was off-putting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Business leaders and travel industry stakeholders agree, saying immigration rules are discouraging Vietnamese from visiting at a time when the city is trying to bolster ties with Southeast Asia as part of its post-pandemic recovery efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s top diplomat backs Hong Kong membership of world&#39;s biggest trading bloc&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;For years, the government has been eyeing membership in the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership, or RCEP, the world&#39;s largest free-trade deal that links Asean members with Australia, China, Japan, New Zealand and South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Winnie Wong Wing-yee, general secretary of the Hong Kong Business Association Vietnam, said in an interview on Thursday that city authorities urgently needed to relax visa requirements or the city could lose business opportunities to regional rivals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the post-pandemic economic recovery, there are companies here that want to send staff to Hong Kong for training, but it is so difficult to apply for a visa for leisure or work purposes that businesses or opportunities will be diverted to Singapore and Malaysia as a result,” said Wong, who has lived and worked in Ho Chi Minh City for the past 18 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ho Chi Minh City, still widely known as Saigon, is home to about 9.3 million people and is the country&#39;s financial and cultural hub.过去十年，香港一直是其六大主要外国投资来源地之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港将在东盟伙伴关系中加入全球最大的自由贸易协定&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;黄指出，在Covid-19结束后，越南重新开放边境后，香港居民访问越南的签证要求有所放宽。申请可以通过电子方式完成，费用已减半至 25 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，大湾航空开通了每周两次从香港出发的直飞航班，连通性也得到了提升。这是继国泰航空、越南航空和廉价航空越捷航空之后，第四家运营两地直飞航班的航空公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黄表示，她希望在放宽签证规定方面取得突破，并指出香港保安局局长邓炳强将于下个月底访问河内，旅行许可规则是议程项目之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望这次访问至少能缩短申请旅行签证的时间，因为申请比申请旅行签证更复杂。”保安局发言人表示，香港的签证政策会不时检讨，而越南领事馆并未就是否预计放宽对香港人的规定发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南将于 8 月 15 日放宽对来自 25 个国家的外国游客的签证要求，但不包括香港居民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港贸易发展局印度支那主任 Tina Phan 同意&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在香港有很多贸易展览，代表团也从胡志明市或越南其他地区来到香港，但（从香港当局）获得签证是一个问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;大湾航空开通香港与胡志明市之间的航班&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;东瀛旅行社业务发展助理总经理冼丹尼表示，越南当局应进一步简化香港人的签证申请，包括付款方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;冼先生知道，有些信用卡虽然被官方认可为有效的结算方式，但在电子签证申请平台上却不被接受。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冼先生表示，由于不明原因，网上支付失败，他需要支付150美元购买特快电子签证，但仍需要三个工作日才能收到。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“除非香港旅客跟团旅行，否则对于不太懂技术的人来说，申请电子签证是一项挑战。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港旅游发展局视越南为新兴居民旅游目的地。数据显示，今年上半年有 11,776 名越南人前往香港，相当于疫情爆发前水平的 42%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南人仍占香港游客总数的一小部分，六个月期间有近 1,300 万人次到访香港，相当于新冠疫情爆发前水平的 37%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年上半年，有 541 万名来自世界各地的游客前往越南，相当于近两倍。是新冠疫情前水平的三分之一。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Marcos Jnr pitches ‘New Philippines’ plan with nod to father’s rule]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3228626/marcos-jnr-pitches-new-philippines-plan-nod-fathers-rule?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 12:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/23/268309ad-73ba-43d3-9998-a498be9315f 0_42cd9401.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;菲律宾总统小费迪南德·马科斯 (Ferdinand Marcos Jnr) 将于周一制定未来几个月的优先事项，结束他执政的第一年，其政策将回归其父亲的二十年统治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小马科斯 (Marcos Jnr) 表示，他计划在国会利用他的第二次国情咨文向公众提交一份政绩报告。在发表讲话的前几天，他的政府以一个口号定下了基调：“新菲律宾”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在全球前景黯淡以及通胀偏离目标和借贷成本上升等国内挑战的背景下，总统必须领导亚洲表现最好的经济体之一。小马科斯一直保持着国会和公众的广泛支持，这给了他推进议程的余地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“马科斯的主要原因似乎是试图恢复他父亲的名誉，”马尼拉雅典耀大学经济学教授莱昂纳多·兰佐纳说。 “他说他父亲的很多计划都没有完成，所以他试图把它们带回来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位菲律宾领导人的一些选择和计划与他的父亲、已故独裁者费迪南德·马科斯的计划相呼应。首先，他的土地改革和农民工秘书是老马科斯部长的后裔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小马科斯也借鉴了他父亲作为农业部长的做法。他的旗舰计划之一名为“卡迪瓦”（Kadiwa）——国家帮助直接向消费​​者出售农产品——于 20 世纪 80 年代老马科斯执政期间首次实施。大米生产和食品券计划也得到恢复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，小马科斯签署了一项法律，创建主权财富基金，这是对强人的回归。它的名字“Maharlika”在当地通常被认为是贵族的词语，让人想起马科斯老先生领导的一支游击队——这一说法后来被历史学家揭穿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国银行首席经济学家多米尼·贝拉斯克斯(Domini Velasquez)表示，总统仍然需要解决当前的挑战，包括厄尔尼诺现象重新引发通胀的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“短期内，解决通胀问题仍应是首要任务，”贝拉斯克z表示，价格上涨的风险依然存在。她说，政府还应加快基础设施建设，以改善物流、降低成本并减少对企业的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防部长吉尔伯托·特奥多罗表示，改革军队养老金制度是小马科斯的另一个优先事项。财政部长本杰明·迪奥克诺 (Benjamin Diokno) 早些时候警告说，如果国家继续为士兵养老金提供全额资金，国家将面临“财政崩溃”的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项改革是政府计划在国会通过的 20 项措施之一。其他立法优先事项包括对互联网交易征税、提高纳税便利性以及修改银行保密法以加强对逃税和洗钱的检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汇丰控股有限公司经济学家阿里斯·达卡奈 (Aris Dacanay) 表示，小马科斯的演讲中提及军事养老金改革以及解决通货膨胀的措施“可能向市场发出一个信号，表明菲律宾经济的宏观经济基本面可能会改善”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[G20 energy ministers fail to agree on road map for ending use of fossil fuels]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3228628/g20-energy-ministers-fail-agree-road-map-ending-use-fossil-fuels?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 12:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/23/e8159b68-8a98-434a-811e-6eef43c90 35a_f545ded1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周六在印度举行的 20 国集团能源部长会议未能就逐步减少全球能源结构中化石燃料使用的路线图达成一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会后的最终声明甚至没有提及煤炭这一导致全球变暖的主要因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;煤炭也是许多发展中经济体的主要能源来源，例如世界上人口最多的国家印度和世界上人口最多的国家中国第二大经济体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;活动家们对未能在果阿就 COP 目标达成一致感到沮丧，这些目标包括到 2030 年将世界可再生能源发电能力增加两倍，能源效率提高一倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管七国集团领导人 5 月在广岛同意“加速逐步淘汰未减少的化石燃料”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球气温正创下历史新高，引发洪水、风暴和热浪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;h3>;美国和中国可以在气候政策上进行合作，但技术仍然很棘手：专家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;G20主席印度在解释僵局时表示，一些成员强调了寻求“根据不同国情逐步减少不减量化石燃料”的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但“其他人对此事有不同看法，认为减排和清除技术将解决这些问题，”它补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;独立气候智库高级研究员奥尔登·迈耶(Alden Meyer) E3G谴责了这次会议的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着世界各地的温度记录每天都在刷新，气候变化的影响逐渐失控，世界需要听到G20能源部长采取行动的号角，”他在一份声明中表示。 “相反，我们得到的确实是非常淡的茶。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟主要经济体（包括德国和法国）和一些最脆弱的岛屿国家组成的联盟本周敦促二十国集团加快实现净零排放和逐步淘汰化石燃料的计划，并补充道：“人类不能再拖延”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们呼吁温室气体排放最晚在 2025 年达到峰值，到 2030 年与 2019 年相比减少 43% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但许多发展中经济体认为，作为遗留污染者和温室气体排放者，西方发达国家必须付出更多代价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们坚持认为，任何转型都需要巨额资金和新技术，而放弃污染性燃料而没有负担得起的替代品将使其大量人口陷入贫困。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;G20东道国印度本身仅承诺到2070年实现净零排放，比许多其他国家的承诺晚了20年。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为其担任 G20 主席国准备的一份报告估计，能源转型的成本为每年 4 万亿美元，并强调了发展中国家低成本融资和技术转让的重要性，这是新德里的一项关键需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些主要石油生产国也抵制快速摆脱化石燃料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;面向气候的通信公司 GSCC 的埃德·金 (Ed King) 指责俄罗斯和沙特阿拉伯在会议上缺乏进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国将确定自己的碳减排之路：习近平&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;金在推特上写道，他们“阻止了就将清洁能源增加三倍、以化石燃料削减为目标的协议的努力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将主持 COP28 谈判的阿布扎比​​国家石油公司首席执行官苏丹阿尔贾比尔 (Sultan Al Jaber) 表示，他预计化石燃料将继续发挥作用，使用经常引起争议的技术来“减少”或中和排放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，一个阶段减少化石燃料既是“不可避免的”又是“必要的”，但一直不愿明确具体的时间框架。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan may be about to lose more diplomatic ground to Beijing in Central America amid Nicaragua’s proposal]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228497/taiwan-may-be-about-lose-more-diplomatic-ground-beijing-central-america?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/a2399cb8-2533-4c0f-9b1c-19af44f1b 55e_99c10087.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;台湾正面临新的外交挑战，将取消其在中美洲议会的常任观察员地位，为北京让路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项由尼加拉瓜提出的提议正值台北密切关注下个月在危地马拉举行的总统决选之际，一位竞争者承诺，如果当选，将与北京建立更密切的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾的外交存在如果失去该地区组织的观察员地位以及危地马拉（其为数不多的盟友之一）的正式承认，中美洲的台湾可能会在很大程度上被消灭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;名为 Parlacen 的议会设在危地马拉，该国是唯一仍与台湾保持官方关系的成员。其他国家——萨尔瓦多、多米尼加共和国、洪都拉斯、尼加拉瓜和巴拿马——近年来都转而与北京建立外交关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾自 1999 年以来一直是帕尔拉森的五个常任观察员之一——另外还有墨西哥、委内瑞拉、波多黎各和摩洛哥。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但尼加拉瓜总统丹尼尔·奥尔特加在 6 月 23 日提出一项动议，要求帕尔拉森取消台北的观察员地位，并以北京取代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，副议长奥尔特加向议会表示，除危地马拉外，所有成员国都在外交上承认北京，因此应该给予其观察员地位，而不是台北。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾外交部上周表示，尼加拉瓜试图“讨好”北京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尼加拉瓜提出驱逐台湾以允许中国进入，无疑是再次试图讨好北京，希望获得经济援助和政治支持，以解决其国内问题。 ” s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为其领土的一部分，必须将其置于其控制之下，必要时可使用武力。自蔡英文于 2016 年当选总统并拒绝接受一个中国原则以来，它加大了对这个自治岛屿的压力 — — 包括挖走其外交盟友并在附近举行战争游戏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;萧呼吁奥尔特加停止“安抚”北京，并恢复民主和宪政制度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该提案预计将在危地马拉于 8 月休会的帕拉森重返会议时获得通过。台湾的唯一支持者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美籍华人对台湾的好感度高于中国：皮尤调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周三，美国驻台湾大使桑德拉·奥德柯克 (Sandra Oudkirk) 在被问及相关情况时在台北对记者表示，华盛顿坚信台湾“在国际社会中可以发挥积极和建设性的作用”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她表示，美国“完全支持台湾参与不以国家地位作为成员资格和有意义的要求的国际组织”。 ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;像大多数国家一样，台湾最大的非正式盟友和武器供应国美国不承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对任何单方面以武力改变现状的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士表示，如果帕拉森议案获得通过，这将是台北争取国际承认的另一次打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北京在中美洲的影响力与日俱增。”台北智库台湾国际战略研究会常务理事马克斯·罗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“帕拉森的六个成员国中有五个与大陆保持着官方关系，台湾除了试图说服代表发挥道德勇气投票反对该提案外，无能为力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗说，北京可能下一个目标是危地马拉，以孤立台北。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京和台北将密切关注危地马拉第二轮总统决选。 8 月 20 日，中左翼塞米拉党的前外交官和反腐败候选人贝尔纳多·阿雷瓦洛 (Bernardo Arevalo) 将与社会民主希望民族团结党的中间派、前第一夫人桑德拉·托雷斯 (Sandra Torres) 展开对决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;托雷斯在 6 月份的第一轮选票中获得 16% 的选票，阿雷瓦洛仅落后第二轮 4 个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿雷瓦洛表示，如果当选，他将加强与北京的关系，正如大多数人一样。该地区国家已经这样做了。 6 月 27 日，他对危地马拉城一家广播电台表示，该国需要“基于自身利益的外交政策”，除了危地马拉之外，没有人有权“决定该国（在选择盟友方面）的立场”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;托雷斯誓言将继续推行现任总统亚历杭德罗·贾马泰与台湾保持正式关系的政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在台北，外交部表示将竭尽全力继续与危地马拉深化双边交流合作，追求双方利益，“无论谁当选总统”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾在中美洲只剩下危地马拉和伯利兹两个官方伙伴。 They are among a dwindling list of allies – only 13 remain – that still maintain formal diplomatic ties with the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lo noted that Taipei could also lose its observer status at the Central American Integration System – the economic and political body of the member states.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nicaraguan leader Ortega also called for Taiwan&#39;s observer status to be revoked from that body – which it has held since 1992, a year after it was formed – in his statement in April last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing&#39;s trade deals tempt Taipei&#39;s allies in Latin America – but not Pacific&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lo said Beijing had expanded its influence in Latin America, helped by Donald Trump cutting hundreds of millions of dollars in foreign aid to countries in the region when he was US president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Washington still has significant influence in the region, with President Joe Biden embracing multilateralism, according to Huang Kwei-bo, a professor of diplomacy at National Chengchi University in Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Though the US is no longer as influential as before in some countries like Nicaragua and El Salvador, it is still able to exercise its grip in coordinating with other countries in Latin America when it comes to helping Taiwan in its diplomatic tussle with Beijing,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why do Hong Kong students shine in the International Baccalaureate? ‘Selective’ entry, well-resourced schools and wealthy homes at play: educators]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3228623/why-do-hong-kong-students-shine-international-baccalaureate-selective-entry-well-resourced-schools?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/23/826e95b6-90db-4d51-bb74-c8c9046dc672_58050d1f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s two major university entrance exams, the International Baccalaureate (IB) and Diploma of Secondary Education (DSE), made headlines this year for a decline in the number of students with perfect scores.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only 23 out of 2,275 IB candidates achieved top marks this year, compared with 93 in 2022. The DSE, with 48,762 candidates, also saw a record low of only four students with perfect scores across all seven subjects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the city&#39;s IB results were in line with the global trend, with 179 candidates worldwide achieving the perfect score of 45, down from 640 last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;ChatGPT gets Hong Kong students thinking, but teachers stay ahead with human touch&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Overall, Hong Kong remains a place where students excel in the IB, their scores consistently surpassing the global average.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post looks at the reasons behind the city&#39;s success and why some consider it an “IB factory”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;1. What is the IB?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Swiss-based IB Diploma Programme, which lasts two years, is an internationally recognised university entrance qualification.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Hong Kong, where most students sit the DSE, the IB is offered at only 71 international and private schools which charge high fees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;IB students&#39; scores are based on a mix of final exam results and assignments done during their two years, unlike DSE candidates who are graded almost entirely on their final tests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Students in the IB programme have to complete three core elements – a 4,000-word extended essay, a theory of knowledge course, and a creativity, activity and service component.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They choose subjects from six groups: studies in language and literature; language acquisition; individuals and societies; sciences; mathematics; and the arts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Exam results account for about 80 per cent of their final grade, with the rest based on their performance in assignments marked by their teachers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;International school fees for IB students range from HK$120,000 to HK$192,000 (US$24,560) per year, while local private institutions charge between HK$26,240 and HK$100,000 annually.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2. How well do local IB students perform?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;They do very well. The global IB pass rate fell from 85.6 per cent last year to 79 this year, but Hong Kong&#39;s pass rate rose from 95 per cent to 97.7 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past five years, Hong Kong candidates have consistently surpassed the global average by about six points.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even with fewer perfect scorers this year, the city&#39;s average IB score of 36.4 stayed in the excellent range, higher than the global average of 30.24. There were 706 students who scored more than 40 points.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average scores are even higher in some elite schools. For example, Diocesan Boys&#39; School in Mong Kok had an average score of 42 points and the German Swiss International School on The Peak obtained an average score of 40 points.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong students are very good at taking exams and studying. They are taught how to take exams from a very young age,” said Ruth Benny, the founder of education consultancy Top Schools.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s ethnic minority, special needs pupils look to the future after DSE exams&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;3. Do IB results reflect how students are picked?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Educators have said it is not surprising that the relatively small number of students who sit the IB do so well.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Benny said there was a “selective process” at play, with some schools allowing only their top students into the programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A local teacher, who has taught in both the DSE and IB programmes for 10 years and preferred to stay anonymous, said it was unfair to compare the two.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Referring to the IB schools, she said: “First, they are rich schools that have resources to choose the IB programme, and secondly, they can select the best students for the programme.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She explained that institutions which did not hand-pick their IB students, such as English Schools Foundation schools which allowed all students to do the IB, would not be able to achieve an average of 41 points.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average score for ESF schools this year was 36.1 points.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Hong Kong teachers, students must defend national security under patriotic bill&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;4. Do wealthy students perform better?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Associate professor Tan Cheng-yong, of the University of Hong Kong&#39;s education faculty, said the IB schools&#39; success reflected the high socioeconomic status of their students.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Because the fees are so exorbitant overall, we can expect that a certain group and profile of students will be attracted to IB schools,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Parents, teachers and school leaders are aspirational because they know these kids have the resources and the ability to actually do well after graduation. They can go to top universities, they are less restrained by economics.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said international schools also had a high number of foreign teachers who were usually motivated, highly qualified and aware of latest teaching strategies, all of which benefited students.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tan said that in Hong Kong, parents, society and the government all worked to help children succeed, but those in IB schools had an edge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In IB schools, because of the extra factors that students have from schools and home, they benefit double from the very positive climate that they are learning in.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;5. Is the IB better than DSE?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Charles Wu, IB coordinator at the elite Diocesan Boys&#39; School, which offers both programmes, said it was not fair to compare the two.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said both offered a pathway to university in Hong Kong and internationally, and the number of top scorers did not reflect the value of the two programmes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Depending on the year, it might be more difficult to get a top score,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Education consultant Benny said the IB programme offered “excellent preparation” for students interested in studying overseas, and aimed to develop an inquiring mind, encouraging critical thinking, creativity and independent learning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the other hand, the DSE focused on Chinese, English and mathematics as core subjects, along with other electives, and was often considered more content-based, requiring more memorisation and rote learning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A tutor from All Round Education Academy, a tutorial centre mainly for international school students, said some parents valued the creativity and independent learning of the IB programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A lot of parents think the DSE does not really teach their children to think for themselves, they just have to cram a lot of material, whereas the IB is more about really being a critical thinker,” said the tutor, who preferred to remain anonymous.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;6. If you&#39;re bad at Chinese, should you choose IB?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Some local students prefer being in the IB programme to avoid sitting the DSE&#39;s Chinese exam, dubbed the “paper of death” for those who do not do well in the language.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chloe Kwok, 15, is transferring to Li Po Chun United World College for the IB Diploma Programme this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I&#39;m not good at Chinese … and IB Chinese is less demanding,” she said, indicating that she hoped to go to university in Britain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Clarisse Poon, 13, from St Paul&#39;s Co-educational College, hoped to do the IB curriculum too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A major advantage of the IB is that scores are accumulated from coursework in addition to the examination,” she said. “In this way, the assessment is more comprehensive and predictable than DSE, and less stressful.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Indonesia’s Prabowo Subianto sheds strongman image as he guns for top job by being ‘Jokowi’s man’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3228519/indonesias-prabowo-subianto-sheds-strongman-image-he-guns-top-job-being-jokowis-man?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/e9bb5186-24ee-4756-9212-ced7843dda5a_1250f5a8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Prabowo Subianto is hoping it will be third-time lucky in his bid to become leader of Indonesia as Joko Widodo&#39;s two-term presidency ends next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With recent public opinion polls pointing to Prabowo as a front runner, this might be the 71-year-old defence minister&#39;s best chance to finally seize the top job.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in his way stands the younger, arguably more charismatic, Central Java governor Ganjar Pranowo, the candidate of the ruling Indonesian Democratic Party of Struggle (PDI-P), as well as Anies Baswedan, the former Jakarta governor backed by Indonesia&#39;s influential Islamic parties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A survey published earlier this month by pollster Lingkaran Survei Indonesia showed Prabowo in the lead with a 34.3 per cent approval rating, gaining ground after months of consistently placing behind Ganjar, who received 32.7 per cent of the vote. Anies remained in third place with 22.1 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But how did Prabowo, after two failed presidential bids, make his way to the top of opinion polls?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts suggest the former military general has worked to rebrand himself, , shifting away from his former strongman persona by taking a softer tact in his speeches and using an impressive social media campaign to connect with younger voters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prabowo lost to Widodo in both 2014 and 2019&#39;s presidential elections. After the latter poll, he accused the government of electoral fraud, despite falling short by around 17 million votes, prompting deadly riots in the streets of Jakarta. The two politicians eventually reconciled, with Prabowo being co-opted into Widodo&#39;s cabinet through his appointment as defence minister.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Accusations that used to trail the minister of a concerning human rights record have largely been forgotten by the media and the public, experts say, replaced with an image of an even-tempered and easy-going politician, sharing viral selfies wearing a hoodie sporting his Gerindra Party branding.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You have to admit, Prabowo&#39;s style of communication is completely different from what it was like in the last election in 2019,” said Yoes Kenawas, a political researcher from Lingkaran Survei Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He has been working to present himself as a team player as part of Jokowi&#39;s administration,” Yoes said. “He&#39;s portraying himself as Jokowi&#39;s man.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This perceived closeness to Widodo – popularly known as Jokowi – might be the key for Prabowo, analysts said. Even as he exits leadership, Widodo has managed to keep his approval rating at an all-time high, and he is widely considered the kingmaker of the coming election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But with the vote still seven months away, Prabowo faces a long road ahead if he wants to translate his recent momentum into a win.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Widodo, himself a member of the ruling PDI-P party, had a hand in selecting Ganjar as the party&#39;s presidential candidate. But he has not shied away from also expressing his support for Prabowo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Back in November, Widodo even quipped that 2024 “belongs to Prabowo”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pair have met at least three times in the past month. “The president asked about my future plans,” Prabowo said after a meeting at the presidential palace in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There have also been some more indirect indications to suggest that Prabowo has Widodo&#39;s backing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As Prabowo goes off script, Indonesia&#39;s Jokowi teases Pranowo as political heir&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Many of the volunteer groups that supported Jokowi and were pivotal in his electoral victories have already endorsed Prabowo,” said Alexander R. Arifianto, a senior fellow with the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies&#39; Indonesia programme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One such group is led by Gibran Rakabuming Raka, Widodo&#39;s elder son and the current mayor of Solo. Gibran and Prabowo&#39;s growing closeness has sparked unease among some in the PDI-P&#39;s higher echelons, leaving Gibran to insist his meetings with Prabowo should not be equated with an endorsement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ultimately, it was in Widodo&#39;s best interests to make sure the next leader of Indonesia would secure his legacy, said Wasisto Raharjo Jati, a political analyst with the Jakarta-based National Research and Innovation Agency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Jokowi wants to ensure that his successor will continue his work and policies after he retires in 2024,” Wasisto said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prabowo has repeatedly stated that he would carry forward Widodo&#39;s programmes as president if he is elected in February, including continuing the construction of a new US$32 billion capital Nusantara in Borneo, and the revamping of the domestic mining industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a high-ranking PDI-P member, Ganjar is very likely to also continue these programmes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, analysts say that Ganjar&#39;s support from the public – and likely from Widodo too – might be dwindling due to his ties to party chairwoman and former president Megawati Soekarnoputri.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Is there a rift between Jokowi, Megawati in battle of Indonesia&#39;s kingmakers?&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Despite leading surveys for most of the year, Ganjar&#39;s polling dipped after he was engulfed in an antisemitism row for opposing Israel&#39;s participation in the Fifa Under-20 World Cup that had been set to be held in Bali. The May tournament was later moved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Observers say Ganjar was following the PDI-P&#39;s line on the issue. But the controversy resulted in Indonesia being stripped of its hosting rights by Fifa, which did not sit well with ordinary Indonesians, particularly younger voters in the football-crazy country.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Indonesians angry, sad as Fifa pulls U20 World Cup over its Israel stance&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Over the past few months, rumours have also surfaced that Megawati would have the exclusive right to pick Ganjar&#39;s cabinet appointments, prompting concerns from non-PDI-P members of Jokowi&#39;s coalition that they would no longer have a seat at the table.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ganjar brushed off the rumours, but soon afterwards, leaders from coalition members Golkar and the National Mandate Party were spotted meeting with Prabowo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s going to be a challenge for Ganjar, who so far has not shown that he has an independent personality apart from being a candidate of the PDI-P and of Megawati,” Arifianto said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Prabowo is going to show that he is an independent persona, and that he would make a strong and decisive leader in his own right.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Will tycoon-turned-minister Sandiaga Uno run for Indonesia&#39;s top job?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;With candidate registration in October fast approaching, Prabowo has yet to choose a running mate. Observers say who he picks could prove crucial. In his last campaign, he ran with businessman turned politician Sandiaga Uno. This time around, incumbent state-owned enterprises minister and business tycoon Erick Thohir has been polling as a top choice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Prabowo might go down a different path, analysts say, and choose a candidate who has strong links to an Islamic organisation like Nahdlatul Ulama to win support from its large voting bloc.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anies, the ex-governor of Jakarta who has close ties with the conservative Muslim parties, has been trailing in the polls and Prabowo might be looking to absorb their votes and rally supporters to his side.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The smart move would be to appeal to the Islamic constituency, and his vice-presidential pick can help him secure that,” Arifianto said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden to establish national monument honouring lynched black teen Emmett Till]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228621/us-president-joe-biden-establish-national-monument-honouring-lynched-black-teen-emmett-till?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/23/22ce8a4f-f221-4a9b-936b-696553d15a12_445aab70.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden will establish a national monument honouring Emmett Till, the black teenager from Chicago who was abducted, tortured and killed in 1955 after he was accused of whistling at a white woman in Mississippi, and his mother, a White House official said on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden will sign a proclamation on Tuesday to create the Emmett Till and Mamie Till-Mobley National Monument across three sites in Illinois and Mississippi, according to the official. The individual spoke on condition of anonymity because the White House had not formally announced the president&#39;s plans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tuesday is the anniversary of Emmett Till&#39;s birth in 1941.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The monument will protect places that are central to the story of Till&#39;s life and death at age 14, the acquittal of his white killers and his mother&#39;s activism. Till&#39;s mother&#39;s insistence on an open casket to show the world how her son had been brutalised and Jet magazine&#39;s decision to publish photos of his mutilated body helped galvanise the Civil Rights Movement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden&#39;s decision also comes at a fraught time in the United States over matters concerning race. Conservative leaders are pushing back against the teaching of slavery and black history in public schools, as well as the incorporation of diversity, equity and inclusion programmes from college classrooms to corporate boardrooms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, Vice-President Kamala Harris criticised a revised black history curriculum in Florida that includes teaching that enslaved people benefited from the skills they learned at the hands of those who denied them freedom. The Florida Board of Education approved the curriculum to satisfy legislation signed by Governor Ron DeSantis, a Republican presidential candidate who has accused public schools of liberal indoctrination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“How is it that anyone could suggest that in the midst of these atrocities that there was any benefit to being subjected to this level of dehumanisation?” Harris asked in a speech delivered from Jacksonville, Florida.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DeSantis said he had no role in devising his state&#39;s new education standards but defended the components on how enslaved people benefited.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“All of that is rooted in whatever is factual,” he said in response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The monument to Till and his mother will include three sites in the two states.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Illinois site is Roberts Temple Church of God in Christ in Bronzeville, a historically Black neighbourhood on Chicago&#39;s South Side. Thousands of people gathered at the church to mourn Emmett Till in September 1955.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Mississippi locations are Graball Landing, believed to be where Till&#39;s mutilated body was pulled from the Tallahatchie River, and the Tallahatchie County Second District Courthouse in Sumner, Mississippi, where Till&#39;s killers were tried and acquitted by an all-white jury.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;White woman who accused lynched black teen Emmett Till dies&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Till was visiting relatives in Mississippi when Carolyn Bryant Donham said the 14-year-old Till whistled and made sexual advances at her while she worked in a store in the small community of Money.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Till was later abducted and his body eventually pulled from the Tallahatchie River, where he had been tossed after he was shot and weighted down with a cotton gin fan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two white men, Roy Bryant and his half-brother JW Milam, were tried on murder charges about a month after Till was killed, but an all-white Mississippi jury acquitted them. Months later, they confessed to killing Till in a paid interview with Look magazine. Bryant was married to Donham in 1955. She died earlier this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The monument will be the fourth Biden has created since taking office in 2021, and just his latest tribute to the younger Till.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Black History Month this year, Biden hosted a screening of the movie Till, a drama about his lynching.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March 2022, Biden signed the Emmett Till Anti-Lynching Act into law. Congress had first considered such legislation more than 120 years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Justice Department announced in December 2021 that it was closing its investigation into Till&#39;s killing.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Mainland young people are very polite’: Hong Kong customer praises Chinese delivery driver for returning cancelled order and sorting refund]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3228320/mainland-young-people-are-very-polite-hong-kong-customer-praises-chinese-delivery-driver-returning?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.23 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/c3303d1d-d553-4565-833d-2e9984b4056c_5427b664.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Hong Kong resident&#39;s praise for a mainland delivery driver&#39;s “honest and kind” work attitude has resonated online in China and highlighted the often challenging conditions these workers face.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hong Kong woman posted on July 3 in a Facebook group about a friend who ordered groceries online from Shenzhen in southern China using the app Meituan to be delivered to the city&#39;s border for collection.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The poster said her friend unexpectedly could not meet the driver due to a personal emergency and called him to tell him he could keep the groceries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her friend was surprised when she received a refund from the platform and learned that the driver had helped return the items for no charge so she would be eligible to receive the full refund.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The poster said her friend was “impressed with the kindness, honesty and polite attitude of mainland delivery workers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that her friend tried to compensate the driver for his extra work but could not get in touch once the order was closed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Meituan, a delivery driver will not receive any payment for cancelled orders. However, they can apply to the platform for compensation if they are not responsible for the cancellation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story reflects the recent trend of Hong Kong consumers buying mainland delicacies and cheap groceries from Shenzhen using online personal shoppers called daigou and delivery apps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The post resonated with other consumers who have used mainland services for groceries and other goods.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Mainland young people are very polite. Service workers at restaurants also have a positive work attitude, from which Hong Kong people should learn,” commented one person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I travelled to the mainland after the borders were reopened and was attracted by their dynamic, honest and polite attitude,” said another person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A third person once witnessed a mainland delivery driver voluntarily clean a messy table while waiting for his order at a coffee shop said: “His selfless act won my respect!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some online observers also pointed to the increasing number of new university graduates working as delivery couriers amid massive youth unemployment in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official figures show the jobless rate among people aged 16 to 24 hit a record high of 21.3 per cent in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, China&#39;s two food delivery giants, Meituan and Eleme, employed 7.38 million delivery drivers in the country.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 23 Jul 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>