<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Chinese navy says it’s testing the planet’s most powerful coil gun]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3232258/chinese-navy-says-its-testing-planets-most-powerful-coil-gun?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 13:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/5e7bc1c6-0738-4ba4-889f-71a6c785fdde_2db4bc4f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;据报道，中国海军正在测试地球上最强大的线圈炮 - 一种电磁炮能够以极高的速度和精度发射射弹的动力武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在首次向公众展示的发射测试中，电磁发射器将 124 公斤（273 磅）的射弹加速到 700 公里/小时的速度据参与该项目的科学家称，不到 0.05 秒（435 英里/小时）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是线圈枪实验中使用的已知最重的射弹。虽然该武器的确切尺寸和最大射程仍处于保密状态，但以如此速度移动的炮弹可能会击中数公里外的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国科学家制造高超音速发生器为未来武器提供动力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;线圈枪也称为高斯枪或磁力加速器。该武器具有沿着枪管排列的一系列线圈，每个线圈构成一个“阶段”。每个线圈依次通电，产生磁场，使弹丸悬浮并向前推进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弹丸在发射过程中通常保持悬浮在线圈中心，这有助于使其保持直线并防止其接触桶壁。它可以重复、快速地发射，不会对部件造成磨损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;线圈炮可以彻底改变战争的方式，可以对敌方目标进行更快、更准确和毁灭性的攻击。它们还可以发射导弹或将卫星送入太空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项技术已经存在了几十年，但材料科学和电子学方面的挑战使得构建大型且功能强大的模型变得困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;与中国线圈炮最接近的竞争对手之一，美国桑迪亚国家实验室的120毫米口径电磁线圈迫击炮测试装置，可以发射重达18公斤的弹丸。它是有史以来最大的此类设备之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据以色列科学家在 2017 年发表的一项研究，世界各地的其他系统通常可以发射重量仅为几克、直径为几毫米的射弹。一月份的《科学报告》杂志。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;线圈火炮越大，发射与传统火炮类似的射弹的能力就越好。美军使用的标准155毫米炮弹重约43公斤，而意大利的靛蓝防空导弹重120公斤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;线圈炮与传统火炮相比具有多项优势，包括发射速度更高、发射速度更低、海军工程大学管晓村教授领导的中国团队表示，发射成本和准备时间更短。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它在速度、射程、功率、精度、安全性、灵活性和可靠性，”关和他的同事在本月发表在同行评审期刊《中国电工技术学会学报》上的一篇论文中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它广泛应用于武器系统、近邻系统等领域。 -地球卫星和高速导弹发射。”他们补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们的 30 级线圈炮仍处于测试阶段，目前还不清楚何时或是否会部署在现场。然而，中国军方近年来一直在这项技术上投入巨资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“海军工程大学在建造大型线圈火炮方面克服了一系列困难”，中国海军工程大学首席科学家马伟明表示。 6月发表的一篇论文中介绍了中国军方的电磁发射计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马说，挑战包括大口径高磁密度线圈的设计和制造以及紧凑型脉冲功率技术。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;他补充说，中国目前正在开发一种威力更强大的线圈炮，能够以 3,600 公里/小时的速度发射弹丸，这可以将武器的杀伤距离提高到 100 公里以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国研究人员转向人工智能制造未来武器&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据管的团队称，线圈枪在中国的快速发展部分归功于传感器技术的突破。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;线圈枪产生强磁力发射时会产生磁场，会干扰电子设备和传感器，因此电磁发射器的研究通常需要通过外部手段测量弹丸的飞行行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，管的团队提出了一种配备传感器的新型智能弹丸由于采用特殊材料，它们可以免受电磁干扰，从而使它们能够收集有关弹丸飞行行为的高质量数据。来自内部传感器的精确数据可以帮助科学家提高线圈枪的效率和稳定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在发射过程中保持弹丸悬浮在线圈中心可能是一项挑战，因为任何偏离中心的偏差都可能导致弹丸接触枪管壁并影响其轨迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机载传感器帮助中国科学家发现了计算机建模遗漏的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据该团队称，发射开始时，测试弹由于重力作用位于驱动线圈的底部。当脉冲电流开启时，测试弹体被电磁力向上推。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于弹体尾部电磁力较强，导致弹体倾斜并与内部碰撞。他们说，驱动线圈的壁，导致加速度数据波动。当测试弹经过后期时，由于脉冲电流在错误的时间触发，它开始摆动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这样的发现可以帮助科学家提高线圈枪的性能。例如，可以通过调整流经线圈的脉冲电流的触发时间来减少摆动。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump makes history with scowling jailhouse mugshot]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3232260/donald-trump-makes-history-scowling-jailhouse-mugshot?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 12:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_analysis/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/5279696b-9567-4392-9332-a14f0fc58eb2_c2b2ed0e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;相机发出咔嗒声。在不到一秒的时间里，快门打开然后关闭，永远冻结了面前的图像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，当相机快门在亚特兰大市中心的一所监狱内闪烁时，它创建并记录了美国生活中的一个微小的转折点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为后人所拍，历史上第一次有一位美国前总统被捕，并以通常与毒贩联系在一起的方式被捕。或醉酒司机。权力的象征在那一瞬间消失了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;留下了：在唐纳德·特朗普去世很久之后，一个持久的形象将出现在历史书中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它将永远成为一部分南加州大学安纳伯格传播学院教授马蒂·卡普兰 (Marty Kaplan) 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;照片中，特朗普面对着淡灰色背景前的镜头。 ，他的眼睛在强烈的眩光中与镜头相遇。他穿着蓝色西装、白色衬衫和红色领带，肩膀平直，头稍微向镜头倾斜。警长的标志已以数字方式添加到他的右肩上方。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国前总统特朗普在佐治亚州投降，照片已发布&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在佐治亚州被指控的其他 18 名特朗普人中，有一些人脸上微笑着预订照片就像为年鉴摆姿势一样。不是特朗普。他的蔑视是显而易见的，就好像他通过镜头凝视着一个宿敌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普面临指控对于 2023 年的美国人来说是一个熟悉的景象，他们看到他在纽约法庭上站在法官面前，或者亲眼目睹了特朗普面临的指控。迈阿密和华盛顿联邦法院内部不允许拍照的水彩草图。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是不同的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正如安德森·库珀 (Anderson Cooper) 在 CNN 上所说：“前总统美国有一个囚犯号码”。确切地说，P01135809。但直到他面临试图窃取佐治亚州 2020 年选举的指控（这是他今年的第四项起诉）投降之前，他避免了像在他之前被指控犯罪的数百万人那样摆出一张标志性的预订照片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没关系特朗普和所有美国人一样，在法庭被证明有罪之前是无辜的；这张照片及其所蕴含的一切，都带有额外的情感和文化冲击力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;照片是刑事司法系统的内心表征，是失去自由的象征。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它永远存在纪念一个人一生中最糟糕的日子之一，一个不适合剪贴簿的时刻。对于一个出生于特权阶层的人来说，这一定是特别陌生的，他以喜欢掌控一切、高度关注自己的形象并成为世界上最有权势的人物而闻名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“&#39;起诉书” ’是一个不流血的词。与图像相比，文字显得苍白无力。”前副总统沃尔特·蒙代尔 (Walter Mondale) 的演讲撰稿人、好莱坞编剧卡普兰 (Kaplan) 说道。 “面部照片是一种类型。它的框架是：“这是一只被车头灯困住的鹿。”这就是被钉住的骗子。”这是耻辱时刻。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普不太可能将这张照片视为耻辱时刻，因为他正在寻求在白宫连任，同时在四个司法管辖区对抗刑事指控。据他的竞选团队报告，每次他被起诉时，捐款都会激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;图像本身呢？特朗普并没有回避这一点。事实上，他的竞选团队早在它成为现实之前就炮制了这一计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普的保证金禁止恐吓证人。他会遵守这一规定吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周四晚上，在他在佐治亚州被拍照的几个月前，他的竞选团队利用拍摄照片的机会作为筹款机会。任何人都可以花 36 美元购买一件印有特朗普假订票照片和“无罪”字样的 T 恤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有数十种类似的设计可以在网上购买，其中包括许多吸引特朗普批评者的设计.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在他们有了一个真正的合作伙伴。这张大头照发布后几分钟内，特朗普的竞选团队就在其网站上发起筹款呼吁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;竞选团队最新筹款电子邮件的主题行是“突发新闻：大头照就在这里”，该邮件宣传了带有图像的新 T 恤。还有这句话：“这张照片将作为美国反抗暴政的象征而永远载入史册。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普本人也不浪费时间，将其发布在 X（该网站以前称为 Twitter）上，以及他自己的社交媒体平台 Truth Social 上的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;X 帖子是特朗普 2.5 年来的第一篇帖子，此前他的账户在 2021 年 1 月 6 日特朗普袭击美国国会大厦后被禁止。支持者。埃隆·马斯克(Elon Musk)去年在收购 X 后不久就恢复了特朗普的账户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了表达对特朗普的声援，美国国会女议员马乔里·泰勒·格林 (Marjorie Taylor Greene) 在 X 上发布了一张她在灰色背景前灿烂微笑的照片，左上角有警长的标志，模仿监狱的风格 - 本质上是她自己制作的杯子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我与特朗普总统站在一起，反对共产党 DA Fani Willis，”她猛击佐治亚州富尔顿县说道。说服大陪审团起诉特朗普的地区检察官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近的历史充满了政客从预订照片中寻求政治红利的情况。他们露出灿烂的笑容或挑衅的傻笑，并试图充分利用自己的困境。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;当然唐纳德·特朗普可以再次获胜&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;然而，这是总共 45 位总统之一美国历史上的杰出人物 – 不仅掌握着世界上最强大政府的钥匙，而且在当今的许多日子里，无论是在国内外，他所担任的职位都代表了美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看到那张脸看着他没有寻找镜头的相机——这是一个强有力的时刻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“静态图像有一种力量，这是无可争议的，”纽约大学名誉教授米切尔·史蒂文斯说约克大学写了一本关于图像在现代社会中的地位以及它如何取代文字的书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它有点冻结了一个时刻，在这种情况下，它冻结了唐纳德·特朗普的不快乐时刻，”史蒂文斯说。 “而且这不是他可以点击就可以离开的东西。这不是他可以轻易置之不理的事情。那一刻将继续存在。它完全有可能最终成为历史保留的这个人的形象——他的第一张照片。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href= “https://feedx.best” style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 12:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan next to shoot for moon after Russia and India missions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3232252/japan-next-shoot-moon-after-russia-and-india-missions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/7cf78114-0503-46b9-9709-fcbbf894c481_86f98a5b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本将成为本周末瞄准月球的最新国家，就在几天后俄罗斯航天器与月球表面相撞，印度的月船 3 号在月球南极附近着陆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本宇宙航空研究开发机构 (JAXA) 的 H2-A 火箭计划于周日上午从种子岛航天中心起飞在日本南部，搭载了一颗先进的成像卫星和一个轻型着陆器，预计将于 1 月或 2 月登陆月球。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;成功可以为 JAXA 提供急需的推力，以开始重建其在一系列事件后受损的声誉。过去一年中遭受代价高昂的挫折。其中包括几次发射失败，导致下一代火箭的推出和该机构首次发射商业卫星的尝试都脱轨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;笠原次郎表示，这些失误给日本宇宙航空研究开发机构带来了额外的压力，要求他们这次做好准备。名古屋大学航空航天工程系教授。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在移动天体上着陆是一项需要掌握的非常重要的技术，”他说。虽然其他航天机构已经从失败的尝试中恢复过来，但日本宇宙航空研究开发机构（JAXA）如果再次陷入困境，将很难反弹。 “日本对此只有一次机会，”笠原说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JAXA 的困境始于去年 10 月，当时它在飞行途中放弃了第六次 Epsilon 火箭发射。该火箭搭载了 JAXA 第一批商业合同中的两颗卫星，这是满足私营部门不断增长的需求的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Luna-25 坠毁预计不会破坏中俄月球基地合作伙伴关系&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;这是自 2003 年以来日本火箭的首次重大故障，JAXA 的一项调查将其归咎于部件故障，导致火箭无法保持直立进入轨道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11 月，JAXA 公布了一项研究该团队伪造了在模拟国际空间站生命的实验中收集的大量数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月份，该机构推迟了 H3 的首次发射，H3 是 JAXA 的 H2-A 的后继者，原因是系统发生了故障主发动机和侧助推器之间的故障导致火箭停飞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三菱重工有限公司花了近十年的时间开发 H3，这是一种一次性火箭，旨在为竞争对手提供更便宜、更可靠的替代品，例如 H3 火箭。例如 SpaceX 可重复使用的猎鹰 9 号火箭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三月初的第二次尝试因火箭第二级发动机未能点火而以戏剧性的方式结束。操作员在它升空后发送了自毁代码，导致飞船及其携带的卫星垂直坠入菲律宾海。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后在 7 月，Epsilon S（火箭的第七代）在地面测试中爆炸，引发火焰和烟雾，吞噬了日本北部秋田县的一处设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然没有人员伤亡报告，但这一事件不仅对 Epsilon 系列来说是一次挫折但对于 H3 来说也是如此，因为两种火箭都使用相同的新型固体火箭助推器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“考虑到最近发生的其他事件，我们正在寻求尽一切努力来改善这种情况，”JAXA 主任 Hiroshi Yamakawa事故发生后的新闻发布会上说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本宇宙航空研究开发机构 (JAXA) 8 月向政府小组表示，该机构已将 H3 故障的潜在原因缩小到火花塞或第二级发动机中的控制单元。 23. 该机构现在可以采取措施，防止下一次 H3 发射尝试重演，该发射计划定于 2024 年 3 月本财政年度结束前进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国通过以下方式披露了载人登月任务的第一个细节： 2030&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“今年之前，日本火箭一直表现良好——也许太好了——这可能导致了某些疏忽，”东京理科大学空间系统创新研究中心主任木村新一表示，并补充说，本周日的发射为 JAXA 提供了一个从这些痛苦教训中汲取教训的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“无论从科学角度还是象征意义上来说，这都是一项重要的任务，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;木村和笠原调查 H3 故障的政府小组的顾问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当日本企业家试图建立自己的太空初创企业时，他们得到了 JAXA 的一些支持。该机构于 4 月份宣布将投资 Space Walker Inc，这是第一家获得 JAXA 资助的私营火箭公司，并且该机构计划支持更多太空业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同类公司中最引人注目的公司今年早些时候也遇到了挫折。总部位于东京的 Ispace Inc 的 Hakuto-R 着陆器距离实现日本首次登月仅几步之遥，但在遥测故障导致飞船误判陨石坑边缘后与任务控制中心失去了联系。随后，它耗尽了燃料，并在最后一次进场时开始自由落体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ispace 表示，它将按原计划于 2024 年初启动第二次任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JAXA 的 H2-A，该机构最可靠的火箭，自 2001 年以来的 42 次发射中只出现过一次失败，如果周日发射的话，将搭载用于调查月球的小型着陆器（SLIM）。着陆器高度不到 3 米（9.8 英尺），可以为其他具有高导航精度的探测器铺平道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;火箭还将携带 X 射线成像和光谱任务（XRISM），一颗卫星将帮助科学家观察恒星和星系中的等离子体。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Brics adds 6 new members, Thaksin’s return to Thailand, Hongkongers spend in Shenzhen: SCMP’s 7 highlights of the week]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3232233/brics-adds-6-new-members-thaksins-return-thailand-hongkongers-spend-shenzhen-scmps-7-highlights-week?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 12:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/a648dc36-3801-47e0-8b7a-01654028a35d_88b5b60c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;我们从本周的新闻中精选了七个故事，涵盖香港、中国大陆、更广泛的亚洲地区及其他地区与我们的读者产生共鸣，并阐明了热门问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果您想查看我们的更多报道，请考虑。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;房地产大亨斯雷塔·塔维信 (Srettha Thavisin) 将成为泰国第 30 任总理，周二议员投票选举他为泰国第 30 任总理，这一天发生了一场高度政治戏剧性的事件，前领导人他信·西那瓦 (Thaksin Shinawatra) 在流亡 15 年后重返泰国并直接入狱。服八年徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这里阅读全文。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周四在约翰内斯堡举行的金砖国家峰会上，南非总统西里尔·拉马福萨，该组织现任主席表示，阿根廷、埃及、埃塞俄比亚、伊朗、沙特阿拉伯和阿拉伯联合酋长国将从 2024 年 1 月 1 日起成为正式成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此处阅读全文。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;自 2 月 6 日中国大陆和香港恢复免检疫旅行以来，截至 7 月底，通过六个陆路口岸前往深圳的旅客量已超过 2,240 万人次，即每周约 90 万人次。但香港人跨境旅行的趋势正让该市的餐饮业因业务损失而哀叹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此阅读全文。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中文国家主席习近平未能出席周二在南非举行的金砖国家商业论坛，预计他将与其他国家领导人一起发表讲话。商务部部长王文涛代其宣读了批评美国“霸权”倾向的讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全文请点击此处。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;环境官员表示，在政府测试和第三方评估证明来自核废水排入大海后受影响的 10 个县的货物是安全的之前，本周生效的香港对日本海鲜的禁令不会解除。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;请阅读全文。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国最大的房地产开发商之一的债券违约引发第一波冲击波两年后，北京方面承诺一切都会顺利进行。控制变得越来越难向投资者推销。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这里阅读完整的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一位中国医生拯救了陌生人的生命本月早些时候，由于注意到一名在同一家餐厅就餐的女性出现脑肿瘤症状，该活动被作为该国医生节的一部分进行庆祝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此处阅读完整的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt; hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 12:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping pledges more help to Africa in both industrial and agriculture sectors]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3232237/xi-jinping-pledges-more-help-africa-both-industrial-and-agriculture-sectors?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/858a829d-d545-44f4-8497-4a7f6ac2aff7_c702130c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国将为非洲工业化和农业生产分配更多资源，并培训数千人中国国家主席习近平周四向非洲领导人承诺，将提高非洲学生的职业技能水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在约翰内斯堡金砖国家领导人峰会结束后，习近平会见非洲领导人并出席中非领导人圆桌对话会，他表示，中国将发起一项支持非洲工业化的倡议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国将利用自身资源……支持非洲发展制造业，实现工业化和经济多元化，”习近平表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时习近平没有透露具体资金数额，但表示中国将向工业化项目提供更多援助和投融资资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，习近平表示，中国将帮助非洲国家扩大粮食种植园，鼓励中国企业&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平承诺提供支持之际，乌克兰持续战争加剧了许多非洲国家面临的粮食危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11 月，中国将在中国海南岛举办第二届中非农业合作论坛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为应对部分非洲国家特别是非洲之角国家的粮食危机，中国将增加粮食紧急援助.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平表示，“中国有信心非洲通过自己的努力实现粮食自给自足。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这番言论反映了与过去十年的转变，当时中国投入了数十亿美元通过“一带一路”倡议（BRI）将美元投入港口、铁路、高速公路和水坝等大型项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但批评者也指责中国进口更多原矿，这造成了不健康的贸易对中国有利的不平衡——这解释了为什么津巴布韦、纳米比亚和刚果民主共和国等拥有大量锂矿藏的国家禁止出口电池原材料原材料，而是希望在当地加工这些矿物。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;新金砖国家成员夸耀石油、雄厚的财力和战略位置：分析师&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;不过，农业最近已成为中国与非洲接触的新焦点，北京已承诺从非洲进口更多食品非洲大陆，包括鳄梨、腰果、芝麻和辣椒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，5月份，中国通过国有贸易商中粮集团从南非进口玉米，以实现全球粮食来源多元化。中国90%以上的玉米进口严重依赖美国和乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿史汀生中心中国项目主任孙云早些时候告诉《南华早报》今年，非洲农产品引起了中国的关注，部分原因是“过去对硬基础设施的关注不再可行”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这也是北京落实习近平增加非资源进口承诺的更广泛战略的一部分来自非洲。 2021年塞内加尔中非合作论坛期间，习近平承诺为非洲农产品开辟“绿色通道”，加快检验检疫速度，免除更多关税，力争到2025年进口额达到3000亿美元。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;除了允许从非洲进口某些农产品外，北京还对十几个非洲国家的产品降低了98%的关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国还表示支持非洲联盟成为非洲联盟的一部分。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明表示，非洲欢迎中国对非洲工业化、人才发展和农业现代化的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非洲欢迎中国对非洲工业化、人才发展和农业现代化的支持。 p>;&lt;p>;此外，中非合作应注重加强现有全球体制机制，确保发展中国家的参与，从而实现包容性和全球信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“长期合作”联合声明指出，应解决多边金融机构和联合国安理会改革的突出问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周四的会议上，习主席还承诺培养非洲人才，特别是在职业培训方面。中方计划每年为非洲培训500名职业院校校长和教师，为非洲培训1万名兼具汉语和职业技能的技术人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平和莫迪同意优先解决喜马拉雅边境地区局势&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;习近平表示，中方将邀请2万名非洲国家政府官员和技术人员参加研修班和研讨会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共同主持会议的南非总统拉马福萨表示，中国的“一带一路”倡议导致非洲大陆出现新的公路、铁路、港口和能源投资。他表示，基础设施投资促进了创新和生产力，降低了交易成本，并将改善非洲的一体化和互联互通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉马福萨称非洲大陆自由贸易区 (AfCFTA) 是非洲大陆增长的核心；中方承诺为其秘书处的运作提供资金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在支持非洲大陆自贸区有效实施的过程中，中非合作应促进投资，促进价值链发展，增强相互生产和消费能力。”拉马福萨说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，对工业化的支持应包括加强对微型、中小型企业和非正规经济的支持。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Burning questions after Putin calls Wagner’s Prigozhin a ‘man of complicated fate’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3232249/burning-questions-after-putin-calls-wagners-prigozhin-man-complicated-fate?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/25/8410a0b3-3a72-4f4f-96f4-a4dc2df5d5ea_8df4c720.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;雇佣军军阀叶夫根尼·普里戈津 (Yevgeny Prigozhin) 在飞机失事中被推测死亡是一种激烈的报复俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果是的话，是否会让普京变得更强大 — — 或者加剧两个月前普里戈任流产叛变所暴露的根本弱点？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些问题不仅引起了反响在俄罗斯境内，但在乌克兰这个主权邻国，普京在18个月前发动了全面入侵，在乌克兰努力收复被入侵者夺取的领土时，西方国家纷纷向乌克兰提供援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;周三晚上，莫斯科西北部的俄罗斯村庄库曾希诺附近的居民听到天空中爆炸声，然后看到巴西航空工业公司的喷气式飞机撞上俄罗斯乡村并起火。俄罗斯航空部不久后表示，普里戈任是机上 10 人之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坠机事件发生整整 24 小时后，普京打破了对这一事件的沉默，据官方媒体报道，他向遇难者家属表示哀悼.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在国家塔斯社报道的言论中，他称 62 岁的普里戈任（瓦格纳集团私人军队的负责人）是一个“命运复杂的人”，他“认真对待”普里戈任曾是一名热狗小贩，后来却以残酷的雇佣军领袖而闻名&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在乌克兰入侵期间，普里戈任一直占据着这个角色他经常痛斥俄罗斯军事领导层——但从来没有批评普京本人——因为他说他在发动战争方面无能。这激怒了军方高层，但他的带有脏话的视频长篇大论仍然起到了作用。俄罗斯强硬派因攻势不稳而感到沮丧，这是一种释放阀门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;导致坠机的原因仍然是个谜。周四在华盛顿，五角大楼新闻秘书表示，有关地对空导弹击落普里戈任飞机的报道被认为是不准确的，但他没有详细说明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的初步评估是，普里戈任很可能是美国空军准将帕特·莱德在新闻发布会上说。其他未获授权发表评论且不愿透露姓名的美国官员表示，未经证实的可能性是飞机上装有炸弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普里戈任被推定死亡的时间——距他发射飞机的两个月后。企图起义，夺取南部军事总部，并派遣装甲纵队向莫斯科进军，这引起了人们对普京精心策划的阴谋的怀疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些分析人士认为，也许这标志着一个令人讨厌的人物的灭亡，他的用处– 作为一项不可否认的军事资产、国际调解者和亲克里姆林宫的媒体黑魔法大师 – 已经走到了尽头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果普京确实下令杀死普里戈任，那么这一行为的纯粹厚颜无耻可能会阻止那些—— be opponents, at least in the short term, said Andrea Kendall-Taylor, a Russia intelligence expert at the Centre for a New American Security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“(The) thing that is so spectacular about this was that they didn&#39;t need to use any cover of an accident or leave any uncertainty,” she said. “This was a clear demonstration to others who might consider challenging Putin of what kind of fate awaits them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But in an authoritarian state, tactics such as the assassination of political foes – if that was what transpired – is a long-term sign of a leader&#39;s ebbing power and influence, some analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Nobody knows what will come next in Putin&#39;s Russia,” Brian Klaas, an associate professor in global politics at University College London, wrote on his Substack. “But anyone who thinks that killing a rival to reassert control is a show of strength, not weakness, is delusional. Strong leaders don&#39;t need to kill their rivals, because they inspire loyalty instead.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Wagner boss Prigozhin joins list of Putin foes who suffered mysterious fates&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Others saw a move by the Kremlin to shore up Putin&#39;s authority.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the last two months, we saw the Kremlin machinery move to reconsolidate control. To my mind, it doesn&#39;t say much about weakness or strength. Rather, it shows that the Kremlin machine can reconsolidate and reconstitute itself,” said Alina Polyakova, who heads the Centre for European Policy Analysis. “The bottom line is that they&#39;ve neutralised the threat.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Ukraine, President Volodymyr Zelensky made a thinly veiled jab at Putin but stopped short of accusing the Russian president of being behind the crash, even as he disavowed any Ukrainian involvement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are not involved in this situation, that&#39;s for sure,” Zelensky said at a news conference in Kyiv alongside the visiting Portuguese president. “I think everyone is aware of who is involved.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How the entire Prigozhin episode will affect Wagner, the lucrative private army that became the centrepiece of Prigozhin&#39;s business empire, remains to be seen. But a glance at the names of those who were also believed aboard the fatal flight hints at a plan not just to decapitate the Wagner Group, but to dismantle it altogether.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also aboard the jet was Dmitry Utkin, the decorated, former special forces officer with Russia&#39;s military intelligence service who was the mercenary group&#39;s founder and spiritual father.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His penchant for Nazi lore spurred him to choose the call sign “Wagner”, a reference to Richard Wagner, Hitler&#39;s favourite composer, and the name was eventually adopted by the whole group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another passenger was Valery Chekalov, who was reported to fill a senior position in Prigozhin&#39;s holding company Concord and who owned a shell company on Prigozhin&#39;s behalf.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Biden jokes about Prigozhin poisoning, says Putin &#39;already lost&#39; Ukraine war&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Utkin was responsible for all combat training and operations planning and had extremely high authority, while Chekalov was in charge of all logistics and supply routes for Wagner, from Syria to Venezuela, in addition to the security service,” said Anton Mardasov, a non-resident scholar at the Middle East Institute and the Russian International Affairs Council focusing on Wagner&#39;s work in Syria.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mardasov added that the deaths of those figures left Wagner with no real leader.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without them, no council of commanders for Wagner would be valid,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the wake of the aborted coup attempt, Wagner&#39;s presence in Ukraine was all but excised, but the forces nevertheless continued to operate in Africa, even doubling down on their presence in the continent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prigozhin&#39;s last video appearance, which was presumably taken this week, showed him in what appeared to be somewhere in Africa, kitted out in military fatigues and an assault rifle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re working in over 122-degree temperatures here; it&#39;s just how we like it,” he said, adding that Wagner was making “Russia greater in all the continents”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, among Russia&#39;s constellation of pro-war military bloggers, the apparent loss of Prigozhin was seen as a major blow.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roman Saponkov, a military blogger close to Wagner, called it an “assassination” and said the death would have “catastrophic consequences”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Writing on the Telegram messaging app, Saponkov declared that those “who gave the order do not understand the mood in the army and the morale at all”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In South Korea, Japan’s Fukushima water release inflames political tensions, public anger]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3232210/south-korea-japans-fukushima-water-release-inflames-political-tensions-public-anger?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/edfcc3d8-3ddd-4c14-b608-d09a436a6e60_27278fbf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Japan&#39;s Thursday release of treated water from the destroyed Fukushima Daiichi nuclear plant has become South Korea&#39;s latest domestic political football, as resistance against the plan threatens thawing ties between the neighbours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Yoon Suk-yeol&#39;s administration has said while it does not necessarily back Tokyo&#39;s plan, it has no problems with the scientific and technical aspects of the water release. The stance has, however, only exacerbated public disquiet and political divides.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korean Prime Minister Han Duck-soo on Thursday said there was “no need to be excessively concerned” about the plan as long as the contaminated water was treated and discharged in accordance with scientific standards and international procedures, as was promised by Japan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han&#39;s comments came a day after Lee Jae-myung, leader of the liberal opposition Democratic Party of Korea (DPK), slammed the water release as an “act of terror” and compared it to the start of a second Pacific war that would bring about “irreversible disaster” to South Korea and Pacific coastal countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han also criticised what he called a “politically driven” campaign using “fake news” to fan fears.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Social media posts in China and South Korea have included false claims about the release, including doctored images of deformed fish with claims they were linked to Fukushima.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite this, Han appeared to contradict the administration&#39;s stance by calling on Japan to ensure transparency in the water release plan, and vowing to stick with an existing ban on seafood from Fukushima and surrounding prefectures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The government urges the Japanese government to disclose relevant information transparently and responsibly in the discharge process that will continue for the next 30 years,” Han said. “What matters now is whether Japan will strictly adhere to scientific standards and provide transparent information as promised to the international community.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kim Gi-hyeon, head of the ruling People Power Party (PPP), also charged the opposition with spreading “fake news” about the health risks of the radioactive water and stirring up public resentment against both Japan and Yoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The DPK must immediately stop its anti-national activities that are destroying fishermen and civilian life with false propaganda in order to … win [the parliamentary elections in April next year],” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The DPK, which has a legislative majority over the PPP, on Thursday accused Japan of “environmental crimes”, and said it was planning new legislation similar to a China-like blanket ban on all Japanese seafood produce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China on Thursday extended its import ban to cover all of Japan, while Prime Minister Fumio Kishida said Tokyo had demanded Beijing “immediately eliminate” the ban, calling for “science-based discussions”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Outrage continued to mount across South Korea on Thursday despite the government&#39;s reassurance, with 16 university students arrested while attempting to break into the Japanese embassy in Seoul in protest against the water discharge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 40 fellow students later held a press conference in front of the building, waving banners and chanting slogans against the water release, local media reports said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representatives of fishermen from across the country on Thursday held an emergency meeting in Seoul and called for authorities to step up radiation monitoring and take measures to help bolster seafood consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The consumption of seafood has already plummeted due to the spread of political debates and uncertain information even before the release of contaminated water,” they lamented in a statement. “This crisis is threatening the very existence of the fishery industry.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The DPK on Thursday staged a street march in the city centre, following a candlelight protest outside the National Assembly the previous day that drew more than 1,000 participants. It has also called for a massive rally on Saturday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan has said the water release is safe. The International Atomic Energy Agency approved the plan in July, saying that it met international standards and that the impact it would have on people and the environment was “negligible”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Critics accuse Yoon of approving the Fukushima water release for the sake of improving bilateral ties despite the legacy of Japan&#39;s colonial rule over the Korean peninsula, and the United States&#39; attempts to rope both countries into countering China, Russia and North Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Park Won-gon, a political-science professor at Ewha University in Seoul, said the mounting outrage in South Korea over the discharge was turning into political capital for the opposition in the lead-up to next year&#39;s parliamentary elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is no room left for science to work in this highly charged atmosphere. With an absolute majority of Koreans opposed to the release, the opposition party won&#39;t let go of this chance to rally support to it ahead of the elections,” Park told This Week in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“However, the Yoon government is unlikely to yield to pressure and call for Japan to stop the release of contaminated water to the detriment of its efforts to improve ties with Japan.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters, Agence France-Presse&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan’s semiconductor sector faces offshore production dilemma as island struggles for water, power, people]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3232156/taiwans-semiconductor-sector-faces-offshore-production-dilemma-island-struggles-water-power-people?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/c8afb0d1-2ca4-4e38-906f-10998245722d_66a8f9ee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A US$40 billion compound in the United States to be operated from 2025 by Taiwan&#39;s flagship semiconductor manufacturer may help its hosts win a race with mainland China for chip superiority, but has the potential to undermine the tech-reliant island economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Offshoring chip production could undo Taiwan&#39;s semiconductor world dominance unless the industry solves a series of difficult problems at home, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC), the world&#39;s largest contract chip maker, will operate the site in Arizona, while it also plans to expand into Japan and Germany.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TSMC had a revenue of US$75 billion in the past financial year and its own network of lesser-known Taiwanese suppliers, but if they left, part of Taiwan&#39;s economy could be affected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At the core of this question is TSMC&#39;s ability to remain the unassailable leader of the world&#39;s semiconductor manufacturing process,” said Rupert Hammond-Chambers, president of the US-Taiwan Business Council advocacy group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If that continues, Taiwan&#39;s chip ecosystem remains central to the world&#39;s commercial needs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are some challenges, however, that relate more to public policy. Water and land issues impacting new investment are real and need to be managed in a way that prioritises the needs of the economy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After its chip sector took off in the 1980s, making Taiwan a magnet for customers including Apple and Qualcomm, it supplies around 60 per cent of the world&#39;s semiconductors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But US President Joe Biden is aiming to expand the US semiconductor industry through the Chips and Science Act, which was signed into law last year. The law targets manufacturing and supply chains, with a focus on research and development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July, Germany proposed a US$22 billion plan to improve its semiconductor manufacturing, as well as other elements of its hi-tech industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Korea&#39;s Ministry of Trade, Industry and Energy also said in July it had identified “specialised complexes” for semiconductors, with deregulation and tax incentives being considered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The escalating trade tensions between China and the United States, along with other geopolitical issues, have prompted governments worldwide to recognise the importance of possessing their own semiconductor manufacturing facilities,” said Joanne Chiao, an analyst with the Taipei-based market research firm TrendForce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan can stay ahead of the US, Germany, South Korea, and mainland China even while TSMC and its suppliers move offshore, but only if it offers the right incentives for the US$150 billion industry at home, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Curbs imposed by the US and allies, including Japan, on chip-making equipment sold to mainland China have accelerated a tech self-sufficiency drive by Beijing over the past three years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In that vein, Chinese companies have stepped up development of components and equipment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But chip makers in Taiwan have little land for expansion, while a series of droughts have prompted a search for new water sources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The costs of imported fossil fuel, plus their potential greenhouse effects, further vex the industry, and a declining birth rate threatens to sap the workforce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We just can&#39;t provide chip makers with a perfect environment to keep them,” said Kent Chong, managing director at professional services firm PwC Legal in Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a drought in 2021, the government rationed water near a TSMC plant, but spared the company and other major manufacturers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A new Taiwan factory of TSMC&#39;s scale would increase daily water intake by 118,000 metric tonnes, the Taiwanese news outlet Commonwealth estimated. It said that amount equals 7 per cent of Kaohsiung&#39;s water consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Starved of chips, China faces &#39;unprecedented&#39; pressure to become No 1 economy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Chip makers, though, are unable to increase renewable energy because Taiwan&#39;s electricity provider relies mostly on fossil fuels despite investment in offshore wind power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, the island closed one of its three nuclear power plants over public safety concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, renewables made up 8.6 per cent of its energy supply, with 9.1 per cent from nuclear power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Access to power “remains dogged by under investment”, Hammond-Chambers added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;The right direction&#39;: Taiwan seeks 400,000 foreigners for critical sectors&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A population decline that began in 2020 also has the potential to limit the number of engineers, with any solutions requiring “significant reforms to Taiwan&#39;s immigration laws”, according to Hammond-Chambers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To secure power as Taiwan tries to derive one-fifth of its energy from renewable sources by 2025, TSMC said in April it had signed a 20,000 gigawatt hour joint procurement contract with a subsidiary of the Taipei-based ARK Solar Energy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than a dozen TSMC suppliers are expected to participate, the firm said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, the Taiwan Water Resources Agency said an industrial park in the southern city of Kaohsiung would rely on recycled water to “assure stable supplies”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TSMC&#39;s Kaohsiung plant will need more water following “production adjustments”, the agency added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government-run Taiwan Power Company last year approved an issue of corporate bonds of NT$18.8 billion (US$592 million) to stabilise power supplies with upgrades at three power plants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To plug talent shortages, Taiwanese officials announced last year they would seek 400,000 people from overseas, including 40,000 professionals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think Taiwan&#39;s government is very supportive of the whole [integrated circuit] industry,” said Albert Liu, the Taiwanese founder of Kneron, a California-based artificial intelligence chip designer which employs 180 people in Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu believes Taipei may offer support, including possible tax incentives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other countries could take a while to build up semiconductor “clusters” with raw materials, equipment suppliers, chip factories and end customers, Chiao added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Taiwan has been deeply engaged in semiconductor manufacturing for several decades, and the formation of semiconductor clusters did not happen overnight,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chiao acknowledged that “demand for talent and workforces” are among the most “crucial” issues.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Torn between China and US, Taiwan&#39;s chip sector may just stay at home&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Industrial Development Bureau under Taiwan&#39;s Ministry of Economic Affairs declined to comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It, though, still might make more sense to allow the Taiwan chip sector to expand overseas, given constraints on the island, plus geopolitical pressures, analysts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If mainland China takes military action against Taiwan, chip technology could easily be transferred to other locations with Taiwan-operated factories, said Chong at PwC Legal in Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mainland China sees self-ruled Taiwan as a breakaway territory that must be unified, by force if needed. Relations have deteriorated over the past seven years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US officials have asked South Korea and Japan since February to apply for a cut of the US$50 billion that Washington has set aside as part of the Chips and Science Act to revitalise its chip sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To help TSMC and its Taiwanese suppliers in the US, Washington is also discussing a deal to avoid double taxation with Taipei, a move which could encourage investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[We] welcome positive dialogue on the issue of double taxation”, a TSMC spokeswoman said in mid-August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TSMC owned 30 per cent of the world&#39;s non-memory chip market last year, up from 26 per cent in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[A taxation deal] implies that Taiwan and the US will be more linked economically, making capital, investment, production, and people move more freely between the two economies,” said Hu Jin-li, an Institute of Business and Management professor at National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University in Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is, of course, a gravity that economically pulls Taiwan to the US side.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australian political assassin or innocent migrant  community leader? The tale of Phuong Canh Ngo]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3232124/australian-political-assassin-or-innocent-migrant-community-leader-tale-phuong-canh-ngo?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 11:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/6e740173-1907-4b49-884b-14af3e2de8e2_111fcd7d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As a nation born from a penal colony, Australia has a long history of colourful and loathed criminals, but few are more reviled than Phuong Canh Ngo, a former Vietnamese refugee who holds the unenviable title of being the country&#39;s first and only convicted political assassin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June 2001, a supreme court jury found that Ngo had masterminded the murder of John Newman, an MP in the state of New South Wales. Newman was shot dead in front of his fiancée, Lucy Wang, outside the couple&#39;s home in Cabramatta – a suburb within his electorate in the Fairfield local government area of western Sydney – on the evening of September 5, 1994.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Home to the largest migrant hostel in the state before its demolition in the early 1990s, Cabramatta has long been a nesting ground for migrants from all walks of life. But the arrival of boatpeople in Australia after the end of the Vietnam war, coupled with a massive jump in migration following the Southeast Asian country&#39;s relaxing of departure restrictions in 1990, transformed Cabramatta into a thriving Asian community nicknamed “Little Saigon”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By 1995, a third of the suburb&#39;s population identified as Vietnamese, according to the Australian Bureau of Statistics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today, the main thoroughfare of John Street resembles a historic Chinatown, with a large crimson-coloured Chinese gateway celebrating liberty and democracy, bronze lion statues symbolising strength and piglet sculptures representing prosperity. Asian grocers sell frozen durian and dragon fruit from Indonesia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are gold traders, thrift shops, haberdasheries galore, and Vietnamese restaurants that dish up the best pho and banh mi south of the Mekong Delta.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why Chinese migrants to the US risk deadly journey via South America&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But things were not always rosy in Cabramatta. Freed from the strict hierarchies that would normally contain their rebellious streaks back home, scores of Vietnamese-born teenagers found themselves on the wrong side of Australian law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By the 1990s, Cabramatta had become a no-go zone for law-abiding Australians: heroin was sold openly, users overdosed on the streets and Asian gangs such as the notorious 5T ruled the roost. The drug problem was so severe that police dubbed the train between Sydney city and Cabramatta the “junkie express”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MP John Newman pulled no punches as to who was to blame. “The Asian gangs involved don&#39;t fear our laws but there is one thing they do fear: possible deportation back to the jungles of Vietnam because frankly, that is where they belong,” he told the Australian Broadcasting Corporation at the time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Newman held particular disdain for Ngo, who he believed ran illegal gambling, heroin and money-laundering operations at Cabramatta&#39;s Mekong Club, of which Ngo was honorary president and which was often patronised by members of 5T.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nick Kaldas, then-head of the New South Wales homicide squad, who led the investigation into Newman&#39;s murder, concurred.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the morning, Ngo would sit on the board of the Area Health Service, go to council meetings and present a respectable veneer,” he told The Daily Telegraph in 2014, referring to Ngo&#39;s role in local government. “At night, he sat in his headquarters, the Mekong Club, and controlled the 5T gang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When Ngo was arrested and charged, hundreds of people from Cabramatta signed a petition pleading with the judge not to grant him bail, which is an example of the fear he instilled in many. By ridding the Vietnamese community and Cabramatta of Ngo, the area became the colourful piece of multicultural Sydney it is today.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Ngo had never been charged with a crime until after Newman&#39;s death; rather, he was a poster boy for multiculturalism and immigration in Australia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After arriving penniless in Cabramatta in 1982, he got to work building a business and community power base that earned him de facto leadership of Sydney&#39;s Vietnamese community. He also founded Dan Viet, a popular Vietnamese-language newspaper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1987, Ngo was elected as a municipal councillor representing the people of Cabramatta on the Fairfield City Council. In 1990, he was elected deputy mayor of Fairfield – a remarkable accomplishment for an immigrant who could barely speak English eight years earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yet it wasn&#39;t enough for Ngo. He wanted to join the political big league and dreamed of becoming the first Vietnamese-Australian elected to parliament. But one man – Newman – kept standing in his way, defeating him soundly at state elections in 1991 and denouncing him as a crime boss at every given opportunity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police would later allege that Ngo decided to kill his political rival after his loss at the polls and made four botched attempts on Newman&#39;s life until he finally succeeded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t know much about enemies, but I do know that Newman didn&#39;t have many friends,” Ngo told police when they first interviewed him nine days after the murder, adding: “We had differences. I must stress I never liked the man.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With Newman&#39;s distraught fiancée unable to recall the face of the shooter or any details about the getaway car, Ngo was allowed to go about his business. Within six months of Newman&#39;s death, he had assumed the presidency of the Cabramatta State Electoral Council of the Australian Labor Party – Newman&#39;s political party – and was No 1 on the ticket and chief fundraiser for the party in the Fairfield council elections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And so it appeared Ngo had got away with orchestrating an assassination – until initially reluctant witnesses began to cooperate with police, giving them the evidence they needed to charge him with first-degree murder in 1998.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After three years on remand and three trials – the first was aborted and the second ended with a hung jury – Ngo was found guilty of orchestrating Newman&#39;s murder.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a result of New South Wales&#39; Byzantine mandatory sentencing regime and the gravity of his crime – described by presiding judge John Dunford as an “attack on democracy” motivated by “naked political ambition” – Ngo was sentenced to life behind bars without the possibility of parole.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Case closed?不完全的。 Ngo has always maintained his innocence, and to this day the shooter and driver remain at large.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;David Dinh, a Vietnamese man who worked at the Mekong Club and who police accused of pulling the trigger, and Quang Dao, the alleged driver of the getaway car, were both acquitted during the third and final trial and remain adamant that Ngo could not have been involved in the crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I know for sure that Phuong is not involved in that murder,” Dao said, claiming he used the alleged getaway car – a white Toyota Camry – to pick up his children at the time of the shooting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a 2008 documentary feature by the Australian Broadcasting Corporation&#39;s Four Corners news programme that raised serious doubts about the validity of Ngo&#39;s conviction, Dao described how police offered to drop the charges laid against him and grant him clemency if he changed his story and gave evidence against Ngo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“They said if I cooperate they would put me in [the] witness protection programme, not only me but my whole extended family, and I refused that,” said Dao.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cooperate. What did they want you to do?” Four Corners asked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cooperate means like saying what they want to say, which is saying Tony and Phuong were guilty of the charge that they made up about them,” said Dao, referring to a third co-accused who worked at the Mekong Club and later turned state witness against Ngo, and whose real name was suppressed by a court order.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I told them we have no deal. I don&#39;t agree to do that.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The story of how Tony changed his evidence and had his murder charge dropped is extraordinary,” Four Corners reported, saying he only changed his mind after his teary-eyed mother visited him in prison.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Dear Quang,” Tony said in a tape recording played to Dao and later obtained by Four Corners in which he tried to explain why he became a police snitch, “I suppose you will be surprised when you hear my voice in this tape. Perhaps you will be very angry but please listen to what I have to say to you.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Let me explain. Mum was crying, and she said, &#39;Tony, if you still love your mother, you have to listen to the advice&#39;. I told my mother, &#39;Mum, I cannot do it, because if I did, I will jeopardise other peoples&#39; lives, especially Quang and his family. My conscience doesn&#39;t allow me to do that.&#39;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My mother said, &#39;If you don&#39;t listen to me, I will take my life&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dao says Tony was forced “to choose between his mum, the person who raised him, and two others, who were just acquaintances. And knowing the pressure his mum was under after he heard [her] threatening to kill herself if he didn&#39;t do what the Crime Commission wants, I feel more sorrow for him than anger”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Dinh, who spent two years in prison before he was acquitted, was less forgiving. “How can someone sit there, and you work with and see day in and day out, make up all these bullc**p stories,” he told Four Corners, fighting back tears.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the Four Corners investigation was aired on national television, the New South Wales government commissioned a multimillion-dollar inquiry into Ngo&#39;s conviction, headed by retired judge David Patten. But it didn&#39;t go Ngo&#39;s way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Crown in a criminal trial has very few opportunities to &#39;choose&#39; its witnesses. So it was in this case that it became obliged to call witnesses who had themselves engaged in criminal activity,” Patten wrote in his 210-page report, adding: “It was likely that the honesty and reliability of such witnesses would be severely tested in cross-examination and indeed it was.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Patte n also highlighted the fact that Ngo chose not to testify at his third and final trial after his lawyers advised him on “the risk of exposing himself to cross-examination”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Patten discounted questions raised by Four Corners that suggested police may have planted the murder weapon: a rare .32 Beretta police divers uncovered in the nearby Georges River four years after Newman&#39;s death – and only 20 minutes after the search began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Beretta was so corroded that ballistics experts were unable to conclude that it was the actual murder weapon and prosecutors had to rely on an expert in Germany to testify against Ngo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police had alleged that Ngo dumped the murder weapon in the Georges River half an hour after Newman&#39;s murder – a conclusion they reached after triangulating Ngo&#39;s mobile phone record, the first time this investigative technique was used in Australia. But Four Corners obtained new research that showed “grey areas” near mobile phone towers that cast doubt about Ngo&#39;s whereabouts after the murder.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China needs to step up its fight to contain growing mpox outbreak&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ngo&#39;s lawyer later argued in court that “the idea that Mr Ngo would arrange contract killers to kill Mr Newman and then take an active role in the disposal of the murder weapon is such an unlikely proposition that I can scarcely believe the prosecution had the audacity to run it”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pat t en also shot down this argument, saying that irrespective of the phone records and use of triangulation technology, “Mr Ngo&#39;s supporters had sought to create a major issue out of what seems to be a relatively minor feature of the case” given that Ngo had admitted to being in the vicinity of the Georges River after Newman was killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Patten concluded he found nothing that “casts doubt upon or raises a sense of unease in respect to the conviction of Mr Ngo” or suggested the police investigation into Newman&#39;s murder was not conducted “thoroughly or competently by police officers dedicated to the task”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Homicide squad chief Kaldas commended the inquiry for its findings. “Police are of the firm view that this was one of the most compelling briefs of evidence to go before a jury and they have no doubt whatsoever that the jury reached a correct verdict of guilt against Phuong Canh Ngo,” he said, describing the case as “one of the most scrutinised investigations in the state&#39;s history”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Leslie Smith, a retired applied scientist mentioned in Patten&#39;s report as one of Ngo&#39;s most steadfast supporters, believes the retired judge&#39;s findings were incomplete since he failed to take into account key discrepancies in the trials. And there is good reason to listen to him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1982, a woman named Lindy Chamberlain was found guilty of murder after her nine-week-old baby, Azaria, disappeared during a camping trip in the Australian outback.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chamberlain claimed Azaria had been taken by a dingo (an Australian wild dog) while sleeping in a tent but a jury found her mother guilty of murder after a stain found on the dashboard of her car was identified by a forensic pathologist as blood containing haemoglobin that is present only in infants less than six months of age.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then Smith stepped in, drawing on his decades of experience to establish that the stain was, in fact, a “sound deadener” accidentally sprayed on the inside of the car during the manufacturing process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coupled with the discovery of Azaria&#39;s jacket near a dingo den, Smith&#39;s observation gave Chamberlain&#39;s lawyers the evidence they needed to reopen the case and prove their client&#39;s innocence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A decade after Chamberlain was exonerated, Smith was asked by a friend to look into Ngo&#39;s case, and what began as a passing interest turned into an obsession that consumed thousands of hours of the scientist&#39;s time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have combed through all the court transcripts, the committal hearings, inquests and inquiries and I sat through the third trial,” he says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I also visited Phuong in prison twice. It gave me an understanding of the case I think few other people have. I became particularly concerned about some discrepancies in the evidence used by the prosecution, especially sudden switches in context.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One element Smith finds particularly troubling is the evidence of two witnesses whose identities have been suppressed by a court order and who we will name Witness 1 and Witness 2.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the committal hearing before the first trial – a court date where prosecutors present evidence to the magistrate – a police running sheet presented by the prosecution claimed Ngo gave Witness 1 a photograph of Newman, and asked Witness 1 to find someone to do “nasty stuff” to the politician.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some time later, Witness 1, who it was claimed worked at a Vung Tau fish shop behind the Mekong Club at the time, offered the job to Witness 2 as he was delivering detergent to the shop. Witness 2 subsequently turned down the offer but Ngo&#39;s intent was clear, the Crown alleged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The problem,” Smith says, “is that the Vung Tau fish shop didn&#39;t open until nine months after Newman was shot, and police knew that. We have two witnesses who gave evidence about a conspiracy to commit to murder at a place that didn&#39;t exist, so it appears the conversation was fabricated.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;They called it &#39;Humiliation Day&#39;: the Canadian law that split Chinese families&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“What was the source of this coincidental evidence? I have come to the view that police acted as a conduit while these witnesses fabricated this evidence and the reason they did that was that police leaned on them because both these witnesses were dealing drugs and were offered a deal to testify against Ngo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If there was a pattern of misconduct that runs through all three trials, where police placed witnesses under surveillance, identified weaknesses and made offers of clemency in exchange for accounts of the Crown&#39;s hypothesis of how and why Newman was murdered, then the entire process was fraudulent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Smith says he attempted to present this information to the inquiry into Ngo&#39;s conviction but found there was no interest in anything he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you read the findings of the inquiry,” he says, “you will see Judge Patten did not call these two witnesses who would have been most able to assist him. He declined to hear them and it is very clear to me why: the authorities would prefer if Ngo stays in prison and this case goes away.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A retired journalist who covered the crime beat for the Fairfield Champion and other local newspapers in western Sydney for nearly a decade, Carlotta McIntosh attended all three of Ngo&#39;s trials. And she clearly remembers the moment when the conversation between Witness 1 and Witness 2 was first presented during a pre-trial hearing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The police said they had an incriminating conversation from April 1994, about five months before the murder, where [Witness 1 and Witness 2] discussed killing Newman and allegedly [Witness 1] was asked to do so by Ngo,” she says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Phuong was in the prison box and whispered to his lawyer that the fish shop did not open until the following year. His lawyer subsequently raised the point. The prosecutor still used that evidence at the first trial but by then the conversation no longer took place at the fish shop but at a different address.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McIntosh, who is currently writing a book about Ngo&#39;s conviction and how she “came to believe there was something wrong” with the trials, says that “the narrative about Newman being a crime fighter and upstanding member of the community and which painted Phuong as an evil crime boss was very simplistic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I met Phuong many times before the shooting. He was charming, very smart, a fast learner, very good at languages, a political animal. He didn&#39;t need to kill to get what he wanted. He negotiated, bargained and struck deals across party lines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Claims that he was some kind of drug lord or head of the 5T gang in Cabramatta were absolute nonsense. I covered the courts for years and there was never a scintilla of evidence that he was involved in crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Newman,” McIntosh continues, “was a different kind of person. He was tyrannical, a bully, both verbally and physically, an intimidating man and he terrorised his staff. The only thing that really seemed to bother him was the growing number of Vietnamese living in his area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Bob Carr, who was then leader of the Labor Party in New South Wales, was very worried about the bad publicity Newman was causing and wanted to replace him at the next election.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The accepted narrative, she says, led to Ngo&#39;s alleged motive and the harshness of his sentence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When Phuong was sentenced the judge talked about an assault on democracy, and that was what put him in the worst category of criminals. But it is simply not true because everyone close to Phuong knew he had given up on becoming a member of the lower house [of parliament where Newman held a seat] and wanted a seat in the upper house instead.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A police running sheet detailing a conversation between Ngo and the then New South Wales Labor Party general secretary, John Della Bosca, at a restaurant in Sydney&#39;s Chinatown on the day of Newman&#39;s murder appears to substantiate McIntosh&#39;s opinion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Newman was mentioned during lunch,” the running sheet reads. “Della Bosca suggested that Ngo run against Newman in the next election. Ngo said words to the effect of &#39;No, I&#39;ve given my word to Newman that I won&#39;t run for the legislative assembly as member for Cabramatta, [he] would not oppose Newman in pre-selection&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McIntosh says the meeting and numerous other pieces of evidence that are on the public record “completely destroy” Ngo&#39;s apparent motive for the crime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If I was on the jury, I would not have found him guilty beyond a reasonable doubt,” she says. “Sure, there was loads of evidence against him but that doesn&#39;t mean the evidence was correct. Most of it came from the Crime Commission, which journalists can&#39;t report on. It&#39;s all shrouded in secrecy, like an inquisition.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Questions about Ngo&#39;s apparent motive are central to a campaign by a small but determined number of supporters urging the attorney general of New South Wales to launch an inquiry into Ngo&#39;s sentencing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;She faced racism, sexism on her rise to CEO. Now she gives others a leg-up&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“As Australians, we claim the moral high ground about our record on human rights. Yet when it comes to sentencing laws, New South Wales is now seriously out of step with the international community and its human rights initiatives,” wrote John Anderson, Felicity Wardhaugh and Daniel Matas, lecturers in law at the University of Newcastle Legal Centre, in an opinion piece published by The Sydney Morning Herald in 2013.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When the New South Wales Supreme Court sentences an offender to life without parole or the possibility of review, then arguably there has been a breach of Article 7 of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights,” the trio wrote. “No penal system is to be purely retributory in nature.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The view that it&#39;s time for New South Wales to abolish mandatory sentences, trust in the wisdom and experience of its judges and honour Australia&#39;s commitments to progressive human rights is shared by many of the state&#39;s most eminent legal minds, including retired High Court judge Michael Kirby and Nicholas Cowdery, a former director of public prosecutions for New South Wales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his 2019 biography, Frank and Fearless, Cowdery wrote that, “Mandatory sentencing laws stop judges and magistrates from doing an important part of their job – making the punishment fit the crime and the criminal and achieving justice”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even Dunford, Ngo&#39;s sentencing judge, who died in 2003, believed Ngo&#39;s case deserved future review: “This is not a case where I believe he necessarily needs to be kept in custody for the whole of that time, and if I had the power to do so, I would fix a non-parole period,” Dunford wrote in his sentencing remarks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that during Ngo&#39;s three years on remand, when the trials were taking place, Ngo had been a “model prisoner” who had “assisted young prisoners” and set up the Fairfield Drug Intervention Centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year marks the 25th anniversary of Ngo&#39;s incarceration, meaning he has already served a life sentence, including a 13-year stint at the Goulburn “supermax” Correctional Centre, the toughest prison in the country, after prison officials linked him to a gang called W2K, or Willing to Kill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has not had any opportunity to make his case for release since 2014, when he lost a final bid to appeal his life sentence in the High Court. Ngo is now 64.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The public still believes the myth that Phuong was a crime boss so it doesn&#39;t look good for him,” says McIntosh. “He has exhausted all avenues for appeal so unless Leslie [Smith] comes across a convincing piece of evidence like he did with Lindy Chamberlain, by the time Phuong dies he will have spent two life sentences in jail. Even if he is guilty, does he deserve that?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The office of the Attorney General of New South Wales Michael Daley did not respond to inquiries about the campaign to review Ngo&#39;s life sentence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Corrective Services New South Wales refused to facilitate an interview with Ngo “for a range of reasons, including limiting opportunities to re-traumatise victims and their families”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Newman&#39;s family would likely agree. “Phuong Ngo wanted the upper house,” Newman&#39;s half-brother, Peter Naumenko, told a media pack after the verdict was announced in 2001, “Now he&#39;s got the upper bunk. I hope he enjoys it.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Australia joins Singapore, China, Japan in tackling woes of an ageing population]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3232200/australia-joins-singapore-china-japan-tackling-woes-ageing-population?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/24/f3aead6c-c371-4fa9-bf49-0b0d2dc2e3b4_29e1c81f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;About one in four Australians will be older than 65 years old within the next four decades, up from one in six as of 2022-23, as Canberra joins the many governments in the Asia-Pacific facing an ageing problem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A new “intergenerational report” that forecasts outcomes in Australian society released on Thursday shows that not only is the number of older Australians rising, the country&#39;s population growth will slow to 1.1 per cent annually in the next 40 years, from 1.4 per cent in the last 40 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The double whammy of an ageing and slowing population is endemic of many countries in the region such as Singapore, Japan and China, where fertility rates have fallen and people are living longer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ageing population will place pressure on Australia&#39;s financial resources, with the report forecasting that around 40 per cent of the projected increase in government spending in the next four decades will be driven by Australians getting older.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Changes to the age structure and the old-age dependency ratio have economic and fiscal implications for Australia. For example, there was higher demand for education when the baby boomer generation was young, while demand for health and aged care services increases as more people age past 65,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The intergenerational report says Australia must plan for an older population, including reducing barriers to labour force participation for older people and for “women and historically under-represented groups” who may wish to work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Employers can make themselves more attractive to older workers by being more flexible about when and where they work, and by training older workers, the report adds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Separately, the report indicates Australia&#39;s labour productivity – output per unit of labour – has continued to fall and is now at 1.2 per cent versus 1.5 per cent in the last intergenerational report in 2021. If productivity was higher at 1.5 per cent, real GDP would also have been about 9.5 per cent higher in 2062-63.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A strategic migration plan can offset an ageing population, but it does not resolve ageing, as migrants also age, the report cautions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In releasing the report, Australian Treasurer Jim Chalmers ruled out another round of baby bonus, saying the “policy levers” were different now and there were policies that encourage women to have children such as parental leave and cheaper childhood education. In the early 2000s, Australia offered a baby bonus of up to A$5,000 (US$3,200) for every baby born.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Social egg freezing: can it help boost Singapore&#39;s flagging birth rate?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;These problems are shared by many countries in the region, which are “ageing rapidly”, according to a report by the United Nations Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP) late last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ESCAP said the number of people aged 60 years or older would rise to 1.3 billion by 2050, or one in four people, as compared with one in seven in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Due to a large population of the world living in the region, the Asia-Pacific is ageing more than the rest of the world, ESCAP said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The share of older people in populations in Hong Kong, mainland China, South Korea and Singapore would exceed 40 per cent by 2050, it added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the weekend, Singapore Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong addressed the city state&#39;s rapidly ageing issue during a key annual policy speech.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One in four Singaporeans would be older than age 65 by 2030, according to Lee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today, we are an aged society.很快，我们将进入“超老龄化”社会。这具有巨大的社会和经济影响。 We have much to do to help our seniors age well,” he said on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Active ageing” will become more important, said Lee, pointing to new Active Ageing Centres where seniors could join activities and meet friends.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore&#39;s single women &#39;not supported&#39; even as egg-freezing rules are eased&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In Hong Kong, the ageing problem is becoming chronic as it faces a shortage of elderly homes by 2032.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong will become the world&#39;s oldest society by 2050, with its population also ageing rapidly. By 2050, 40.6 per cent of its population will be aged 65 and older, according to the United Nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, whose economic engine is fuelled by its 1.4 billion population, is also suffering an ageing crisis where the number of citizens aged over 60 will grow by an average of 10 million per year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, China&#39;s population declined for the first time in six decades, with the national birth rate for 2022 falling to a record low.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Zombie takedown’: China taekwondo team banned for ‘blasphemous’ ghoul dance in Qing dynasty costumes at world contest]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3231905/zombie-takedown-china-taekwondo-team-banned-blasphemous-ghoul-dance-qing-dynasty-costumes-world?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.25 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/bb46fd29-b97d-4446-84df-5f848f84a269_17264055.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A taekwondo martial arts team from China has been punished and the licence of its coach has been revoked after it performed a “Zombie dance” wearing Qing dynasty costumes at an international competition in South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The offending dance was performed by members of a taekwondo studio from southern China&#39;s Guangdong province at the 2023 Seongnam World Taekwondo Hanmadang in South Korea on July 24.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Online footage shows seven members of the studio performing taekwondo techniques wearing Qing dynasty (1636-1912) officials&#39; uniforms while performing actions typical of zombies in classic Hong Kong horror films.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On August 21, the Chinese Taekwondo Association issued a formal denunciation of the performance saying that it “smeared the image of the nation and blasphemed Chinese culture”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The association cancelled the studio&#39;s membership and banned it from participating in national taekwondo contests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also revoked the licence of the team&#39;s coach, Liu Hao, who choreographed the dance, prohibiting him from participating in training and competitions held by the association.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, opinion was divided on mainland social media about the punishment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think the performance respected neither taekwondo nor China,” one person said on Douyin, the mainland&#39;s version of TikTok.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Has the association overreacted here?这只是一个非政府团体玩得开心而已。 Why be so sensitive,” said another online observer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think it is creative.我小时候也很喜欢看香港丧尸片。 There is no need to make a fuss as long as we are confident in our culture,” commented a third person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another online observer supported the punishment and said the performance fuelled stereotypes pushed by Western countries that depict Chinese people as “old fogeys in robes with long braids”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While a number of videos of the full performance were removed online, several media outlets quoted coach Liu as saying the performance ended with the seven “zombies” “taking off their robes and receiving the world&#39;s recognition of their brand-new image”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The classic Qing Dynasty zombie image first appeared in the 1985 Hong Kong horror film Mr Vampire, directed by Ricky Lau Kwan-wai, which starred Lam Ching-ying.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deviating from zombies in Western films, who usually move in a freestyle fashion, in Mr Vampire they used stiff body movements that lay the foundation for 1980s and 1990s Hong Kong zombie productions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is believed that Mr Vampire&#39;s zombie image was derived from the Qing dynasty shamanistic practice of ganshi, or driving corpses, which prevailed in the Western region of today&#39;s Hunan province in southern China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Performers of the practice travelled thousands of miles with the bodies of people who died unwillingly, such as from the death penalty, to their hometown to be buried.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to transport more than one body, ganshi practitioners attached the bodies&#39; arms to bamboo poles, so it looked like the corpses were hopping with their arms stretched out.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 25 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>