<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Storm Hilary lashes southern California after drenching northern Mexico]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231743/storm-hilary-lashes-southern-california-after-drenching-northern-mexico?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 10:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/0870af6d-5ee4-4319-97d2-e329dae0512e_114a9c4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;热带风暴希拉里历史性地登陆加利福尼亚州，预报员警告可能会发生灾难性洪水该系统给墨西哥下加利福尼亚半岛带来了暴雨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，墨西哥半岛发生山洪，部分道路被冲毁，社交媒体上的图像显示汹涌的洪流冲垮城市街道，造成一人死亡已变成河流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加利福尼亚州州长加文·纽瑟姆宣布南加州大部分地区进入紧急状态，并在整个更习惯干旱的地区发出山洪警报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在洛杉矶以东约 160 公里（100 英里）的河滨县沙漠度假胜地棕榈泉，这座城市通常全年降雨量约为 12 厘米（4.6 英寸），这场风暴可能会导致 15-25 厘米降雨量。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;正在南加州旅游的纽瑟姆表示，周日离开时棕榈泉已经干燥，但一个小时后，棕榈泉迎来了“棕榈泉历史上 60 分钟内最大的降雨量”泉”。街道很快就被淹没了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这就是这个系统移动的速度。纽瑟姆在洛杉矶举行的新闻发布会上表示，他向美国总统乔·拜登通报了最新情况，后者命令联邦机构向该地区运送人员和物资。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平敦促中国加快行动速度气象部门表示，截至周日下午，希拉里正以 85 公里/小时（50 英里/小时）的风向北移动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数百个航班在圣地亚哥、拉斯维加斯和洛杉矶被取消，职业体育比赛重新安排。该州最大的两个学区洛杉矶联合学区和圣地亚哥联合学区周一取消了课程。危险的海浪袭击了南加州的海滩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;墨西哥边境以北的圣地亚哥县遭遇了有史以来第一次有记录的热带风暴。美国国家气象局表示，加利福尼亚州、亚利桑那州、内华达州和犹他州的部分地区可能会发生龙卷风，但迄今为止只报告称，发生在亚利桑那州偏远地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在所有风暴准备工作中，距离洛杉矶西北约 130 公里的文图拉县奥海市发生了 5.1 级地震。目前还没有人员受伤的报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪水冲过洛杉矶河的混凝土河岸，而洛杉矶河通常几乎没有细流。在圣地亚哥以东约 145 公里的沙漠小镇奥科蒂洛 (Ocotillo)，岩石滑坡导致 8 号州际公路上的巨石滑落，导致通往亚利桑那州的高速公路交通延误。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这样的风暴在南加州极为罕见。 1997 年，诺拉袭击了因皮里尔县东部的偏远地区，1939 年，在风暴被命名之前，另一场风暴在洛杉矶县北部的长滩登陆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;山区和沙漠地区可能会受到影响。预报员称，降雨量将达到 12-25 厘米。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在沙漠的某些地方，降雨量相当于一年的降雨量，”圣地亚哥国家海洋和大气管理局的高级气象学家亚历克斯·塔迪 (Alex Tardy) 告诉新闻简报。 “八月份南加州和圣地亚哥的正常降雨量不算什么。因此，这里正在发生一件非常不寻常的事件。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;降雨引发山体滑坡，印度喜马拉雅山脉至少有 48 人死亡&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;希拉里周日早些时候在墨西哥下加利福尼亚州北部登陆据该国军队称，该半岛有近 1,900 人被疏散到避难所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这场风暴在低收入地区尤其危险，那里的许多房屋不符合建筑规范。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，在下加利福尼亚半岛东侧的沿海小镇穆莱格附近，一名男子的家人在过小溪时被冲走，不幸身亡。墨西哥军方表示，灯柱倒塌后，周围几个村庄的电话线和电力被切断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;墨西哥海军还从希拉里路径上的五个岛屿疏散了约 850 人，该岛屿此前被指定为减弱前为 4 级飓风。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Malaysia’s LGBTQ ‘sexual deviants or sinners’ stance stokes fears of violence as Islamists gain more ground]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3231741/malaysias-lgbtq-sexual-deviants-or-sinners-stance-stokes-fears-violence-islamists-gain-more-ground?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 11:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/b1c3ce21-2767-426f-989c-8a1b8e732ff1_54e20e4f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;艺术家 Carmen Rose 曾经定期在马来西亚演出，直到去年的一次警方突袭导致在伊斯兰主义者迅速获得政治影响力之际，这位经验丰富的变装皇后的行为结束了，并加剧了 LGBTQ 群体的恐惧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从袭击中逮捕了几名派对常客后，罗斯就不再做表演了，并且很少冒险穿着戏服出现在公共场合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“变装外出总是有风险的。如果发生突袭，我们该给谁打电话？我们要带男孩的衣服以防万一吗？”罗斯说，由于担心遭到报复，她拒绝透露自己的非变装身份。 “他们认为我们是性越轨者或罪人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚酷儿和人权组织表示，尽管这位长期反对党领袖享有进步人士的声誉，但在总理安瓦尔·易卜拉欣 (Anwar Ibrahim) 的领导下，LGBTQ 群体面临着越来越多的审查和歧视。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士表示，11 月大选后上任的安瓦尔面临着在穆斯林占多数的群体中增强其伊斯兰信誉的压力，面对日益受欢迎的极端保守派反对派，该反对派已稳步获得更多政治支持。自投票以来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚的反对派集团包括伊斯兰党伊党，该党提倡严格解释伊斯兰教法并反对 LGBTQ 权利。该党有史以来首次在议会中拥有最多席位，并且在本月的州选举中获胜增强了其政治影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“明显的司法嘲弄”：马来西亚安瓦尔公开谈论鸡奸审判&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一名伊党议员最近表示，LGBTQ 人群应被归类为“精神病患者”。另一位伊斯兰党领导人敦促政府取消酷玩乐队的演唱会，因为该乐队支持酷儿权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“安瓦尔感觉政治不稳定，所以他必须比对方更加伊斯兰化，”詹姆斯说Chin，澳大利亚塔斯马尼亚大学的政治分析师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鸡奸在马来西亚是一种犯罪行为，马来西亚也有伊斯兰教法禁止同性行为和异装。这个多民族、多信仰的国家拥有双轨法律体系，穆斯林的伊斯兰法与民法并存。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然安瓦尔从未表达过对 LGBTQ 群体的支持，但活动人士表示，他们希望他能够表达对 LGBTQ 群体的支持。在25年的反对党生涯中，他倡导包容性社会，表现出更多的宽容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当安瓦尔上台时，人们曾希望改革议程能够在一定程度上渗透进来，”Dhia Rezki 说Rohaizad，JEJAKA 的副总裁，JEJAKA 是一个支持同性恋、双性恋和酷儿男性的组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“令人失望的是，这一切没有发生。至少，我们希望他们不要打扰我们，不要主动迫害我们。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔今年发誓，马来西亚永远不会承认 LGBTQ 权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的政府禁止出版“宣扬 LGBT 生活方式”的书籍，拘留了表达支持酷儿权利的示威者，并没收了瑞士制表商斯沃琪 (Swatch) 生产的骄傲主题手表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，当局叫停了一场音乐节，原因是乐队主唱英国流行乐队 The 1975 在舞台上亲吻了一名男乐队成员，并批评马来西亚的反 LGBTQ 法律。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及政府对 LGBTQ 权利的立场时，政府发言人兼通讯部长 Fahmi Fadzil 表示：“无论总理说什么&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些分析人士表示，安瓦尔对 LGBTQ 权利的不妥协立场源于他希望消除对自己性取向的怀疑，这种怀疑是在他因鸡奸而入狱近十年后出现的。安瓦尔一再表示这些指控是捏造的且具有政治动机，但一些政治对手仍然质疑他的伊斯兰价值观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;活动人士表示，针对马来西亚酷儿群体的网络骚扰和死亡威胁在社交媒体上十分猖獗，而卧底警察也经常出庭。 LGBTQ 友好活动。许多团体现在确保在这些活动中配备律师，以防遭到突袭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;LGBTQ 倡导组织“正义姐妹”的创始人 Thilaga Sulathireh 表示，政府拒绝马来西亚酷儿群体等同于侵犯人权。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这让保守派和右翼更加胆大妄为，让针对 LGBT 人群的歧视和暴力行为不受惩罚，”使用“they/them”代词的 Sulathireh 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>; Swatch 起诉马来西亚政府扣押 LGBTQ Pride 手表&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;姐妹正义组织 (Justice for Sisters) 收到了更多来自在其他国家寻求庇护的马来西亚 LGBTQ 人的询问，他们补充说，该社区也越来越多地采取自我审查，以保持在雷达。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;变装皇后卡门·罗斯表示，由于担心再次遭到镇压，她取消了今年的一场演出。她偶尔会到邻国新加坡演出，现在正在考虑离开马来西亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这不是我逃跑。我只是累了，我还必须考虑我自己和我自己的幸福，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Guatemala election: anti-corruption crusader Bernardo Arevalo wins presidency by landslide]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3231745/guatemala-election-anti-corruption-crusader-bernardo-arevalo-wins-presidency-landslide?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 11:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/3a42c9bb-f85f-4e37-a179-0b1bb0e391d8_049d3533.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;危地马拉反腐败斗士贝尔纳多·阿雷瓦洛周日被选为总统，初步结果事实表明，许多选民希望这场胜利能够扭转对腐败和前几届政府独裁主义的广泛指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿雷瓦洛是一位 64 岁的前外交官，也是前总统的儿子，他已经建立了无可争议的优势在 94% 的选票清点完毕后，他以 59% 比 36% 的优势领先前第一夫人桑德拉·托雷斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在暴力和粮食不安全席卷全国之际上台，引发了新的浪潮的迁移。危地马拉人现在是寻求进入美国的中美洲人中人数最多的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;媒体公布选举结果后，阿雷瓦洛的一些支持者走上街头庆祝。许多危地马拉人还表示，他们希望阿雷瓦洛的胜利预示着更美好的未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我投票给阿雷瓦洛，因为他是我们唯一的选择。 74 岁的会计师罗伯托·阿尔瓦雷斯 (Roberto Alvarez) 在危地马拉城投票后表示：“投票给桑德拉就是支持那些之前投票的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;托雷斯取消了原定于周日晚上，当地媒体报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;为什么台湾正在关注谁将成为危地马拉的下一任总统&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;阿雷瓦洛出人意料地从政治默默无闻中脱颖而出，与他的塞米拉一起发起了一场大规模的反腐败运动在许多其他反对派候选人被禁止参选之后，他的胜利标志着对危地马拉拥有巨大影响力的既定政党的否定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当阿雷瓦洛出人意料地获得第二名时在 6 月的第一轮投票中，应一位著名检察官的要求，他的政党被短暂停职，随后危地马拉最高法院推翻了禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;投票结束后，没有关于暴力或骚乱的报道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;美洲国家组织（OAS）在危地马拉拥有一支由 86 名选举观察员组成的团队，该组织的一位主要代表表示，投票进展顺利。代表团团长埃拉迪奥·洛伊萨加 (Eladio Loizaga) 表示，这次选举“履行了所有艰巨的义务”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在竞选活动受到一些人的企图破坏后，包括美国在内的国际社会正在密切关注这次选举。一些官员将阿雷瓦洛和他的塞米拉党从竞选中剔除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即将离任的保守派总统亚历杭德罗·贾马泰发誓要确保有序投票和权力过渡。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;厄瓜多尔总统选举投票紧张因候选人被谋杀而蒙受损失&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但许多危地马拉人仍然持怀疑态度，因为政府近年来将调查人员从联合国支持的反腐败机构中驱逐出去，并针对法官和反腐败活动人士，其中许多人流亡国外.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贝尔纳多·阿雷瓦洛 (Bernardo Arevalo) 是危地马拉第一位民选总统胡安·何塞·阿雷瓦洛 (Juan Jose Arevalo) 的儿子，1958 年出生于乌拉圭蒙得维的亚 (Montevideo)，他的父亲流亡在那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他曾学习过毕业于以色列耶路撒冷希伯来大学社会学，并在荷兰乌得勒支大学获得博士学位。他撰写了有关冲突后社会和军队在拉丁美洲的作用的书籍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他于 20 世纪 90 年代担任外交部副部长和驻西班牙大使，并在日内瓦参与建设和平任务，在 2019 年当选国会议员之前。他有六个孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法新社和彭博社的补充报道&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong stocks slump to 9-month low as regulators’ measures to prop up growth fail to inspire investors]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3231742/hong-kong-stocks-slump-9-month-low-regulators-measures-prop-growth-fail-inspire-investors?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 10:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/ea89c38e-8db6-4843-9731-b73837f21d22_b26a16c6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;最新措施令人失望，港股跌至九个月最低水平金融监管机构公布提振经济的举措，股市表现不及预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恒生指数周一上午 9 点 56 分下跌 1.4%，至 17,691.65 点，创 11 月 28 日以来最低收盘价。恒生科技指数下跌 1.5%，上证综合指数下跌 0.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;跌幅最大的是航运公司东方海外国际，下跌 11%，至 107.80 港元，华润啤酒则下跌 11%，至 107.80 港元。下跌4.2%至45.20港元。中国人寿下跌 3.6%，至 11.16 港元，平安保险下跌 2.9%，至 44.10 港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在提振信心的最新举措中，中国证监会周五晚间表示，将帮助在美上市公司在香港上市，完善融资程序，完善跨境投资渠道。然而，它没有回应削减股票印花税的呼吁，并拒绝恢复股票当日卖出做法的呼吁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恒生指数下跌近上周，股市下跌 6%，创下五个月来最严重的抛售，股票交易员新一轮平仓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月政治局会议后缺乏强有力的刺激措施，房屋销售持续下滑，增长前景黯淡，同时有迹象表明，流动性紧缩已蔓延至财富管理行业，中融国际信托及其股东中植集团拖欠付款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最新的季度回顾中，恒生指数编制者周五宣布，国药集团将被纳入恒生指数基准，而陷入困境的房地产巨头碧桂园控股将被剔除，这些变化自9月4日起生效。国药控股上涨0.9%，至21.40港元，碧桂园上涨4 %至0.79港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生产运动控制产品和功率芯片的江苏协昌电子科技在深圳上市首日上涨105%至106.40元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他主要公司亚洲市场涨跌互现。日本日经 225 指数和韩国综合指数均上涨 0.4%，而澳大利亚 S&amp;P/ASX 200 指数下跌 0.1%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 10:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese weapons supplier Norinco expands influence in West Africa, challenging Russia and France]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231408/chinese-weapons-supplier-norinco-expands-influence-west-africa-challenging-russia-and-france?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/a6766991-4b7e-4481-87a1-ccfa332c6acb_9141043d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国正在扩大其在西非的军事和安全参与，其中包括中国国有企业国防集团北方工业公司在塞内加尔达喀尔开设了销售办事处，向法国和俄罗斯武器供应商发起挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士表示，中国北方工业公司（Norinco）将利用新办事处帮助扩大其在塞内加尔的军事采购业务。中国在该地区拥有巨大的经济利益，包括最近遭受军事政变打击的马里、尼日尔、布基纳法索和几内亚等国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据国防出版物《军事非洲》报道，中国北方工业公司还旨在在马里和科特迪瓦开展业务，这家中国军事承包商已经通过武器销售在这两个国家占据了市场份额。它还计划在这些西非国家建立车辆和军事装备的维护、修理和大修中心。中国北方工业公司已在尼日利亚、安哥拉和南非设立了地区办事处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据非洲军事公司称，中国北方工业公司今年年初向塞内加尔提供了 VN2 装甲步兵战车和其他侦察车。据该出版物报道，据报道，这家中国公司还在与塞内加尔政府进行讨论，为该国环境部供应轻武器和弹药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括中国北方工业公司在内的中国武器制造商希望一次性增加市场份额据观察人士称，乌克兰战争大大削弱了莫斯科向非洲国家供应的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国和俄罗斯争夺厄立特里亚在非洲的战略地位&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;法国也失去了影响力马里和布基纳法索的军政府驱逐了法国军队，而与俄罗斯有联系的瓦格纳集团雇佣兵则介入填补了空缺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿非洲战略研究中心的中国问题专家保罗·南图亚(Paul Nantulya)，表示，最初中国不愿被视为挑战法国在西非，特别是前法国殖民地的军事影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;语言障碍使中国关系变得复杂。然而，这些障碍已慢慢被克服，特别是中国北方工业公司一直处于中国建立和扩大军事和安全关系努力的前沿，Nantulya 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在达喀尔设立销售办事处的举动是基本上是为了利用和扩大这一业务，特别是考虑到俄罗斯国防公司遭受的严厉制裁以及该地区反法情绪日益高涨，这可能会使法国作为许多国家的杰出军事伙伴的角色变得复杂Nantulya 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，中非交往方面的军事化程度不断提高，中国国防企业也越来越愿意在商业、影响力、实力等方面更大胆地挑战西方同行。合作伙伴关系并将中国定位为首选合作伙伴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，这家中国公司一直在向西非提供各种军事产品，例如战舰、近海巡逻舰、便携式防空系统、直升机、无人机（UAV）、装甲车、主战坦克、战斗机（喷气式飞机和教练机）、大型火炮和运输机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据波士顿大学全球发展政策中心的中国对非洲贷款数据库， 2000年至2020年间，中国向8个非洲国家发放了27笔国防贷款，价值35亿美元。其中大部分资金（21 亿美元）预付给赞比亚用于购买飞机、战斗机教练机和军事装备，以及建造军警住宅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;David Shinn，中非问题专家、赞比亚大学教授乔治华盛顿大学埃利奥特国际事务学院表示，中国北方工业公司多年来一直是非洲国家的主要武器供应商，并不断努力增加整个非洲大陆的销售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“达喀尔新办事处是其中的一部分辛恩说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，俄罗斯历来是非洲的主要武器供应国，但乌克兰战争削弱了其这样做的能力，为包括中国北方工业公司在内的中国武器制造商打开了大门。以牺牲俄罗斯公司的利益来增加市场份额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国正在努力增加向非洲国家出售的武器的数量和先进程度，”希恩说。 “这些协议有时会带来长期供应和培训安排，从而加强非洲军队和解放军之间的安全合作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丹麦研究所高级研究员卢克·帕蒂 (Luke Patey)国际研究中心表示，中国已在非洲军火领域建立了牢固的立足点，而北方工业公司处于这些影响的最前沿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“非洲大陆新冲突和叛乱的兴起为中国军火商带来了不断扩大的商机”帕蒂说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，中国北方工业公司在塞内加尔的新机构等地区办事处提供了一个稳定的环境，可以向稳定的地区政府以及马里等受围困的国家出售武器、设备和车辆。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帕蒂表示，由于武器需要培训、零件和维修，中国北方工业公司的新交易将在未来几年加深中国在西非和其他地区的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗朗索瓦·弗雷 (Francois Vrey) 教授，斯泰伦博斯大学非洲治理和领导力安全研究所的军事科学研究协调员表示，军火公司在寻找潜在市场的地方开设办事处，并为购买其产品的客户提供支持。他说，后者后来成为向客户提供的一揽子计划的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了供应武器和军事武器外，中国北方工业公司还在许多非洲国家（例如非洲民主共和国）的合同中发挥着重要作用。刚果矿业，最近赢得了南苏丹原油管道建设12亿美元的合同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国北方工业公司全资子公司汇邦集团将担任工程、采购和供应商。承包公司。 6月，北方工业公司也是入围收购赞比亚莫帕尼铜矿的四家公司之一。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US must play ‘long game’ with China, says Singapore’s Tharman Shanmugaratnam, not go for short-term gains, risk worse ties later]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3231737/us-must-play-long-game-china-says-singapores-tharman-shanmugaratnam-not-go-short-term-gains-risk?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 10:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/21/2b71bdb3-3f73-4f2f-880a-8023c58e524c_11abba77.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国在与中国打交道时需要关注“持久战”即将到来的新加坡总统选举的领跑者尚达曼 (Tharman Shanmugaratnam) 表示，要抵制短期利益的诱惑，因为这可能会导致以后的关系变得更加困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚达曼是一位享誉国际的前财政部长和央行行长，他表示，他担心美国近期针对中国的出口管制和投资限制等举措将对世界其他国家产生深远影响。 “我认为我们正走在去风险化的错误道路上，或者无论人们想用什么术语。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚达曼在 9 月 1 日大选前接受《亚洲周刊》采访时说道。尽管新加坡总统在很大程度上是一个礼仪性的国家元首，没有行政职务，但该办公室对使用共和国的巨额储备金和任命公共部门最高职位拥有一定的阻止权。总统还在国际上代表新加坡 — — 如果当选，尚达曼可能会比他的前任更积极地发挥这一作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着建国总理李光耀于 2015 年去世，新加坡失去了一位全球政治家。尚达曼的国际地位尽管其地位无法与已故的李光耀相比，但在新加坡现任领导人中也是无人能及的。他是第一位担任国际货币基金组织政策咨询委员会国际货币和金融委员会主席的亚洲人。他还于 2017 年至 2022 年担任二十国集团全球金融治理知名人士小组和三十国集团主席。他目前担任全球水经济委员会联合主席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他辞去了自己的职务上个月作为高级部长竞选总统，公众普遍认为这一决定得到了李显龙总理及其内阁的支持。由于宪法要求总统必须无党派，尚达曼也辞去执政党人民行动党的职务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在宣布竞选总统时表示，希望利用自己的国际经验。世界正在进入一个更加困难的紧张和两极分化时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新加坡将于 9 月 1 日举行三场总统竞选&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;被问及中国经济放缓将如何影响该地区和新加坡”，他指出，中国正在经历“一系列非常复杂的挑战，部分是周期性的，部分是结构性的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我一直告诉我的国际同事，永远不要低估中国面临的挑战的复杂性，”他说。 “它们比任何其他主要经济体面临的问题都要复杂。即使拥有最好的技术官僚能力，也需要不断的平衡。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚达曼表示，他相信中国有能力度过经济放缓期，但这“可能需要一些时间”。&lt;当被问及美国限制某些先进零部件向中国出口的举措，以及最近限制对华投资作为“去风险”战略的一部分时，尚达曼指出，这是“一个术语”。这比解耦更流畅”。但他表示，随着时间的推移，这些行为会带来严重风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你必须打持久战，”他说。 “中国最终将发展自己的能力。它不仅会自行实现这一目标，还会通过复杂且相互依存的全球市场经济来实现这一目标，其中会有其他参与者愿意与它们接触，包括那些不是美国永久朋友的国家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;他补充说，离开中国所产生的影响“有点像海市蜃楼”。他说，中国的出口在出口到美国之前，先通过第三国转移，“这些国家现在正在作为新的制造中心受益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它已经成为一套更加多元化的供应链，但中国仍然这是其核心，这是正确的，因为它是一个极具竞争力的全球制造和物流基地。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚达曼表示，他希望美国能够以更长远的眼光看待与中国的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;“中美这两个大国之间希望建立什么样的长期关系？它是一种相互依存关系，并且对这种相互依存关系有一些非常仔细规定的限制吗？或者是一种逐渐分离的关系，这种关系最终不会阻止中国的崛起，但从长远来看会导致更加对立的关系？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还指出，无论是美国或中国将能够要求其他国家长期加入他们的阵营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“大多数亚洲国家不会决定放弃中国，在贸易和投资方面，大多数国家亚洲不会做出这样的决定。因此，这也必须成为长期战略计算的一部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚曼表示，他担心美国民主共和党双方都没有什么国内动力停下来，更不用说阻止与中国的“经济战升级”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“因此，美国目前正在发展的民主内部的激励措施并没有很好地与美国的长期利益相结合，也与美国的长期利益相结合。”全球繁荣，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“除了政府之外，国会还需要新的领导层的联合，以实现这一长远目标。这不是对自由贸易和自由投资流动的盲目信仰。这是一种战略观点，考虑到什么符合美国的长期利益，也符合我们所有人所依赖的全球秩序的利益。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚达曼表示，如果当选，他将利用自己丰富的经验和他是国内和国际网络的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在中国、印度、美国和欧洲，当然还有我们周围的地区，人们都认识我，”他说。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;“作为一个小国，我们必须始终谦虚地说话，但迄今为止我们发出新加坡‘理性之声’的能力并没有被忽视。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;新中关系基于政策，而不是对文化利益的“偏见”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他说，新加坡不必因为其国土面积小而不敢发声。 “我们必须始终比这更强大，通过说服而变得更大。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他强调，这不仅仅是为了投射新加坡的狭隘利益，而是为了成为“解决我们在新加坡所面临的挑战的桥梁角色”。 ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我在各种全球论坛中的领导角色包括寻找方法让每个人都了解世界不同地区，特别是发展中国家正在经历的挑战，并找到一种方法大国知道，小国和中等强国希望在避免整个体系分裂方面发挥作用。这些都是积极的角色，我将继续扮演。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二部分，明天：尚达曼谈他计划成为什么样的总统&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Singapore’s stablecoin rules could boost crypto’s ‘mainstream’ banking role]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3231578/how-singapores-stablecoin-rules-could-boost-cryptos-mainstream-banking-role?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/55a7b79e-5118-49b3-ab7c-1a9679ddbbdf_9fd2deea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;加密货币不可预测的价格波动对无数人来说是一场生死攸关的游戏几个月来，亚洲各地的投资者都在关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，只有少数地区政策制定者敢于将这些不稳定的资产纳入主流金融格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，新加坡央行的最新举措分析师表示，为稳定币引入监管指南可能会成为稳定币在银行等传统渠道中快速采用的一个里程碑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与其他加密货币不同，稳定币被视为避险资产，因为其价值与传统货币挂钩货币或政府债券和黄金等其他资产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡金融管理局 (MAS) 上周宣布的法规将适用于与新加坡元或任何来自新加坡的货币挂钩的单币种稳定币的非银行用户。世界十大经济体，并要求发行人维持低风险准备金，并在收到赎回请求后五天内向投资者返还票面价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“金管局似乎正在为增强信任铺平道路以及稳定币可能正式融入银行系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，由于这些法规计划于 2024 年生效，因此将 [需要] 密切监控它们对银行交易的确切影响，”陈说Zhuling，加密金融网关 RockX 的创始人兼首席执行官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在议会通过使该框架生效的修正案之前，央行需要举行立法磋商。这些代币将被标记为受 MAS 监管的稳定币。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国加密货币挖矿公司被指控经营传销&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;央行监管的稳定币与不受监管的稳定币的区别分析师表示，稳定币可能会缓解对其稳定性的担忧，这种担忧限制了其在实物交易中的使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;稳定币一直是加密货币交易的支柱，有可能将与传统银行系统相关的交易成本大幅削减至nominal amount, while speeding up processing times to seconds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But stablecoins have in the past failed to make inroads into mainstream financial systems because of a lack of transparency about their reserves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anndy Lian, author of the book NFT: From Zero to Hero, said Singapore&#39;s guidelines could bridge the gap between fiat currrencies and digital assets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But this should not necessarily mean that banks will start to accept all kinds of cryptocurrencies. The volatility of other cryptocurrencies is still a red flag for many,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Popular cryptocurrencies like bitcoin and ether tend to suffer from high price volatility, whereas stablecoins tend to hold steady since they are linked to fiat currencies and other such assets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite their relative safety, clamours for regulation of stablecoins grew after two such sister currencies – Terra and Luna, whose values were algorithmically pegged to the US dollar and not backed by cash – suddenly collapsed in May last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singapore&#39;s strict guidelines are meant to reassure both investors and institutions that could open new avenues for the asset class, industry executives say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Banks may even issue stablecoins for tokenised bank deposits as part of their rapidly developing digital transformations,” said Gerald Goh, co-founder and CEO of Sygnum Singapore, a digital assets fintech group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This model – fully regulated, traditional-asset backed and pegged to a high-quality &#39;stable&#39; fiat currency like the Singapore dollar – has the potential to become a blueprint for the industry,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Singapore&#39;s stablecoin framework will put it among the first jurisdictions to have rules to prevent mishaps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rival financial hub Hong Kong is, meanwhile, undergoing a public consultation on stablecoins and seeks to introduce regulation for them next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The European Commission set the ball rolling with the Markets in Crypto-Assets (MiCA) regulation, which it introduced with the purpose of establishing a global benchmark for governing cryptos.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After being proposed by the commission in September 2020, the European Parliament approved the MiCA regulation on April 20. It is due to come into force for stablecoins from June 2024, and for other assets from December.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anne-Sophie Cissey, head of legal and compliance at crypto firm Flowdesk, said the European legislation has set the tone for markets. “With clarification on the legal status, all crypto actors will feel more at ease to deal with those.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;G20 chair India calls for uniform crypto regulations as Asian markets grow&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Singapore&#39;s regulation could speed up stablecoins adoption across the region, industry executives say.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Regulators now collaborate with international entities, for example, MiCA&#39;s announcement in Europe led to similar guidelines in various countries,” said Danny Cheong, co-founder of online asset tracker Tranchess.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This trend suggests that financial hubs like Singapore and Hong Kong should move towards converging rules. This convergence might take a few years to materialise, rather than happening immediately,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s regulations are likely to follow Singapore&#39;s soon, as it has been earnestly trying to woo crypto investors. In June, it introduced retail trading and licensing guidelines for crypto.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many investors have already begun to gravitate towards tokenised assets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are increasingly seeing more stablecoin adoption in Asia,” said Henry Zhang, founder and CEO of DigiFT, a Singapore-based decentralised digital asset exchange, adding that they were looking forward to introducing MAS-regulated stablecoins.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s digital yuan &#39;at forefront globally&#39;, ex-central bank governor says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tokenised US short-term bills have exploded to US$600 million this year, said Timo Lehes, co-founder of Swarm, a regulated decentralised finance platform based out of Germany, citing data from Coindesk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The digital assets have also started making inroads past intermediaries in traditional financial channels, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are already seeing applications taking tokenised forms of cash and financial products that cut out the middleman. In this new world, financial institutions will need to rethink financial product design that puts consumers at the heart,” Lehes said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Central banks have laid the groundwork for cyptocurrency adoption with countries like China, India and Australia either planning to or having launched a central bank digital currency that can compete with stablecoins, said an industry executive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This will drive the choice and innovation needed in the market that will lead to mass adoption,” said Vincent Chok, CEO of Hong Kong finance firm First Digital.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong driver dies after getting hit by crane truck while out of car near Tai Lam Tunnel]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3231733/hong-kong-driver-dies-after-getting-hit-crane-truck-while-out-car-near-tai-lam-tunnel?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 09:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/21/43baee6a-a9cd-43e0-918d-6336cf8f80ff_cf49b711.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A driver was killed near Hong Kong&#39;s Tai Lam Tunnel early on Monday morning after getting hit by a crane truck while his vehicle was parked at a lay-by, leading to the partial closure of the New Territories crossing during rush hour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Kowloon-bound lane of the tunnel in Pat Heung was closed off, according to the Transport Department at 8am. A one-tube, two-way traffic arrangement was implemented, with motorists advised to drive through the area with “utmost care and patience”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two private vehicles had earlier collided at around 6.30am, about 50 metres from the tunnel entrance as they were heading towards Kowloon after passing toll booths.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Bus driver trapped, passengers stranded in Hong Kong tunnel after crash with crane&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Both vehicles were steered into a lay-by and the drivers got out to assess the situation. One of them was then hit by an oncoming crane truck.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was rushed to Yan Chai Hospital with serious injuries, where he was later declared dead.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China surprisingly holds mortgage rate, raising worries on easing outlook]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/economic-indicators/article/3231734/china-surprisingly-holds-mortgage-rate-raising-worries-easing-outlook?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 09:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/21/58055303-7b50-4690-b503-6eacc39785e5_f39e3757.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China surprisingly held its widely watched mortgage rate on Monday, raising market concerns over how the world&#39;s second-largest economy will tackle the ongoing property crisis and also restore homebuyer confidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The five-year loan prime rate (LPR) – which is a reference rate for mortgages – was left unchanged at 4.2 per cent at the August fixing, the central bank said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts said the cut was not enough and that more targeted and robust policies were required to have a tangible impact.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The People&#39;s Bank of China, though, cut the one-year loan prime rate – the medium-term lending benchmark for corporate loans – from 3.55 per cent to 3.45 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The latest move by the central bank follows an across-the-board weakening of China&#39;s economy in July, particularly the further decline of private investment and a deepening property crisis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Monetary stimulus is of limited use in the current environment and won&#39;t be enough, on its own at least, to put a floor beneath growth,” Capital Economics said last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Monday&#39;s move was the latest rate reduction during the current easing cycle, coming after a round of cuts in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The LPR has been considered China&#39;s de facto benchmark funding cost since 2019. The rate is decided by a group of 18 banks and is reported in the form of a spread over the interest rate of the central bank&#39;s medium-term lending facility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last week, the PBOC cut the rate of the one-year medium-term lending facility (MLF) from 2.65 to 2.5 per cent when selling 400 billion yuan (US$55 billion) of the liquidity tool before the release of July&#39;s macroeconomic data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s central bank had also cut the MLF by 10 basis points in June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The current situation would need cuts by 50 basis points or more, or other measures such as cuts to the reserve requirement ratio, extra government spending and other tangible moves to boost growth,” said Xu Tianchen, an economist with the Economist Intelligence Unit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Top leaders should introduce supportive policies with urgency, including the relaxation of markets in the biggest cities. Better still, they should commit additional liquidity support to large distressed developers to avoid confidence tanking further.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world&#39;s second-largest economy confirmed weak economic data for July earlier, with investor and consumer confidence faltering.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;No turnaround, jobless rates halted: 7 takeaways from China&#39;s July economic data&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Property investment fell by 8.5 per cent, year on year, from January to July, after dropping by 7.9 per cent in the first half of the year, marking the lowest growth rate this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UBS economists also said last week that it was necessary to roll out more potent and swift relaxation of real estate policies, which are crucial for stabilising real estate activities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rate cuts could restore confidence in the property market from the demand side, but China&#39;s monetary policy needs to be more powerful and targeted, said Bruce Pang, chief economist at global real estate services company JLL.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Monetary policy alone cannot effectively and efficiently solve the triple whammy on the Chinese economy – near-term cynical disruptions, medium-term structural issues and longer-term mega-trends,” said Pang.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 09:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Family in China spend 3 nights buried in books in search of names for soon-to-be-born twins, delighting social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3231396/family-china-spend-3-nights-buried-books-search-names-soon-be-born-twins-delighting-social-media?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/21/83b90844-07df-4d93-b19d-81999b66afcc_825362c6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The heartwarming story of a mother-to-be mobilising her whole family to come up with names for her soon-to-be-born twins has delighted mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Star Video reported that the unidentified mother-to-be from Shandong province in eastern China went viral after sharing a video about four members of her family spending three nights pouring over ancient Chinese texts and dictionaries to find names for the twins – a boy and a girl – she is expecting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the video, the expectant mother clocks the time on a smartphone to be 10.35pm on a Tuesday as four members of her family are sat around a table with their heads buried in books.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mother-to-be said that by the Thursday of the same week, a three-night period of family study had not yielded a result.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is unclear which family members were involved in the name-finding marathon, but the video shows a young woman and man, as well as an elderly couple.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The young woman was reading Three Hundred Tang Poems, a compilation of popular poems from the Tang Dynasty (618-907), and the elderly woman next to her was holding another classic, 300 Song Lyrics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The heftiest masterpiece was in the hands of the elderly man. Known as Cihai, it is a huge Chinese language dictionary and encyclopaedia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mother-to-be said that the surname of her unborn twins would be Liu. However, because Liu is one of the most common surnames in China, the difficulty in finding special names for the twins was increased.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said that none of the family had studied hard when they were younger, and this made her appreciate their hard work and dedication even more.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The focus and attentiveness they have shown could overload a central processing unit,” she joked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story delighted mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One online observer said: “Oh god, the thickness of Cihai scares me.” While another person suggested: “How about finding a fortune teller?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Chinese culture, a name is not just a symbol, it represents parents who place hope and wishes on the next generations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parents or other senior family members believe that good names will bring good luck and fortune to their children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also, as respect for seniority plays a big part in Chinese culture, older members of the family take priority when it comes to choosing names.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to China Highlights, the most common surnames in 2022 were Li, Wang, Zhang and Liu, with the numbers of people bearing them, in millions, being 95.3, 88.9, 84.8, 64.6, respectively.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most popular given names for girls were Ai, which means love, Fang, fragrance, Jing, quiet, and Li, pretty. For boys, the names were Qiang, strength, Guo, country, An, security, and Gang, strong.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Will wealthy Hongkongers fly Maldives’ new all-business class airline? Beond sets sights on travellers with cash to splash]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3231704/will-wealthy-hongkongers-fly-maldives-new-all-business-class-airline-beond-sets-sights-travellers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.21 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/20/5ce78624-e120-4c56-8031-ece84bdcd599_0a6601d6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A new luxury airline from the Maldives has set its sights on flying to Hong Kong next year following its expected launch this autumn, the Post has learned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new business-class only airline Beond – pronounced “beyond” – is targeting affluent holidaymakers to the Indian Ocean archipelago of 1,192 islands, offering a private jet experience with fully flat beds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dubai and Delhi are expected to be the first destinations when it launches later this year, pending regulatory approval.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to the Post from Dubai, Beond chief executive officer Tero Taskila said the carrier was “very close” to taking off and was about to receive its first aircraft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The carrier based in Male hoped to start a non-stop service to Hong Kong early next year with a flying time of about six-and-a-half hours, subject to securing aircraft and government approvals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taskila said it aimed to add three to five destinations in China, including Hong Kong, over the next 12 months depending on how quickly it could introduce new aircraft and complete regulatory negotiations with Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Airfares high and flight inquiries go up as Hong Kong quarantine rules loosened&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Hong Kong is a significant market. We are a niche carrier in a way that we are operating purely a private jet experience on a full premium class cabin and there are people who appreciate that kind of environment,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beond will start with an Airbus A319 with only 44 seats, whereas other airlines fit 150 economy class seats in the same aircraft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It expects to add the larger Airbus A321 aircraft next year, modified to have 68 seats where other airlines fit 220.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has not announced fare details between Hong Kong and Male but said a round-trip ticket from Dubai to Male would be about HK$23,500 (US$3,000).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taskila anticipated significant demand from Hong Kong, saying the airline hoped to attract passengers seeking “affordable luxury”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the cabin would be configured in rows of two seats, designed and made in Italy, with an Apple iPad Pro and wireless headset replacing the usual screens. Passengers would be offered chauffeured airport transfers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new carrier is jointly owned by Maldivian-based trading company SIMDI Group and United Arab Emirates&#39; airline start-up Arabesque, and has ambitions to fly to 52 destinations in five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since Hong Kong lifted all Covid-19 travel restrictions earlier this year, not all airlines that used to fly to the city have resumed operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About a fifth of the 72 carriers in the Board of Airline Representatives industry group have yet to resume flights to the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Airlines say high costs at Hong Kong airport and labour shortages slow recovery&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;There are currently no direct flights between Hong Kong and Male.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were 1.7 million visitors to the Maldives in 2019, according to official data. As of July, there were a total of 1.02 million visitors this year, the top five markets being Russia, India, the United Kingdom, China and Germany.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The Maldives has a plastic problem. One resort gets creative to solve it&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Most counts put the current number of island resorts in the Maldives at more than 160. Some hotels are spread out on their own private islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong Airlines and Cathay Pacific Airways flew to Male in 2020, but have not restarted their services there.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Dash for 50,000 cheap Cathay Pacific return tickets leaves Hong Kong users annoyed&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Three Chinese carriers currently fly between the mainland and Male, according to aviation analytics firm Cirium.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Jebsen Travel agency, Gulf carriers Emirates and Qatar Airlines fly from Hong Kong to Male via Dubai and Doha, respectively, for about HK$6,400 and HK$7,800 on economy and HK$37,000 for business class.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singapore Airlines flies from Hong Kong to Male via the city state for HK$7,600 on economy and HK$22,000 for business class.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taskila said Beond would keep costs down by using the more efficient narrow-body Airbus aircraft, compared with the wide-bodied planes used by other international carriers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the airline would work closely with travel agents to sell packages, rather than directly to passengers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Recovery of Hong Kong&#39;s aviation industry &#39;in sight&#39;; city pursues air service deals&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lily Agonoy, managing director of Jebsen Travel, expected the new airline to appeal to a niche market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This would be for top-end luxury travellers, because the Maldives has many luxury hotels. If you look at the hotel rates, and if you stay for one week, the airfare is nominal compared to the whole stay,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shukor Yusof, founder of aviation advisory firm Endau Analytics, was sceptical of Beond&#39;s business model, saying many of the wealthiest visitors to the Maldives, including celebrities and royalty, typically flew by private jet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for people on a once-in-a-lifetime trip for their honeymoon or anniversary, he wondered whether there would be sufficient numbers to fill regular flight schedules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It appeared to him that Beond was appealing to the “money-no-object” type of traveller at a time when middle-class travellers were increasingly watching how much they spent, given global economic conditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Taskila remained optimistic that his target group of passengers would show up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When you have something you are really looking forward to – a honeymoon, a wedding, an anniversary – you will save for it,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 21 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>