<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[‘Untouchable’ hardline pro-war Putin critic Igor Girkin detained in Moscow]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3228557/untouchable-hardline-pro-war-putin-critic-who-had-role-mh17-incident-detained-moscow?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 23:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/4b692e34-ccce-4b6c-bf04-bf90cc174b0 2_2077f1b0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯调查人员周五拘留了著名的俄罗斯民族主义者伊戈尔·吉尔金，他曾公开指责总统弗拉基米尔·普京和军队高层没有足够严厉或有效地起诉乌克兰战争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的妻子、律师和加拿大皇家银行新闻媒体报道了这一举动，表明当局已经厌倦了他对所谓的俄罗斯“特别军事行动”的批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 上个月，另一位直言不讳的批评者、瓦格纳雇佣兵部队的头目叶夫根尼·普里戈津 (Yevgeny Prigozhin) 领导了一场未遂的兵变。他仍然自由，但大幅减少了自己的言语攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉尔金 (Girkin)，又名伊戈尔·斯特雷科夫 (Igor Strelkov)，于 2014 年帮助俄罗斯从乌克兰吞并克里米亚，然后组织亲俄民兵从基辅控制了乌克兰东部的部分地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还被判处无期徒刑。 2022 年，他因涉嫌参与 2014 年乌克兰东部上空马来西亚航空公司 MH17 航班被击落事件而被荷兰法院缺席审理，造成 298 名乘客和机组人员丧生。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;瓦格纳的普里戈任如何从普京好友转变为军事批评者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这位前联邦安全局 (FSB) 官员因其背景和与当局的关系而被许多人认为是不可接触的，但在&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉尔金在五月宣布，他和其他人成立了“愤怒的爱国者俱乐部”，进入政界，以拯救俄罗斯免受他所说的乌克兰军事失败造成的动乱危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时被问到他是否天真地认为自己可以在没有克里姆林宫同意的情况下发起一场政治运动，他说：“我希望你不要说我是一个天真的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他的一篇文章中7 月 18 日，吉尔金在其官方 Telegram 频道上发表了一篇有超过 76 万读者阅读的帖子，其中对普京进行了人身攻击，并敦促他将权力移交给“真正有能力和负责任的人”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在吉尔金官方 Telegram 帐户上发布的消息中，他的妻子 Miroslava Reginskaya 表示：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天上午 11 点 30 分左右，调查组的代表活动委员会来到我们家。我不在家。据礼宾部称，很快，他们就抓住我丈夫的双臂，将他带往未知的方向。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，朋友们告诉她，吉尔金被指控犯有极端主义。 “我不知道我丈夫的下落，他没有联系过我，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局没有立即发表评论。吉尔金的律师告诉国家通讯社塔斯社，目前尚不清楚他的当事人被拘留的原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;MH17 判决：因 2014 年马来西亚飞机坠落事件，三人被定罪，一人无罪&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;加拿大皇家银行援引两名未透露姓名的执法消息人士的话称，吉尔金在莫斯科的住所正在接受搜查，他因瓦格纳前雇员对他的投诉而被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; R Politik 分析公司的创始人塔蒂亚娜·斯塔诺瓦亚 (Tatiana Stanovaya) 表示，俄罗斯执法和权力部门的负责人长期以来一直想逮捕吉尔金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Strelkov [吉尔金] 很久以前就超越了所有可以想象的界限”，她说。 “这是普里戈任叛变的直接结果：军队指挥部现在拥有更大的政治影响力来镇压公共领域的对手。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯坦诺瓦亚表示，吉尔金的拘留是一个信号，表明任何对莫斯科战争方式最严厉的批评者都可能面临起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Axed China Initiative’s racial profiling legacy haunts scientists in US]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3228493/axed-china-initiatives-racial-profiling-legacy-haunts-scientists-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/aa5645ed-3420-4b59-9166-d6fe9f8ec0f c_9986ca8d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当一队武装的联邦调查局特工闯入他在费城的家中，并用枪威胁他的家人时，物理学家郗小星的生活永远改变了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郗小星于 2015 年 5 月 21 日被捕并被指控分享敏感的美国公司技术，三年前，唐纳德·特朗普政府针对被认为与北京有联系的美国科学家发起了备受争议的“中国计划”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对郗小星的指控是被指控试图向中国传输有关袖珍加热器设计的信息 - 四个月后被撤职，但在此之前他失去了费城坦普尔大学物理系主任的职位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在联邦调查局的调查期间，习近平也被禁止出现在校园，申请研究资助或与他的学生交谈，甚至私下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一次非常痛苦的经历，”习近平说。 “作为一名科学家，通常不会想到会发生这样的事情，所以这非常令人震惊，没有任何迹象表明类似的事情会发生。这是一次非常戏剧性的经历。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平说，美国政府的案件是基于从他天普大学地址发送的四封电子邮件，这些电子邮件与袖珍加热器无关。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国出生的美国科学家就失败的案件向联邦调查局追索赔偿&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;相反，这些消息是基于习近平广泛发表的研究的学术合作，这一事实得到了该领域领先专家提供的宣誓书的证实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平或该协议是在前总统巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 领导下达成的，但特朗普政府的举措极大地扩大了后来对美国华裔科学家进行调查的范围。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 150 名学术科学家受到公开调查，其中 20 人受到刑事指控，该举措于 2022 年 2 月被司法部取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但华裔科学家告诉研究人员，审查从未停止，几乎没有迹象表明乔·拜登政府正在采取足够措施来修复损害。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“中国倡议”被吹捧为对北京“经济间谍活动”的回应，当时被美国公民自由联盟严厉批评为“违宪”，该联盟表示，该倡议基于种族定性，因为它“根据种族、族裔或国籍来挑选科学家”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据普林斯顿大学、哈佛大学和麻省理工学院的研究人员的一项研究，该倡议的持久影响是许多具有华裔血统的科学家仍然普遍感到恐惧（麻省理工学院）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项研究于上个月发表在美国国家科学院同行评审期刊《PNAS》上，发现普遍的恐惧和焦虑感导致许多科学家考虑离开美国或不再申请联邦拨款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员于 2021 年 12 月至 2022 年 3 月进行的一项在线调查中，超过 70% 的受访者表示，作为华裔学术研究人员，他们在美国感到不安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;同一项调查发现，65% 的受访者担心与中国的合作，而 45% 的受访者表示，他们过去曾获得过联邦资助，他们倾向于避免申请资助。共有 61% 的人表示曾考虑离开美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国实验室因调查而关闭，“痒基因”科学家加入深圳研究院&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;习近平表示，他“完全理解”调查受访者表达的恐惧。 “从我的角度来看，我担心的是，我每天所做的一切都可能被政府扭曲来指控我。从心理上来说，这是一件非常可怕的事情。这让我的生活压力很大。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在成为 FBI 的目标之前，Xi 的研究由 9 项联邦拨款资助，他的团队有 15 人。如今，习近平获得了一笔资助，研究领域要小得多，只有一名研究人员来帮助他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当时我的研究领域更广泛，但现在只有一个课题。我当时做的很多研究现在都没有做，”习近平说。他补充说，他现在做每件事都非常小心，“以免惹上麻烦”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;越来越担心在美国的华裔美国科学家成为攻击目标&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;麻省理工学院机械工程教授陈刚于 2021 年 1 月因“中国倡议”被捕，指控一年后被驳回。他表示，由于担心被种族歧视，他不敢申请联邦拨款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“基本上，我已经不再接受联邦资助了，”陈告诉我。八月份的 NBC 亚美节目。据《自然》二月版报道，他还从具有明显商业应用的纳米技术转向了更基础的研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《高等教育评论》三月份发表的另一项研究发现，中国和其他亚洲科学家的种族定性存在“一致且具有统计显着性的模式”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚利桑那大学的研究人员对来自美国顶尖研究型大学的约 2,000 名科学家进行了调查，得出的结论是，尽管“中国倡议”结束了，但对种族定性的担忧仍然存在。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;美国针对的中国出生的科学家“发现了世界上最好的半导体”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;研究人员表示，“在美国的中国科学家继续作为犯罪分子受到调查，不是因为间谍活动，而是经常被归结为与税收相关的指控。”主要作者珍妮·李表示，没有任何迹象表明“政府采取任何行动来消除中国倡议的有害影响”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国的大学也处于跟上步伐的困难境地。李说，“因此，各机构采取了相当保守的做法，就好像中国倡议仍然有效，他们仍然需要密切监控利益冲突。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管受到镇压，美国科学家仍与中国同行保持联系：研究人员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该研究发现，42% 的中国科学家感到受到美国政府的种族歧视，而非亚裔科学家的这一比例为 4.7%。研究人员还发现，感受到种族歧视与考虑离开该国之间存在显着关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于在[新闻]头版上看到这些指控的普通科学家来说，这让他们对自己的工作有了不同的看法，而不仅仅是研究。这也是他们以前没有想到的高风险研究。”李说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“许多人实际上认为，在中国工作，即使是在中国共产党统治下，也比在重视学术自由的美国工作风险要小。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;从美国脑研究流亡的科学家在中国发现了资金充足的实验室&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一位最近因该倡议的影响而返回中国的美籍华裔科学家表示，该倡议的目的是作为美国遏制中国科学进步努力的一部分，它一直在科学家中制造恐惧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[美国]已经达到了目的。美国的科学家正在返回中国，而中国的科学家则不敢返回美国，”这位科学家表示。由于该话题的敏感性，他要求匿名。 “这种事每天都在发生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但一些专家认为，切断与中国学术界的关系破坏了华盛顿与北京竞争并赢得技术竞赛的意图。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;研究称，美国的“中国计划”阻碍了科学创新&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国国家科学、工程和医学院去年警告说，这种做法可能会“损害和减缓美国的创新速度”，而不是限制其他国家取得的进步。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在当今相互依存的全球创新体系中，最大的威胁是美国将无意中削弱其创新生态系统，而其他国家则继续效仿历史上为美国在技术开发和商业化方面带来优势的行动，”其2022年报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于现在回到中国的匿名科学家来说，已经有证据表明“美国有巨大的战略担忧”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国现在拥有许多人才和资金。在这些高质量期刊中，大约三分之一的作者是中国研究人员。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国大学在研究质量方面的排名高于牛津、剑桥和加州理工学院&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，美国的研究经费未能跟上成本上涨的步伐，在过去 30 年里基本保持不变。这位科学家表示，曾经资助实验室运营的拨款现在只能提供一名研究人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据日本国家科学技术政策研究所的数据，中国自 2017 年以来一直是科学论文产出最多的国家，最近在另一个里程碑上超越了美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究所去年发布的一份报告显示，2018 年至 2020 年间，中国在全球最常被引用的研究中占前 1% 的比例超过任何其他国家。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国学术影响力上升而美国影响力下降：调查&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;普林斯顿大学副研究员、《美国国家科学院院刊》研究报告的合著者黄俊明表示，美国应该“继续欢迎和吸引中国科学家，以长期保持其在科技领域的全球领先地位”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们从‘中国倡议’中学到的一个重要教训是，我们不能用大刀阔斧地解决问题和应用政策。我们需要外科手术般的精确性和基于数据的解决方案，为解决具体问题提供真正的步骤。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管美国华裔科学家报告了这些挑战，但并不是每个人都会返回中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;谢晓亮是最新一位放弃美国公民身份的中国科学家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;华盛顿大学的一名博士生由于问题的敏感性而要求匿名，她表示她不会很快返回中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究人员表示，探索尖端技术及其多样化方向是她个人的兴趣。 “从这个角度来看，我认为美国和欧洲仍然是目前最开放的地方。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，习近平继续努力向法院寻求对自己经历的纠正。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017年针对联邦调查局首席特工和其他人提起的诉讼，指控他们“故意或鲁莽地做出虚假陈述”以支持他们的调查和起诉，该诉讼于2021年被地区法院驳回。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国出生的教授起诉联邦调查局特工因“间谍”逮捕&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;习近平去年对该判决提出上诉，五月第三巡回上诉法院裁定他的案件被错误地驳回。他说，习近平和他的家人正在等待美国政府是否会对裁决提出上诉并推动案件进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平在 2021 年提交的书面证词中表示，“无论美国和中国处于冷战还是热战状态，执法部门根据中国科学家的出身来对他们进行定性分析都是错误的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所有中国教授、科学家和学生都不是中国的非传统收藏家或间谍，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h 3>;人工智能专家朱松春将从美国返回中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;习近平上周在接受《南华早报》采访时表示，《中国倡议》是基于中国科学家“涉嫌为中国从事间谍活动”的假设。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是所有这些案件和所有调查的根本原因……从某种意义上说，‘无罪推定’。”这种情况没有改变。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张理查德的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China says US is dumping critical chemical into domestic market, undercutting industry]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3228525/china-says-us-dumping-critical-chemical-domestic-market-undercutting-industry?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/fb3b0521-5ccf-4a0a-86cd-ebfa01b37420 _6eda2f89.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国对美国丙酸发起反倾销调查，这种广泛使用的化学成分对美国供应的严重依赖给国内行业敲响了警钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;商务部表示，本次调查于周五开始，将持续至少一年，在特殊情况下可能会延长至2025年1月21日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丙酸通常用于食品、农药、医药及药物中间体。它可以抑制霉菌和某些细菌的生长——作为一种常见的防腐剂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反倾销调查请求是由江苏省化学工业协会提出的，该协会是一家国内主要生产商，占有中国一半以上的市场份额，商务部表示，其目标是2019年至2023年前三个月美国在中国销售的丙酸。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“只有穿鞋的人才知道鞋夹在哪里”：中国出口商的艰难时期&lt;/h 3>;&lt;p>;此次调查是在中美紧张局势加剧的背景下进行的，而且北京方面以国家安全考虑为由禁止出口两种用于半导体的关键金属——锗和镓。但此举被广泛认为是对美国针对中国不断加强的技术遏制措施的回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;倾销通常是指商品在正常贸易过程中以低于中国正常价格的价格进入一国市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据商务部提供的附件，该协会表示，今年第一季度中国丙酸价格比去年同期下降了28.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在此之前价格下跌了6%。该协会称，自2019-22年起，中国国内化工行业的关税下降了9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了抢占或保持在中国的市场份额，美国制造商开始采取降价策略，向中国市场倾销大量丙酸产品，这对国内产业造成了严重影响和损害。”商务部发布的文件称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果不立即采取反倾销措施，国内产业将遭受更严重的损害。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为全球最大的消费市场，中国对丙酸的需求近年来持续增长，据工信部称，2022年丙酸总消费量较2019年增长26. 7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而工信部数据显示，美国是中国丙酸的主要供应国，中国从美国进口的丙酸份额从202年的97.41%上升今年第一季度，美国对中国的科技限制“走向收紧”，尽管呼吁各方保持冷静&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据北京市场研究机构新闻网 1 月份发布的一份报告，2023 年第一季度该化学品的消费量也比去年同期增长了 3.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报告称，自零新冠疫情放宽以来，该化学品的消费量也较去年同期增长了 3.5%。深圳研究咨询公司Chyxx.com去年提供的数据显示，中国近60%的丙酸用于农业谷物和饲料保鲜，而北京对粮食安全的呼吁同样推高了国内需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018年华盛顿发起对华贸易战时，丙酸被列为据《华尔街日报》上月底报道，现在华盛顿正在加大对中国科技行业的围攻，因为它正在考虑对英伟达和其他芯片公司向中国客户生产的芯片实施新的出口限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Federal judge sets Trump’s classified documents trial to start May 20, 2024]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3228554/federal-judge-sets-trumps-classified-documents-trial-start-may-20-2024?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 22:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/8371e643-b0a3-4cbe-8125-72f456dab8 e9_37668131.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;负责监督前总统唐纳德·特朗普处理机密文件不当案的审判的联邦法官已将审判日期定为 5 月 20 日，拒绝了司法部在 12 月审理此案的提议，也拒绝了前总统推迟到 2024 年大选之后的请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佛罗里达地区法官艾琳·坎农 (Aileen Cannon) 在 7 月举行的备受关注的预审听证会后于周五确定了审判日期18. 虽然检察官今年无法审理此案，但坎农的举动对特朗普来说是一个挫折，特朗普曾要求她不要设定审判日期，因为他正在处理各种审判、悬而未决的刑事调查和他的竞选活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该裁决使特朗普的刑事审判距离 2024 年 11 月美国总统大选还有不到六个月的时间。这位 77 岁的老人是共和党总统提名的领跑者，审判将在初选最激烈的时候进行，以选出该党的选举旗手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坎农首先拒绝了特朗普推迟制定确定时间表的请求，并写道，她发现“有必要”让案件的其余部分步入正轨。她说，特朗普基于 2024 年竞选要求而提出的支持推迟的论点对她的决定来说是“不必要的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她写道，考虑到与使用机密材料相关的证据数量和复杂性，政府 12 月的提议“非典型地加速，并且与确保公平审判不一致”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普在机密文件案中不认罪后继续攻击&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;佛罗里达州的审判是多项法律义务之一罗列了特朗普进入 2024 年选举周期的日程安排，包括涉及他的生意的案件、诽谤指控以及多年前向一名成人电影明星支付封口费的指控。特朗普也是与推翻 2020 年大选结果相关的联邦和州刑事调查的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;审判日期是在几乎所有初选完成之后，但在 7 月的大会上正式提名共和党总统候选人之前。如果特朗普在这些初选中赢得足够多的胜利，那么当审判开始时，他可能会成为共和党总统候选人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特别顾问杰克·史密斯(Jack Smith)办公室以及特朗普及其共同被告沃尔特·诺塔(Waltine “Walt” Nauta)的辩护团队都一致认为，坎农最初计划于8月14日举行审判的时间太早了，因为他们表示需要更多时间准备。但他们就法官应该下令做什么争论不休。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周二的听证会上，为史密斯工作的联邦检察官要求坎农将审判安排在 12 月，而特朗普的律师表示，目前还没有必要设定日期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果这一日期如期举行，紧接着纽约将就数十项伪造商业记录的州指控对特朗普进行单独审判。这也意味着审判要到总统提名日程的深入阶段才会开始，而且很可能是在共和党提名人确定之后很久——尽管在共和党全国代表大会上正式提名该人之前。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普在未来一年可能还会面临更多审判。他本周透露，他收到了一封信，通知他，他是司法部针对撤销 2020 年总统选举的另一项调查的目标，佐治亚州检察官计划在几周内宣布指控决定，以调查特朗普及其盟友试图颠覆当地投票的行为。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Legco blocks Hong Kong public hearing to discuss controversial proposal to change make-up of Chinese University’s governing council]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3228552/legco-blocks-hong-kong-public-hearing-discuss-controversial-proposal-change-make-chinese-universitys?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 21:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/3bf6790a-1ab3-4cfc-ac3a-468884931ece _d7f31f22.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周五，香港立法会议员拒绝举行公开听证会，以讨论旨在重组中文大学管理机构的一项有争议的法案，其中一位立法者表示，他担心这可能会导致“对个人的攻击”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在立法会第一次法案委员会会议上，讨论增强外部成员对大学管理委员会影响力的提案时，大多数立法者选择通过收集书面声明来收集意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“中文大学的管治改革，甚至学校成员的改革，一直备受社会关注，颇具政治性。”提出该建议的三名立法会立法会议员之一的立法会议员邓家彪在会上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果举行公开听证会，恐怕人们会攻击他们不喜欢的个人或事物，而不是检讨有关规定是否令人满意或需要改变的地方。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但立法会议员江玉芬表示，公开听证会会更加公开和透明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公开听证会的要求是由杨宇明提出的，他以法定校友会主席的身份加入大学理事会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一呼吁是在法案委员会会议讨论中文大学提案的前夕提出的，并得到了《华盛顿邮报》接触的至少另外两名校董会成员的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杨宇明在致立法者的公开信中表示，猛烈抨击私人议员法案背后的三名立法会议员等人“完全无视大学议员和校友的意见”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中大校董会议员敦促香港立法者推迟修例&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;邓、张宇恩及刘国勋提出的建议，建议将校董会成员由55人减少至34人，但增加外部代表的比例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划，如果获得通过，将意味着外部成员与内部任命的比例将在该机构中占主导地位，而内部任命目前占理事会成员的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案还希望将理事会决定大学校长的投票门槛从三分之二提高到四分之三。该提案还将增加政府选出的成员数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拟议的修正案是在段崇智教授再次被任命为大学副校长直至2026年之前引起争议之后提出的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市建制派阵营的成员指责段崇智同情参与2019年社会骚乱期间抗议的学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;大学三人组猛烈要求支付费用香港私人议员法案草案&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;立法会议员李伟宏在条例草案委员会询问大学校董会是否已妥善讨论有关建议，以及是否应透过私人议员法案改变院校的运作方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大学校董会主席柴逸超教授向立法会表示，大学多年来多次推动校董会重组，支持优化管治、精简架构及加强校董会的运作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示校董会曾于2009年及2016年提出重组建议，但没有送交立法会审议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柴补充说，去年12月的校董会会议批准成立专责小组以重新启动改革计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法案委员会将于下周重新召开会议，届时将检讨法案的细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China and US can still cooperate on climate policy but tech remains tricky, experts say in wake of Kerry visit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3228548/china-and-us-can-still-cooperate-climate-policy-tech-remains-tricky-experts-say-wake-kerry-visit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/c1c22f4c-d88b-4e5b-aab9-5be1e009ef9 9_45cf7c3f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国气候特使约翰·克里周三结束了对中国为期四天的访问，几乎没有取得任何突破，但观察人士表示，虽然中美两国很难在气候技术方面开展合作，但两国仍有可能在政策上进行合作并分享最佳实践。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里在周三的新闻发布会上表示，他与中国官员的会谈“非常富有成效”，并补充说还有更多工作要做。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们来这里是为了开辟新天地，因为我们认为这是至关重要的，”克里说。 “但我们进行了一系列非常广泛的坦诚对话，并意识到需要做更多的工作才能取得新进展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里表示，北京和华盛顿同意共同努力，确保今年晚些时候在迪拜举行的《联合国气候变化框架公约》第二十八次缔约方会议（COP28）取得积极成果，双方同意“在未来几周内密切合作”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了稳定世界关系作为两个最大的温室气体排放国，克里在访问期间会见了一系列中国高级官员，包括中国国家主席解振华、国务院总理李强、国家副主席韩正和高级外交官王毅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;气候变化在美中双边关系中发挥着关键作用，但在美国前众议院议长南希·佩洛西于 2022 年 8 月访问台湾后，两国的气候谈判暂停。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，鉴于中美之间的地缘政治紧张局势不断加剧对于北京和华盛顿来说，他们仍然可以就气候问题进行对话这一事实意义重大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;绿色和平东亚分部驻北京的高级政策分析师李硕表示，两个最大的国家相互对话势在必行。否则，李说，“就这一紧迫问题达成全球解决方案的希望更渺茫”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果两国不能缓和关系，我认为世界其他国家肯定会承担后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们确实需要认识到这些交流的另一个层面，那就是除了美国和中国之外，地球的命运，世界其他国家的命运也受到威胁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国表示愿意与美国合作克里结束访问时谈到气候问题&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;克里在新闻发布会上表示，没有一个国家能够独自赢得应对气候变化的战斗，因为没有一个政府有足够的资金独自推动气候转型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最终，我们必须将私营部门、慈善组织和政府联合起来……我们必须加快新技术的研究和部署。 We must accelerate [developing] what we know works, especially renewable energy,” he was quoted as saying by online news site The Paper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Byford Tsang, a senior policy adviser at the think tank E3G, said although technology cooperation between China and the US would be politically challenging, cooperation on policy or sharing best practices would still be within reach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are talks happening at the international level … that the world should set a global renewable energy target for 2030. That&#39;s something the US and China can work together to see how much they can bring to the target,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsang added that the two countries could also cooperate in supporting developing countries and deploying renewable technologies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, because China dominates the solar photovoltaic (PV) market, as well as other renewable energy industry fields, the US and other countries have deep concerns about supply chain security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some of them have introduced legislation to boost their domestic markets to reduce reliance on China, but experts said it would be difficult for other countries to avoid Chinese supply chains, at least in the near term.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is a global leader in the renewable energy industry. According to the International Energy Agency (IEA), over 80 per cent of solar panel manufacturing capacity is located in China, including the production of polysilicon, ingots, wafers, cells and modules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The IEA also estimates that China produces three-quarters of all lithium-ion batteries and makes 85 per cent of anodes – a key component of batteries. It recommended governments diversify solar PV supply chains to ensure supply security and reduce supply chain vulnerabilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2022, the US enacted the Inflation Reduction Act, which Washington has called its “most aggressive action” to combat climate change and improve its energy security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The legislation provides nearly US$400 billion in federal funding for clean energy with the aim of accelerating America&#39;s low-carbon transformation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was passed after the Biden administration banned imports of solar products from a company in China&#39;s far western region of Xinjiang due to forced labour allegations in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US ban on Xinjiang solar products heaps pressure on supply chains&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Biden administration also imposed trade restrictions on five Chinese companies over allegations of human rights abuses. The Chinese foreign ministry said Washington&#39;s accusations were “nothing but rumours with ulterior motives and downright lies”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US has pledged to cut its greenhouse gas emissions to 50-52 per cent below 2005 levels by 2030. To meet the pledge goals, renewable power generation would have to deliver about half of the country&#39;s electricity by 2030, quadruple the 2021 level, according to an analysis by researchers from the University of Maryland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheng Li, head of the Centre on the Governance of China and the World at the University of Hong Kong, said the United States&#39; low-carbon transformation would be slow and costly if it decoupled from China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Utilising the scale and know-how of Chinese manufacturers will be key to ramping up domestic supply in any industry in which the United States is playing catch-up in the global market,” Li wrote on the website of the Brookings Institution last month. Li formerly headed the Brookings Institution&#39;s John L. Thornton China Centre.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Decision-makers in both countries need to be strategic and bold to set the boundaries of competition and leave room for collaboration to avoid harmful competition that will doom the future of our planet,” Li wrote.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[British man who killed ailing wife by suffocating her, cleared of murder by Cyprus court]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3228547/british-man-who-killed-ailing-wife-suffocation-cleared-murder-cyprus-court?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 21:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/f4609afd-c174-40ee-a30d-11f108e0b867_eaceb742.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Cyprus court on Friday found a British man who killed his ailing wife in their home guilty of manslaughter, saying that the prosecution didn&#39;t prove beyond reasonable doubt that the 76-year-old man committed premeditated murder.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a unanimous decision, the three-judge bench said that David Hunter&#39;s decision to suffocate his 74-year-old wife Janice as she was sitting in a recliner in December 2021 was a spur-of-the-moment decision: he snapped as he could no longer stand seeing her weeping in pain.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court accepted witness testimony that Janice feared her blood ailment would develop into full-blown leukaemia and had repeatedly pleaded with her husband to take her life because she didn&#39;t want to share the fate of her sister who died of the disease.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hunter attempted to take his own life by consuming a large amount of pills after doing something “he never before thought possible – closing his hands over his wife&#39;s mouth and nose,” the court heard, but medical staff saved his life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court cited expert testimony that Janice Hunter suffered from myelodysplastic syndrome, a type of blood cancer which “to a large degree” – as much as 45 per cent – could turn into leukaemia, although there was no proof that she had indeed developed the disease because no definitive tests were conducted.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the court said both husband and wife believed that Janice would develop it because of her sister&#39;s fate.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Assisted suicide pod now legal in Switzerland offers &#39;painless death&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The court also accepted that the actions of David Hunter who “loved his wife and took care of her even under the most difficult circumstances without complaint” were motivated only to end her suffering and that Janice had repeatedly asked him to end her life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;David Hunter&#39;s earlier assurances to Janice that he would help her fulfil her wish to end her life and not suffer any more didn&#39;t indicate any premeditation, the court said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court will reconvene July 27 for mitigation pleas before passing sentence. The decision means Hunter avoids a maximum life sentence that a premeditated murder conviction carries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Michael Polak from Justice Abroad, a group that defends Britons facing legal troubles in foreign countries, said the ruling allows the court to hand down a suspended sentence which would be appropriate given the time that Hunter has already spent in custody.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was detained immediately after his wife&#39;s death, and has spent the intervening year and a half in prison, awaiting trial.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This remains a tragic case. Janice and David were in a loving relationship for over 50 years and it is clear that David did what he did out of love for Janice upon her request,” Polak said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We strongly believe that no proper purpose would be served by David spending any further time within Nicosia prison.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prosecution said Cypriot authorities didn&#39;t want to set a precedent for any husband to kill his wife and claim after the fact and without proof that the killing was done with the wife&#39;s consent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;State prosecutor Andreas Hadjikyrou told reporters the Attorney General would examine the verdict with a view to filing an appeal. He said a key point of scrutiny would be about proof the couple had indeed agreed for David Hunter to take his wife&#39;s life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As indebted governments boost military spending, what about climate change and other pressing needs?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3228393/indebted-governments-boost-military-spending-what-about-climate-change-and-other-pressing-needs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/d8aa5e30-9027-4725-99dc-5fcec3802e56_4d4bbb4b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As Russia&#39;s cynically named “special military operation” in Ukraine grinds ruinously on, the direct toll in lives, dollars and the dislocation of the global food trade continues to mount. The cost of military and humanitarian support to Ukraine, according to the Kiel Institute, had risen to US$185 billion by the end of May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But of even greater concern, the indirect cost runs to trillions, in particular as governments boost defence budgets in the name of national security. For arms producers, their lobbying efforts have rarely been more effortless and rewarding. But few citizens can share their joy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The depressing reality is that every extra dollar spent on defence and the military is a dollar not available for other pressing needs. It means dollars not available to fight climate change or build the renewable energy infrastructure needed to replace fossil fuels and halt global warming.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It means more procrastination across the “rich” world over unkept promises to provide US$100 billion a year in climate finance to developing economies struggling to keep their heads above water – sometimes literally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It means dollars not available to rebuild healthcare after Covid-19, and protect us against the next pandemic. It is a major contributor to the big squeeze on government budgets across the world, with few political leaders clear on where new funds for defence will come from, and where spending will have to be cut. The challenges are made worse by the surge in inflation, which has sent debt-service costs soaring.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the first to boost military spending after Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine was Germany, with Chancellor Olaf Scholz promising a €100 billion (US$112 billion) increase (over an unclear timeframe) in his speech about a Zeitenwende, or start of a new era. Since then, many European countries have followed, pledging increases in defence spending to levels not seen since the Cold War.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most promise to lift their military budgets to at least 2 per cent of their gross domestic product. What used to be Nato&#39;s target for military spending – historically ignored by most members – is becoming a spending floor. Defence spending increases in Europe recorded last year by the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI) were already significant – 13 per cent in Belgium, 12 per cent in the Netherlands and Sweden, and 11 per cent in Poland, for example.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Few European governments making clear where these extra funds will come from, but the 2 per cent of GDP measure is likely to be a firm target. In France, President Emmanuel Macron has just committed to a 40 per cent boost in military spending to €413 billion (US$460 billion) over the budget period from 2024 to 2030, with critics mocking him for building “a bonsai army” – with a range of capabilities but on a tiny scale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How Macron and other European leaders finesse these commitments against massive government debt and huge political pressure over spending cuts (note France&#39;s street riots over efforts to cut spending on pensions) remains unclear.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ukraine, admittedly in a category of its own, saw military spending rise by 640 per cent last year to US$44 billion, obviously with no idea how to meet the ultimate cost of the war and rebuilding.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Outside Europe, and only partly driven by the Ukraine war, both Japan and Australia have committed to big increases in defence spending. In Japan, the Kishida government plans to lift defence spending from 1.1 per cent of its GDP to 2 per cent by 2027 – an increase of about US$36 billion a year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Australian government, which is committed under the Aukus agreement to expand its military reach across Asia, will have to do so “unsupported by any additional funds for the next four years” due to a tight budget, according to the Australian Strategic Policy Institute. But from 2027, defence funding will begin rising: from 8.2 per cent of government spending today to 9.7 per cent in 2032.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With A$9 billion (US$6 billion) needed for new nuclear submarines, A$3.8 billion to strengthen its northern military bases, A$2.5 billion to develop long-range strike capability and A$924 million for “enhancing Pacific engagement”, the boost in military spending is likely to be permanent, and will come at a cost to other services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The biggest single diversion of funding will, of course, come in the United States, whose military spending at US$877 billion last year dwarfed every other country&#39;s. It accounted for 39 per cent of military spending worldwide, 12 per cent of US federal spending, and almost half of the US government&#39;s discretionary spending.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Notwithstanding this huge commitment, the US has been the biggest single supporter of Ukraine (US$19.9 billion last year), and the US Defence Department is pressing for an extra US$30 billion for munitions and US$315 billion for new weapons. With the US political obsession over “national security” only likely to grow in the run-up to the presidential elections next year, there is little doubt these demands for additional funding will be met.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Where the needed funds will come from is another matter: national debt sits at an eye-watering US$32 trillion, and Republicans and Democrats are at loggerheads over where spending can be cut to make additional defence spending possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reviewing this global picture of a seemingly irresistible and long-term pressure for large increases in defence spending that is likely to amount to hundreds of billions of dollars a year, only one set of conclusions is clear. Government debts are set to continue rising, funds for all other pressing needs are in jeopardy and rich-country promises to help developing countries in the challenging decade ahead are cynically hollow. Germany&#39;s Scholz is right to talk of a Zeitenwende.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China ups food security drive as Xi Jinping calls ‘farmland the lifeblood of food production’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3228526/china-ups-food-security-drive-xi-jinping-calls-farmland-lifeblood-food-production?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/97aef899-52f2-465c-afc5-0fd8bb4de678_123c96e8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s top officials have vowed to strengthen farmland protection and make better use of its large areas of salty soil as part of Beijing&#39;s food security drive amid frequent climate shocks and an uncertain global market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reclaiming new farmland and improving its quality was top of the agenda at a meeting chaired by President Xi Jinping on Thursday, according to the state-backed Xinhua News Agency, as concerns over self-sufficiency in feeding the 1.4 billion population mount.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Targeting “non-traditional farmland”, including saline and alkali soil, in its farmland reclamation campaign, China needs to “steadily expand the space for agricultural production”, Xi told the meeting of the Central Financial and Economic Affairs Commission.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The discussion came before warnings from agricultural officials on Friday that China&#39;s autumn harvest is facing “extremely severe challenges” from expected extreme climate events after the first drop in summer production since 2018 occurred earlier this year due to bad weather.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Droughts and floods are expected to hit parts of the country simultaneously, while disease and insects are increasingly problematic, officials from the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since the beginning of the year, the weather in our country has indeed shown obviously abnormal features,” said Pan Wenbo, head of the ministry&#39;s crop production department.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We encountered rare rain before harvest in the Yellow River and Huai River areas, and there have been record high temperatures in the north since the start of summer.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of Beijing&#39;s major approaches to tackle the risks is to increase sowing acreage, which requires ample arable land.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Farmland is the lifeblood of food production,” Xi said at Thursday&#39;s meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite reversing a declining trend in the size of arable land in the past two years, the “task of protecting farmland hasn&#39;t become lighter, but heavier instead”, Xi added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s annual grain output has remained above 650 million tonnes for eight consecutive years until 2022 amid its strong emphasis on food security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing is aiming to at least maintain the level and raise it to 700 million tonnes by 2025, according to the central government&#39;s five-year plan for agriculture released last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As the mercury rises, will climate change impact energy, trade and agriculture?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But this year&#39;s outlook is overshadowed by a 0.9 per cent drop in summer yields, mainly caused by prolonged rain that battered mature wheat in its top-growing province of Henan before the harvest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, China still has sufficient grain stocks, added Pan, with rice and wheat reserves at “relatively high levels”, which can support an entire year&#39;s consumption.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has invested in utilising less suitable land in recent years to expand total acreage, including soil harmed by soluble salt or clay soil with a high pH level, known as saline and alkali soil.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Salty soil, no problem. China hails record rapeseed output in food security push&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China has over 33 million hectares (81.5 million acres) of usable saline and alkali soil, with around a third potentially suitable for farming, according to figures widely quoted by officials and state media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Researchers have developed over 40 technologies to treat saline and alkali soil and more than 50 salt-tolerant crop species, CCTV reported in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, a national institution to study the improvement and utilisation of saline and alkali land was also founded in Shandong province, with the aim to breed 80 new crop species within three years.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: Dutch chip equipment giant ASML buoyed by Chinese demand ahead of new export curbs]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3228531/tech-war-dutch-chip-equipment-giant-asml-buoyed-chinese-demand-ahead-new-export-curbs?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/a763848e-df59-4f7d-96b3-4b0555cbd568_ab2eee55.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;ASML Holding defied a slump in the semiconductor industry and boosted its full-year sales outlook on strong demand from Chinese customers, ahead of restrictions that could further impede China&#39;s access to the company&#39;s advanced technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The semiconductor equipment maker raised its guidance for net sales growth in 2023 to around 30 per cent after revenue came in above expectations, with China representing 24 per cent of shipments made in the second quarter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While deliveries of ASML&#39;s advanced extreme ultraviolet (EUV) lithography machines to the US and Taiwan have slowed because of poor macroeconomic conditions and a lack of skilled workers to get new facilities up and running, the company has found overwhelming demand for its older products in mainland China, according to ASML CEO Peter Wennink.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ASML has only been able to fulfil less than 50 per cent of equipment demand for its more mature technology in China over the past two years, but that is changing, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Anything that doesn&#39;t ship to another country goes to China, but there&#39;s still some demand that will move into 2024 because we still don&#39;t have a 100 per cent fill rate today,” Wennink said in an investor call on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under US pressure, the company currently does not sell its EUV lithography systems to China, but it continues to ship its less advanced deep ultraviolet (DUV) systems to clients in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our Chinese customers say: &#39;We are happy to take the machines that others don&#39;t want&#39;, because their fabs are ready and they can take the tools that become available,” Wennick said in a video interview released by the company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese semiconductor manufacturers have been scrambling to stockpile chip-making equipment, the Post reported in February, after the US, Japan and the Netherlands agreed to coordinate export restrictions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From September, ASML will be required by Dutch authorities to apply for a licence to ship its higher-end DUV systems, such as the Twinscan NXT: 2000i, which can be deployed to produce advanced 7-nanometre and 5-nm chips. US-led export curbs, however, have held back China&#39;s goal to produce chips of this size.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has condemned Washington for “coercing” allies into imposing a technological blockade on China and “undermining market rules and international trade”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wennick said he expects the new rules to have negligible implications for the company, as rising geopolitical tensions and global demand for mature chips are set to sustain Chinese equipment purchases from ASML.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Albie Amankona, analyst at research firm Third Bridge, agreed that the Dutch export controls will have a limited impact on ASML&#39;s sales target. “The demand for both EUV and DUV machines is expected to exceed supply for the next few years,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Still, Amankona cautioned that ASML is “missing out on a promising growth market, as the Chinese government heavily invests in the semiconductor industry”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wennink said ASML is monitoring reports that the US is seeking to extend restrictions on advanced semiconductor technology shipments to China, but he expects any potential additional US measures to have no material impact on the company&#39;s financial outlook for the year.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fukushima row: Hong Kong’s Japanese seafood ban ‘necessary’ if waste water discharge goes ahead, John Lee tells country’s envoy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3228540/fukushima-row-hong-kongs-japanese-seafood-ban-necessary-if-waste-water-discharge-goes-ahead-john-lee?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.21 20:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/21/0f6e0929-768d-42fb-b248-317de0234165_acf9fb46.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A prospective ban on seafood from 10 Japanese prefectures was a “necessary” step to guard against health risks if a controversial plan to dispose of nuclear waste water went ahead, Hong Kong&#39;s leader told the country&#39;s top diplomat in the city on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The warning was issued at a closed-door meeting between Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu and consul-general Okada Kenichi to discuss Japan&#39;s scheme to release treated waste water from the Fukushima power plant into the Pacific Ocean from as early as August.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the exchange requested by Kenichi, Lee said the “unprecedented” plan to dispose of a large amount of nuclear waste water over 30 years would cause “unavoidable risks to food safety and the environment”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;No compensation for Hong Kong eateries over Japanese seafood ban: environment chief&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Tokyo has maintained the treated waste water is safe after undergoing a filtration system used to remove radioactive materials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Should the Japanese side insist on proceeding with the discharge, the [Hong Kong government] must put in place measures with the view to protect food safety and safeguard the health of citizens in Hong Kong,” Lee said. “ Such measures are essential and necessary.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;City authorities said they were open to discussing the situation further with the Japanese government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong earlier warned it would ban the import of all aquatic products from 10 prefectures – Tokyo, Fukushima, Chiba, Tochigi, Ibaraki, Gunma, Miyagi, Niigata, Nagano and Saitama – over safety concerns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They will also require five prefectures – Fukushima, Chiba, Gunma, Ibaraki and Tochigi – to provide radiation certificates for other types of food exports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official figures showed that major food imports from Japan last year amounted to about 2 per cent of Hong Kong&#39;s total food supply, with 6.75 per cent of all seafood consumed locally coming from the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some experts have raised concerns about the proposal&#39;s rationale as it included four landlocked prefectures, while a Japanese official has accused Hong Kong of “trying to win brownie points from Beijing” with its tough stance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mainland Chinese authorities earlier this month said they would continue to ban imports from 10 Japanese prefectures, including Fukushima, while all shipments from other parts of the country would have to undergo full screening instead of spot checks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Figures from Japan&#39;s Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries showed the mainland market accounted for 19.6 per cent of all seafood exports from the former in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s ban on Japanese seafood imports: an overreaction or science-based move?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s foreign ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning on Thursday reiterated its opposition to Japan&#39;s discharge plan and urged Tokyo to “listen to the international community” and “undertake serious international control”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s proposed ban has also prompted concerns from some Japanese restaurants. Catering industry leaders said they expected 30 per cent of such eateries to shut down because of the measure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Environment and Ecology Tse Chin-wan last week said any restaurateurs who suffered a drop in business due to the ban would not receive compensation from the government.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 21 Jul 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>