<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[UN refuses to retract its condemnation of Israel over Jenin military operation]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3227044/un-refuses-retract-its-condemnation-israel-over-jenin-military-operation?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 01:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/32f0797c-e404-41eb-9c94-a1da57baf55b_2da5ca72.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;以色列驻联合国大使呼吁秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯撤回对该国的谴责联合国副发言人法尔汉·哈克 (Farhan Haq) 表示，秘书长周四表达了他的观点，“他支持这些观点”，这是二十年来最大规模的针对约旦河西岸难民营的军事行动。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古特雷斯对以色列空袭和袭击杰宁难民营的影响感到愤怒，他表示，这次行动导致 100 多名平民受伤，数千名居民被迫迁离，学校和医院受损，并扰乱了秩序。水电网络。他还批评以色列阻止伤者获得医疗护理，阻止人道主义工作人员接触到每个需要帮助的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列旨在镇压巴勒斯坦武装分子的为期两天的攻势摧毁了杰宁难民营狭窄的道路和小巷，迫使数千人逃离家园，并杀害了 12 名巴勒斯坦人。一名以色列士兵也被杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古特雷斯对记者表示：“我强烈谴责所有针对平民的暴力行为，包括恐怖行为。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被问及这种谴责是否适用于以色列时，他回答说：“这适用于所有过度使用武力的情况，显然在这种情况下，以色列军队过度使用了武力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列驻联合国大使吉拉德·埃尔丹称联合国秘书长的言论“可耻，牵强附会，完全脱离现实。”他说，以色列在杰宁的军事行动“只是为了打击针对无辜以色列平民的凶残的巴勒斯坦恐怖分子。”联合国发言人哈克表示，古特雷斯“明确谴责所有影响以色列的暴力行为”。以色列和被占领巴勒斯坦领土上的平民，无论肇事者是谁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;以色列军队结束了多年来最大规模的西岸攻势&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;联合国安理会讨论了以色列在应阿拉伯联合酋长国的要求，杰宁于周五闭门举行会议，并听取了助理秘书长哈立德·希亚里的简报。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃尔丹在安理会会议前致信 15 名安理会成员和古特雷斯，表示过去一年，52名以色列人被巴勒斯坦人杀害，多起袭击事件是从杰宁或该地区发生的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国际社会和安理会必须无条件谴责最近发生的巴勒斯坦恐怖袭击事件，并遏制巴勒斯坦人的行为。”领导层负有责任，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安理会没有采取任何行动。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Suspended Twitter account tracking Elon Musk’s jet moves to rival Meta’s Threads]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/article/3227043/suspended-twitter-account-tracking-elon-musks-jet-moves-rival-metas-threads?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.09 00:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/09/ff7717b7-760d-4412-8474-877168c30cd3_c9df1ab4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Jack Sweeney，实时跟踪埃隆·马斯克私人飞机的帐户的创建者，去年被 Twitter 暂停后，现已转向马克·扎克伯格的 Twitter 竞争对手 Threads。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ElonJet 已登陆 Threads！”阅读 Sweeney 周四通过账户@elonmusksjet 发布的第一篇帖子，截至周六上午，该账户拥有超过 21,000 名关注者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ElonJet 使用公共领域的数据跟踪了马斯克私人飞机的动态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;随着竞争对手 Threads 的崛起，Twitter 威胁要起诉 Meta&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;去年 12 月，马斯克旗下的 Twitter 暂停了 ElonJet 帐户，这位亿万富翁在表示他的儿子被“疯狂跟踪者”错误地跟踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meta 拥有的 Threads 对 Twitter 构成了直接挑战，在数小时内吸引了数百万用户，其中包括金·卡戴珊 (Kim Kardashian)、詹妮弗·洛佩兹 (Jennifer Lopez) 和美国民主党众议员等知名人物亚历山大·奥卡西奥-科尔特斯 (Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez)，在马斯克做出一系列混乱的决定后，该公司试图利用竞争对手的弱势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sweeney、Twitter 和 Meta 没有立即回应路透社的置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sweeney、Twitter 和 Meta 没有立即回应路透社的置评请求。 p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Free Hong Kong harbourside concerts start with splash, but some say floating stage too far away]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3227040/free-hong-kong-harbourside-concerts-start-splash-some-say-floating-stage-too-far-away?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 23:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/3c6353b0-d213-461d-9acb-22be3298f853_0031056f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周六晚上，数千名音乐爱好者聚集在香港湾仔海滨，欣赏耗资 4,000 万港元的 Harbour Chill Carnival 拉开了帷幕，这是政府为振兴这座城市而组织的为期五个周末的计划的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，由于舞台搭建在离岸驳船上，所以只有站着的人前排可以看到表演者和数十名歌迷爬上栏杆，以便清楚地观看音乐会，音乐会由粤语流行歌手陈慧琳拉开序幕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Becca Shi，23 岁来自深圳的一位四岁游客前往这座城市观看她的偶像陈的表演。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在小红书（类似 Instagram 的社交媒体平台）上了解到此次活动后，尝试在线预订门票&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过她表示，有朋友成功拿到了两张门票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这里氛围很好，充满激情和活力。陈凯莉是我童年的一部分，”她解释道。 “但舞台离看台真的很远。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;40多岁的香港居民曾美仪(Bee Tsang)与朋友一起观看了演唱会，他表示这次经历很令人失望，他想抵达后不久就离开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港自称为国际城市，却举办如此高质量的音乐会，真是太遗憾了，”从事金融工作的曾先生说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们不得不在炎热的天气里走很长一段路才能到达这个区域......而且我们几乎看不到舞台，驳船低于视线水平。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾表示组织者应该选择中环海滨或其他设施齐全的政府运营场地举办音乐会。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港歌迷在几分钟内抢购 14,000 张 Harbour Chill Carnival 免费门票&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;10 场免费音乐会中的第一场从周六开始的五个周末，城市女子组合 Lolly Talk 和男子组合 Nowhere Boys 也亮相。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港歌手陈柏宇和台湾歌手 Hush 也参加了活动的后半场。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;音乐会开始前大约半小时，音乐会观众聚集在海滨音乐会区，一些人举着霓虹灯牌以示对偶像的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前两个音乐会周末的 14,000 张免费门票7月8日至9日和15日至16日，上周二半小时内就被抢购一空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;买不到票的人仍然可以在湾仔码头旁边的大屏幕上观看演出，现场直播-直播了整个活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数百人聚集在屏幕区域观看表演，并享用嘉年华设立的六个小吃摊的小吃和饮料。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港人受邀与泰森一起放松耀西在价值4,000万港元的海港嘉年华上表演&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;码头旁还举行了街头表演，包括杂技、舞蹈、X-game、滑板和功夫艺术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港精英滑板手陆俊贤是码头的表演者之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这里表演感觉很棒。这是一次难得的在繁忙的市中心玩滑板、与公众接触的机会。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次活动也让我能够与海外运动员交流，进一步弘扬滑板文化。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;由香港旅游发展局主办的嘉年华系列将在接下来的四个周末，从金紫荆广场到红磡海底隧道，于星期日及星期六及星期日继续举行，并承诺会有更多精彩活动。&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong students from across border expected to fill spots at city’s semi-private schools, as enrolment rate hits 16-year low]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3227035/hong-kong-students-across-border-expected-fill-spots-citys-semi-private-schools-enrolment-rate-hits?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 22:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/1e2581a4-70c6-46fa-b899-fbf50648948f_56cbf31b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在中国大陆的香港学生预计将填补该市半校的名额一位行业领导者表示，在直接补贴计划 (DSS) 覆盖的机构入学率达到 2007 年以来的最低点后，私立学校的入学率下降了。媒体平台向家长和学生展示如何进入该市的一些顶尖学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 9 月的政府统计显示，该计划覆盖的 59 所中学有 43,892 名学生入学，这让机构拥有更多自由与其他政府资助的学校相比，他们可以选择课程、费用和入学标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些学校被认为是该市中等收入家庭的热门选择，旨在为孩子提供出国留学的机会，因为院校可以提供非本地课程，例如国际文凭课程和英国 GCE A-level 课程。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港学校被告知将中一班级的“上门”名额减半&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;一份入学统计报告称，此类学校的入学率创16年来新低，且连续三年下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021-2022学年半私立学校的入学率为44,636 名学生，较上年的 45,586 名有所下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港直接资助计划学校议会主席陈志安周六表示，学校的部分名额已被内地学生填补随着二月份跨境旅行限制的放松。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们看到今年内地学生向学校申请的数量明显增加，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;身兼英华书院校长的陈先生补充说，退学的学生人数从上学年的“几十人”下降到本学年的“十人左右”。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;他说，一些离开的学生已经移民到其他国家或转学到国际学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;资助中学议会主席李宜英表示，该组织一些最受欢迎的院校边境重新开放后，也收到了不少内地学生的申请。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但他们是生活在内地的香港学生，所以他们都有资格到香港公立学校读书。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李补充说，政府在12月推出的顶尖人才通行证计划也为资助学校引进了另一批学生，但指出目前数量未知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;政府在今年 9 月完成下一次人数统计后，预计来自内地的学生涌入程度将在明年的报告中披露。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港学校因移民而减少 33,600 人，但官员仍保留乐观&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;类似 Instagram 的中国社交电子商务平台小红书上的个人资料正在分享学生如何准备香港公立和私立校园（从幼儿园到中学）面试的技巧。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;平台上的一些教育中介还提供“一站式”服务，帮助家长从头开始报名学校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帖子中包含学费、申请期限等详细信息&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港私立学校面临倒闭，首推移民潮为原因&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“直资学校的教育资源香港的国际学校的教学质量远远优于大多数政府资助的学校，而且学费也低于香港的国际学校。因此，他们是很多新移民家长心中的热门选择。”一位中介写道，他声称已帮助超过1000名家长进入该市名校。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一则帖子列出了涵盖的10所学校该计划适合“内地新移民”，并补充说：“如果父母成为城市居民，让孩子进入香港学校并不困难。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine vows it will not use cluster munitions in Russia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3227036/ukraine-vows-it-will-not-use-cluster-munitions-russia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 22:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/0f6205b3-8407-4de6-a637-87bb74a3b69d_c503223c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;乌克兰国防部长奥莱克西·雷兹尼科夫 (Oleksii Reznikov) 对美国向基辅运送集束炸弹的决定表示欢迎，他说它将有助于解放乌克兰领土，但承诺这些弹药不会在俄罗斯使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国周五宣布，将向乌克兰提供广泛禁止的集束弹药，以用于对俄罗斯占领军的反攻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国周五宣布，将向乌克兰提供广泛禁止的集束弹药。 >;&lt;p>;雷兹尼科夫表示，这些弹药将有助于拯救乌克兰士兵的生命，并补充说乌克兰将严格记录其使用情况并与合作伙伴交换信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国将向乌克兰发送集束弹药，吸引来自人权组织的批评&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们的立场很简单——我们需要解放我们暂时占领的领土并拯救我们人民的生命，”雷兹尼科夫在推特上写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“乌克兰将使用这些弹药只是为了解除对我们国际公认领土的占领。这些弹药不会在俄罗斯官方承认的领土上使用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;100多个国家禁止使用集束弹药。它们通常会释放大量较小的炸弹，可以在大范围内不分青红皂白地造成杀伤。那些未能爆炸的会造成数十年的危险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫斯科周六再次批评美国的决定，称其为华盛顿“反俄罗斯”方针的又一个“令人震惊”的例子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p外交部发言人玛丽亚表示：“华盛顿和基辅在不考虑其严重后果的情况下指望另一件‘神奇武器’，它不会以任何方式影响特别军事行动的进程，特别军事行动的目的和目标将得到充分实现”扎哈罗娃在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登的国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文周五寻求向乌克兰提供武器，以收回自俄罗斯 2022 年 2 月入侵以来夺取的领土。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我们认识到集束弹药会造成未爆炸弹药造成平民伤害的风险，”沙利文告诉记者。 “但是，由于乌克兰没有足够的火炮，如果俄罗斯军队和坦克越过乌克兰阵地并占领更多乌克兰领土并征服更多乌克兰平民，也存在造成平民伤害的巨大风险，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雷兹尼科夫表示军队不会在城市地区使用集束弹药，只会使用它们“突破敌人的防线”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯、乌克兰和美国尚未签署《集束弹药公约》，该公约禁止生产、储存、使用和转让武器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公约签署国西班牙表示反对这一决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“西班牙基于坚定的承诺西班牙国防部长玛格丽塔·罗伯斯周六在马德里集会上对记者表示：“英国与乌克兰有坚定的承诺，即在任何情况下都不能运送某些武器和炸弹。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国也是该协议的签署国。总理里什·苏纳克 (Rishi Sunak) 表示，该公约禁止生产或使用集束弹药并阻止其使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将继续尽自己的一份力量，支持乌克兰抵御俄罗斯的非法无端入侵，”他告诉记者周六记者。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese-led Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank says it found no evidence it is dominated by Communist Party]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227034/chinese-led-asian-infrastructure-investment-bank-says-it-found-no-evidence-it-dominated-communist?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 22:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/44409012-5067-4c1e-a9b6-55efadee2b09_357c9d5a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国主导的亚洲基础设施投资银行（AIIB）表示尚未发现任何证据在前通讯主管高调辞职后，共产党的影响力受到了影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该银行周五表示，在加拿大国民鲍勃·皮卡德公开辞职后，该银行立即启动了审查，称该银行“此次审查于 6 月 15 日至 26 日期间进行，由亚投行总法律顾问、巴西公民阿尔贝托·尼尼奥 (Alberto Ninio) 领导。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;Ninio 表示，审查发现“没有证据支持或验证”指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该银行表示，在“全面审查文件材料”和 30 多项文件后，皮卡德的指控“不正确且未经证实”。采访了包括银行行长、高级管理层和员工在内的高级职位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它表示，没有证据表明“来自任何国家的任何政党的工作人员”干扰了绩效，而且从来没有任何关于政治影响决策的指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但皮卡德驳斥了这项审查，称其为“笑话”，并将其与“袋鼠法庭”进行比较。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;加拿大立法者否认他的报道。该银行于 2016 年在北京成立，为铁路和其他基础设施项目提供融资，有时被描述为美国领导的世界银行和亚洲开发银行的中国替代品。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是亚投行最大的捐助国，拥有约26.5%的投票权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚投行有106个成员，其中包括大多数亚洲国家以及加拿大、俄罗斯、法国和英国。不过，日本和美国不是成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该银行表示，此次审查是由 10 名员工组成的“跨国且性别平衡”小组进行的，并就加强领导层招聘流程提出了建议&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中包括“强制性的全面背景调查、至少对最近五个组织的背景调查，包括领导力概况评估，以及改善”员工申诉机制的运作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;皮卡德告诉《华盛顿邮报》：“他们仍然认为我的指控毫无根据，现在他们发表了一份垃圾报告，充其量是一堆不光彩的谎言和半真半假的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[亚投行]用低品格的调查结果来贬低我，比如说他们会改善未来招聘的背景调查，就好像我看到他们的真实面目有问题一样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还坚持自己的指控，即银行该行行长金立群曾担任中国财政部副部长，并在其 31 名高层中总共担任过 8 名。领导职务由中国公民担任，其中包括五名曾在财政部工作过的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们负责监督组织内的重要运作，包括政策、预算以及主权和非主权贷款。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;在回答有关审查的问题时，亚投行表示“透明度对于我们 106 个成员、我们的多边同行、我们的发展伙伴、我们的民间社会组织以及我们所服务的公民的信任至关重要。”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;皮卡德的辞职引发了加拿大和中国之间的争吵，驻渥太华大使馆表示这些指控“纯粹是耸人听闻的炒作和彻头彻尾的谎言。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京外交部表示，该银行遵守“在招聘和管理员工时遵循“公开、精英和透明的原则”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但加拿大副总理兼财政部长克里斯蒂亚·弗里兰表示，该国将停止亚投行所有“政府主导的活动”，并已开始审查&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于共产党的指控，加拿大停止了亚投行“政府主导的活动”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;加拿大外交部尚未回应对该报告发表评论的请求。亚投行在回应有关皮卡德批评的问题时表示，该审查是“基于证据的”，并且维护了“多边治理的最高标准”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该审查还表示，“没有证据”表明这一点皮卡德要求亚投行保护他在职期间的安全，或防止他的安全受到任何威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但皮卡德表示，在与加拿大政府和警方沟通后，已决定尽快离开中国，甚至已他留下了钱包和大部分财产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示，他曾与迈克尔·斯帕弗(Michael Spavor)进行过交谈，迈克尔·斯帕弗在华为高管孟晚舟及其同胞迈克尔·康明凯(Michael Kovrig)被捕后因间谍罪名被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我就我的担忧咨询了政府。我们加拿大人对迈克尔两人的残暴绑架事件深受影响。我不想留下来寻找答案，”皮卡德补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US-China relations: Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen says close cooperation vital for economy and to fight ‘existential threat’ of climate change]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3227032/us-china-relations-treasury-secretary-janet-yellen-says-close-cooperation-vital-economy-and-fight?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 21:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/08/aecca999-e700-493b-b38d-edab1122d101_f7fdf21a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;来访的财长耶伦强调美中需要保持沟通周六，合作应对气候变化的“生存威胁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦在北京钓鱼台国宾馆发表讲话时告诉中国副总理何立峰，两国在出现问题时应“直接”互动&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她表示，他们必须继续对话以避免误解，并“帮助双方更全面地了解全球经济前景，并做出更好的决策来加强我们的经济”。&lt;/p>;&lt;去年双边贸易额达 6900 亿美元，耶伦表示：“尽管近期局势紧张，但我们在 2022 年创下了双边贸易纪录，这表明我们的企业有足够的空间参与贸易和投资。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她强调，华盛顿并不是采取赢家通吃的做法，也不是寻求对中国的经济优势，而是希望通过“公平的规则”确保良性竞争，使双方都受益。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他回应说，北京对去年 11 月乔·拜登总统与习近平会晤后发生的“意外事件”破坏了改善中美关系的努力表示遗憾。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;美国财长耶伦访华有何期待&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“两国元首共识的落实存在一些问题，”他表示，但没有进一步详细说明。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二月份，美国军方击落了一个所谓的间谍气球，国务卿安东尼·布林肯取消了对中国的访问计划。这次访问最终于上个月进行，五角大楼上周表示气球没有收集到任何信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶伦将在中国度过四天，作为双方努力修复紧张关系的一部分。在周五与李强总理会面时，耶伦表示，她希望她的中国之行能够“促进更多正常的沟通渠道”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六早些时候，耶伦在与中国和国际气候专家交谈时表示，世界气候变化正在发生变化。两个最大的经济体必须共同努力应对全球变暖，并补充说，之前的合作，例如 2015 年《巴黎协定》，使全球突破成为可能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为世界上两个最大的温室气体排放国和最大的投资者在可再生能源领域，我们有共同的责任和能力来引领潮流，”耶伦说道，并补充说气候变化是“全球挑战的首要问题”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国政府都希望她说，支持新兴市场和发展中国家努力实现气候目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还要求北京支持绿色气候基金和气候投资基金等多边气候机构，以实现“更大的气候变化”。 ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到2022年，中国的碳排放量占全球总量的32%，其次是美国的14%和印度的8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但根据气候观察的最新数据，就人均排放量而言，中国的排放量约为美国的一半，使其成为第28大污染国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方之间的气候谈判是去年，美国前众议院议长南希·佩洛西访问台湾后暂停，北京认为台湾严重侵犯了其主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但联合努力可能很快就会恢复，拜登的气候特使约翰·克里 (John Kerry) 计划在作为间谍门事件后重新交流的一部分，我将在不久的将来访问中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了布林肯上个月的访问之外，中国商务部长王文涛于 2017 年在华盛顿会见了美国商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多 (Gina Raimondo)。梅和外交政策负责人王毅在维也纳会见了国家安全顾问杰克·沙利文。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国瞄准东盟伙伴关系，以“反击”中国在南海的行动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;观察人士表示，距离下一次美国大选还有不到 18 个月的时间，总统乔·拜登 (JoeBiden) 取消了其官员为稳定关系所做的一些努力，包括他最近将习近平描述为“独裁者”的言论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，拜登告诉美国有线电视新闻网，鉴于中国对西方投资的依赖，在中国领导人三月份访问弗拉基米尔·普京后，他曾警告习近平不要进一步发展与俄罗斯的经济关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登表示，他已告诉中国领导人：“你已经告诉我，你们的经济依赖于欧洲和美国的投资，要小心，要小心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社和法新社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 21:50:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How China’s K-pop fans skirt ban on South Korean content in strained political landscape]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3226879/how-chinas-k-pop-fans-skirt-ban-south-korean-content-strained-political-landscape?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/07/4f8154d4-588d-466a-b8ef-0d114bec6f72_d57a0e2c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国的韩流粉丝找到了应对北京事实上的禁令的新方法韩国内容，尽管两国关系之间的裂痕不断扩大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自禁令开始放松两年以来，粉丝们不断想出创造性的方法来放纵自己的激情，同时也努力让他们的偶像得到中国社会的认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对韩国娱乐业的限制，包括禁止韩国流行偶像进入中国电视节目，是在 2017 年首次引发的，当时首尔安装了美国-在星州县北部制造了末段高空区域防御系统（萨德）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首尔表示，需要该系统来阻止来自平壤的威胁，而北京则将其视为安全风险，声称该系统可用于监视军事活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然北京从未正式承认该禁令，但韩国艺术家和电视剧已停播多年。中央广播电视总台与韩国广播公司于 2021 年达成的协议标志着未明文限制的放松，从那时起，尽管电视上仍无法播放这些节目，但韩国流行偶像，例如少女时代的郑秀妍和韩国广播公司的刘采洁， (x)——两人都拥有美国公民身份——在中国取得了主流成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使去年8月宣布扩大萨德系统后双边关系跌至低点，中国粉丝表示他们并没有在继续他们的活动过程中遇到了很多困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;23 岁的新疆人迈拉·曹瑞阳 (Myra Cao Ruiyang) 是一名长达十年的韩国流行音乐爱好者，她表示粉丝俱乐部帮助会员避免了购买专辑和商品时遇到的潜在困难。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果偶像拥有大量粉丝，他们的粉丝俱乐部会提供团购服务，这意味着专辑在海外批量购买，然后运到中国，”曹说。 “无论如何，都有办法购买它们，即使可能不方便。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，官方网上商店此后已重新向中国粉丝开放，有些甚至可以通过中国支付应用程序付款。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然曹以其他方式经历了首尔与北京关系的低谷，例如看到中国公司在 2017 年抵制韩国零售商乐天，但她表示韩国流行音乐粉丝并未受到重大影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我认为即使在禁令之下，每个人都知道如何仍然访问和享受他们偶像的内容，”她说。 “唯一的区别是韩国明星不能出现在中国官方频道……但现在没有人真正看电视，所以没有太大影响，粉丝们仍然很热情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于曹来说和她的朋友们，真正影响他们支持的是反华情绪或来自韩国艺术家或作品的文化不敏感材料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一般来说，如果[争议]涉及针对中国的侮辱性言论，并且一旦艺术家“他们关注的是侮辱中国的事件，他们将停止在他们身上花钱。”曹说，并补充说，她和她的朋友随后会卖掉他们拥有的商品，转而关注其他艺术家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近流行的韩剧《欢迎来到威基基 2》就引发了这样的争议。该剧因让一个无家可归的角色穿着又脏又破的北京奥运会夹克而受到中国互联网用户的批评。鉴于中国主办全球体育赛事的文化和政治意义，许多人认为此举是对中国的蓄意攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，尽管不尊重的言论受到谴责，但明星的积极言论却受到了赞扬香港教育大学文学与文化研究助理教授周鹭鹭表示，韩流粉丝在双边关系恶化的情况下帮助支持自己的偶像。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“明显的趋势受到这些限制的原因是，中国大陆的粉丝在表达对偶像的支持方面变得相对低调，尤其是与中国明星的粉丝相比。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但周也表示，一些粉丝会故意突出一些例子当艺术家表现出对中国文化的尊重，以帮助保护他们免受反华指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;王毅指责美国加剧中日韩之间的紧张关系&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;她指出，荣格的粉丝在社交媒体上大肆宣传她使用的“中国新年”一词，而不是“农历新年”，希望公众将她视为中国文化的盟友。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“Her fans would also encourage each other to avoid mentioning her too much on some public platforms, thinking that if she had too much of a presence on Chinese social media, fans of domestic artists would feel agitated,” Zhou said, adding that K-pop fans had made some of their activities more subtle after the ban.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shenzhen resident Grace Wang, a fan of nine-member girl group Twice, said merchandise was actually more accessible in China compared with the United States, where she studies, due to her hometown&#39;s geographical proximity to South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Albums and photocards are much cheaper in China, and it is easier to purchase merchandise here since shipping from South Korea and Japan is pretty convenient,” Wang said. She collects Twice&#39;s photos and albums, and pays for a subscription on Bubble, a platform for artist-to-fan communications.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Changes in the relationship between Seoul and Beijing have not impeded the 18-year-old, with her sense of national identity not affecting the entertainment she consumes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think we have a moral obligation to feel collective national pride – I personally don&#39;t feel it strongly – but those who do feel that should be respected and have the right to express that, and other people should understand,” Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that an idol&#39;s political views did not affect her own feelings towards them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When a performer at the opening ceremony of the Beijing Winter Olympics wore the hanbok, a traditional Korean dress, K-pop singer Chungha was accused of taking a jab at the fashion choice, saying on a live broadcast: “Please keep that in mind. It is our traditional clothing, hanbok.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The performance featured representatives from each of China&#39;s 56 ethnic groups carrying the national flag, and Joseonjok, or Chinese Korean, is the country&#39;s 13th largest minority group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I understand people who can&#39;t tolerate idols speaking against their own country, but I don&#39;t really care about this,” Wang said. “When I pay for idols&#39; products and merchandise, I don&#39;t see their personal political views as being part of the package.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite government policies reducing the exposure of South Korean stars in China, Zhou said K-pop devotees remained relatively independent in their consumption choices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Fans may have spent money and devoted a lot of time and energy to their idol, but in fact, this is all a way to help them achieve their cultural identity,” Zhou said. “They develop friendships, learn new languages and understand other cultures in the process.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[More than 670 people caught in 9-day Hong Kong crackdown on train fare dodgers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3227030/more-670-people-caught-9-day-hong-kong-crackdown-train-fare-dodgers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 21:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/08/c133d7bc-0175-42ca-a409-c2053dc6c5af_0325a4f3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A crackdown on fare dodgers by Hong Kong rail operator MTR Corporation has seen more than 670 penalty notices handed out in just nine days and cheats who abused the HK$2 subsidy scheme for elderly and disabled people accounted for 13 per cent of offenders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The MTR Corp said on Saturday that 671 people were slapped with penalties between June 25 and Monday, 89 of them for misuse of the subsidy scheme, which allows people aged 60 or over and the disabled to travel at the flat HK$2 rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The company has strengthened the frequency of ticket inspections and deployed the manpower, and at the same time enhanced publicity and education on correct fare payment,” MTR Corp explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 671 cases of fare cheating coincided with the introduction of increased fines for evaders on June 25.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fines for passengers on heavy rail services doubled to HK$1,000 and went up by HK$80 from HK$290 to HK$370 on the light rail network.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A total of 4,042 cases of cheating on fares were uncovered in 2022, down from 10,082 in 2021 and 10,985 in 2020, when people&#39;s mobility was heavily restricted by coronavirus pandemic restrictions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The increased fines were launched as part of a drive by the rail giant to target fare cheats amid a debate over whether the subsidy scheme can remain viable because of the city&#39;s ageing population.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A recent government-commissioned report said the extension of the fare reduction programme to the 60-64 age group would push the cost up to HK$8.6 billion in 2031, equivalent to 5.3 per cent of the city&#39;s social welfare budget, compared with 1.6 per cent in 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s MTR to raise fines for HK$2 fare scheme abuse with crackdown on way&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The get-tough policy is part of efforts by the MTR Corp as well as the authorities and other transport providers to tackle people who abuse the concession.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials earlier warned that passengers caught cheating on the elderly and disabled fare scheme would face arrest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A citywide law enforcement action was launched last month at a variety of bus, ferry, green minibus and participating red minibus routes, covering all service hours, including Sundays and public holidays.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three-strong teams – one worker from the transport operator, a Transport Department officer and a security guard – carry out patrols and take action if they suspect a passenger is wrongfully using a discounted ticket.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The teams will not be deployed at MTR stations, but the rail operator said it would assign staff to check whether passengers were exploiting the concessionary rate.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Raise HK$500 fine to curb abuse of ticket scheme for elderly on Hong Kong&#39;s MTR&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Franchised bus operators KMB and sister company Long Win Bus, as well as Citybus and New World First Bus, said they would “actively cooperate” with the government as part of the measure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The discount, the Government Public Transport Fare Concession Scheme for the Elderly and Eligible Persons with Disabilities, was introduced in 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Travellers aged 60 and over and eligible people with disabilities can travel on the MTR, franchised buses, ferries, trams and kaito private ferries, as well as on red and green minibuses using the reduced fare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But there is nothing to distinguish the Octopus cards for the elderly, and anyone can buy a card without providing proof of identity or age.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 4 million Octopus cards for people aged over 65 were issued in 2019, even though there were only 1.32 million people in the age group in Hong Kong that year.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Knockoff luxury items no longer taboo as Gen Z shoppers embrace ‘superfake’ designer bags, shoes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3227031/knockoff-luxury-items-no-longer-taboo-gen-z-shoppers-embrace-superfake-designer-bags-shoes?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 21:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/08/387f17a3-dace-4ad2-9fb1-587589e7fcc1_5bb96ed8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;There is a new type of knock-off that is making it even harder to ensure your Gucci handbag or Yeezy sneakers are authentic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Designer brands have been combating knock-offs for decades, but a rising category of “superfakes” can trick the most experienced experts. Fabricators have become increasingly savvy at making a product look eerily similar to the real thing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Here is how superfakes became so difficult to tell apart from the real thing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Are luxury Chanel and Hermès bags really a good investment? 7 expert tips&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While knock-offs of designer clothing and accessories have been around for more than a century, they gained prominence in the 80s and 90s as logos became a status symbol on everything from Juicy Couture tracksuits to Tommy Hilfiger bucket hats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who could not afford the designer price tags went to thriving street markets like Canal Street in New York City, where sellers hawk counterfeit handbags, wallets, and shoes. Most of these fakes were not fooling anyone. They may have had a Gucci or Chanel logo, but they were cheaply made and often had telltale signs of inauthenticity, like fake leather, inconsistent stitching, or low-quality hardware.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Knock-offs have a long history. Genuine and counterfeit Dior bags are displayed at the Counterfeit Museum in Paris in 2009. Superfakes have taken the practice to a new level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But superfakes are not your Canal Street knock-off. Chinese manufacturers have become increasingly skilled at replicating designer goods in such detail that even the most experienced authenticators can struggle to decipher a superfake.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a New York Times article, these manufacturers are known to source leather from some of the same Italian suppliers as the fashion houses and often buy the real designer handbags to study how they are made.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Social media and the pandemic&#39;s e-commerce boom have bolstered the knock-off market. Gen Z consumers are increasingly interested in luxury products and are fuelling a movement that embraces knock-offs as subversive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These young shoppers, born between 1997 and 2012, wear fakes with pride. They have decided that is cool to buy dupes and knock-offs, opposed to previous generations that deemed them taboo. TikTok puts Gen Z&#39;s obsession on full display; there are thousands of videos on where to shop for dupes of handbags, cosmetics, and sneakers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is important to note that dupes and knock-offs are not the same. A dupe is simply a cheaper product that looks similar to a designer item, but does not infringe on a brand&#39;s intellectual property or trademark.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, any product that intentionally replicates a brand&#39;s product, using its logo, name, or intellectual property is considered a knock-off. Selling counterfeits is illegal in the US and in some countries, such as France and Italy, it is illegal to wear them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While they are cheaper than the real thing, superfakes are more expensive than an average knock-off. The price of a real Hermes Birkin bag starts at US$10,000, while a superfake can cost up to US$2,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Buying a superfake handbag also is not as easy as purchasing an average knock-off. According to a TikTok video by creator Charles Gross, you usually have to know someone who has bought a superfake to get a seller&#39;s contact information.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are also Reddit threads devoted to the best sellers. Typically, bags are made to order and the seller sends quality-control photos throughout the process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, the fashion industry lost more than US$50 billion in potential sales because of counterfeit merchandise. Both designer brands and third-party marketplaces have invested millions in combating counterfeits, but the issue is so widespread that it is impossible to stop them all.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Climate scientists cover Sichuan’s Dagu glaciers with Tencent-sponsored hi-tech blanket to impede their melt amid global warming]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3226846/climate-scientists-cover-sichuans-dagu-glaciers-tencent-sponsored-hi-tech-blanket-impede-their-melt?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.08 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/07/cc9e6d84-ee56-47d0-a9e9-2aec43694cde_e6611a5c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A giant blanket has gone up over a portion of China&#39;s most accessible glacier to slow its melting, as climate scientists race to stem their retreat amid global warming.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the Dagu glaciers in the Tibetan region of southwestern China&#39;s Sichuan province, thick rolls of white sheets now cover an area of over 400 square metres. Supported by poles and anchored with wooden boards, the sheets feature a newly developed film that achieves radiative cooling, which scientists hope can slow down the melting rate of Dagu&#39;s glaciers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our material is lighter in texture, water-repellent, more eco-friendly, and can be reused multiple times,” said the Nanjing University&#39;s associate professor Zhu Bin, during a visit two weeks ago to the area. “The cost of it is also on par with traditional geotextiles.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu leads a team supported by the university&#39;s three-year partnership with the Tencent Carbon Neutral Lab, a unit set up in 2021 by the world&#39;s biggest video games publisher Tencent Holdings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The team is racing against time to slow down the melting of glaciers, fighting a losing game to retard, if not entirely stop the process. Floods that burst out from glacial lakes when glaciers melt threaten 15 million people around the world, putting 1 million at risk in western China&#39;s Xinjiang, Tibet, Qinghai, Sichuan and Yunnan regions, according to a study.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 8,000 glaciers, or 15 per cent of the total in China, have melted in the past 50 years due to global warming, according to calculations by Kang Shichang, the director of the State Key Laboratory of Cryosphere Sciences at the Chinese Academy of Sciences, the country&#39;s national science think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Half of the Earth&#39;s 215,000 glaciers could disappear entirely by 2100 – with ramifications for the world&#39;s supply of fresh water and ecosystems – even if humanity can successfully curb global warming to 1.5 degrees Celsius, according to research published in the Science journal in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although China has committed to reduce greenhouse-gas emissions to reach carbon neutrality by 2060, the country&#39;s meteorological administration announced last month that the El Niño climate phenomenon is expected to bring more extreme weather, including record high temperatures, to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Evidence of global warming is everywhere, even at Dagu, which has become a popular tourist destination since the glaciers were first discovered in 1992 through satellite imagery. Thousands of tourists throng the area – six hours drive from Chengdu – all-year round, paying 180 yuan (US$25) each for a 15-minute ride in the world&#39;s highest cable car to reach a viewing platform located 4,860 metres (15,944 feet) above sea level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only 11 glaciers covering 1.46 square kilometres remain at Dagu, from 17 spanning 5.6 square kilometres as recently as 1971, according to the Dagu Glacier Management Bureau&#39;s deputy head Huang Shihai. The volume of the glacier, located by the Heishui River, has shrunk by more than 70 per cent over half a century, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When I first came here in 2006, the length and width of the glacier were still quite impressive,” said Huang, 43 years old. “I&#39;ve almost never worn short-sleeve shirts before 2013, but nowadays I need to wear one during the hottest days in July and August.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Glacier blankets are not exactly new. Swiss and Italian scientists have been using geotextiles and tarpaulins to cover glaciers in the Alps from the sun&#39;s rays for almost two decades. The technique can reduce snow and ice melting by between 50 per cent and 70 per cent, according to Matthias Huss, the director of the Swiss Glacier Monitoring Network and a senior scientist at ETH Zürich in Switzerland.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nanjing University&#39;s material reflects more radiation and radiates more heat, Zhu said. In experiments carried out in 2021 at Glacier No. 1 at the Tianshan mountains in Xinjiang region, Zhu covered 200 square metres of snow with his new material. The result, published last February in the peer-reviewed Science Advances journal, found that the melt was reduced by 1.5 metres over 50 days, or three to four times better than traditional materials, Zhu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Mitigation and adaptation are two major strategies to deal with climate change,” said Xu Hao, head of Tencent&#39;s Carbon Neutral Lab. “Both are complementary to each other and very important.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The material used at Dagu is even better, due to upgrades, Zhu said. When the northern hemisphere summer ends in September, his team will return to Dagu to remove the blanket and assess their result.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The method has the potential to preserve ice locally, but not to fight against climate change,” said Huss. “It will never be possible to cover a large [glacier] or all glaciers, just to save them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blankets, however advanced they are, are not “scalable” to save the entire glacier. “The cost of such an endeavour would be huge and completely uneconomic,” he said, adding that widespread and large-scale use could damage surrounding ecosystems.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These materials are best used to preserve the ice at specific locations where it is absolutely needed for snow-related tourism such as ski slopes. Cutting the emission of greenhouse gases is a far more efficient way of saving glacial ice, not to mention reducing all the other negative impacts of human-induced warming, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Local interaction does not stop glacier retreat,” Huss said. “There&#39;s only one way we can save all glaciers, and thus avoid negative impacts: It&#39;s by saving the climate.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 08 Jul 2023 19:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>