<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong developers whipsawed by 16-year high inventories, lofty interest rates and China slowdown]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3231571/hong-kong-developers-whipsawed-16-year-high-inventories-lofty-interest-rates-and-china-slowdown?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/2542ee5b-9fe1-4d0f-975b-29ed864e55d7_9b09a7f4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;内地房地产危机加剧，香港开发商乌云密布当该市的建筑商已经在努力应对利率上升、经济放缓和新办公空间大量涌现的致命组合时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几个月来住宅交易量的疲软已经浇灭了持续复苏的希望由于中国的重新开放未能产生预期的资金流入，资金流入已从疫情期间的低点回升。令该行业雪上加霜的是抵押贷款利率上升，与一年前相比至少贵了三分之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港房地产公司短期内缺乏乐观情绪，盈利可能会下降让人失望。香港私募股权投资公司开元资本首席投资官布洛克·西尔弗斯(Brock Silvers)表示，内地经济低迷还远未结束，当局仍不愿接受房地产盈利模式已经改变的事实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港多年来，房地产业受益于美国的低利率和中国的强劲增长，但现在情况却发生了逆转。过去一年，香港商业银行将抵押贷款利率提高了近五分之一，而中国的经济困难导致大量研究机构降低了增长预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年第二季度，未售出的存量根据中原地产的数据，住宅单位数量增至 19,085 套，为 2003 年以来的最高水平，当时住宅单位数量达到 22,000 套。此后，随着香港金融管理局上个月宣布的最新一轮加息，抵押贷款利率进一步上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“较低的平均售价和较高的利率可能会侵蚀开发商的利润，并会影响开发商的利润。”对未来一到两年的预订产生持久影响，”美国投资银行 Jefferies 股票分析师 Sam Wong 告诉《华盛顿邮报》。在最近的一份报告中，他全面下调了香港开发商的盈利预期，理由是利润率、利息支出上升以及人民币贬值，这些因素都考虑到其中一些公司在内地的风险敞口相当大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人民币对于那些在中国风险敞口相对较大的香港房地产品牌来说，贬值可能会成为一个阻力。” “历史上新世界发展、长实集团、恒隆地产和香港置地在人民币贬值周期中往往表现较弱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，在宏观经济状况改善的背景下，需求回升得到满足Jefferies 表示，去年下半年积压的供应充足，有 12,000 套已获得预售批准但尚未推出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;库存过剩意味着平均价格追踪香港新建住宅物业的数据提供商 Dataelements 的数据显示，今年 6 月新房售价为每平方英尺 19,600 港元（2,508 美元），是自 2022 年 9 月每平方英尺 18,800 港元以来的最低水平。 6 月份的价格也比一年前低了 20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023 年上半年的总体售出率（指已售出的房屋百分比）接近 80%杰富瑞 (Jefferies) 表示，但黄表示，尽管销量不错，但购房者的需求受到利率上升的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，香港商业银行今年第二次提高了最优惠利率，此前，香港金融管理局与美联储同步将香港基准利率上调了四分之一个百分点。中国银行（香港）、汇丰银行和恒生银行将最佳客户贷款利率上调12.5个基点至5.875%。一年前，最好的利率约为 5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在此期间，开发商可能会优先考虑去库存，而不是激进的定价，”杰富瑞 (Jefferies) 分析师 Wong 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港的库存根据物业服务公司 JLL 的数据，已竣工项目中的未售出单位数量达到 2007 年以来的最高水平，目前共有 83,000 套住房可供出售，预计 2023 年将有约 25,000 套住房投入市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;可以肯定的是，在开发商利用需求复苏的机会匆忙推出房产、寻求先发制人的过程中，库存卸载已经开始认真进行。本月早些时候，香港亿万富翁李嘉诚的旗舰开发商长实集团降价并售空其海岸线的全部626个标准单位后，Villa Garda III住宅项目的开发商纷纷涌向市场，以折扣价发布第一份价单。 II 九龙发展。价格比该地区的市场价格低约 16%，目前人们正在关注将于 8 月 20 日星期日开始出售的 Coast Line I 和 Villa Garda III 项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们预计兴趣会增加穆迪投资者服务公司在本周的一份报告中表示，利率和资本市场波动将限制未来几个季度的购房者情绪。 “我们预计这些情况将导致未来 6 至 12 个月内价格出现中高个位数下跌，很大程度上回吐 2023 年上半年积累的涨幅。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港住宅杰富瑞 (Jefferies) 分析师表示，鉴于利率正常化、供应恢复到更正常的水平以及人口流入支持住房需求，价格更有可能在 2024 年出现实质性复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但情况在改善之前可能会恶化。&lt;中原地产表示，第三季度新房销量将回落至3,000套左右，环比减少约500套。随着近期市场放缓，下半年新房销售将出现下滑。中原地产将2023年新屋销售预估下调至13,000套，较上季预估减少2,000套。 2023年一手案件数量将是近10年来第二低水平，仅次于2013年的9,753起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年第二季度新屋销售数量为2,753套，下降据美联物业统计，较第一季的3,468套减少约20.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于大型豪宅新屋销售放缓，新屋销售价值暴跌26.2%至293.6亿港元美联地产称，第二季度将出现这种情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“短期内利率将继续困扰投资市场，”美联地产香港和澳门住宅部门首席执行官 Sammy Po 表示。 “房价已显示出疲软的迹象。由于加息周期何时结束尚难以确定，第三季度香港楼市将继续承压。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;开发商积极进取，新房对购房者更具吸引力定价策略。 Po 预计第三季度新屋销售量将仅环比增长 2%，达到 2,800 套。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲地产控股有限公司董事长 Raymond Tsoi 拥有 38 年房地产行业经验，现任 Hong Kong 总裁拥有 3,000 多名会员的香港专业房地产顾问商会认为，情况正在缓慢恶化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“房价将继续下降，”Tsoi 告诉《华盛顿邮报》。 “不会是急剧暴跌，而是逐渐下降。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsoi预计下半年下降5%至7%，全年下降2%至3% ，随后明年将下跌 10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市场预测未来几年私人住宅市场将充斥着新的供应，这也印证了悲观的前景。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;根据彭博资讯 (Bloomberg Intelligence) 引用的团结香港基金会的预测，今年和 2024 年平均将有约 20,200 个私人住宅单位竣工，到 2025 年将增至 20,900 个单位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中原地产表示，与上半年售出的6,310套相比，开发商的表现不佳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“开发商为了利益，会以低价销售来抢夺和竞争。”许多开发项目都需要启动，”蔡说。 “开发商必须推出。否则他们就没有结果。如果市场疲软，他们是否必须降价？几家卖得好的大开发商不得不通过回扣、高贷贷比、高佣金和低价来[刺激销售]。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内地开发商开发的鸭脷洲滨海路根据截至 7 月底的交易登记册显示，合景泰富集团控股公司和龙光集团自 1 月份首次投标以来，仅售出了 295 套公寓中的 3 套。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前的交易量为创历史新低，”蔡说。 “亏损交易也不少。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上半年，全市亏损住宅交易1,964笔，占总数的14.6%，创降温以来最高水平据利嘉阁地产称，这些措施于 2010 年下半年推出。地产代理机构将其归咎于去年房价下跌15%和移民潮。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中原地产称，7月份房产交易总数创八个月新低，为4,426套。对于那些急于出售的人来说，损失不断增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tsoi 还指出，土地价格暴跌是市场情绪疲软的一个迹象。政府于 7 月初进行的本财政年度首次土地招标，取得了自 2002 年 6 月以来港岛区最低价格，比 11 月份上一次招标的价格低了 25% 以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时经济低迷提供了整理资产负债表的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港房地产公司应通过减少债务、提高效率和专注于国内市场来渡过难关。一旦中国开始重组境内房地产行业，或许香港终于能看到几缕阳光。”西尔弗斯说道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A Hong Kong relaunch must create space for youth art and culture]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231250/hong-kong-relaunch-must-create-space-youth-art-and-culture?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/7cbe34d5-10dd-43dd-8ab5-ba21ea8db5a8_4e2594b8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;作为一座综合中国文化遗产、英国历史影响以及与华人侨民的联系的城市香港位于东南亚，对国际友人和来自四面八方的旅客基本开放，拥有 750 万人以千种声音说话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我们寻求踏上新方向时，在过去几年的困难时期，艺术和文化在确定这次重新启动的基调方面发挥着至关重要的作用，我们需要做大量的工作来促进这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;幸运的是，香港长期以来一直以其当地的创意艺术和文化多元化而闻名。插画家 Don Mak 升华了屯门和元朗等拥挤街区的喧嚣。我们拥有摄影师梁威廉 (William Leung) 拍摄的住宅区图像的几何精度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后是香港灵魂令人惊叹的当代表演艺术，它在爱丁堡边缘艺术节上演了三个节目，以及宽阔、生动的壁画香港岛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城市超现代性覆盖着香港街道原有的工业风貌，是创意艺术的有机加速器。这座城市不断壮大的创意人才群体借鉴了新旧亚洲和西方传统的健康组合以及各个演变阶段的有机趋势，通常使用我们的后工业城市景观作为画布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当谈到香港年轻人的艺术时，我们必须鼓励和帮助更多的人在任何媒介的创意表达中找到满足感。特别是，我们应该通过露天展览、街头节日和精选的工作室空间，为年轻人提供不受约束的平台，而不是消除使艺术如此自发强大的杂音。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们为什么要这样做？最明显的原因是，年轻的创意表达是香港重新吸引未来人才和领导者的最有力手段之一，将个人和创意的实现放在首位。这也是振兴我们城市美学的最佳方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在制定复杂的城市更新方案方面投入了大量的精力和资本。与真正对社区充满热情的年轻人互动可以找到更有效的解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鼓励崭露头角的艺术家与过去进行斗争，同时展望未来，这正是街道所要解决的问题。艺术可以为城市更新做贡献。新街、拉斯卡阁和艺术巷只是艺术家留下印记的几个地点，为香港成为适合步行的城市的愿景增添了艺术色彩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;变革性的亚文化，例如污垢在英国的嘻哈音乐和美国的嘻哈音乐在贫穷的工人阶级社区（东伦敦和纽约的布朗克斯）出现，作为一种年轻人的表达形式。&lt;​​/p>;&lt;p>;在香港，波西米亚风格深水埗大南街的咖啡馆和屯门充满活力的 HANDS 篮球场使社区焕发活力并改善人流量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在社区共同创造青年友好文化也具有声誉层面的意义。当今最伟大的城市是那些能够利用年轻人主导的创意表达生态系统的城市——比如北京、伦敦、纽约或东京。在马德里，楚埃卡 (Chueca) 社区因庆祝多元化性取向和性别认同而闻名，帮助这座城市吸引了 LGBTQ 旅行者和进步人才。香港刺激的街头文化也可以发挥类似的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港变装团体保持原始状态——忘记鲁保罗的变装比赛&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;街头文化不仅仅是街头艺术；它也是一种艺术。它还包括借鉴城市景观的摄影、写作和音乐，以及对此类创作中所蕴含的价值观的庆祝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论是壁画的细微差别，每个人都能从中找到一些东西那些将自然融入自己作品的人所画的作品，质疑日常假设的毫无歉意的对抗性涂鸦，或者密集住宅区的照片，例如好莱坞大片《变形金刚：绝迹重生》中出现的鲗鱼涌英皇道上的建筑物和攻壳机动队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;街头艺术是青少年和年轻人在公民生活中发挥积极作用并与同龄人和其他人进行建设性对话的重要渠道。从挑战性取向和性别认同严格规范的酷儿艺术，到以新自由主义逻辑证明不平等的涂鸦，例如班克斯的作品，在街头激进、前卫的展示中可以找到很多智慧。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;长期以来，年轻人与老年人之间、香港大部分人口与精英之间存在着脱节。虽然支持、欣赏和提供一个宣泄街头艺术创作的平台并不能完全解决问题，但至少有助于解决问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就像未来属于年轻人一样，这座城市属于所有人我们。让这里变得更宜居、更有吸引力、更适合所有人，是我们的集体责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 08:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba’s Taobao and Tmall to fill 2,000 new job openings for fresh graduates as Chinese Big Tech firms seek new growth]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3231590/alibabas-taobao-and-tmall-fill-2000-new-job-openings-fresh-graduates-chinese-big-tech-firms-seek-new?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/52a880ab-9929-476d-bcc2-6cd1c9ae626e_87ad81d4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴集团旗下国内电子商务部门淘宝和天猫正在招聘超过 2,000 名员工入门级职位，这是中国大型科技公司在经历多年裁员后正在为增长做好准备的新迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部门是阿里巴巴旗下六大业务集团之一，正在寻找应届毕业生来帮助他们该公司在一份声明中表示，在其家乡杭州以及北京、上海、南京和广州等地填补了从工程到算法和数据等各种职位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次招聘工作是总体计划的一部分《南华早报》的所有者阿里巴巴今年将在公司范围内增加 15,000 名员工，其中包括 3,000 名应届毕业生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家科技巨头在大幅削减工资后，又恢复了积极招聘。根据其最新财报，截至 6 月底，阿里巴巴拥有 228,675 名员工，较 3 月底减少 6,541 名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;社交媒体和视频游戏巨头腾讯控股周四宣布将提供国内外大量职位空缺，涵盖人工智能、云计算、机器人、工业互联网等领域，也纷纷进行裁员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家总部位于深圳的公司截至6月底共有员工10.45万人，其财务报表显示，较上年同期减少了 6,200 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国 6 月份青年失业率创下新高，加大了当局增加雇用年轻人的压力。预计周二公布 7 月份数据的国家统计局暂停发布青年失业数据，引发公众对情况可能恶化的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国科技巨头一直面临着严峻的考验。过去几年，随着北京采取行动遏制“资本非理性扩张”并追求“共同繁荣”，监管审查现在在吸纳今年夏天约 1150 万大学毕业生中发挥着重要作用。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;政府对互联网行业的打击导致公司估值蒸发了数万亿美元，并导致数千个工作岗位消失。但随着经济逆风加剧，北京的态度在 2022 年底发生了重大转变，开始强调互联网平台可以给国家带来的积极价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国最高经济机构国家发展和改革委员会规划机构7月份赞扬互联网公司“推动高水平科技自力更生努力”和“为推动高质量发展作出贡献”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一高调认可之后，中国国务院总理李强与阿里云创始人王健和小红书创始人曲芳等主要科技公司代表进行了友好会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着北京放松对大型科技公司的控制，其他几家科技公司也纷纷扩张上个月末，运营着中国领先的食品配送平台的本地按需服务巨头美团宣布向应届毕业生开放 6,000 个新职位，高于去年的 5,000 个类似职位空缺。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;中国第二短视频应用运营商快手科技当月公布了 200 多个新职位空缺。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japanese wear clothes with built-in fans to beat the heat as temperatures soar to record high]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3231597/japanese-wear-clothes-built-fans-beat-heat-temperatures-soar-record-high?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/f20e4630-e273-4d39-b05e-b2241ac3fa06_42e29dd2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;销售内置风扇的夹克、颈部冷却器和感觉寒冷的 T 恤，日本公司正在开发不断增长的产品市场，以帮助人们应对夏季炎热。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本与其他国家一样，正经历着越来越炎热的夏季。今年 7 月是 100 年来最温暖的七月，至少有 53 人死于中暑，近 5 万人需要紧急医疗护理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为建筑工人制作衣服的 Workman 推出了一款风扇夹克。随着需求的增长，将于 2020 年适应大街。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;机制很简单 - 夹克背面安装有两个由可充电电池供电的手掌大小的电动风扇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;它们吸入空气，然后以不同的速度将微风吹到穿着者的身体上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;夹克零售价为 12,000 至 24,000 日元（82 美元至 164 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Workman 发言人 Yuya Suzuki 表示：“随着天气越来越热，以前从未穿过带风扇的衣服的人们想要找到降温的方法……因此更多的人有兴趣购买它。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只是就像当你在家拿着风扇时会感到凉爽一样，只要穿上[夹克]就会感觉凉爽，因为风一直吹过你的身体，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本作为居民烘焙警告称，十年一遇、危及生命的高温&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;日本的夏季以炎热和潮湿着称，但今年七月，东京确实出汗了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平均气温为28.7 摄氏度（83.7 华氏度），这是自 1875 年以来的最高记录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中暑在日本尤其致命，日本的人口老龄化程度仅次于摩纳哥，位居世界第二。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去五年中，超过 80% 的与高温相关的死亡都是老年人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些人死于中暑，”销售颈部冷却管的 MI Creations 公司的 Nozomi Takai 说道。主要针对工厂和仓库工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“个人和公司每年都在采取越来越多的努力来采取措施，”高井说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他公司内的凝胶非常明亮彩色管子——售价 2,500 日元——在冰箱里放置 20 分钟后就足够凉爽了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将它戴在脖子上将“让整个身体明显凉爽”约一个小时，她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说。 p>;&lt;p>;高井公司今年参加了在东京举行的“应对极热措施”博览会，展示了帮助用户在酷暑中保持凉爽的新产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在另一个展位上，总部位于东京的公司Liberta 推出了一系列服装，包括 T 恤和袖子，这些印花采用了让用户感觉凉爽的图案，尤其是在出汗时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些印花使用了木糖醇等材料，与水和汗水发生反应时会感觉凉爽，他们说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于大阪的 Chikuma 公司甚至生产了配备电风扇的办公夹克和连衣裙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们开发它们的想法是，它可以在Chikuma 的 Yosuke Yamanaka 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普通的风扇装会让穿着者看起来浮肿，因为它们需要拉上拉链，而且袖口很紧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;但山中伸弥表示，Chikuma、电动工具制造商牧田和纺织巨头帝人联合开发的夹克不需要扣上扣子，这要归功于将风扇夹在两层中并保持凉爽空气的特殊结构。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在日本，遮阳伞通常与注重肤色的女性联系在一起，以防止夏季晒黑，但现在事实证明，它也更受男性欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小宫山书店，一家小型奢侈品店东京的雨伞制造商在环境部鼓励人们使用遮阳伞后，于 2019 年左右开始生产男士遮阳伞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;店主 Hiroyuki Komiya 表示，之前，许多男性顾客认为遮阳伞“是女性专用的，这让他们感到尴尬” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一旦使用，就无法放手。”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着极端天气事件的增加，热浪每 5 年就会袭击中国一次：研究&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;在热门旅游胜地浅草的繁忙街道上，42 岁的宫清 (Kiyoshi Miya) 说，他决定“把伞当遮阳伞使用”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“就好像我总是在阴凉处，风感觉很凉爽。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位游客川岛昌马 (Shoma Kawashima) 脖子上挂着一个可穿戴的风扇，以便在烈日下保持凉爽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“天气太热了，我想要这位 21 岁的年轻人说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小工具很有帮助，但“不是解决”气温上升的办法。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mpox cases rise in China, but response is affected by anti-LGBTQ bias and ‘technology nationalism’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/3231470/mpox-cases-rise-china-response-affected-anti-lgbtq-bias-and-technology-nationalism?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 07:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/3f9ccc66-8fdd-42b2-8317-3d20a8cce063_564b5a5e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;防护服、PCR 检测、隔离和接触者追踪 - 很难不感受到几周前，当中国疾病预防控制中心发布了遏制疾病爆发的新指南时，人们有一种似曾相识的感觉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但所发生的并不是另一波 Covid-19 浪潮。相反，中国政府正在解决一个潜在的重大新公共卫生问题：mpox。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界卫生组织 (WHO) 报告称，中国目前正在经历世界上 MPOX（以前称为猴痘）病例增长最快的情况），国家需要迅速采取行动遏制疫情蔓延。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然美洲和欧洲已基本遏制了 2022 年中期开始的 MPOX 疫情，但亚洲已成为该疾病的新热点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;日本、韩国和泰国去年均出现零星输入病例，但 2023 年每周新增病例数均达到两位数，这意味着该病毒已在国内人群中传播。&lt;/p>;&lt;但根据向世界卫生组织报告的最新数据，中国已超过世界上所有其他国家，在过去三个月内确诊病例达到315例——尽管北京的病例报告不规范，导致无法了解疾病的真实规模&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着疫苗接种中心开放，“无需对香港 MPO 病例激增感到恐慌”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;MPOX 的传染性低于 Covid-19，但自 2022 年以来超过88,000 人感染了这种疾病，这可能会给一些人带来痛苦，甚至使人衰弱。超过 150 人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些国家在控制国内 MPOX 疫情方面比其他国家更成功 — — 可以说，这些国家的成功很大程度上归功于疫苗接种活动等积极措施。但中国政府才刚刚开始采取行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与对 Covid-19 的反应相比，[中国]的反应肯定是截然不同的，”全球研究中心高级研究员黄延忠说。美国外交关系委员会的健康状况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管[mpox]不太可能在该国发展为大规模疫情，但盲目乐观的态度可能会鼓励该疾病在美国民众中传播。高危人群——除非他们采取更积极的行动来对抗这种疾病。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月，世界卫生组织宣布，mpox 不再是国际关注的突发公共卫生事件 (PHEIC)，因为病例已经消失去年爆发大规模疫情的国家（主要是美洲和欧洲）的感染率大幅下降。 （MPOX 几十年来一直在西非和中非流行，并且仍然如此。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“总体而言，与去年相比，我们绝对处于不同的境地，”Krutika Kuppalli 说，传染病医生兼美国传染病学会全球健康委员会主席。 “我们的病例少得多，但我们看到世界不同地区出现零星疫情。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，当世界卫生组织撤销 PHEIC 声明时，许多亚洲国家的病例数已经开始上升。日本是 3 月份第一个报告 MPOX 病例大幅增加的亚洲国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月份，该国研究人员的一份报告警告说，由于日本与日本之间的联系，这种疾病可能会在整个亚洲激增。和其他亚洲国家，以及该地区的 MPOX 疫苗接种率较低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究人员指出，如果疫情发展到西方的水平，预计仅日本一国的病例数就可能超过 10,000 例mpox 已被成功遏制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚不清楚中国到底发生了什么。根据世界卫生组织收集的数据，5月至7月中国报告新增MPO病例315例。如此高的病例数表明并非所有病例都与旅行有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，在另一种让人想起其 Covid-19 应对措施的情况下，中国并不像其他国家那样及时提供疾病数据；它不每周发布新病例报告。相反，它发布了一份一次性报告，显示 6 月份记录的 MPOX 病例数：106 例。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港将于周四开设专门的 MPOX 疫苗接种中心&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国政府没有尚未发布 5 月份的数据，在撰写本文时，尚未发布有关 7 月份病例的任何数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，世界卫生组织包括来自台湾的病例数，台湾有自己的政府和中心疾病控制和香港在中国的数据。而且公众没有办法分离数据。因此，315 的数字包括北京称 6 月份发现的 106 例，加上台湾和香港 5 月、6 月和 7 月的感染人数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一切都进一步掩盖了中国 MPOX 病例的真实数量。中国大陆 - 尽管在传染病爆发期间尽快掌握情况至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们还需要更多地了解感染者，”库帕利说”，“例如 [...] 人口统计数据、临床表现、他们的免疫状态以及他们如何接受护理。我认为这类信息很重要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对该疾病的传播方式缺乏明确性，导致中国一些人感到恐慌。该国开始出现MPO病例的消息已经流传了数周。但直到 7 月 26 日，中国疾病预防控制中心和卫生部才联合发布了如何预防其传播的新指南，但即便如此，仍有一些问题没有得到解答。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该指令要求将所有确诊的 MPOX 患者转移到医疗机构除非症状较轻，否则将被隔离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它表示将对每位患者进行三周前的接触者追踪，并要求其密切接触者自我隔离三周。它还建议地方当局监测某些地区废水中的mpox病毒水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国监测疫情的难度在于，与西方一样，目前mpox的传播主要是在中国在男男性行为者 (MSM) 群体中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与美国和欧洲发生的情况类似，这种关联在中国一直被误解，认为 MPOX 只是男同性恋传播的一种性传播疾病through sexual activity – a particularly dangerous connection, as the LGBTQ community is increasingly targeted in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many Chinese social media users who have spotted men with skin lesions in public have been posting their photos to ask whether it is an mpox symptom. And the Chinese name for mpox – houdou – has also been thrown around casually as a slur against gay men.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To stop the spread of mpox, public health officials need to strike a delicate balance between destigmatising the disease by dispelling the idea that it affects only gay men and prioritising the MSM communities that are most vulnerable to it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Working with the people that are affected, helping to have non-stigmatising language and communication, has been hugely effective in helping to curb the outbreak” in the West, Kuppalli says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So far, some LGBTQ communities in China feel they are on their own. M, who works for a queer rights organisation in Guangzhou and asked to be identified only by his first initial given the sensitivity of his work, points out that the CDC recommended waste-water monitoring specifically near venues that MSM communities frequent, including bars, clubs and saunas.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Anti-LGBTQ China mouthpieces and &#39;Christian&#39; bigots don&#39;t speak for Hong Kong&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He says this has become controversial within the Chinese LGBTQ community, and that some organisers feel this puts a target on their backs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another LGBTQ organiser, Suihou, in Hubei province, who asked to be identified by a pseudonym, says that even though contact tracing information is supposed to be strictly confidential, he has seen one example in which an mpox patient&#39;s private information, including phone number, national ID, address and HIV status, was leaked and passed around on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Organisers such as M and Suihou are doing their own work to mobilise a disease response. To spread information about mpox prevention, M has recently sent text messages to 700 people and hosted in-person lectures that reached more than 900 people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suihou has worked with one mpox patient closely, helping him get testing and treatment. Not all the medical workers they have encountered have been trained on how to handle the sensitivity of these cases, he says; during the contact tracing process, the doctor told the patient that this disease is a problem for “your kind of people”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suihou warns that some people may avoid seeking medical help altogether, particularly given the lack of state support for mandatory quarantine and contact tracing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From the individual cases that I have heard of, everyone who has a confirmed case is being asked to go to a quarantine facility,” Suihou says. But, he explains, since the government has not provided a budget to help cover the quarantine, as it did with Covid-19, patients have no choice but to pay for the hospital stay and all medical tests out of their own pockets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many marginalised individuals, who are also more vulnerable in an infectious-disease outbreak, may not be able to afford that.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With the slowdown of the [Chinese] economy, local governments don&#39;t have the physical capacity or even the willingness to invest more in public health,” Huang says. Even the WHO doesn&#39;t have funding specifically earmarked for mpox prevention; it has been using its emergency fund to cover mpox-related work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A lot of the financial burden will again fall on local organisers. M says his organisation is using funds intended for HIV prevention to conduct mpox outreach work.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All of this could further discourage people who get infected from seeking medical tests and treatment. This in turn would make the community spread of mpox even harder to track – and could undermine prevention efforts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As with Covid-19, vaccination is one of the best ways to get mpox under control. Worldwide, three vaccines are currently being used for mpox prevention: ACAM2000, MVA-BN (also known as JYNNEOS in the US) and LC16m8.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All these vaccines were originally designed for protection against smallpox but have been found effective against mpox.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Monkeypox to be renamed mpox by WHO&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US has administered more than 1.2 million MVA-BN and ACAM2000 shots. And in Asia, South Korea imported 10,000 MVA-BN shots last year and is planning to procure another 20,000 this year, while Taiwan, despite its small size, has procured and administered more than 72,000 MVA-BN shots so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan, meanwhile, has relied on a Japanese company to produce its own LC16m8 while also donating doses of the vaccine to countries including Colombia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But none of these vaccines has been approved for use in China. The situation recalls China&#39;s refusal to import any mRNA Covid-19 vaccines, instead relying on a few home-grown vaccines that were shown to be less effective.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this case, though, the country doesn&#39;t currently produce any of its own smallpox vaccines; production was terminated after smallpox was eradicated globally in 1980.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bavarian Nordic, the Danish company that produces the MVA-BN vaccine, says it can&#39;t disclose client information unless requested by the government and can&#39;t confirm whether China has procured any MVA-BN shots. But it says the company is not in the process of applying to register the vaccine in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The WHO also has a sharing mechanism in place that allows member states to receive vaccines if needed. But it is unclear whether China has applied for mpox vaccines. The organisation did not immediately respond to an inquiry about whether there are plans to send vaccines to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new Chinese CDC guidance on mpox made no mention of any vaccine as part of its outbreak response.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s quite unlikely that China will focus on procuring vaccines at this moment, since there&#39;s no precedent and [no] emergency approval of the vaccines. Rather, there seems to be a focus on surveillance, monitoring, quarantine, contact tracing, etc,” says Zoe Leung, a senior associate at Bridge Consulting, a Beijing-based communication consultancy specialising in public health.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It may not be this way forever: Sinopharm, a Chinese state-owned pharmaceutical company, announced in November 2022 that it had developed the world&#39;s first mRNA vaccine against mpox, and it has been found to be effective in preclinical studies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On July 13, Sinopharm officially applied for clinical trial approval for a “replication-defective mpox vaccine”, though it is unclear whether these are the same products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sinopharm did not immediately reply to questions about its mpox vaccine development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is domestic research [into an mpox vaccine], but we don&#39;t know when it can be commercially available. It will take a long time,” says M. “I have some friends who have already travelled to Hong Kong or Macau to get vaccinated against mpox.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for Chinese people to get vaccinations outside mainland China, there is often a high cost, a long wait and layers of bureaucracy to wade through. It&#39;s again similar to trends seen earlier in the pandemic, when Chinese people with means travelled to Hong Kong to get mRNA Covid-19 vaccines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It doesn&#39;t necessarily mean [Beijing is] not interested in vaccines,” says Huang, “but there&#39;s this technology nationalism that discouraged them from rapid approval of the use of foreign vaccines.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And that, he warns, “certainly contributed to the rapid increase in Covid-related mortalities”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Wildfires threaten western Canada’s Kelowna as far north evacuated: ‘100 years of firefighting in one night’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231625/wildfires-threaten-western-canadas-kelowna-far-north-evacuated-100-years-firefighting-one-night?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 06:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/19/86ffa928-e7e4-4551-b258-5ca8bf693808_6935f281.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Wildfires on Friday bore down on Kelowna in western Canada – a city of 150,000 – while efforts to clear Yellowknife in the far north turned it into a ghost town as scorching flames burned ever closer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two fronts in British Columbia and the Northwest Territories are just the latest in a summer of devastating wildfires across the country that have forced tens of thousands from their homes and left millions of acres scorched.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Kelowna, officials described “a hard night” beating back flames, at times forcing crews to pull back and some firefighters to become trapped behind lines while making “heroic efforts” to rescue residents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We fought hard last night to protect our community,” West Kelowna fire chief Jason Brolund told a briefing on Friday. “A significant number of structures were lost,” he said, but no injuries or fatalities were reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was like 100 years of firefighting all at once, in one night,” he said, adding that he expects “another scary night tonight” under an eerie glow of the fires.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 2,500 homes and businesses on Kelowna&#39;s west side were ordered evacuated late Thursday, while another 4,800 were advised to be ready to leave at a moment&#39;s notice.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city is nestled in the Okanagan Valley that is home to some of the country&#39;s top wineries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The emptying of Yellowknife continued in the far north, meanwhile, with cars snaking along the lone highway connecting the remote capital of the Northwest Territories to southern Alberta province ahead of a 12pm deadline.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese scientists calculate mammoth emissions from Canadian wildfires&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The exodus has also continued by air, with thousands of residents flying out and an increased number of flights scheduled Friday to evacuate the regional capital&#39;s more than 20,000 inhabitants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The nearest evacuation centre is 1,150km (700 miles) away, in Alberta, where several sites have been set up. Prime Minister Justin Trudeau will meet refugees in the provincial capital Edmonton in the afternoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Air Canada pilot Chad Blewett, who flew one of the first relief flights out of Yellowknife, told public broadcaster CBC that the lakeside city was “pretty empty already.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The stragglers, he said, were mostly essential workers “building fire breaks and working with airlines [to facilitate evacuations].”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Crews have scrambled to erect defences as the flames approached Yellowknife, while water bombers have been seen flying low over the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strong winds over the next two days will send the fire, already within just a few kilometres of the city&#39;s perimeter, “in directions we don&#39;t want”, Northwest Territories&#39; fire information officer Mike Westwick said late on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several military aircraft have already been dispatched, along with more than 120 soldiers to help beat back the flames.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Defence Minister Bill Blair told reporters “conditions remain very difficult” in the north, and warned that the highway out of the city was open “for now”. As the evacuation winds down, he said, “the priority [will now be] to make sure that Yellowknife and all its property are safe”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s scary&#39;: New York has world&#39;s worst air as Canada fire smoke drifts south&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The flight from Yellowknife means half the population of the near-Arctic territory has been displaced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several towns and Indigenous communities were also already under evacuation orders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Canada is experiencing a record-setting wildfire season, with official estimates of over 13.7 million hectares (33.9 million acres) already scorched. Four people have died so far.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, the fires have also emitted an unprecedented amount of carbon dioxide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scientists say human-caused global warming is exacerbating natural hazards, making them both more frequent and more deadly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It shows how quickly our climate is changing if a place like Yellowknife, so close to the Arctic Circle, is on fire,” Adria McPherson told the CBC while fleeing the fires in the north by car.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The evacuation of Yellowknife is the second time an entire Canadian city has been cleared due to wildfires since 100,000 residents of Fort McMurray in Alberta&#39;s oil and gas producing heartland were forced out in 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this year, suburbs of Halifax on the Atlantic coast were also evacuated.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 06:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Brics summit: African countries wait in the wings for expansion of economic bloc]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231482/brics-summit-african-countries-wait-wings-expansion-economic-bloc?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/4d5b7012-973f-4589-89d6-f69a666830bc_1b398a70.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese President Xi Jinping&#39;s visit to South Africa for the Brics summit next week will be a stage for Beijing to promote its post-Covid charm offensive, including agenda items like membership expansion and de-dollarisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the Johannesburg summit is not expected to yield any concrete results, it will be watched closely by developing countries looking to the Brics group – Brazil, Russia, India, China and South Africa – as a major counterweight to Western influence in global governance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South African President Cyril Ramaphosa, as Brics chairman for 2023, will also host Brazilian President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva and Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi for the summit. Russia will be represented by Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov, with President Vladimir Putin to participate virtually.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, Xi and Ramaphosa will hold talks to strengthen ties and will witness the signing of various agreements, according to the South African president&#39;s office.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why African nations are keen to join the expanding BRICS club&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On August 10, ahead of Xi&#39;s visit, Chinese companies signed 20 deals to buy products worth US$2.2 billion from South Africa.南非贸易部长易卜拉欣·帕特尔和中国商务部部长王文涛在旨在促进南非制造业对华出口的经贸联委会会议上见证了该协议的签署。 Anglo American Platinum, Glencore, Sappi and Pioneer Fishing were among South African companies involved in the agreements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi will also co-chair a China-Africa Leaders&#39; Dialogue on the sidelines of the summit, according to China&#39;s foreign ministry – welcome news for African countries such as Algeria, Egypt, Ethiopia, Nigeria and Senegal, which are eager to move another step closer to joining the bloc.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yun Sun, head of the Stimson Centre&#39;s China programme in Washington, said China had been focused on its post-Covid diplomatic charm offensive for some time now, and developing countries and emerging markets were a big part of it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The] Brics summit this year covers both.我确信非洲债务可持续性、新冠疫情后经济复苏、乌克兰战争以及金砖国家成员扩大等问题将成为议程的重点。”孙说。 “China needs to show that it is still firmly committed to the future of Africa, provide reassurance and offer assistance. Africa needs the commitment from China as well.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Across Africa, Brics members are seen as important trade partners, sources of foreign investment and champions of the concerns of so-called developing countries, according to Tim Zajontz, a research fellow in the Centre for International and Comparative Politics at Stellenbosch University, South Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We can expect President Xi to stress at the summit that China and the Brics are at the centre of South-South cooperation and ready to boost economic development across Africa,” Zajontz said, referring to collaboration among countries in the Global South.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is little surprise that countries like Burundi, Egypt and Ethiopia want to join the grouping,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While their immediate accession appears unlikely, the fact that President Ramaphosa has invited other African leaders to attend the Johannesburg summit shows that there is keen interest to increase the Brics&#39; footprint on the continent.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Expansion of the bloc as well as trade in local currencies as an alternative to the US dollar are likely to be the two main topics discussed – even if they do not end up leading to any firm outcomes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is among the supporters of Brics expansion among the five countries, but we are unsure if any country will be able to fully join Brics at this summit, as the criteria for new admissions has yet to be finalised,” said Steven Gruzd, head of the Africa-Russia Project at the South African Institute of International Affairs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the debate turns to currencies, it is likely the summit will push for reforms of the international economic governance system, including political discussion about the dominance of the US dollar and the euro in trade and financial transactions. But Carlos Lopes, a professor at the University of Cape Town&#39;s Nelson Mandela School of Public Governance, said not to expect any major decision on this.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neither is it expected – whether hoped or feared – that the Brics&#39; New Development Bank (NDB), led by former Brazilian president Dilma Rousseff, is ready to compete with Western-centred international financial institutions at this stage, according to Lopes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zajontz, who is also a lecturer in international relations at Dresden University of Technology, said the future of the NDB would be high up on the agenda at the summit as its lending had decreased lately and the bank had faced challenges to raise capital following sanctions against Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the medium to long term, the NDB wants to further de-dollarise its capital base by increasing local currency lending and by increasing NDB membership,” he said. Egypt joined the NDB in 2021, and Algeria and Zimbabwe have expressed interest to join as well.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But [it is] not just the question of possible new African NDB members but also whether the NDB might soften its current policy to only lend to member countries,” Zajontz said, adding the many African states “are keen to diversify their creditors in times of tight development finance”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Brics meeting comes as tension between the West and the East is growing. Many African political actors, including recent army putschists in Mali, Burkina Faso, Sudan and Niger, are trying to take advantage of this discord to either protect their acquired power or contest established authority, according to Lopes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The summit will be an opportunity for Brics, and countries invited, to demonstrate independence in relation to the West while reserving endorsement of their nemesis, Russia, and their competitor, China,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cameron Hudson, a senior associate at the Centre for Strategic and International Studies&#39; Africa programme, said that as well as trying to diversify their external partnerships, African countries were looking to have a greater voice on the world stage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said African leaders would want to explore how Brics could be used as a forum where policies that benefited developing countries were created and coordinated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Africans are not interested in the illusion of coordination. They want to see real change and real impact in tangible ways that benefit them and their societies,” Hudson said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 06:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Stop posing for naked photos in our sunflower field, UK farm owners beg visitors]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3231624/stop-posing-naked-photos-our-sunflower-field-uk-farm-owners-beg-visitors?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 04:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/19/0b1ba70a-289a-4c7b-918b-c8faace90530_1b2781da.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The owners of an English farm are begging visitors to quit posing for naked pictures in its sunflower field.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a Facebook post earlier this month, Stoke Fruit Farm – which is located off the southern coast of England on Hayling Island – made the request that visitors stay fully clothed when in their sunflower field.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Reminder to all we are a family area and please keep your clothes on in the sunflowers!” the farm wrote on Facebook.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are having a increase of reports of naked photography taking place and this must not happen during our public sessions please!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The farm then promptly erected signs in its field that say “no public nudity,” according to photos obtained by CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNN spoke to the owners of Stoke Fruit Farm, Sam Wilson and his sister Nette Petley.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wilson said there have been at least six instances of public nudity among the flowers since the end of July when the field opened for visitors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;ve always had people take risqué pictures but this is the first year it&#39;s been a problem, which is why we&#39;ve put signs up,” Wilson told CNN. The farm staff had to put up the signs after some kids caught a peek of what was going on in the field, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russian woman &#39;lay naked to cool down&#39; while scaling Malaysia&#39;s tallest tower&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“We are a really free and happy farm but we just can&#39;t have nudity in public view,” Wilson said, according to CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Petley echoed Wilson&#39;s sentiment that the farm is a “really happy and fun place” that gives “you that empowering feeling”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But it&#39;s about the people around and being respectful of that,” Petley told CNN. “The site is huge and there are so many places that you can hide away without anyone finding you for over an hour, but these incidents were blatantly public.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stoke Fruit Farm has 350 acres of land and produces wheat, peas, potatoes, pumpkins, squash, sweetcorn, hay, and sunflowers, according to CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wilson first planted the sunflowers with his then fiancée behind the church where they married six years ago, intending to have their wedding surrounded by the sunflowers, but they did not bloom in time, according to CNN. Instead, they sprang up while the couple was away on their honeymoon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While they were gone, Wilson told CNN that Petley called him and said: “People want to pick your flowers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CNN reported at that point, Wilson and Petley set up an “honesty box for visitors”, but the sunflowers have since gained massive popularity over the years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now, paying visitors, who travel far and wide to see the field, can walk among 2 million sunflowers in the massive 50-acre field, Wilson told CNN.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump to skip Republican primary debate, do interview with Tucker Carlson instead, report says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231622/donald-trump-skip-republican-primary-debate-do-interview-tucker-carlson-instead-report-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 03:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/19/ec266b11-b634-45e8-ac24-44e2fc8fe3df_f7cff0a0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Former US president Donald Trump plans to skip the first Republican primary debate next week and instead sit for an online interview with former Fox News host Tucker Carlson, The New York Times reported, citing people briefed on the matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump has for months suggested that he would likely pass on Wednesday night&#39;s debate in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, arguing that it did not make sense to give others a change to attack him given his sizeable lead among Republicans in national polls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump has also criticised Fox, which is hosting the debate, over its recent coverage of him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s absence could mean Florida Governor Ron DeSantis, a distant second in the polls, will become the focus of attacks from other candidates looking to position themselves as the primary alternative to the former president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump campaign spokesman Steven Cheung said nothing had been confirmed on the candidate&#39;s debate plans, without elaborating.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representatives for Fox, which parted ways earlier this year with Carlson, and the Republican National Committee could not immediately be reached for comment. Carlson, who now is starting his own media company, also could not be reached.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the most recent Reuters/Ipsos poll released this month, Trump held 47 per cent of the Republican vote nationally, with DeSantis dropping six percentage points from July down to just 13 per cent. None of the other candidates due to attend the debate have broken out of single digits.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s rivals for the Republican presidential nomination ahead of the 2024 election will gather at the debate to tout their candidacies, but so far only a few have aggressively criticised Trump despite his mounting legal troubles.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;22 years in jail for Canadian woman who sent poison-laced letter to Trump&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Trump has an August 25 deadline to voluntarily surrender in Fulton County, Georgia, after being charged this week in a fourth criminal indictment, for an alleged scheme intended to reverse his 2020 election loss to Democrat Joe Biden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most self-identified Republicans polled in June said they saw politics behind the indictments of Trump up to that point.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump also faces two federal indictments over his handling of classified documents after leaving office in January 2021 and over his alleged role in efforts to overturn his election loss.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also faces charges in New York over alleged hush money payments to a pornographic film star ahead of the 2016 election.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Sweden considers allowing police to stop Koran burnings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3231621/sweden-considers-allowing-police-stop-koran-burnings?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 01:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/19/39c47b20-4c9f-4d0e-8bb0-8d49b2fa18db_deb203bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Sweden&#39;s government is considering changing the Public Order Act to make it possible for police to deny permission for acts such as burning the Koran but only if they threaten national security, it said on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sweden raised its terrorist alert to the second highest level on Thursday, saying it had thwarted attacks after Koran burnings and other acts against Islam&#39;s holiest text outraged Muslims and triggered threats from jihadists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Insults towards public figures or against religions are protected by Sweden&#39;s far-reaching freedom of speech laws and the government rules out changing them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Minister of Justice Gunnar Strommer said on Friday he would appoint a commission to look into giving police wider powers to deny acts such as Koran burnings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Of course, general international dissatisfaction or vague threat should not be enough – it must be about serious and qualified threats,” Strommer told a news conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added it could give police the power to select a different location for a protest or to dissolve it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An Iraqi living in Sweden has damaged several copies of the Koran in recent months. Many Muslims view desecrating the Koran, which they see as the literal word of God, as a grave offence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A media outlet linked to militant group al-Qaeda has urged violent retribution against Sweden.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Iraq expels Swedish ambassador over Koran burning&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The decision to appoint a commission met with immediate scepticism from several political parties, including the government&#39;s support party, the anti-immigration Sweden Democrats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Even if different values always need to be weighed against each other, the Sweden Democrats will never accept that we adapt to threats and pressure from Islamists and dictatorships,” Sweden Democrats&#39; party leader Jimmie Akesson said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier on Friday, the government said it had tightened security at embassies and other missions due to an increase in threats against Swedish interests abroad.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sweden&#39;s Foreign Minister Tobias Billstrom told TT that Sweden has increased security at embassies and other missions, without giving detail for security reasons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But the safety of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs&#39; staff is the highest priority,” he said, adding that the safety of families of diplomats and local staff was also taken into account.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So there are different categories that are affected by this security work that is now being intensified,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Billstrom did not reply to a request for comment&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 02:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[To speak up against Western labels, China must first find its own words]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231417/speak-against-western-labels-china-must-first-find-its-own-words?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.19 01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/cf5c77e4-5699-4855-91d8-7feb33a68492_8e53bd6b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;文字很重要。但当言语失败时，就会产生问题。中国面临这一挑战，一些西方词语试图解释中国的某些方面。中国已经采用了自己的语言中的一些词语，但西方认为这令人困惑或无法理解中国的语境。西方对中国的一些言论中国认为是有害的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以汉语如何教授“过去时”为例。汉语没有过去时，也没有任何与此相关的时态。但在教授西方学生时，很多中国老师都采用这个术语。当学生问如何表达过去时时，这些老师说他们可以在句子中添加“了”字，以表示所描述的动作已经发生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问题是，汉语实际上并不是这样的。有描述过去事件但没有此字的句子，也有不描述过去事件但有此字的句子。结果，当老师陷入试图解释“过去时”的困境时，学生们却感到困惑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个例子是“民主”一词。这通常指的是西方以核心价值维护的政治制度。当中国在其官方文件中使用“民主”一词时，西方国家会持怀疑态度（委婉地说）。但这有助于理解语境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去时”和“民主”似乎至少在动荡的 19 世纪末和 20 世纪初就已经进入汉语。出于寻求变革的动机，许多中国学者将目光投向西方，试图将西方的语法概念强加于汉语，将西方的社会政治术语强加于中国社会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国经济的崛起，一些词语正在被取代。提出来描述其国际关系。一个例子是“冷战”。西方一些分析人士一致认为，中美之间已经开始了第二次冷战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国否认自己正在进行冷战，并多次呼吁西方放弃冷战。战争心态。但西方认为这纯粹是说说而已。为什么西方这么难理解中国真的不想冷战？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要找到答案，我们得看看西方文明的摇篮——古希腊。古希腊人在观察自然界的运动后得出结论，宇宙的一个基本特征是两个对立面之间的永恒竞争，例如黑夜驱赶白天，热驱寒冷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但古代中国人得出了一个结论：不同的结论。他们认为宇宙是和谐的，看似竞争的对立面是同一本质的各个方面，一个无缝且连续地转化为另一个。他们认为，大自然包容一切，每个人都可以发挥自己的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一理念体现在副总理刘鹤一月份在达沃斯世界经济论坛上的讲话中，他说： “我们认为，公平的国际经济秩序必须得到各方共同维护。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国处理对华关系的方式、新冷战观念的兴起以及投机性的修昔底德陷阱，都符合西方的对抗传统。中国本着其传统，一再否认自己正在进行冷战。具有讽刺意味的是，它的抗议却让这一概念变得突出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个例子是“殖民主义”一词，西方用它来描述中国与一些发展中国家之间的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几个世纪以来，西方殖民主义者以残酷的武力蹂躏当地人民。然而数百年前，当中国海军上将郑和远航至非洲时，他带了豪华礼物送给当地领导人。西方将中国对发展中国家的参与视为新殖民主义，这只是在投射其过去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但就像冷战概念一样，拒绝贴上殖民主义标签似乎对中国没有多大帮助。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论是自愿采纳还是强加，来自西方的言论都让中国陷入了语言地狱，中国永远无法发出自己的声音。只有一套基于中国经验、现实和解释的新鲜词汇才能使其自由。提出这些话的必须是中国，而不是西方。一本好的语法书可能是一个开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 19 Aug 2023 01:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>