<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China’s rising clout in Latin America setting off alarm bells for US, says senior Pentagon official]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3230070/chinas-rising-clout-latin-america-setting-alarm-bells-us-says-senior-pentagon-official?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.05 05:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/05/9f87983f-2b56-4437-bec0-7b4be087eb58_74c56180.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国在拉丁美洲（特别是关键基础设施领域）不断上升的影响力和积极的投资策略，美国一名高级军事官员周五表示，这给美国敲响了警钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国南方司令部司令劳拉·理查森将军就拉丁美洲和加勒比地区的安全挑战及其潜力发表了看法在华盛顿智库战略与国际研究中心主办的一次讨论中，讨论了对美国安全的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的影响力“绝对是全球性的，就在我们眼皮子底下，离我们的祖国如此之近”，理查森说，他的司令部负责与加勒比海、中美洲和南美洲的应急计划和安全合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中华人民共和国正在做的事情看起来是投资，但我实际上称之为开采......我想说，它处于红色区域。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;理查森说，虽然现在西半球没有中国基地，但北京通过“一带一路”倡议进行的广泛基础设施投资表明，中国有可能建立一个基地。未来，这一事态发展将“显着加剧美国的安全担忧”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位将军的言论发表之际，华盛顿对中国在美国附近进行所谓的军事扩张感到不安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;《华尔街日报》6月份援引美国机密情报报道称，中国即将在古巴建立间谍基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京和哈瓦那还讨论了建立联合军事训练设施的问题，进一步深化声明称，华盛顿对中国军队距离美国海岸仅 145 公里（90 英里）感到担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;有关中国在古巴间谍基地的报道遭到了拉丁美洲的耸耸肩&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;白宫随后证实了该基地的存在，并称该基地自 2019 年以来一直在古巴运营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;理查森进一步指出，北京在该地区的技术影响力正在增强，有 5 个国家采用中国的 5G 骨干网，另外还有 24 个国家采用中国的骨干网络将其用于 3G 或 4G 网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济实惠的 5G 升级的吸引力使得这些国家的领导人“通常只有四年任期”很难拒绝中国的提议，她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了对抗北京，理查森主张加强该地区志同道合的民主国家之间的合作，并将这一想法描述为“团队民主的力量”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;5 对中国的贸易举措2023 年在美国的拉丁美洲后院实现了&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;拉丁美洲领导人“正在研究秒表，而不是日历，我们必须能够有替代方法、替代公司、替代方案他们能够选择……而不是中国竞争对手”，她说。 “这就是我们现在在竞争中被中国人击败的地方。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位将军还对中国资助的基础设施在该地区用于军事目的的可能性表示担忧。她指出巴拿马运河沿岸有五家中国国有企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;具体而言，理查森担心中国公司可能将这些公司用于军事目的，并在南部具有重要战略意义的麦哲伦海峡指出了类似的担忧智利将南美洲大陆与火地群岛分开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，她说，一些加入以中国为中心的“一带一路”倡议的国家正在经历“买家因项目失败而悔恨”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“该地区乃至全球都有项目进展不顺利的例子，”理查森说。 “它们存在设计缺陷、成本超支。存在巨大的延误。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她认为，需要基础设施帮助的国家向北京求助是可以理解的，她说：“当有人向你扔一根绳子时，你不一定要看是谁给的。你是绳子。你只要抓住它。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，理查森敦促美国及其盟友提供替代投资和商业模式，帮助拉美国家抵制中国的影响力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;否则，她警告说， “如果我们不参与竞争，他们就会选择”中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;习近平告诉拉丁美洲和加勒比地区，中国将与“新时代”建立联系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国人周五，驻华盛顿大使馆捍卫了“一带一路”倡议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;使馆发言人刘鹏宇表示，其项目的特点是全面对话、相互协作、共享优势，“这体现在它创造了 42 万个就业岗位和”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“‘一带一路’受到世界各国普遍欢迎，最重要的是因为它是共商、共建、共享的倡议。”刘补充道。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“中国从不把自己的意志强加于其他国家，也不将任何自私的地缘政治议程纳入“一带一路”之中。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 05 Aug 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US discusses ‘creative ways’ to help Mongolia export rare earths]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3230069/us-discusses-creative-ways-help-mongolia-export-rare-earths?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.05 04:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/05/05719546-4fb8-4513-85eb-80148aff787b_4111b57c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国和蒙古官员本周讨论了确保内陆国家、美国国务院官员周五表示，依靠邻国中国和俄罗斯的善意，可以将关键矿产推向世界市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理 L. Oyun-Erdene 周三在会见美国副总统后表示。总统卡马拉·哈里斯在华盛顿表示，蒙古将深化与美国在稀土和其他高科技应用矿物开采方面的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，他会见了美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯，并签署了“开放”协议。天空”民用航空协议，双方承诺进一步开展经济合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国务院官员向记者通报称，国家航空公司蒙古航空将能够直飞尚未决定的美国机场明年之前。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方还讨论了如何落实国务院与蒙古矿业和重工业部6月签署的谅解备忘录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去几天我们进行的许多讨论都在讨论我们可以帮助蒙古了解其拥有什么、提取什么以及生产什么的具体领域。”该官员表示。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“我们当然渴望帮助蒙古人找到创造性的解决方案，从而帮助他们更好地控制采矿、勘探、提取和生产关键矿物和稀土元素。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被问及如何为了确保蒙古能够无障碍地出口此类商品，该官员表示，蒙古地处内陆，处于“艰难的地缘政治局势”。 “所以我们讨论了......非常有创意的方式，我们可以将其......推向市场。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;瑞典的重大稀土发现被视为中国主导地位的“游戏规则改变者”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;稀土地球和铜对于包括国防设备在内的高科技应用以及美国总统乔·拜登推动汽车市场电气化以帮助应对气候变化的努力至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国热衷于确保其他来源的资源它的主要全球竞争对手中国去年占世界稀土产量的 70% 以上。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 05 Aug 2023 04:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Thailand can draw closer to China despite US rivalry and geopolitical tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3229780/how-thailand-can-draw-closer-china-despite-us-rivalry-and-geopolitical-tensions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.05 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/04/d14babdb-807c-491d-9771-4bf63d69e743_233cf520.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;7月1日是中泰建交48周年。如今，中国是泰国最大的贸易伙伴，去年贸易额达 1,350 亿美元，约占泰国贸易总额的 18%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国对中国的出口额也猛增，从 1995 年的 18.2 亿美元增至 37.7 美元到 2021 年，中国的中产阶级将增长 10 亿美元，这证明了中国新兴的中产阶级以及泰国作为制造业和农业强国的竞争力不断增强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凭借文化和人际关系的联系，中国家庭明显偏爱在泰国度假和合资企业的成功从医疗保健到尖端初创企业和创新，两国长期以来一直享有资本、人才和知识汇集的协同效应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一带一路”倡议在推进区域基础设施建设方面取得了巨大成功泰国是一个有效的东南亚中心地带，通过先进的火车和物流网络将中国与老挝、缅甸、柬埔寨和马来西亚连接起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，为泰党领导人 Chonlanan Srikaew 在接待中国代表团时承诺“推动更多贸易协定，促进投资、相互进出口、旅游业以及技术交流”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，为了切实深化、拓宽中泰关系并经受住未来几十年的考验，北京曼谷必须解决房间里的大象：初期的地缘政治紧张局势主要源于中美竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首先，泰国寻求深化与中国的军事协调，同时与泰国保持深厚的军事和防务关系。美国作为主要的非北约盟友。这种做法与泰国的“竹子外交”相一致，即在大国之间谨慎平衡并坚定捍卫国家利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，随着华盛顿越来越多地向东南亚国家施加压力，要求它们在问题上选边站队。它被认为是为了加强其地区影响力，以应对来自中国的潜在挑战，泰国可能被迫做出选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近和正在进行的一系列联合军事演习反映了北京和曼谷压制中立的共同意图。地区冲突和紧张局势，但它们是在美国重新有兴趣讨好东南亚的背景下发生的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了继续中泰军事合作，必须明确划分泰国军队的职权范围和界限需要与美国和中国同行建立关系。更具建设性的是，即将上任的泰国内阁应利用该国与北京和缅甸军队的历史关系，寻求中国与东盟斡旋的和平协议，以恢复缅甸的一点民主。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其次，在全球金融和供应链日益巴尔干化的背景下，泰国应将自己定位为投资的避风港。乌克兰战争引发了跨国公司和资产的一系列重组，其中许多公司从中国转移到东南亚，以寻求更大的政策确定性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东北亚的中小企业感到担忧由于台湾海峡军事紧张局势的潜在影响，一直将泰国视为成本更低、区域联系更紧密的生产基地。这种撤资激励措施也适用于在国内外寻求增长沃土的中国企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国对中国国有企业并不陌生，例如与正大集团合作的上汽集团集团将利用泰国作为产品国际化的中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国东部经济走廊也为海外公司的多元化努力提供了绝佳的机会。同样，面对可能扰乱关键矿产和其他原材料供应的潜在突发事件，泰国制造商必须投资于提高抵御能力和自给自足能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国的主要政策制定者可以利用该国的资源稀土资源丰富。反过来，在全球地缘政治金融急剧武器化的情况下，北京方面应确保其在泰国的合资企业保持不受制裁和稳健。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后，任何健康的双边关系的核心都是真诚和扎根的民间交流。 ——人员交流。泰国是中国在疫情过后首批恢复团体旅游的国家之一，副总理兼公共卫生部长阿努廷·查维拉库 (Anutin Charnvirakul) 一月份在素万那普机场迎接中国游客。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然泰国企业在很大程度上过去几十年来，虽然中国的购买力和中国市场的天文数字增长使这些国家受益匪浅，但一些人认为，这种红利并没有惠及中下阶层和工薪阶层。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的“零美元”游客由于旅游团的消费集中，且大部分返还给中国旅行社，当地对此反应冷淡。乘数效应显然没有发挥作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国民众与中国游客之间的紧张关系很可能因多种因素而出现，包括经济根源的怨恨，以及刻板印象、宗教分歧或日益政治化的媒体空间中国崛起的观点常常受到既得利益的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在泰国的中国游客因踩珊瑚、摸海星而面临牢狱之灾&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;泰国政府必须努力确保其媒体不受媒体报道外国干涉以及对与美国和中国关系的报道仍然是平衡、坦诚和以事实为导向的。另一方面，北京必须谨慎、批判性地思考中国如何才能获得更多信任，并赢得泰国人心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港当然可以发挥作用。随着行政长官李家超去年首次出访泰国，这座城市的特殊联系显然将变得越来越重要，成为中国与泰国关系的另一个渠道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A中泰合作共赢，但首先要克服关键障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 05 Aug 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As US House and Senate hammer Pentagon budget bill into shape, China remains sharply in focus]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3230068/us-house-and-senate-hammer-pentagon-budget-bill-shape-china-remains-sharply-focus?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.05 02:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/05/bb4b02b1-50a4-44cc-a837-4d4e1e411014_f9178afa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;经过数月梳理1000多项修正案，美国参议院最终通过了其版本上周，《国防授权法案》通过了——正如近年来的情况一样，对抗中国的措施已经成熟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防授权法案（NDAA），制定最高预算并指导政策五角大楼下一个财政年度的法案是一项“必须通过”的法案，因为该法案的颁布是军人按时领取工资和福利所必需的。因此，与国防没有严格联系的条款经常被纳入该法案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;民主党领导的参议院以 86 比 11 的结果通过了该版本，而共和党领导的众议院则在 7 月初以微弱优势通过了该版本。 ，219-210。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接下来将两项法案协调成一项法案，然后将其发送给美国总统乔·拜登签署成为法律，通常是在年底附近。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;人们普遍猜测中国国家主席习近平已命令中国人民解放军做好在 2027 年之前武力占领台湾的准备，这个自治岛屿在最近的国防授权书中越来越受到重视。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;该法案的两个版本都有许多涉及台北国防的条款，包括评估对中国大陆的燃料封锁以及解放军攻击台湾时的其他军事选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国防授权法案（至少在其众议院版本中）首次呼吁国务卿和国防部长维持对台湾的非战斗人员撤离计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国宣布向台湾提供 3.45 亿美元的军事援助帮助对抗中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为一个流氓省份，最终必须与大陆统一，必要时可使用武力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与大多数国家一样，美国是台湾最大的非正式经济体盟友和武器供应商——不承认该岛是一个独立国家。但华盛顿依法承诺支持台湾的军事防御能力，而北京方面强烈反对这一立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡南洋理工大学拉惹勒南国际研究学院研究员科林·科说： 《国防授权法案》中众多与台湾相关的条款表明，国会在与北京发生冲突的可能性上存在共识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此类新措施似乎发出了关于这些焦虑的更不祥的信号，”他说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;除了要求对台湾的国防需求和美国的战争准备进行全面评估外，众议院版本的法案还寻求对在发生武装冲突时美国对中国实施海上封锁化石燃料的可行性进行分析.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参议院版本要求对中国对该岛持续军事封锁进行风险分析，并提交一份关于 2030 年冲突的“地缘政治和经济后果范围”的报告。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这将使五角大楼向国会通报北京军事态势的频率从每年一次增加到每六个月一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在去年国防授权法案中类似措施的基础上，参议院法案还将建立一个“全面的”为台湾军队提供培训、咨询和机构能力建设计划，更好地提高台湾的自卫能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国大陆播放纪录片，暗示准备攻击台湾&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;就其本身而言众议院法案要求五角大楼考虑建立一个美台联合军事规划小组。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法案还呼吁国防部长邀请台湾参加美国主导的环太平洋军事演习该法案颁布后 30 天内举行——首次设定了邀请的最后期限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环太平洋军演是世界上最大的海上演习，有来自两打以上海军的船只参与，自此以来每隔一年举行一次1992 年，台湾没有加入，尽管之前立法呼吁将台湾纳入其中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两项法案都首次呼吁与台湾进行网络安全合作，以“积极保卫军事网络、基础设施和系统”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;p>;近几个月来，台北指责北京增加了对台湾的网络攻击，《纽约时报》报道称，拜登政府已指示搜寻隐藏的恶意软件，这些恶意软件可能会在与台湾发生冲突时中断美国的军事行动。中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但与前几年一样，这些法案在很大程度上避免了明确挑战美国一个中国政策的措施，其中华盛顿“承认”北京关于台湾是中国一部分的立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;众议院法案包括一项条款，禁止五角大楼资助任何描绘“台湾、金门[又称金门]、马祖、澎湖、乌措、绿岛或兰花岛为中华人民共和国领土一部分的地图” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这一规定与美国政府最近对地图的指导相矛盾，并且可能会被淡化，就像去年国务院拨款法案中的类似提议一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京大学海洋战略专家胡波表示，国会支持台湾的努力反映了五角大楼“持续”努力与台湾接触，包括增加美军在那里的存在。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Blackpink,芭比娃娃和北京在越南的南海主张发生冲突&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“最近，华盛顿似乎想降低对台湾问题的关注和敏感度，”胡补充道，暗示五角大楼打算“多做少说” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析人士还质疑一些建议的实用性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯坦福大学弗里曼·斯波利国际问题研究所研究员奥丽安娜·斯凯拉·马斯特罗 (Oriana Skylar Mastro) 称美国的能源封锁“非常可行”，但也持怀疑态度，因为解放军的任何攻击都可能发生得太快，这样的举措无法发挥作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果中国发现自己陷入与美国的旷日持久的战争中，而这可能会发挥作用，那么华盛顿美国企业研究所非常驻高级研究员马斯特罗说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;NDAA 草案还重点关注遏制北京方面的努力。技术进步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参议院法案要求美国企业在投资先进半导体、人工智能、量子信息科学和高超音速等对军事能力发展至关重要的领域的中国技术之前通知财政部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;该措施的共同发起人、宾夕法尼亚州民主党参议员鲍勃·凯西 (Bob Casey) 表示，该措施“将提高美国在高度敏感和关键领域对中国的投资的透明度”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白色预计众议院将于本月晚些时候发布一项关于对外投资的行政命令，该命令可能会重点关注类似行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;针对参议院上周的提案，中国外交部发言人毛宁表示：“任意放置限制工业界和私营部门的正常投资活动违反市场经济原则，扰乱全球产业链供应链，最终只会损害美国投资者的利益。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院法案呼吁五角大楼的年度中国军力报告将包括对北京新兴技术发展的评估。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两个版本都旨在向北京提供资金，并禁止五角大楼资助中国的研究，包括武汉病毒学研究所的研究，以及生态健康联盟，这是一家总部位于美国的非营利组织，与武汉研究所合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，参议院一项禁止中国企业参与联邦政府投资计划的提案被取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与前几年一样，限制中国在美国的影响力仍然是焦点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参议院法案禁止来自中国、俄罗斯、伊朗和朝鲜的实体参与购买美国农田和农业企业 - 发起立法者以粮食安全和间谍活动为借口来证明其合理性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一修正案还要求将农业部长加入美国外国投资委员会 (CFIUS) – 审查入境外国投资的机构间委员会。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;DeSantis 签署限制中国土地所有权、学校使用 TikTok 的法案&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;众议院法案中包括一项措施，要求研究人员由政府资助五角大楼披露国籍和教育背景等个人信息——白宫强烈反对此举，批评其增加行政负担，造成“无意的国家安全风险”，并可能阻碍五角大楼“吸引最优秀、最聪明的外国人才”的能力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院的几项措施希望阻止中国的意识形态影响，其中包括禁止五角大楼支持中国审查的电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两个版本都针对孔子学院，这将到 2026 年有效关闭美国所有现有机构。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;参议院和众议院法案也支持印太地区现有的区域安全举措。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;参议院版本支持与包括澳大利亚、日本和印度在内的地区盟友的海域意识倡议以及印度-太平洋战役倡议等计划，这将增加美国在该地区的军事演习和合作伙伴参与的频率。&lt;/p>;参议院法案省略了将快速向澳大利亚转移核动力潜艇的措辞，这是说服拜登政府（拜登政府已经承诺向其奥库斯盟友提供此类潜艇）增加投资的一部分。先在国内生产，然后再运往国外。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 05 Aug 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[West African leaders make plan for military intervention in Niger]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3230067/west-african-leaders-make-plan-military-intervention-niger?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.05 02:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/05/e9f443ae-19da-4b56-8f5b-da47eaaf0fa3_5b2a0cea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;西非国防部长已制定一项潜在军事干预计划，以扭转上周的政变西非国家经济共同体 (ECOWAS) 领导人周五表示，将在尼日尔部署部队，包括如何以及何时部署部队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该地区集团不会向政变策划者透露何时何地部署部队的信息。西非经共体政治事务、和平与安全专员阿卜杜勒-法托·穆萨表示，这一决定将由各国元首做出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“所有因素都会影响他在尼日利亚首都阿布贾举行的为期三天的会议结束时表示，这里已经制定了任何最终干预措施，包括所需的资源、我们如何以及何时部署部队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;西非经共体已对尼日尔实施制裁，并表示，如果政变领导人在周日之前未能恢复民选总统穆罕默德·巴祖姆的权力，则可以授权使用武力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尼日尔政变：西非集团的威胁将如何？使用武力是什么样子？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这个由 15 名成员组成的机构周四派出一个代表团前往尼日尔寻求“友好解决方案”，但随行人员的一位消息人士称，在机场与军政府代表的会面没有取得突破.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望外交发挥作用，我们希望向他们清楚地传达这样的信息：我们正在给他们一切机会扭转他们的所作所为，”穆萨说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 05 Aug 2023 02:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Putin critic Alexei Navalny gets 19 more years added to his prison sentence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3230064/putin-critic-alexei-navalny-gets-19-more-years-added-his-prison-sentence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.05 00:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/05/9b0bc51f-adb4-4275-a049-e6c14134e50a_3960d5ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;被监禁的俄罗斯反对派政治家阿列克谢·纳瓦尔尼 (Alexei Navalny) 于 2019 年 被追加 19 年徒刑周五，他和他的支持者称，这起刑事案件是捏造的，目的是让他入狱并长期远离政治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;47 岁的纳瓦尔尼是弗拉基米尔·普京总统最激烈的国内批评者，已经在服刑。总共 11-1/2 年的欺诈和其他指控，他说也是伪造的。他的政治运动已被取缔，并被宣布为“极端主义”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他位于莫斯科以东约 235 公里的 Melekhovo 的 IK-6 流放地的一家法院于周五结束了对他的六项单独指控的审判，包括煽动和资助极端主义活动以及创建极端主义组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭闭门进行审判，音频质量非常差，几乎无法听清法官的讲话。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者没有被允许进入法庭，但可以在附近的一个特殊媒体室观看闭路电视的诉讼过程，尽管宣判后几乎立即切断了直播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纳瓦尔尼的团队表示，法官已将他的现有刑期延长 19 年。州检察官要求提供 20 份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳瓦尔尼穿着深色囚服，在律师的陪伴下，在听法官陈述时偶尔微笑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前博主、律师和腐败调查员他把自己塑造成一位政治烈士，他的目标是向俄罗斯人证明，抵抗普京是可能的，尽管要付出巨大的代价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一个新的、自由的、富裕的国家要诞生，它必须拥有父母。那些想要它的人。谁期待它，谁愿意为它的诞生做出牺牲，”纳瓦尔尼在上个月的闭幕词中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;被监禁的克里姆林宫评论家阿列克谢·纳瓦尔尼认为瓦格纳叛乱是一个“笑话”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;在周四发布在社交媒体上的一条消息中，纳瓦尔尼曾预测他将被判处长期监禁，但他表示这并不重要，因为他还受到单独的恐怖主义指控的威胁，这可能会导致他再被判处十年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳瓦尔尼称给予他额外监禁时间的目的是吓唬俄罗斯人，但敦促他们不要被吓倒，认真思考如何最好地抵制他所谓的“克里姆林宫里的恶棍和小偷”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些指控与他在俄罗斯境内现已不复存在的运动中所扮演的角色有关，当局指控该运动试图通过破坏社会政治局势稳定来煽动革命。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟谴责了所谓的另一场政治活动。积极的裁决并呼吁立即释放纳瓦尔尼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京自 1999 年以来一直掌权，预计将在 2024 年再次竞选六年总统任期。俄罗斯在俄罗斯发动了他所谓的“特别军事行动”乌克兰陷入了他所说的与西方的一场生死存亡之战，普京表示，该国保持团结至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月，普京命令 FSB 安全部门加大力度“识别并制止那些试图分裂和削弱我们社会的人的非法活动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳瓦尔尼在 2010 年代带领数万人走上街头反对普京统治，并于 2021 年 1 月被拘留从德国返回莫斯科后，他在那里接受了西方专家所说的苏联时代神经毒剂中毒的治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;克里姆林宫一度指责他与中央情报局合作破坏俄罗斯否认参与并否认迫害纳瓦尔尼。它将他描绘成破坏分子，并表示他从未代表过严肃的政治竞争，他的案件纯粹是法院的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳瓦尔尼的支持者将他视为俄罗斯版的南非纳尔逊·曼德拉 (Nelson Mandela)谁将有一天出狱治理国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong low-income households rose by 160,000 in 25 years up to 2021; poorest families make less than HK$4,700 a month]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3230062/hong-kong-low-income-households-rose-160000-25-years-2021-poorest-families-make-less-hk4700-month?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.04 22:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/04/96fa9f12-29c6-48a4-8a5c-946937772f60_bf12be66.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港低收入住户在25年里增加了16万户根据政府统计数据，到 2021 年，最贫困家庭的月收入仅为 4,700 港元（602 美元），低于 1996 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这些家庭中，近四分之三的成员是were not part of the labour force, according to a data analysis report released by the Legislative Council on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Society for Community Organisation (SoCO) attributed the high proportion of economically inactive households to the Covid-19 pandemic and warned that people unfit to work might be under-represented, urging authorities to enhance day care services and employers to allow more job flexibility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Legco report said the number of low-income households, which make up the lowest 20 per cent of income, increased by 44 per cent from 371,000 in 1996 to 534,300 in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The data showed that the median monthly income among low-income households dropped from HK$5,400 in 1996 to HK$4,700 in 2021, despite a slight increase to HK$5,700 in 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the 25-year period, the proportion of economically inactive households among low-income families increased from 34 per cent to 74 per cent, representing close to 400,000 families.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among these families, 40 per cent, or nearly 160,000, were working-age households, meaning at least one member was under the age of 65. This marks a three-fold increase from the figure in 1996, when the number of working-age and economically inactive households was about 50,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Nearly 1 in 4 young Hongkongers from low-income families &#39;lying flat&#39;: survey&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;According to the report, the 160,000 households included more than 200,000 people, and 40 per cent, or 81,300, were homemakers and early retirees with no care responsibilities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It might be worth gaining a better understanding of the reasons why they were unable to, or had actively chosen not to participate in the labour market and [help] them overcome the relevant obstacles,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It would not only raise the prospect of improving the income situation of these low-income households, but might even alleviate to a certain extent the impact of a tight labour force on the local economy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report also noted a heavy reliance on social welfare among low-income households, with cash benefits accounting for more than 80 per cent of their household income in 2021, up from only 27 per cent in 1996.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong &#39;to offer 3,000 children after-school care &#39; under coming pilot scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Public expenditure on the cash benefits saw a fourfold increase to HK$70.6 billion in 2021.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sze Lai-shan, deputy director of SoCO, warned that people unable to work were likely to be under-represented in government statistics, stressing that most poor families were working hard to make ends meet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some people have physical conditions that prevent them from working long hours, but they have not managed to get a medical certificate for the issue,” she said, adding that homemaking duties prevented many women from participating in the labour market, especially those with big families.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;I hope my children will have a good life&#39;: what can Hong Kong do to break poverty cycle?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Those people struggle to find a job because the positions they are fit for, mostly labour-intensive ones, have long working hours and inflexible shifts , but they need to take care of their families at the same time,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many members of low-income households had lost their jobs during the Covid-19 pandemic and had to rely on welfare, and while many managed to eventually find employment, their pay was lower, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sze called on the government to bolster day care services to help low-income families, adding flexible arrangements were needed to cater to parents &#39; long working hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, employers should allow more flexible scheduling to provide more options for low-income workers, she added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s digital yuan ‘at forefront globally’, former central bank governor Yi Gang says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3230028/chinas-digital-yuan-forefront-globally-former-central-bank-governor-yi-gang-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.04 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/04/6d9d7b36-4e6a-4654-904f-f50f43921626_7a9a39f7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s former central bank governor used the final two lectures of his five-year tenure to highlight the digital yuan, hailing it as being “at the forefront globally”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yi Gang, 65, was formally replaced by 60-year-old Pan Gongsheng as the head of the People&#39;s Bank of China (PBOC) at the end of last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The digital yuan focuses on retail payments, which enables the most significant improvements in efficiency, payment system redundancy and advancing inclusive finance,” Yi said at Tsinghua University in Beijing on July 5, according to a transcript of the closed-door lecture released on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s digital currency, known as the e-CNY, could facilitate a wide range of domestic retail payments, including by foreign visitors, while it also has overseas use, added Yi.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China names new central bank governor as twice-a-decade finance conference nears&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The digital yuan, along with green finance initiatives, highlight Yi&#39;s legacy as central bank governor, in addition to traditional tasks of helping the coronavirus-hit economy, preventing financial risks and controlling inflation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yi is now the president of the Chinese Society for Finance and Banking, while he is also a deputy director under a government advisory body, the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With Pan now at the helm, the central bank pledged during its midyear work conference this week that it will continue pushing research and trials of the digital yuan, while also enhancing its financial infrastructure and services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China was the one of the first major economies to study a central bank digital currency, with a research institute chartered under the PBOC in 2016 preceding moves by the European Central Bank and the US Federal Reserve.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PBOC has designed a two-tier centralised digital yuan, which is primarily used for retail payments, with pilot schemes conducted in 17 provinces.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has managed anonymity in payments to ease market concerns over privacy, and it wants to dilute its store of value function “because it will generate other problems”, Yi added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PBOC will also prioritise monetary sovereignty in cross-border use of the digital yuan, aiming to increase efficiency and lower costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of March, 891.86 billion yuan (US$124 billion) has been spent across 750 million digital yuan transactions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around 100 million e-wallets have also been opened through the digital yuan app, with a total balance of 8.67 billion yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The promotion of the e-CNY should be market oriented, not by administrative orders,” Yi told a lecture hosted by the Monetary Authority of Singapore on July 19.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The e-CNY will coexist with physical cash for a long time. As long as there&#39;s demand for physical cash, the PBOC shall not stop the supply.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s digital yuan has been used in a variety of payment scenarios, from shopping, utility bill payment, payroll and cross-border transactions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June, a new e-CNY exchange machine was set up in the holiday resort of Sanya on the island province of Hainan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It facilitates the exchange of 20 different currencies for digital yuan, offering foreign visitors access to a local mobile payments ecosystem.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 major political parties call for justice department to appeal against court dismissal of ‘Glory to Hong Kong’ ban bid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3230063/3-major-political-parties-call-justice-department-appeal-against-court-dismissal-glory-hong-kong-ban?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.04 23:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/04/a97e8ad5-c839-4408-b7ab-e985741ad078_40fa4308.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Politicians from three major Hong Kong parties have petitioned the Department of Justice to appeal a court&#39;s dismissal of a government bid to ban the promotion of a protest anthem that became popular during the 2019 social unrest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A source close to the government told the Post the administration would probably appeal against the High Court&#39;s rejection of its application for an injunction to ban the promotion of “Glory to Hong Kong”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawmakers from the Democratic Alliance for the Betterment and Progress of Hong Kong (DAB), the Hong Kong Federation of Trade Unions (FTU) and the Liberal Party posted on Facebook within hours of each other on Friday asking government lawyers to consider an appeal against the ruling.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawmakers from the three political groups said there was a need for the government to outlaw the protest song once and for all and denied that they had coordinated their calls for an appeal to be lodged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liberal Party chairman Peter Shiu Ka-fai told the Post the government was forced to resort to legal action because search engines and streaming platforms had refused to remove the song.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Hong Kong government has already expressed the inappropriateness of this song. [ …] If self-discipline [among online platforms] resolves the issue, we don&#39;t need to resort to an injunction,” Shiu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court ruling questioned the effectiveness of a ban and highlighted that the publication and distribution of the song was punishable under laws already on the books.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The judgment added a ban might not compel internet search giant Google and other technology firms to remove the song from their services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Mr Justice Anthony Chan Kin-keung said he would have ruled in favour of the government had it not been for these problems and the injunction&#39;s lack of usefulness,&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan maintained the potential chilling effects of a ban would not outweigh the fundamental need to safeguard national security.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong court dismisses government bid to ban protest song&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Shiu said he was convinced the government would not have applied for an injunction if existing legislation, such as the national security law, could have been used instead.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Holden Chow Ho-ding, the DAB vice-chairman and a lawyer, also rejected Chan&#39;s argument about the potential chilling effects of the injunction in a Facebook post on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He told the Post later he found the legal reasons behind the ruling faulty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is ubiquitously known that this song is used to promote Hong Kong&#39;s independence. This is completely a national security problem, why would freedom of speech be dragged into this?” he said on Facebook.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chow warned that the court ruling could also set a legal precedent for future cases if the government decided not to appeal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kingsley Wong Kwok, the FTU chairman, said it would be a mistake to drop the battle for an injunction and risk national security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think the government, courts and the judiciary all need to deal with this problem. We should not sacrifice national security over technical issues, for the nation&#39;s security is the bottom line,” Wong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A justice department spokesman on Friday said officials would study the judgment and consider the next move.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;AmCham hails court rejection of bid to ban &#39;Glory to Hong Kong&#39; protest song&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Justice Paul Lam Ting-kwok lodged the application last month in a bid to bar promotion of “Glory to Hong Kong” through “broadcasting, performing, printing, publishing, selling, offering for sale, distributing, disseminating, displaying or reproducing in any way”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The authorities maintain the song contained lyrics that threatened national security, such as an appeal to “Liberate Hong Kong” in a “revolution of our times”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The expression was found to be capable of carrying a secessionist meaning in the city&#39;s first national security trial.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Glory to Hong Kong” was played by mistake instead of the Chinese national anthem “March of the Volunteers” at several overseas sports events.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The anti-government song gained popularity among Hong Kong&#39;s mostly young protesters soon after its creation during the unrest triggered by a now-withdrawn extradition bill.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan boy band producer Johnny Kitagawa’s abuse victims deserve apologies and compensation, says UN]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3230061/japan-boy-band-producer-johnny-kitagawas-abuse-victims-deserve-apologies-and-compensation-says-un?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.04 22:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/04/23226be7-2c2c-430b-96af-3be590837737_3f733f81.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The men who came forward to allege they were sexually abused as teenagers by Japanese boy band producer Johnny Kitagawa now have a powerful listener: the United Nations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Damilola Olawuyi, chair of the UN Working Group on Business and Human Rights, told reporters on Friday that the number of victims may total several hundred, and he accused Japan&#39;s mainstream media of standing silent about the alleged abuse for decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Olawuyi raised serious questions about the sincerity of the response from the talent agency Kitagawa founded, Johnny &amp; Associates. He urged other entertainment industry players to carry out a “transparent and legitimate investigation with a clear timeline”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Junya Hiramoto, one of seven men who talked with Olawuyi&#39;s team, was moved to tears by the UN official&#39;s remarks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I felt our message had been clearly relayed,” he said. “They gave me such courage.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pichamon Yeophantong, a member of the UN group who appeared with Olawuyi at the Japan National Press Club in Tokyo, urged the Japanese government to do more.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This case highlights the need for the government, as the primary duty-bearer, to ensure transparent investigations of perpetrators and that victims obtain effective remedies, be they in the form of an apology or financial compensation,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Olawuyi and other experts have been in Japan since July 24. They met with government officials, human rights advocates, trade unions and companies, to learn about how businesses may be violating human rights and harming the environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A full report is set to be presented to the UN Human Rights Council in June, which will include recommendations for change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Foremost on the Working Group&#39;s agenda was the men who allege they were sexually abused as children by Kitagawa, who was a powerful figure in Japan&#39;s entertainment industry before he died in 2019, in his 80s. The head of Johnny &amp; Associates apologised in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Critics say what happened at Johnny&#39;s, as the company is known in Japan, is shameful and indicative of how the nation, apparently a democratic and economic powerhouse, lags behind in its protection of human rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The men who have come forward say Kitagawa abused them in his Tokyo luxury mansion, as well as in other places like his car and overseas hotels, while they performed as dancers and singers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kitagawa was never charged. He was revered over the years, although allegations about abuse popped up now and then, only to be eventually shrugged off.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What is the worst case of sexual abuse in the history of humankind is seeing the light of day,” said Shimon Ishimaru, one of the seven accusers to go public. “这个问题是真实存在的。 It really happened.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Johnny&#39;s, which is still thriving, set up an investigative panel, but what it plans to achieve has been unclear. Ishimaru and others said they were sceptical because they had not received the mental healthcare the company promised.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to a request for comment, Johnny &amp; Associates said all matters are being dealt with as part of the investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a BBC documentary about Kitagawa aired this year, musician Kauan Okamoto spoke in April at the Foreign Correspondents&#39; Club in Tokyo, the first person in decades to make such allegations under his real name.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Associated Press does not usually identify people who say they were sexually assaulted, but Kitagawa&#39;s recent accusers decided to be named publicly in news accounts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kitagawa filed a libel suit against weekly magazine Shukan Bunshun after it published a series of 1999 articles based on anonymous interviews with former performers who said he forced them to have sex.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few years later, Japan&#39;s Supreme Court upheld an appeals court finding in favour of Shukan Bunshun, saying the accusers&#39; testimonies were reliable, and what they said had really happened.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Sex abuse report casts shadow over Pope Francis&#39; Portugal visit&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;What Japan does now may end up being a litmus test for a country where legal revision that officially banned violence against children kicked in only three years ago and reports of child abuse and neglect of children are rampant. Japan raised the age of sexual consent from 13 to 16 only this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Akimasa Nihongi, one of the seven men who spoke with the UN officials, said people like him had suffered enough. He praised the UN&#39;s actions as a big step forward.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A collective voice can ring loud and clear,” Nihongi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The UN Working Group sincerely listened to what we said. And they have now spoken.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 22:50:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tibet plugs into high-altitude wind power technology]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3230046/tibet-plugs-high-altitude-wind-power-technology?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.04 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/04/86eb894f-0eb5-490e-ae4d-cf71dc6e9bae_6a64643a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The first phase of China&#39;s highest altitude wind farm has been plugged into Tibet&#39;s power grid, with plans to expand the system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The official Science and Technology Daily reported on Friday that the wind farm in Cuomei county, in the autonomous region&#39;s southeast, comprised a series of turbines installed at at least 5,000 metres (16,400 feet) above sea level.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The project has been developed by the China Three Gorges Corporation and, once completed, is expected to feed up to 200 million KWh into the grid each year, or enough power to meet the demand of almost 140,000 households, according to state broadcaster CCTV.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Liang, head of the Shannan branch of the corporation&#39;s Tibet Energy Investment, told CCTV that the turbines were optimised for the high-altitude environment, with each turbine blade longer than similar units built at lower altitudes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said the extra blade length would increase the area swept by the turbines by nearly 30 per cent, improving the system&#39;s wind efficiency in the low atmospheric pressure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Typically ultra-high wind farms built between 3,500 and 5,500 metres are considered ultra-high altitude.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Atmospheric pressure decreases with altitude, reducing the energy generated by wind turbines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Wang told CCTV that the project would prove the viability of ultra-high altitude wind projects, disproving the suggestion that winds in the area would be too weak to have any developmental value.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that 30 per cent of the Tibetan region had winds of at least 25km/h but these areas were mainly at altitudes of above 4,800 metres.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the US Energy Information Administration, speeds above 20.9km/h are viable for utility-scale turbines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said the project would lay the foundation for future farms and fill an industry gap.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Chunshan head of turbine technology at the farm, said the turbines had also been designed to withstand the harsh environment of the Tibetan Plateau.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The paint used on the surface of the turbines&#39; blades was highly elastic, making it resistant to the extreme weather on the plateau, Liu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Wang, the turbines are also resistant to low temperatures and ice, and fitted with lightning protection technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, the turbines were designed to limit their impact on the area&#39;s fragile environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The turbines were set further apart to have less impact on animal grazing and topsoil removed to install the turbines was set aside to be reused after the project is completed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Based on the success of the first phase, Wang said the company would continue investing in the technology and bring more turbines online at the farm in the future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that due to the weather and complex terrain, it took about two months to transport the parts for the turbines to the farm site. Detailed road surveys were conducted in order to complete the process, Wang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wind power installation has continued to rise in the first half of this year, with 10.4 gigawatts of newly installed capacity, according to the National Energy Administration. The total installed wind capacity in China reached 389GW as of the end of June.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 04 Aug 2023 22:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>