<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[9,500 Hong Kong drivers sign up for scheme to drive in mainland China, nearly 7 times quota limit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3222238/9500-hong-kong-drivers-sign-scheme-drive-mainland-china-nearly-7-times-quota-limit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 23:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/52016f57-ad1f-44c2-bda4-faa209d6d37c_df333ebe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;大约 9,500 名香港司机签署了一项扩展计划，通过周一开放注册时的巨型桥梁，几乎是 7 月启动第一周配额的七倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过投票赢得配额的人每人需要支付高达 3,000 港元据交通部官员称，相关文件、检查费和保险单等费用（383 美元），并符合一定条件后方可驾车过境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被称为“香港车辆北上行”的该计划将允许居民持自 7 月 1 日起有效期长达一年的许可证通过港珠澳大桥进入广东省。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至 2020 年 1 月 5 日下午 5 点，已收到约 9,500 份申请据交通运输部门称，星期一开始为那些希望在启动的第一周获得跨境驾驶执照的人开放为期两天的登记期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局已确定每天 200 辆汽车的配额第一周，第二周每天 300 个，以确保顺利开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管一个驾车者团体呼吁扩大配额，但交通官员周一表示，需要时间来观察该计划的实施情况&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运输及物流局说：“随着操作熟练程度的提高，我们会考虑提高日常处理能力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港人开车去内地需要知道的事新计划下的中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;第一轮投票的结果将于周三公布。未能获得名额的申请者可以在 6 月 5 日至 8 日期间通过指定网站重新注册。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邮政在周一上午 10 点开始注册后半小时尝试注册，系统显示超过 2,000排队等待的用户，大约需要 20 分钟才能进入登记页面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;运输署表示，由于软件故障，一些车主无法在早上登记网上投票，但问题已在下午 1 点 30 分得到解决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在投票中获胜的司机需要提交正式的跨境驾驶执照申请并提交电子格式的文件，包括车辆登记文件，Hong香港身份证及内地通行证。如果车辆的车龄在六年或以上，还必须提交由该市指定的汽车检测中心颁发的适航证书。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;让更多香港司机通过巨型桥梁的计划面临两个障碍：专家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;要符合该计划的资格，车辆还必须通过中国检验公司（经国务院批准的检测、认证和鉴定机构）的许可。香港唯一认可的跨境车辆检测机构位于元朗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司已将其每日检测限额从报告的 300 辆增加到 700 辆，该局表示正在讨论措施&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;申请者还需提前亲自到广东办理内地驾照，并满足本市和跨境的保险要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，该局表示已注意到广东停车场闸机扫描系统目前无法读取香港车牌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但表示已向内地提交不同的香港车牌样本当局供参考，并表示有信心在 7 月 1 日之前解决这个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会议员、中文大学工程学院副院长黄锦辉教授说：“修改现有的识别系统大陆的停车场并不复杂。只要内地当局要求停车场经营者这样做，就可以迅速完成。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港为安全跨境驾驶做好准备&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该计划还要求私人车主购买内地机动车交通强制责任保险，保障限额为人民币 20 万元（合 25,525 美元），提供第三方伤害和财产损失保障。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法会议员陈培良，兼任中国太平保险香港总经理的他表示，车主还应考虑购买商业汽车保险来补足保费，以弥补他们的损失和第三方责任，最高保额为 1000 万元人民币。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他提醒车主，若在内地发生意外，应立即报警、拍照并联络保险公司，安排本地全程理赔服务。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Iranian female journalist goes on trial on charges linked to Mahsa Amini protests]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3222233/iranian-female-journalist-goes-trial-charges-linked-mahsa-amini-protests?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 22:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/65116ae1-2fe3-43cd-afef-fd30bb6a3265_14df1f09.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名伊朗记者周一接受闭门审判，罪名是与她的报道有关一名库尔德-伊朗妇女的葬礼，她的律师告诉 ILNA 通讯社，她去年在拘留期间死亡引发了数月的骚乱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;22 岁的 Mahsa Amini 在拘留期间死亡警方因涉嫌违反伊斯兰着装规定而在伊朗各地引发了数月来的大规模抗议浪潮，这是伊朗神职人员领导人几十年来面临的最大挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Elaheh Mohammadi 在她的库尔德家乡 Saqez 报道了阿米尼的葬礼，那里抗议开始了。伊朗伊斯兰共和国指责其外国敌人煽动抗议活动，破坏该国稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;伊朗逮捕记者，拘留 80 多名媒体工作者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“对 Elaheh Mohammadi 的审判进展顺利。下一次开庭的日期将由法院宣布，”她的律师 Shahabeddin Mirlohi 告诉 ILNA。记者无法立即联系到他发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在德黑兰受审的支持改革的哈米汉报记者穆罕默迪和 Sharq 报的另一名记者尼卢法尔哈梅迪被指控“与敌对势力勾结”，以报道阿米尼之死。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据伊斯兰法律，这项指控可能会被判处死刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊朗情报部 10 月发表的联合声明指控穆罕默迪和Hamedi 是 CIA 的外国特工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamedi 拍下了 Amini 的父母在德黑兰一家医院里互相拥抱的照片，他们的女儿躺在医院里昏迷不醒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这张照片由 Hamedi 发布在 Twitter 上，这是向世界发出的第一个信号，表明三天前被伊朗道德警察拘留的阿米尼并非一帆风顺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两名记者被关押在伊朗臭名昭著的埃文监狱中自去年九月起，将分别审理。根据司法机构的说法，哈梅迪的审判将于周二开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伊斯兰共和国无视人权组织一再要求对这两名记者进行公开审判的呼吁。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China eyes trillion-yuan output in civilian nuclear sector by 2025, with big industrial and economic gains]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3222212/china-eyes-trillion-yuan-output-civilian-nuclear-sector-2025-big-industrial-and-economic-gains?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/f1c29895-8831-4750-a68d-4adcff5c3240_b40fc2bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国正寻求开辟万亿元的核技术市场，民用-根据中国核能协会 (CNEA) 最近的一份报告，未来几年的重点用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了军事和能源用途之外，该评估反映了北京相信核能进步具有潜力通过在医疗、工业、环保和其他民用领域的更广泛使用，成为经济增长的更大引擎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到 2025 年实现 1 万亿元人民币（1,410 亿美元）的目标将进一步推动新兴的产值从2015年的3000亿元增长到2022年的7000亿元，占去年中国国内生产总值（GDP）的0.57%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;核技术的应用通常是民用的和非电力相关，它们包括辐射和同位素技术。例如，根据世界核协会的说法，制造商可以使用放射性同位素来监测流体的流动、检测泄漏并确定设备是否已经退化或腐蚀。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国的制造业发展如何，还有哪些仍然存在需要做什么？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据上周在 2023 年国际会议期间发布的报告，在中国，超过 50% 的市场用于工业用途，约 20% 用于医疗用途浙江省核技术应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;核技术还可以用于鉴别和评价不同材料的性质；测量污染水平；对组件进行灭菌和消毒；监控和优化工业流程；根据国际原子能机构的说法，改变化学、物理和生物特性以生产新型材料，而辐射可用于分析和处理一系列物质。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，CNEA 报告还指出，中国在高端设备和关键材料方面仍然严重依赖进口，这意味着需要更多的投资和创新来增强国家在该领域的自力更生能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球 150 多个国家和地区已经开展报告称，该技术的相关研究和产业发展。在一些商业模式更成熟、市场集中度更高的发达国家，相关产业产值占GDP的比重超过2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家经济研究中心还指出，我国产业存在的短板包括缺乏顶层规划；高端核探测器和医用同位素依赖进口；过时的分析技术； &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“核技术产业的发展，不仅需要产业政策的支持和引导，更离不开行业内的合作与交流，” CNEA 副理事长兼秘书长张廷科上周在官方媒体《经济参考报》上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的行业参与者应该开展联合研究，共同突破各种障碍。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报告称，核技术应用的进一步发展应以创新驱动，需要加大研发投入实现核心技术的自主可控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;并表示，要更多地应用这些技术来推动传统产业升级改造，同时支持新兴产业的发展。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong protests: 7 plead guilty to rioting as case over Legco storming begins]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3222235/hong-kong-protests-7-plead-guilty-rioting-case-over-legco-storming-begins?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 23:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/630e104c-12f6-4420-8e33-765486bdd02a_b7559a4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;七名抗议者在暴风雨审判开始时承认了骚乱指控在反政府抗议活动高峰期对香港立法会大楼进行了调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官已就 2019 年 7 月 1 日的事件对 14 人提出指控，其中包括 2019 年 7 月 1 日在地方法院认罪的人。星期一是抗议活动组织者刘永康和前学生领袖 Althea Suen。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五名被告否认骚乱指控，包括演员黄宗耀，但他承认擅自闯入立法会会议厅，因为&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其余两名被告人的案件将在稍后处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭获悉，逾千名示威者于下午早些时候聚集在立法会大楼外当年 7 月 1 日，并多次试图用储物车和金属棒砸碎建筑物外墙的玻璃墙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抗议活动恰逢香港从英国移交给中国统治周年纪念日。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;根据 7 名认罪的被告同意的控方案件摘要，抗议者在晚上 9 点之前从公共入口进入大楼，并在内部捣毁了几个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一旦进入会议厅内，抗议者喷漆了立法会主席讲台后面墙上展示的香港标志。会议厅内的几台监视器也被砸碎，电缆也被撕裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在警方表示将清理该地区后，大多数抗议者在午夜后离开了大楼。第二天凌晨 1 点左右，警察进入该建筑群，并没有发现里面有示威者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市立法机构最终花费 36,284,116 港元（4,630,869 美元）修复抗议者造成的破坏，包括更换 45 块玻璃检方说，大楼的一楼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在法庭上出示的证据中，有一段采访一名抗议者的视频，当时抗议者希望留在会议厅内，尽管警察警告警察会进入&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及是否同意检方的案情摘要时，被告人刘在法庭上表示，他“特别同意‘没有暴徒，只有暴政’的部分”，促使法官：重复这个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港抗议：市领导拒绝设定结束警方调查的最后期限&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;抗议者在围困期间在总统讲台上竖起的横幅上写着口号，控方摘要中描述的其中一起破坏公物的事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前香港大学学生会主席苏恩在审讯前的 Facebook 帖子中表示，她会认罪，并补充说：“我从不后悔为自由、正义和民主而战。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她也感谢那些支持和关心她的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;决定不申请的苏恩申请保释，在被带走之前向法庭内的支持者挥手致意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了 Amy Pat Wai-fan 外，七名承认骚乱指控的人的其他指控也被撤销，她也认罪&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭已定下 44 天的审讯时间表，控方计划传唤不到 20 名证人，其中包括立法会秘书长陈伟安。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;法庭还将听取五名警员就被告人林锦群对其口供方式提出质疑的证词。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港抗议活动：3 人因来自九龙中部的骚乱&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;要提供的其他证据是一段 11 小时的视频，该视频汇集了来自各种来源的片段，记录了全天发生的事件。被告帕特通过她的律师要求她本周晚些时候出庭观看视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;审判将继续进行，周二检方将提交开庭陈述。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 14 名被告中，何俊彦没有提出抗辩，因为他的律师早些时候表示，他因精神健康原因不适合这样做。下周将传唤四名医学专家证人出庭作证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一名反对派活动人士欧文周嘉诚将因涉嫌 10 月骚乱而面临审判，原因是与国家安全审判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反政府抗议活动是由拟议的引渡法案引发的，该法案允许将嫌疑人转移到中国大陆和其他司法管辖区。政府最终放弃了该提议。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Sudan bloodshed may see 1 million flee: UN]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3222236/sudan-bloodshed-may-see-1-million-flee-un?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 23:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/a5f5cb50-790f-4c9e-b25f-d6af114b3169_616055e9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;估计大约有 100 万人可能会在 10 月逃离苏丹，这可能是保守的，那里可能会发生冲突联合国难民署负责人周一表示，在脆弱地区贩运人口和扩散武器的风险增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自军队与准军事组织快速支援部队之间发生战争以来，已有超过 350,000 人逃离苏丹边境部队 (RSF) 于 4 月 15 日爆发，其中大部分前往埃及、乍得和南苏丹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苏丹境内有超过 100 万人流离失所，苏丹拥有 4900 万人口，激烈的战斗已经撕裂穿过首都喀土穆的居民区，达尔富尔西部地区也爆发了暴力事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;难民署负责人菲利普·格兰迪 (Filippo Grandi) 预计，六个月内将有大约 80 万苏丹人和 20 万其他国籍的人离开苏丹在访问苏丹边境后在开罗接受采访时说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种预测，即在未来几个月内我们将达到这些高数字，甚至可能是保守的，”他说。 “一开始我不相信会这样，但现在我开始担心了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与苏丹接壤的国家包括南苏丹、中非共和国、埃塞俄比亚和利比亚，都受到了影响&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苏丹法律和秩序的崩溃以及“许多人迫切希望继续前进”将为人口贩运提供肥沃的土壤，而跨境流通的武器可能会引发更多暴力，格兰迪说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在萨赫勒地区的利比亚看到了这一点。我们不希望重蹈覆辙，因为这将加剧危机和人道主义问题，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国已呼吁为其难民应对苏丹危机筹集 4.7 亿美元在六个多月的时间里，格兰迪说只有 1% 的资金到位，并补充说“非常需要”捐助者认捐会议，而国际社会对乌克兰的关注没有给予足够的重视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你可以清楚地感觉到一种非常危险的差距。这场危机有可能破坏整个地区乃至整个地区的稳定，就像乌克兰在欧洲所做的那样，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格兰迪说，联合国难民署正试图在苏丹北部的瓦迪哈尔法镇建立办事处，那里许多 16-50 岁的苏丹男性在申请进入埃及的签证时遇到困难，但他不确定何时可以。妇女、儿童和老人不需要签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;联合国粮食机构在​​ 3 名员工在战斗中丧生后停止了在苏丹的行动&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他还表示，需要将援助物资运送到两者之间的缓冲区埃及和苏丹边境哨所的逃亡者也面临着漫长的等待。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自冲突开始以来，已有近 16 万人从苏丹越境进入埃及，那里已经是一个庞大的苏丹社区的家园。&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong gas firm and government team up to produce hydrogen for heavy transport fuel]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3222228/hong-kong-gas-firm-and-government-team-produce-hydrogen-heavy-transport-fuel?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/d6e115bd-0c5a-4316-8b8a-84505255a76a_2fad745c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港将在试点项目下首批国产氢气用于运输由能源公司 Towngas 和市政当局运营的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Towngas 周一表示，它已经启动了一项从煤气中提取氢气的试验性计划，以利用政府主导的项目，该项目将于今年启动，利用元素作为一种更绿色的能源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市唯一的天然气供应商表示，3 月份进行的一项关于从现有天然气供应中提取氢气的可行性研究可能会达到 99.99% 的纯度水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;该公司补充说，其 3,700 公里（2,300 英里）的地下管网可以为客户提供“安全高效”的氢能，避免与道路交通相关的潜在风险并节省运输成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纯氢气可用于为目前电动汽车技术可能无法覆盖的重型车辆提供燃料，例如双层巴士、垃圾车和轮船。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中华煤气对香港氢能的未来持乐观态度总经理 Don Cheng Hill-kwong 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，这些利益相关者包括香港政府、巴士运营商和环保组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheng表示，该公司在处理天然气和氢气方面 160 年的业绩记录将确保提取工厂的安全性和可靠性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他拒绝透露更多细节，例如时间表和成本，尽管他表示需要 12 年才能完成15 个月建成一个加氢站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财政司司长陈茂波在上一份预算中表示，他将拨出 2 亿港元（2550 万美元）用于新能源交通基金，以开展今年对氢燃料电池双层巴士和重型巴士进行了试验。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;煤气公司准备为巴士公司向低排放氢气过渡提供燃料&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府早些时候设立了一个跨部门工作组负责处理立法修正案以允许使用氢气汽车，因为氢气目前被视为危险物质，而不是能源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环境及生态署署长 Diane Wong Shuk-韩上周表示，该部正计划起草《气体安全条例》的修正案，并预计将于 2025 年向立法会提交提案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;煤气目前依赖于从天然气、石脑油和沼气中收集的天然气、石脑油和沼气香港三个正在使用的垃圾填埋场生产城市燃气，用于为炉灶和热水器提供燃料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;燃料由 50% 的氢气、30% 的甲烷和 20% 的二氧化碳组成。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司的“变压吸附技术”可以在压力下从气体混合物中分离出氢气，因为所涉及的分子特性不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市政当局和电力公司已争先恐后地实现碳中和到 2050 年的目标。习近平主席承诺实现“双碳”目标——到 2030 年达到碳排放峰值，到 2060 年实现碳中和。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港大学推动更便宜、更耐用的氢燃料电池&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;Cheng 表示，港华燃气正在研究从澳大利亚和沙特阿拉伯等地购买绿色氢气的可能性，以逐步取代其能源结构中使用的化石燃料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环保组织绿色和平组织向港华燃气发出呼吁就其计划如何转向清洁能源使用提供更清晰的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前的计划仍然不利于碳减排，”该组织活动家 Tom Ng Hon-lam 说。 “如果煤气公司想帮助减少碳排放，它应该使用绿色氢气，而不是灰色氢气。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Natixis Corporate and Investment Bank 高级经济学家 Gary Ng Cheuk-yan 表示，煤气公司的举动强调了需要以在煤气销量下降的情况下实现收入来源多元化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人们的生活方式偏好可能已经改变，导致家庭用气量减少，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “政府倾向于电力 [for energy transition] 也可能给 Towngas 带来问题。但这不仅仅发生在香港。许多其他地方也发生过这种情况。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;煤气公司的统计数据显示，近年来天然气销量呈下降趋势，从 2018 年的峰值 29,550 太焦耳降至去年的 27,398 太焦耳。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Plastic pollution talks begin in Paris with 175 nations: ‘world’s eyes are on us’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3222226/plastic-pollution-talks-begin-paris-175-nations-worlds-eyes-are-us?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 21:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/91fcb63a-44f7-463e-9b65-fd29bf7167a6_19e928d6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;法国总统埃马纽埃尔·马克龙周一警告说，全球塑料污染是一颗“定时炸弹” ，外交官们在巴黎开始了为期五天的会谈，以期就终止塑料垃圾的条约取得进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;175 个国家的代表在联合国教科文组织总部举行了会议，目标各不相同，旨在取得进展，通过明年，一项涵盖整个塑料生命周期的历史性协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谈判开始时，谈判负责人、秘鲁外交官古斯塔沃·梅萨-夸德拉·贝拉斯克斯 (Gustavo Meza-Cuadra Velazquez) 表示，挑战是“巨大的，因为我们都意识到这里，但并非无法克服。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“世界的目光都在注视着我们，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克龙敦促参与国结束今天的“全球化和不可持续的”生产模式，较富裕的国家向较贫穷的国家出口塑料废物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“塑料污染是一颗定时炸弹，同时在今天已经成为祸害，”他在一段视频信息中说，并补充说基于化石燃料的材料对全球变暖目标以及生物多样性和人类健康构成威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，谈判的首要任务应该是减少塑料生产并“尽快禁止”尽可能”生产一次性塑料等污染最严重的产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考虑到塑料年产量在 20 年内翻了一番以上，达到 4.6 亿吨，而且有望在 40 年内增长两倍，因此风险很高.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此输出的三分之二在使用一次或几次后被丢弃，最终成为废物。超过五分之一被非法倾倒或焚烧，只有不到 10% 被回收利用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国环境规划署负责人 Inger Andersen 告诉代表们，一次性塑料文化正在“大量排放污染，窒息我们的生态系统，使气候变暖，损害我们的健康”，而最脆弱的人受到的打击最大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“事实是，我们无法通过循环利用来摆脱这种混乱局面，”她大声告诉代表们掌声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 2 月，各国原则上同意需要一项具有法律约束力的联合国条约来结束世界各地的塑料污染，并设定了雄心勃勃的 2024 年最后期限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴黎会议一直持续到 6 月 2 日，是该过程中五场会议中的第二场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会谈期间将讨论的政策行动包括全球禁止使用一次性塑料制品、“污染者付费”计划，以及对新塑料生产征税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环保组织对全球塑料污染最终得到解决感到鼓舞，但担心该条约可能不包括减少整体塑料生产的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“冲浪者基金会的倡导者黛安·博梅奈-乔安内 (Diane Beaumenay-Joannet) 告诉法新社，他们对所涉问题和采取行动的意愿达成了共识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环保主义者也对行业游说的影响表示担忧&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塑料无处不在：包装、衣服、建筑材料、医疗工具，甚至尿布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在自然界中，在北极附近的冰和鱼体内发现了微塑料在海洋最深、最黑暗的隐蔽处航行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在人类的血液、母乳和胎盘中检测到微小的塑料碎片。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“北极正在消亡”：严酷警告最大的北极任务&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;塑料也导致全球变暖：2019 年塑料产生了 18 亿吨温室气体，占全球排放量的 3.4%，根据经合组织的数据，到 2060 年这一数字可能会翻一番以上.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东道国法国周六与 60 个国家组织了一次部长级峰会以启动会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们现在不采取行动，到 2050 年会有更多的塑料法国外交部长凯瑟琳·科隆纳 (Catherine Colonna) 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Velazquez 呼吁代表们搁置分歧，努力达成一项“本质上公平，必要时有效”的协议。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;各国之间已经存在分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;18 个月过去了，斯里兰卡需要解决“最大的危险船舶灾难”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一个所谓的雄心勃勃的联盟以卢旺达和挪威为首的 50 个国家，包括欧盟、加拿大、智利和——就在几天前——日本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但许多国家不愿以绝对减产为目标，坚称回收和更好的废物管理是答案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些国家包括中国、美国、沙特阿拉伯和其他欧佩克国家，它们都拥有大型石化工业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会谈还将看到富国和发展中国家之间同样的紧张关系困扰着联合国关于气候和生物多样性的谈判，特别是在发展援助、技术共享和融资渠道方面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“发达国家——最大的消费者和最大的污染者——已经Beaumenay-Joannet 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US, Australian military staff tour China’s Beijing garrison despite freeze on top brass talks]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3222205/us-australian-military-staff-tour-chinas-beijing-garrison-despite-freeze-top-brass-talks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/c0a537e8-88cf-4a13-a593-0450d74a2dd6_10e861d1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;数十名受邀参观人民大会堂的武官中包括美国和澳大利亚的武官周四，解放军在北京的驻军，这是自大流行以来的首次此类活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次访问之际，美国表示不会考虑解除对中国国防部长李尚福的制裁，以为本周在新加坡香格里拉对话会上与美国国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀会面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;观察人士表示，解放军地面部队的邀请表明中国愿意与西方军队进行定期军事交流。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;国防部表示，中国国防部长将在香格里拉对话会上发表讲话&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;地面部队在其微信社交媒体账号上表示，来自 43 个大使馆的 50 多名武官和官员参加了此次访问周日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;部队进行了拳击、枪械演练和反恐训练示范，并带领参观者参观了军官宿舍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;地面部队表示，这是他们首次进行的参观活动自 Covid-19 大流行以来为外国同行组织，标志着中国在“和平发展”的目标下努力促进与其他国家的相互了解、加深互信和建立友谊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研究员周晨明与总部设在北京的远望军事科技智库表示，邀请是向华盛顿发出的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北京希望通过恢复军事交流来告诉华盛顿：不要混淆军事- 与政治进行军事交流，不要使用‘制裁’给你的对手制造麻烦，”周说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民解放军与美国同行保持着中层接触和沟通，但the sanctions on Li have blocked high-level communications between the two militaries since Li was promoted to defence minister in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has also ignored requests by US Indo-Pacific commander Admiral John Aquilino and Austin to speak to or meet their Chinese counterparts, according to US military officers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Song Zhongping, a former PLA instructor, said the garrison tour did not amount to “bilateral face-to-face engagement” – the kind of contact that promoted trust.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In military diplomacy areas, bilateral in-person engagement shows good levels of trust on both sides, which is more valuable and effective than the kind of routine and multiple exchanges [on the garrison tour] ,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ni Lexiong, a professor in the department of political science at Shanghai University of Political Science and Law, agreed the tour was routine but the inclusion of the US and other Western countries indicated “the PLA retains an open attitude to future cooperation with the US and Australia”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PLA statement highlighted the host division&#39;s history as an elite fighting force and its involvement in the anti-Japanese and Korean wars.&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong security chief warns troublemakers ahead of June 4 anniversary, as pro-Beijing groups deny Victoria Park carnival aimed at blocking any vigil]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3222227/hong-kong-security-chief-warns-troublemakers-ahead-june-4-anniversary-pro-beijing-groups-deny?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 22:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/2fcd7326-d69b-4834-9800-f743334573aa_0c3a7447.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s security chief has warned that authorities will take “resolute action” against anyone taking advantage of “a special occasion” to threaten national security as the 34th anniversary of the Tiananmen Square crackdown approaches on Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The warning by Secretary for Security Chris Tang Ping-keung on Monday came as a pro-Beijing group denied that a carnival it was co-hosting this weekend at Victoria Park, where residents had gathered to mark June 4 in the past, was intended to block any possible commemoration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking to the press without naming the June 4 vigil, Tang said: “A very special occasion will arrive in the next few days. Many people might want to take advantage of this special occasion to do things that could threaten national security, such as promoting Hong Kong independence or seeking to subvert state power.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I would like to tell these people: if you attempt to do such acts, we will take resolute action, arrest you and charge you if there is sufficient evidence.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked whether it would be illegal for residents to wear black or hold a candle in Victoria Park on Sunday, Tang said authorities would take into account the intention and behaviour of the individuals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For decades, residents held a candlelight vigil in the park in Causeway Bay every June 4 to remember those killed in the crackdown in Beijing. The event was organised by the Hong Kong Alliance in Support of Patriotic Democratic Movements of China, which disbanded in 2021, and would regularly attract tens of thousands of residents.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong security chief says seizing of sculpture unrelated to June 4 anniversary&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But authorities refused to grant permission for the event in 2020 and 2021, citing the risks to public health posed by the Covid-19 pandemic. No organisation tried to host the vigil in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, three of the alliance&#39;s core leaders were found guilty of failing to assist a police investigation into the group&#39;s suspected violation of the national security law and jailed for four and a half months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year, 26 pro-Beijing federations will jointly host the carnival at Victoria Park from Saturday to Monday. Admission is HK$5 (64 US cents) and residents must pay using their stored-value Octopus card.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stretching across four football pitches, the event will feature cultural dances and musical performances, as well as about 200 booths selling traditional handicrafts and snacks, according to the organiser.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spokesman for the organisers on Monday denied the carnival was being held to block other uses of the space.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The idea had never occurred to us. It is just a coincidence,” said Tang Ching-ho, also the first executive chairman of the Federation of Hong Kong Guangdong Community Organisations. “We hope our carnival can help boost the economy, bring happiness to Hong Kong people and achieve social harmony.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added that organisers intended to hold the carnival around the same time as the anniversary of Hong Kong&#39;s handover, which is on July 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ching-ho declined to discuss the security measures authorities would have in place in case of protests or whether they would disallow people wearing clothes or holding props associated with June 4 to enter the carnival venue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A police spokesman said the force would not comment on operational deployments, nor would he say whether the carnival organisers had contacted them for help in managing the crowd.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Richard Tsoi Yiu-cheong, a former key member of the alliance, said he was not aware of any group trying to organise activities to mark June 4 this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;[This] is almost impossible given the prevailing political climate,” he said, adding groups had faced difficulties in trying to apply for permission to stage public events in recent months.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nvidia founder tells Taiwan graduates to seize the ‘golden opportunities’ of the AI revolution, which has only just begun]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3222199/nvidia-founder-tells-taiwan-graduates-seize-golden-opportunities-ai-revolution-which-has-only-just?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/55f7f6cf-0981-43d7-87a6-968da44e8fcf_8d0b1bb4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Nvidia founder and CEO Jensen Huang Jen-hsun told 2023 graduates of the National Taiwan University (NTU) that they should seize the “golden opportunities” of an artificial intelligence (AI) revolution, with the technology set to change every business.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While some worry that AI may take their jobs … AI will create new jobs that didn&#39;t exist before” such as data engineering, prompt engineering and AI safety engineers, Huang, an honorary doctor of NTU since 2020, said in a commencement address in front of about 10,000 students at the university in Taipei on Saturday. “In every way, this is a rebirth of the computer industry. And a golden opportunity for the companies of Taiwan,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Just as I was with the PC and chip revolution, you&#39;re at the beginning, at the starting line of AI. Every industry will be revolutionised,” said Huang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He encouraged the students to “run” hard and seize opportunities from the AI revolution. “Whatever it is, run after it like we did. Run. Don&#39;t walk. Either you&#39;re running for food, or you are running from being food.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nvidia has recently surged to become the most valued chip company in the world, exceeding Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co (TSMC), with its key products, such as H100 graphic processing units (GPUs), in hot demand as interest in AI ramps up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang&#39;s speech came after Nvidia last Thursday posted net profit of more than US$2 billion and US$7 billion in sales in the first quarter of its 2024 financial year, both higher than industry estimates.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Nvidia says China a &#39;very important&#39; market as AI fuels huge demand for its chips&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wearing a black graduation robe with the university&#39;s plum-blossom emblem instead of his iconic black leather jacket, Huang started his speech by greeting students in Taiwanese but switched to English as he felt “nervous” about his “not standard” local dialect.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang, born in southern Taiwan&#39;s Tainan city in 1963, moved to the United States with his family at an early age. He received a bachelor&#39;s degree in electrical engineering from Oregon State University in 1984, and held various positions at computer chip maker LSI Logic Corp and semiconductor firm Advanced Micro Devices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He co-founded Nvidia with start-up capital of US$40,000 in 1993, one year after receiving a master&#39;s degree in electrical engineering from Stanford University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During his 20-minute speech to students, Huang recounted three Nvidia stories that helped shape the company into the trillion dollar AI leader it is today. He urged graduates to “have the humility to confront failure, admit a mistake, and ask for help”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His first lesson involved Nvidia&#39;s experience with Japanese entertainment company Sega Corp. Huang said a strategic mistake with a chip architecture meant giving up on a contract with the Japanese firm, but sought help from Sega&#39;s then CEO to avoid bankruptcy. “Confronting our mistake and, with humility, asking for help, saved Nvidia,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second story occurred in 2007 when Huang decided to put Nvidia&#39;s pioneering CUDA (Compute Unified Device Architecture) into all of the company&#39;s GPUs, enabling them to process data in addition to 3D graphics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the high cost and poor company performance as a result was met with scepticism by shareholders at the time, who “preferred to focus on improving profitability”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s ChatGPT ambitions could hinge on AI GPU chips under US sanctions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Huang said he resisted this pressure and “risked everything to pursue deep learning” until his efforts paid off many years later when chips started to be used for machine learning amid a new wave of AI development. “The journey forged our corporate character – to endure pain and suffering that is always needed to realise a vision,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last story described the company&#39;s “strategic retreat” from the highly competitive phone market in 2010, and the move towards robotics. “Strategic retreat, sacrifice, deciding what to give up, is … the very core of success,” Huang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As part of a two-week trip to Taiwan which began last week, Huang will also visit several chip suppliers, including ASUS and Wistron, and meet with senior executives at TSMC, according to Taiwan media reports. Last Thursday, a picture showing Huang walking through a Taipei night market went viral on social media.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Visit to Hong Kong by Congolese president shows city’s strategic role in China’s clean-energy transition, observers say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3222223/visit-hong-kong-congolese-president-shows-citys-strategic-role-chinas-clean-energy-transition?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 21:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/f926aedd-d849-40df-a817-8a42ebb9fd22_74c77547.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A visit by the president of the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) to Hong Kong – the first by a foreign leader in four years – shows the city&#39;s financial and professional services play a strategic role in China&#39;s transition to clean energy, observers have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Congolese President Félix Tshisekedi concluded a two-day visit to the city on Monday after meeting Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu, during which the Hong Kong leader emphasised the financial hub&#39;s role in China&#39;s Belt and Road Initiative, a flagship trade project now in its 10th year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Under the &#39;one country, two systems&#39; principle, Hong Kong also reaps the unique benefits of enjoying strong national support while maintaining unparalleled connectivity with the world,” Lee said, referring to the framework under which the city is governed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The city is well-positioned to serve as a key link for the DRC and other African countries to jointly promote the development of the Belt and Road Initiative.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chief Secretary Eric Chan Kwok-ki, Deputy Financial Secretary Michael Wong Wai-lun and Undersecretary for Commerce and Economic Development Bernard Chan Pak-li also attended the meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee said the city had maintained cordial trade relations with the DRC, with average annual growth of 12 per cent over the past five years in total merchandise trade. He added that he saw good potential to further enhance business and trade cooperation between the two places.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An insider said the closed-door meeting at Government House was conducted under the “highest level” of security arrangements.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China and Congo agree to regular checks on mining deals&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The last official visit by a foreign leader to Hong Kong was in April 2019 by then Panamanian President Juan Carlos Varela.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tshisekedi&#39;s visit to Hong Kong was the last stop of his first trip to China, the DRC&#39;s biggest trading partner. He visited Beijing, Shanghai and Shenzhen in the past week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a joint statement on Friday, Beijing and Kinshasa agreed to upgrade bilateral relations to a comprehensive strategic cooperative partnership, China&#39;s highest level for ties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;David Sit Kwun-nam, assistant principal economist at the Trade Development Council, told the Post that the city played an important role in strengthening services to Hong Kong-listed Chinese companies that had growing investments in the mining sector in the DRC, Africa&#39;s second largest country by land mass.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong public universities to &#39;launch campaign to lure belt and road students&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Securing cobalt is strategically important in China&#39;s pursuit of its net-zero targets,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Strengthening Hong Kong&#39;s financial and professional services, such as consultancy and arbitration, to these [Chinese] companies can help them sail through challenges in Africa.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a broader sense, he said, Hong Kong&#39;s role as a gateway could also boost progress in trade and investment under the Belt and Road Initiative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Congo supplies more than 60 per cent of China&#39;s cobalt, a key component in batteries for electric vehicles and electronics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Information from the Observatory of Economic Complexity, an online data visualisation and distribution platform, showed that China&#39;s imports of cobalt from the DRC ballooned by 191 per cent from 2015 to 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the latest deals between Tshisekedi and Chinese President Xi Jinping was an agreement to regularly assess mining cooperation after previous contracts were considered “poorly negotiated”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In return for cobalt and copper, Chinese companies agreed to invest US$3 billion in a mining project in the mineral-rich Katanga province, as well as US$3.2 billion in infrastructure in general.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hung Wing-lok, a scholar at Lingnan University&#39;s China Economic Research Programme, said he believed Tshisekedi could also be interested in potential economic opportunities in the Greater Bay Area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Citing Agenda 2063, a framework formulated by the African Union to transform the continent into a global powerhouse, he said health and education were among key areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hung said that with Hong Kong&#39;s edge in higher education and healthcare services, he saw good potential for the city to work with the DRC in the next five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Mineral-rich central Africa becomes focal point in US-China tug of war&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Samson Abebe Bezabeh, a University of Hong Kong scholar who specialises in African studies, said the trip also carried significance in the city&#39;s exchanges with other French-speaking countries on the continent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The DRC is one of the largest Francophone countries in Africa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Strengthening relations with high-ranking official visits will not only benefit China-Congo relations but also [Hong Kong&#39;s] relations with the French-speaking part of Africa,” said the assistant professor at HKU&#39;s School of Modern Languages and Cultures.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>