<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Outsiders buying Malaysian durian and reselling them as ‘Thai Musang King’ to China raises a stink]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222832/outsiders-buying-malaysian-durian-and-reselling-them-thai-musang-king-china-raises-stink?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 11:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/8feb968b-8247-40f9-9d5e-cea842027d36_3648e2f3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当泰国买家开始在马来西亚彭亨州购买榴莲运回泰国时，农业和食品安全部对其他市场利用 Musang King 榴莲品牌表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;副农业和食品安全部长 Chan Foong Hin 说，泰国榴莲采购商来到劳勿是为了从树上采摘这种水果之王以更高的价格，他声称这些榴莲随后以“泰国猫山王”的标签作为新鲜水果出售给中国，这可能会阻碍未来向中国出口优质马来西亚榴莲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个自由市场，我不阻止你，但我不鼓励[它]，”他说，并补充说该部将向泰国驻马来西亚大使馆提出问题，特别是泰国榴莲买家随后是否将马来西亚榴莲作为“泰国猫山”出售King”在中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，该部已呼吁榴莲种植者和出口商调查此事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们必须使用适当的贸易渠道出口榴莲，以确保当地的榴莲从长远来看，农民不会蒙受损失，保护猫山王的声誉和品牌不被其他市场利用，”他在接受采访时说。 Chan 说，马来西亚检疫局 (Maqis) 将收集数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰国警方对榴莲农场进行夜间巡逻，以阻止小偷&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他说，该部一直致力于并协助获得批准向中国出口新鲜榴莲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我也理解农民迫切希望开发更多销售渠道，包括直接向中国出口新鲜榴莲的可能性，但该部关心马来西亚的国家利益，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，马来西亚的猫山王榴莲在从树上掉下来之前已经成熟，在被运往中国之前用液氮冷冻。同时，一些榴莲出口水果在准备出口之前被采摘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他强调，“在树上成熟的榴莲”是猫山王的卖点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他提醒农民他补充说，新加坡是从马来西亚进口榴莲最多的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，他们不应为了短期利益而损害榴莲的质量和声誉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;根据农业部截至 5 月的记录，多达 44 家冷冻榴莲加工设施已获得中华人民共和国海关总署的出口批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共有 41 家设施正在加工果肉和糊状的榴莲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，还有 20 种榴莲获准出口整个水果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地贸易商目前为“A”级榴莲支付每公斤 30 林吉特（6.55 美元） ” Musang King，而泰国买家每公斤支付 34 林吉特（7.43 美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据了解，劳勿的榴莲农民不是等待榴莲成熟并从树上掉下来，而是在榴莲刚刚成熟时收获它们。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据称，许多榴莲种植者将这一趋势视为业主脱离当地贸易商的突破口。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;榴莲热：中国的王怡对马来西亚猫山王芝士蛋糕赞不绝口&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;Raub 作物生产者协会主席 Nicky Koh 表示，泰国买家愿意为榴莲支付更高的价格，农民认为这是扩大市场的另一种方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说农民已经尚未了解泰国买家在猫山王榴莲被购买并运回泰国后如何处理，或者他们是否将其标记为“泰国猫山王”榴莲，以及他们是否可以采取任何措施来阻止它。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说只有冷冻的大马猫山王榴莲才能出口到中国，出口商要担心液氮气短缺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Koh还说榴莲的早收带来比自然成熟更高的价格，节省人工成本，更长的保质期，并解决营销、价格和成本问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，在榴莲完全成熟之前采摘不会影响它的味道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，马来西亚榴莲种植者协会主席 Tan Sue Sian 博士解释说，榴莲从树上掉下来后，果肉会在果壳中自然发酵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发酵过程会影响榴莲终于入味，发酵时间更长，味道更浓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，早早采摘榴莲需要计算天数和时间并包装出口到中国，这可能会影响不熟悉马来西亚出口的泰国出口商交付的质量猫山王榴莲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 11:50:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Legless warrior’ – from homeless child who lost legs in accident to disability advocate with a passion to climb mountains]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3222321/legless-warrior-homeless-child-who-lost-legs-accident-disability-advocate-passion-climb-mountains?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/01/58a585bc-e81e-4c9c-aff9-938e3124e121_92d5b86e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在中国东部山东省的一个挤满大学生的礼堂里，一个戴眼镜的男人检查一下自己的领带和西装是否整齐，然后用两个木箱当腿，带着自信的笑容走上舞台，开始向人群讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈舟在一次火车事故中失去了双腿，现在已经恢复健康。在内地社交媒体上被称为“无腿勇士”，通过公开演讲提高人们对残疾的认识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 41 岁的老人出生在山东省一个村庄的贫困家庭。当他还是个小男孩由祖父抚养时，他的父母离异并离开了他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在 13 岁那年失去了双腿，当时他偷偷登上火车车厢希望去大城市，但发现走错路后跳下车，被另一列火车撞倒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的双腿瞬间被冲击力从身体上撕裂。他被当地人发现并送往医院，他们向公众筹集资金支付他的治疗费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后，陈开始在街头乞讨，并做一些零工来维持生计，比如卖报纸，捡废品，擦鞋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;18岁时，他加入了一个残疾人音乐团，成为了一名歌手。随后几年，陈和他的残疾同事走遍了20多个省市，在街头举办音乐会，为他赢得了“流浪歌手”的绰号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一切都在2007年改变了应朋友之托，向一群未成年犯发表演讲。陈说，他后来意识到演讲比唱歌更有意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在过去的十年里，陈在学校和电视上发表了数百次演讲，用他自己的生活经历来&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我以前从来没有想过，我所经历、所想、所感、所学，可以给人心灵上的慰藉，使他们的思想得到鼓舞，”陈对《解放日报》说。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“我经常告诉我的听众，‘不要抱怨你的鞋子不漂亮，因为这个世界上有很多人没有腿，所以你应该感到快乐和满足’，”他说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;业余时间，陈某喜欢爬山，曾13次登上中国泰山顶峰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数人爬完泰山需要四到六个小时；对 Chen 来说，这是他依靠两个木箱当腿的两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这个世界上，我忘记了自己是一个残疾人，我为自己感到快乐和自豪，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;已婚并育有两个孩子的陈说：“每天我都得到家人的爱。我怎么会不开心呢？”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈经常给听众讲他女儿的故事。多年前，他第一次去学校接她放学时，她的同学和父母都嘲笑他的残疾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的女儿回应说：“我爸爸怎么了？腿？他没有腿，但他仍然爬山。他会唱歌。他也能挣钱养家。你爸爸能做到吗？”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Alibaba Cloud tech guru Wang Jian tells Hong Kong audience computer power can help save environment by cutting use of natural resources]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3222775/alibaba-cloud-tech-guru-wang-jian-tells-hong-kong-audience-computer-power-can-help-save-environment?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/e098e2c7-aa6e-4a11-87b7-9e38f14d8c0c_5c7c91c3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;世界应该利用计算的力量来减少由技术进步，*阿里云创始人王健在香港之行中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四，王健在对香港进行为期三天的访问期间接受了《华盛顿邮报》的采访，他还呼吁香港在努力加强其在创新和 IT 发展方面的记录时，要跳出框框思考并接受“不确定性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在香港科技大学的一次会议上告诉听众（香港科技大学）人工学习和计算能力可以让世界变得“更聪明”，因为一切都可以用更少的资源完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang 说，过去一个世纪的电气化技术进步加速了自然资源的利用现在是创新关注效率的时候了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们如何才能从增加碳排放转变为减少排放？我认为唯一的方法是通过计算，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在未来，也许我们喝的每一瓶水或我们使用的每样东西都会涉及一些计算，以确定这些资源是否&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为他的“2050”计划的一部分，这位有影响力的科技高管在香港进行了此次活动，该计划旨在将来自不同城市的对创新和航空充满热情的年轻人聚集在一起开会，直到本世纪中叶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang 策划了在全球范围内与亚马逊和微软竞争的云业务的创建，被视为阿里巴巴崛起为电子商务巨头的主要推动者。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;香港聚会是今年以“科技汇聚青年”为主题的四场交流活动之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一场活动于 2018 年在中国首都杭州举行浙江省。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港天然气公司和政府生产氢气用作运输燃料&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;今年在新加坡、香港、杭州和芜湖举行的活动也恰逢一个由飞行员张博率领的机组人员进行洲际飞行，张博是第一位完成环球飞行的中国飞行员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四人座的 Diamond DA42 于 4 月离开芝加哥，并多次经停，包括格陵兰岛、罗马、迪拜和新加坡，在它降落香港之前。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年开始定期上航空课的九龙慕光英语学校的一群学生被这次活动带到了机场组织者近距离观察飞机并进行控制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一进入驾驶舱，我就知道控制装置在哪里。该校航空俱乐部主席、15 岁的 Wong Pak-yin 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong 在学校和家里的模拟器中驾驶过很多次飞行，但这是他第一次接触真实飞机的控制装置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最令人印象深刻的是我可以进入机场的禁区并爬进真实的驾驶舱，”他补充道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王在活动结束后告诉邮报，通过驾驶舱之旅等活动灌输发现感可能会为年轻人“打开一扇窗”来考虑更广泛的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个很大的世界，但，无论出于何种原因，我们只看到了冰山一角，”他说。 “我们在思考问题时总是把自己的思想封闭起来，而像这样的活动让我们跳出框框。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang 强调了他从西贡码头乘帆船到达位于 Clear 的科大校园的经历以 Water Bay 为例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于强烈的雷暴，早上的航行几乎被取消了——但 Wang 说，飞行员和海员面临的不可预测性也提醒他面对不确定性的好处，因为这些时刻通常是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王补充说，这种刺激肾上腺素的不确定感可能对香港有利并释放其潜力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，香港和中国大陆深圳的大湾区经济特区经常被联系起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港需要电动汽车电池回收设施来解决越来越多的废物问题：专家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“为什么要将深圳与深圳进行比较香港？深圳是一个充满不确定性的地方。你不知道那里会发生什么。香港要变得更有活力，我认为它需要更多的不确定性，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“并不是说我们要把一切都搞砸——我们可以通过提出新问题来引入不确定性。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Wang 说，他在乘帆船旅行时了解到，尽管香港有许多可供公众使用的码头，但这项运动在香港人中的影响力有限，部分原因是它与富人有关。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;他说，如果这些信息得到更广泛的讨论，或许会有更多的香港居民能够从水上欣赏这座城市的海岸线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有时候一个问题看起来很简单，但它仍然Wang 解释说，如果其他人不问的话，值得一问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港财政厅长陈茂波在今年的预算案中承诺要实现城市经济数字化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府还在研究人工智能超级计算中心的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早前报道称，王刚恢复了他在阿里云的全职工作，阿里云正在进行重组以从其电子商务中剥离出来母公司准备在未来 12 个月内首次公开发行股票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;*《南华早报》归阿里巴巴所有。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获得更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Coronavirus Hong Kong: sixth infection wave in city peaks with case numbers to drop after ‘few more weeks’, government adviser says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3222830/coronavirus-hong-kong-sixth-infection-wave-city-peaks-case-numbers-drop-after-few-more-weeks?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 11:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_coronavirus_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/d7e2e9cf-014f-4478-8d60-3eee88a0e1c8_6edd0500.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港的冠状病毒感染人数将在“再过几周”后下降在香港第六波疫情达到顶峰后，一位主要的政府大流行病顾问周六表示，向居民保证 Covid-19 已经成为地方病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多香港人在最近几周内第一次或第二次感染中国大学呼吸内科专家许树昌教授说，冠状病毒病例激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这可视为第六波冠状病毒感染。但它已经在上周达到顶峰，预计感染浪潮还会持续几周，然后才会消退，”他在一个广播节目中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这些病例中，大约 95.8% 是感染了 XBB 亚变体，这使得前两代疫苗的效果较差。但对于那些接种疫苗的人来说，他们的感染大多是轻度感染，严重病例较少，死亡风险也较低。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管 Covid 达到高峰，但香港父母仍警告其他呼吸道疾病&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;这位学者还强调，该市的冠状病毒情况已从大流行阶段转变为地方病阶段，大多数 Omicron 病例仅导致轻微症状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“大流行已经转移到一个新的阶段，成为感染三年多后流行。该病毒可被视为普通呼吸道感染，社会无需对感染保持高度警惕，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港将其对冠状病毒感染的反应级别从“紧急”下调星期二“发出警报”，这是政府三级系统中最低级的，并将继续将其视为一种常见的呼吸道疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港卫生局局长说，每天有多达 10,000 人感染新冠病毒&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这一变化表明政府认为该疾病对人口的直接健康影响微乎其微，但仍可能通过人传人在当地传播。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;降级已获批准由市领导约翰·李家超领导的指导委员会根据市卫生局的意见和世界卫生组织的最新建议制定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国际机构于 5 月 5 日宣布，Covid-19 没有不再构成全球紧急情况。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 11:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden may vet Denmark PM Mette Frederiksen as 1st female Nato chief during US trip]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222827/biden-may-vet-denmark-pm-mette-frederiksen-1st-female-nato-chief-during-us-trip?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 10:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/783ac367-a754-400c-a611-684eb3988af0_df196c47.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;丹麦首相梅特·弗雷德里克森将于周一在华盛顿会见美国总统乔·拜登，期间外界猜测白宫将利用这次访问来审查她是否成为北约首位女秘书长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据外交官称，现年 45 岁的弗雷德里克森已成为接替延斯·斯托尔滕贝格的有力竞争者，后者预计将9 月辞去北大西洋公约组织主席一职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，她作为乌克兰与俄罗斯战争的坚定支持者在国际舞台上成为众人瞩目的焦点，并因其努力加强面对冲突，西方团结一致。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我可以花很长时间说梅特·弗雷德里克森 (Mette Frederiksen) 的好话。她是欧洲最有能力的国家元首之一，”挪威首相乔纳斯·加尔·斯特勒上周在被问及弗雷德里克森是否是北约职位的潜在候选人时说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“欧洲非常尊重她作为总理所做的工作以及她在国际合作中所做的工作，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“绝对需要支持”：欧盟欢迎为乌克兰提供 F-16 喷气式飞机的决定&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;她获得候选资格的主要障碍是，丹麦长期以来在国防开支方面落后，并且一直面临着将军费开支提高到 GDP 的 2% 的压力，这是北约成员国的一个关键目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但在 12 月，弗雷德里克森和她的新中间派政府提出了一项计划，将实现北约的目标提前三年至 2030 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，它还宣布在未来 10 年内对国防进行大量投资，并增加军事力量对乌克兰的援助，政府表示这将有助于在今明两年暂时实现北约的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;职业政治家兼社民党主席弗雷德里克森成为有史以来最年轻的丹麦首相她于 2019 年担任部长。她在去年赢得了连任，因为她带领北欧国家度过了 Covid-19 大流行病，尽管她在国界之外的知名度有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你可以说她没有”它确实具有国际知名度，”智库 EUROPA 的安全和国防分析师 Jacob Kaarsbo 说。 “但当俄罗斯开始入侵乌克兰时，情况发生了变化。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2022 年 2 月战争爆发以来，她已三次访问乌克兰。尽管乌克兰的经济存在重大缺陷，但丹麦仍向乌克兰提供了大量财政和军事援助自己的防御。该国还带头培训乌克兰飞行员，并表示愿意提供 F-16 战斗机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 9 月，当北溪管道在丹麦水域爆炸时，弗雷德里克森的回应是组建一个罕见的跨越传统左右分歧的联盟，认为在国际不确定时期需要政治团结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月，她推动了一项不受欢迎的决定，取消了公共假期，她说这是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她在丹麦拥有强大的地位，但她也是分裂人口的人。丹麦前国防和司法部长汉斯·恩格尔 (Hans Engell) 说：“许多人认为她过于强势且渴望权力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普在 2019 年提议购买丹麦王国的主权领土格陵兰岛时，弗雷德里克森认为这一提议“荒谬”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在国际舞台上，她设法避免与土耳其总统塔伊普·埃尔多安和匈牙利总理维克多·奥尔班发生公开冲突，这表明她有能力在冲突中保持务实&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她是一位坚强的女士，而且雄心勃勃。我认为，如果她感觉到北约国家可以团结在她身边，她会同意，当然，尤其是如果拜登邀请她的话，”恩格尔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然她说她不是候选人，但她已经停止了说她对这份工作不感兴趣：“我没有申请任何职位发布。我受邀拜访拜登总统，我很期待。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South China Sea: Chinese boat scavenging scrap metal from WWII wrecks shows Malaysia’s vulnerability to maritime actions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3222756/south-china-sea-chinese-boat-scavenging-scrap-metal-wwii-wrecks-shows-malaysias-vulnerability?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/d511c398-f0f4-477a-ba77-c0abfd5c71bc_36291b44.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;多年来，马来西亚潜水员 Hazz Zain 沮丧地看着沉没的残骸两艘英国二战战舰——被指定为 842 人的战争坟墓——被非法打捞人员抢走了埋在海浪下的历史遗迹的珍贵钢材。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们从 2012 年开始，”Hazz 说，一位专业潜水员，对 68 米深的威尔士亲王号和反击号沉船地点了如指掌，这两艘船被派去保卫新加坡，但在 1941 年 12 月被日本鱼雷击沉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周展示在Asia 拍摄了反击号受损程度的视频片段，她指出了从后炮塔区域撕下的参差不齐的金属片，这些金属片在沉没时完好无损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“看看被非法打捞工作损坏的部分，”她说。 “那是2018年，当时的船还像船。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚扣押涉嫌洗劫英国二战坟墓的中国船只&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hazz对潜水的兴趣始于她年轻的时候1990年代。她被海底的美丽所吸引，在发现散落在全国各地水域的残骸后，她对两次世界大战的船只和飞机产生了兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种浓厚的兴趣让我开始潜水在马来西亚周围的水域以及其他拥有自己独特历史的地方，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凭借超过 30 年的潜水经验，Hazz 遇到了英国当时的威尔士亲王——现在的查尔斯国王– 2017 年，并向未来的君主简要介绍了沉船不断恶化的状况，这些沉船不仅是数百名水手的坟墓，也是英国称霸海洋的愿望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一艘散货船——中国-登记在册的 Chuan Hong 68 – 是罪魁祸首，专家说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，它一直在冲刷马来西亚的沿海浅滩，那里有许多二战残骸。这些“战前钢材”在第一次原子爆炸之前建造，没有核辐射，售价是现代钢材价格的三到五倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“川红 68”号于 5 月 28 日被扣留由马来西亚海事执法机构 (MMEA) 及其 32 名船员组成，其中包括 21 名中国公民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是同一艘驳船，”Hazz 说，她目睹了一艘在该地点周围盘旋的船只年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据新闻报道，这艘驳船曾在 2017 年打捞同样的沉船时被发现，但似乎已经返回继续其非法捕捞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它已注册为据马来西亚当局称，中国公司在福州。但中国表示，这艘船是由一家马来西亚公司租用的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论其运营的幕后黑手是谁，这艘驳船的历史都是神秘海上打捞贸易中金钱和机会主义的故事。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;对残骸的搜查是在离马来西亚海岸如此之近的水域进行的，以至于与中国的联系让许多人对中国船只可能潜入激烈竞争的海域——以及其愿望——感到不安。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但当“川红 68”的船员们故技重施时，他们被一种非常现代的方式绊倒了：TikTok。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名现场工作人员发布的视频显然很高兴看到炮塔正在建造中从一艘驳船上卸下的货物提醒马来西亚当局注意丹绒勿隆哥僻静的红树林覆盖的海岸线上发生的奇怪事件，该海岸线距离新加坡德光岛和马来西亚与邻近城市国家之间的国际边界不远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 21 日，他们发现了废料场散落着来自威尔士亲王号和反击号的零件——包括未爆弹药。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后流传的照片显示，一名马来西亚官员在废料场，被一个笨重的锚和它的链节显得矮小，还有一些专家声称这是生锈的枪管。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这些舰只在战争开始时被日本航空鱼雷击沉——在海战开始两天后香港和入侵马来亚。造成的 800 多人死亡使其成为英国最严重的海军灾难之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在战争过程中，各方 400 多艘船只在马六甲海峡和南部的浅水区沉没今马来西亚附近的中国海。其中埋葬着约 15,000 名在冲突中丧生的水手的尸体，将沉船提升为战争坟墓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;距离马来西亚半岛关丹海岸 60 海里处，威尔士亲王颠倒地安顿在海底 68 米深，而浅水号侧卧在南海清澈湛蓝的海水下 56 米处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为“Force Z”的一部分部署到南海” 为了保护英国在该地区的财产——特别是马来亚和新加坡——在日本帝国海军空袭中击沉船只标志着当时的现代战舰首次在公海上被空中力量击沉。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;它预示着制空权时代的开始和英国海军霸权的终结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国前首相温斯顿丘吉尔在他的战后回忆录中描述说，在听到沉没事件后，他“翻身并在床上扭动着全身的恐惧”，再也没有“受到更直接的冲击”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这片广阔的水域中，日本是至高无上的，而我们到处都是软弱和赤裸的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;失去海空保护，“新加坡堡垒”仅在两个月后就倒塌了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，其历史意义并没有阻止一些人在厚重的高处看到潜在的财富-优质钢材在海底可控深度无人看管，导致许多地点被未经授权的打捞作业破坏。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚潜水教练在热水中亲吻中国游客&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;TikTok 视频，以及当地渔民看到起重驳船的情景，促使专家们对南海沉船现场可能存在的非法打捞活动敲响了警钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8,352-长 122 米乘 32 米的总吨 Chuan Hong 68 起重驳船注册于中国福州连江县的福建亚瑞海运公司，该公司在其网站上将其业务性质描述为“打沉沉船”国内外”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这艘驳船自 12 月以来一直在该地点作业，在那里停留了两个多星期，然后在 Tanjung Belungkor 的码头卸载废料并返回进行进一步的未经批准的打捞作业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;驳船及其 32 名船员——21 名中国公民、10 名孟加拉国人和一名马来西亚人——在 MMEA 的例行检查中因未能出示抛锚许可证而被拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >; 总部位于英国、致力于保护世界水下文化遗产的机构海事天文台表示，其卫星侦察显示，“川红 68”号在未被发现的情况下运行了五个多月，并从威尔士亲王号上卸下了至少六船废料，花费了在现场停留超过 54 天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高级考古学家 Giles Richardson 声称有证据表明驳船在海上为避免被追踪而禁用了其自动识别系统转发器，并涉嫌使用允许移走一艘现代残骸作为进入威尔士亲王遗址的掩护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果属实，这表明官方对船舶运动的检查和对运入丹绒勿隆哥的废料的核实是完全不充分的， ” 理查森告诉《亚洲周刊》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，人们对目睹川红 68 号的担忧是有道理的，因为它还负责在 2017 年在沙巴清除三艘日本二战残骸。&lt;/p>; h3>;尽管紧张局势加剧，中国仍将参加印度尼西亚的多边海军演习&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然人们对川红 68 号了解甚少，但中国政府在 2017 年声称，一家名为埃森哲战略私人有限公司的马来西亚公司租用了起重驳船，之后印度尼西亚海军扣留了这艘船，原因是该船在南中国海最南端的印度尼西亚阿南巴斯群岛附近非法清理一艘瑞典超级油轮的残骸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该公司的注册信息，该公司已更名为 Amenture Strategy私人有限公司Bhd.，并报告其业务活动为填海造地、买卖废金属和“从海底疏浚废料废料”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其营业地址位于柔佛州士姑来，距那里一小时车程从英国军舰上非法打捞的材料被卸下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚“川红”68 号是否仍被马来西亚公司租用。打给该公司的电话无人接听。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于英国朴次茅斯的皇家海军国家博物馆对“威尔士亲王号和浅水号的明显破坏行为表示担忧，这两艘船均被指定为根据英国 1986 年《军事遗迹保护法》，它们被列为受保护的地方。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它们被指定为战争坟墓，”其总干事多米尼克·特维德尔 (Dominic Tweddle) 说。 “我们对海军遗产的流失及其对了解我们皇家海军历史的影响感到不安。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题也带来了地缘政治优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大片南中国海的争议非常激烈，中国声称在所谓的九段线下拥有大部分海域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是威尔士亲王号和浅水号的位置超过 240 海里（445 公里） west of China&#39;s westernmost claim and well within Malaysia&#39;s uncontested exclusive economic zone, making the activities of the Chuan Hong 68 even more egregious.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the barge continued to scour the South China Sea for Japanese and British shipwrecks, an archaeological sweep of the contested waters carried out by China over the span of about three months last year uncovered five ancient merchant ships laden with historical artefacts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the same day news broke of the illegal salvage operations on the Prince of Wales, China&#39;s National Cultural Heritage Administration announced it had begun surveying and mapping two sunken centuries-old Ming-era merchant ships discovered in the contested waterway.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Located in an unspecified area in the northeastern part of the South China Sea, the body said it would now assess how to preserve and protect the two shipwrecks, which it said were of “world-class archaeological importance”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three other wrecks were found in August, in the vast expanse of water between China&#39;s southern coast and the Paracel or Xisha Islands, which are also claimed by Vietnam as the Hoang Sa Islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is expected to use the discovery of sunken ships of Chinese origin to strengthen its claims to a series of disputed islands in the sea, where it has been an active maritime power for centuries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Malaysia&#39;s threadbare naval resources, meanwhile, have been stretched thin by tensions in the South China Sea, militant incursions in the Sulu Sea and piracy along the busy Strait of Malacca.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The navy in particular is reeling from a scandal over the lengthy delay in the construction of six littoral combat ships which began in 2011, with first deliveries expected in 2019. None of the ships are 50 per cent complete, however, and the government is scrapping the last vessel, leaving five to be built.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the Chuan Hong 68 impounded, calls are mounting for Malaysia to urgently protect the sites of the sunken vessels.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For us in the UK, these are important war graves,” said Richardson, the archaeologist.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For Malaysians, they are world- famous diving sites that should bring in tourists and money.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When they&#39;re destroyed, no one benefits.”&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Hope our love will not change’: Chinese woman, 23, surprises Taiwan singer Richie Ren at concert by thanking him for saving her life 22 years ago]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3222296/hope-our-love-will-not-change-chinese-woman-23-surprises-taiwan-singer-richie-ren-concert-thanking?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/31/c18c0fb4-6e52-4662-b758-1002ccaf2ad9_2a503762.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A heartwarming story about a young woman thanking Taiwan singer Richie Ren for a donation that saved her life 22 years ago has touched the hearts of countless people across China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ren, who is much-loved by people who grew up in the 1980s and 1990s, remains popular in mainland China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Songs like “The Sad Pacific”, “Too Softhearted” and “Hey Girl Look This Way” provided memories for many and his generous and positive social image has also ensured a substantial fan base.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He made the donation 22 years ago on his way to a concert in Shenyang in northeastern China&#39;s Liaoning province, and it was in the same city history repeated itself during his 2023 nationwide concert tour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a special session at the concert, where fans can make song requests, a young woman stood up and said: “I&#39;m 23 years old this year, but I&#39;ve known you for 22 years. When I was little, you even held me in your arms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In 2001, when I was just over one year old, I was suffering from congenital heart disease. Due to my family&#39;s poor financial situation my life was in the balance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You read the news about me on your way to the concert in Shenyang and generously donated 30,000 yuan (US$4,200) which enabled me to have the surgery and saved my life.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The girl then requested the song “Don&#39;t change” to express her best wishes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I hope that the love between us will never change and that the universal love and compassion among people will also remain unchanged,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Captivated by the story, Ren&#39;s fans unearthed news reports about the donation made more than two decades ago which carried photos and the singer&#39;s heartfelt message.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Be brave, remember that I&#39;m waiting for you,” Ren said at the time ahead of the girl&#39;s life-saving operation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In China, approximately 160,000 newborns a year are diagnosed with congenital heart disease, a number that has been steadily rising, according to Professor Li Shoujun, at Fuwai Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, reported MedSci.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Clinical data shows that approximately 50 per cent of patients die before the age of three and 60-70 per cent do not survive beyond the age of five if left untreated.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story triggered a flood of touching comments on mainland social media: “I am so moved. It is a mutual journey between kind and grateful people,” one said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another agreed: “On one side, it&#39;s his selfless giving without expecting anything in return, and on the other side, it&#39;s the girl whose life has been saved, both carrying grateful hearts. This is true love. ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others praised Ren as a real role model.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Richie is truly a kind person. I&#39;ve come across several similar news stories about him before, in one he helped parents find their lost kid. Helping others seems to come naturally for him,” one person said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How much should Hong Kong pay for IVF treatments? Couples must weigh cost of test-tube babies as city reluctant to raise subsidies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3222767/how-much-should-hong-kong-pay-ivf-treatments-couples-must-weigh-cost-test-tube-babies-city-reluctant?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/b12b431e-c4b9-4e74-95ab-a277ddf927a1_ffb21543.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong insurance agent Flora Chan, 42, has lost count of the number of miscarriages she has had since getting married in 2009.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She conceived naturally multiple times, only for each to end tragically within as little as five weeks and as much as 11 weeks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After years of disappointment and devastation, Chan and her self-employed husband, also 42, sought in vitro fertilisation (IVF) treatment in 2016 at Prince of Wales Hospital in Sha Tin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To skip the long queue, which could take months, they chose to receive the treatment as a private service, which meant paying about HK$200,000 (US$25,528) in total, but the miscarriages continued.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She then turned to a private specialist, who ran tests which identified a genetic abnormality and she was prescribed medication alongside the IVF treatments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That cost the couple HK$300,000 more, but Chan finally conceived and went all the way to give birth. Their son is now a healthy three-year-old.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan said that while she and her husband could afford the IVF treatments, many other couples might not be able to pay HK$500,000.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Subsidising these treatments may not solve the birth rate issue overnight, but it will surely help to a certain extent,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US$130,000 wasted, her body &#39;destroyed&#39; to avoid freezing eggs in Hong Kong&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;IVF, one of the most common types of Assisted Reproductive Technology (ART) used to treat infertility, refers to a series of medical procedures to retrieve an egg from a woman&#39;s ovaries, fertilise it with sperm in a laboratory and transfer the embryo back to the woman&#39;s uterus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong has seen the number of babies born each year slide to a record low of 32,500 last year, with many younger women and married couples delaying having babies or preferring not to have them at all.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a recent report by the United Nations Population Fund, the city fared worst in the world for its total fertility rate or TFR – the number of children a woman is expected to have over her lifetime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its score of 0.8 was followed by South Korea at 0.9, Singapore at 1.0 and Japan at 1.3. The TFR should be 2.1 for a population to replace itself.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To counter the falling birth rate, several lawmakers have called on the government to expand subsidies on infertility treatments and egg-freezing services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan, Singapore, Israel and mainland China have increased such subsidies, though none have seen significant returns yet.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Screening technology can boost IVF live birth rate, Chinese study finds&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Although Hong Kong authorities and experts largely did not think raising subsidies could make a dent in reversing the declining trend in births, many agreed that more could be done to help couples seeking help with infertility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Figures from the Council on Human Reproductive Technology showed that more than 4,600 Hong Kong women received ART procedures in 2020, with about 1,630 babies born among them, accounting for 3.8 per cent of live births that year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, more than 6,000 had such treatments, with about 2,300 babies born, accounting for 4.4 per cent of that year&#39;s live births.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The treatments are more common among women in their late 30s, followed by those in their 40s and older.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only three public hospitals in the city offer subsidised IVF services to married women under 40 who have to be referred, but only three cycles of ovarian stimulation are subsidised, costing about HK$10,000 each.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Why many women are being denied a chance at motherhood in Hong Kong&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Patients have to wait up to 12 months for subfertility assessments after referral, and another four to seven months to start their treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who prefer not to wait, or are not eligible for public IVF services, may turn to the private sector and pay at least HK$80,000 for each treatment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;More resources needed to shorten queue&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Carol Chan, a Hongkonger in her early 30s, had her pregnancy terminated at Queen Elizabeth Hospital in 2021 after her three-month fetus was found to have thalassaemia major, a serious genetic blood disorder that puts the mother&#39;s life at risk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Chan and her husband, both carriers of the disease, IVF was their only solution because the embryo could be screened for the disease – which had a 25 per cent chance of occurring – before being transferred into the womb.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was referred to Queen Mary Hospital for IVF treatment. She waited six months and paid about HK$40,000 at the public hospital, but the only embryo that cleared the screening did not result in a successful pregnancy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We wanted to start another cycle immediately, but we had to queue for months more, which would further delay the time-sensitive treatment,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The couple then went to the private Union Hospital in Sha Tin where they spent HK$230,000 for a treatment cycle, and their healthy baby girl was born in Toronto last year after they moved to Canada.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It was very expensive for us,” she said. “For the same price I could have done a few more cycles at a public hospital, but we could not wait longer because we were about to emigrate. We were grateful for the service and care at Queen Mary Hospital, but certainly, more resources are needed to shorten the queue.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Professor Ernest Ng Hung-yu, former head of the Division of Reproductive Medicine at Queen Mary Hospital, said more staff and space for consultation, embryo incubation and counselling were needed to increase service capacity and shorten the queue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Having one more medical officer at a public hospital could mean offering an extra 200 cycles of IVF treatments a year, he said. But he felt that subsidising treatments in the private sector would be less cost-effective as the treatments cost more there, with no guarantee of success.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Unlike other procedures, IVF treatments may require multiple attempts to achieve pregnancy,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dr Cheung Lai-ping, honorary clinical associate director of Chinese University&#39;s department of obstetrics and gynaecology, agreed that the public sector needed more resources.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It&#39;s a private pain&#39;: mother-to-be on miscarriage and the &#39;taboo of loss&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“But if the government were to subsidise IVF services in the private sector, patients should undergo a proper assessment, better done at public hospitals, to ensure that the treatment is necessary and prevent abuse,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She explained that many couples went straight for IVF in the private sector, whereas some cases of infertility could be treated with medication and surgery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some couples also mistakenly viewed IVF as a solution allowing them to delay starting a family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The older the woman&#39;s age, the fewer the eggs the ovary can produce, and even if there is a sufficient number of eggs, they are more likely to be of a lower quality,” she said. “That means a lower chance for successful fertilisation and implantation in the lab, and the mother suffers a higher chance of miscarriage.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Can&#39;t make a baby? Check the man first – 50pc of fertility issues down to them&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Women over 40 faced a 40 to 50 per cent chance of miscarriage, and their babies also had a higher risk of conditions such as Down&#39;s syndrome, she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, more than 430 women over 40 underwent frozen-thawed embryo transfer, a common IVF process in which eggs are fertilised and the embryos are frozen and stored until they are thawed and implanted in the woman&#39;s womb.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only 106 of those women became pregnant and from that group, 79 went on to give birth, almost two in five.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of women over 40 who did fresh cycle IVF without freezing and thawing of the embryo, less than 3 per cent achieved ongoing pregnancy, and less than 2 per cent gave birth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Professor David Bishai, director of the School of Public Health at the University of Hong Kong (HKU), also a father of a test-tube baby, said insurance policy regulation was an area the government could address.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most insurance products in Hong Kong currently did not cover the cost of ART procedures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A health insurance policy that doesn&#39;t cover ART is a defective product,” Bishai said. “Mandates on the basic benefit packages in insurance must come from the government and should include approved technologies that help families cope with unexpected medical difficulties.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Plan ahead if you want babies&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In response to lawmakers&#39; calls to set up a centralised egg bank and subsidise more IVF treatments, Secretary for Health Lo Chung-mau earlier this month said such services were not a matter of concern for most family planning couples.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Having a baby or not is a personal choice and the government should not intervene, but the government will strive to provide family-friendly policies to foster a supportive environment for childbearing,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Is my kid alive?&#39;: couple in embryo mix-up raising strangers&#39; son get US$93,000&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“When allocating resources in the public healthcare system, it&#39;s important to find a balance between providing assisted reproductive services and other life-saving medical services, especially services that are unavailable, or maybe more expensive in the private sector.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Paul Yip Siu-fai, a population expert at HKU, agreed that ART could not do much to reverse declining birth trends, pointing to the failure in Singapore and Israel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The collateral benefit is small, and not in proportion to the cost,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added the government should instead advise newlyweds to plan ahead if they hoped to have children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dr Milton Leong Ka-hong, a specialist in reproductive medicine, said couples preparing to marry and newlyweds should have regular fertility tests early.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who discovered signs of deteriorating fertility could then decide whether to have a baby sooner or freeze their eggs and sperm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said the government could give out vouchers for such checks, and expand the service capacity of premarital and pre-pregnancy check-ups by the Family Planning Association.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;It was nerve-racking but worthwhile&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lawmaker Nixie Lam Lam, 41, who is eight months pregnant with a test-tube baby, said more should be done to make women aware of their reproductive health.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She experienced serious period pain growing up, but it was not until 2019, when she was preparing to get pregnant, that she found out that a condition had affected her womb, which later resulted in three miscarriages over four years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lam and her husband, a 34-year-old private investor, then turned to IVF.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many women in Hong Kong do not care about their reproductive health until they turn 30,” she said. “The government should subsidise relevant tests like Pap smears and pelvic ultrasounds for women in their 20s so that problems are spotted sooner.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Video creator Sona Ng So-na, 33, mother of a two-year-old test tube baby girl, recalled her pregnancy as a “nerve-racking” experience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Married to a 32-year-old businessman, she sought IVF treatment in 2020 after three miscarriages. Despite getting pregnant on the first try, she had a lot of vaginal spotting in the first few months and was prescribed progesterone hormone injections, pills and suppositories to maintain the baby.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I woke up every day wishing time would pass faster,” she said, “My belly was covered in bruises from the daily injections, sometimes the needles were full of blood when I pulled them out, it was quite horrifying.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not knowing anyone who had IVF treatments, she struggled to get information to answer her many questions. She wished the health authorities could do more to educate and raise awareness, such as setting up a Q&amp;A webpage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The loneliness she experienced also drove her to set up a social media community that gathered hundreds of mothers preparing to get IVF treatment, hoping to provide a platform for mutual support and information exchange.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But the challenges of the whole IVF process is nothing compared to childbearing,” she said. “One should never try IVF if one is just pressured by parents, or have little affection for children.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the end, however, having a baby made it all worthwhile for Ng and her husband, and they are making plans for a second IVF baby later this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We do love children a lot, and we have never been happier,” she said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UN agency warns there is no let-up in drugs trade from Asia’s Golden Triangle]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3222821/un-agency-warns-there-no-let-drugs-trade-asias-golden-triangle?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/799ca103-e747-4c87-8bc1-2d62210da400_88fcb5ae.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The huge trade-in methamphetamine and other illegal drugs originating from a small corner of Southeast Asia shows no signs of slowing down, the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime warned Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“High volumes of methamphetamine continue to be produced and trafficked in and from the region while the production of ketamine and other synthetic drugs has expanded,” said the agency&#39;s 2023 report, Synthetic Drugs in East and Southeast Asia – the first since the borders reopened post-Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report shows a pattern of criminal groups re-establishing themselves to the pre-pandemic stage, and significantly changing trafficking routes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lion&#39;s share of methamphetamine, in the form of tablets and crystal meth, comes from the area known as the Golden Triangle, where the borders of Myanmar, Laos and Thailand meet. The production of opium and heroin used to flourish there, mainly because of the lawlessness around Myanmar&#39;s remote eastern Shan State. The area, much of it jungle, remains the domain of various ethnic minority militias, some of them partners in the drug trade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Methamphetamine continues to be the most used drug in East and Southeast Asia and that use has increased over the past decade,” the report says.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Thailand temple left empty after all its monks fail drug tests&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;It&#39;s also easier to make on an industrial scale than the labour-intensive cultivation of opium, from which heroin is derived. The drug is then distributed by land, sea and air all around Asia and the Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report says the control that major organised crime groups have over territories “has allowed them to massively increase and diversify supply for the purposes of market expansion and domination.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The most powerful regional trafficking networks are able to operate with a high degree of certainty they can and will not be stopped, and they are able to dictate the terms and conditions of the market as a result,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There have been record methamphetamine seizures almost every year for the past decade in East and Southeast Asia, but the latest data suggest that the total drugs seized declined in 2022 to 151 tons, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A decline in seizures is often associated with weakened production, but the report says “other indicators – arrests, street availability, purity, record low wholesale and street prices, and treatment admissions – indicate the supply has remained very high or unchanged.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jeremy Douglas, UNODC regional representative for Southeast Asia and the Pacific, particularly noted at a news conference Friday in Bangkok that the situation in Myanmar&#39;s Shan State was “quite concerning” due to the past year&#39;s unprecedented drop in drug seizures there, despite being “the epicentre of production for Asia-Pacific,” which he said was directly related to the conflicts and instability in the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report suggests the overall decrease in seizures was due to traffickers changing their smuggling routes from land to maritime to evade authorities, explaining that shipments are made by sea from Myanmar&#39;s coastal regions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thailand recently made two major busts of crystal meth that was expected to be transported to a third country by sea. On Tuesday, nearly a tonne of the drugs was seized off the coast in the Gulf of Thailand, which Thai authorities suspected were en route to be loaded to a bigger ship in international waters. Drugs that were seized in several recent raids were supposedly bound for Australia, Thai authorities have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Traffickers are a little more successful last year than in the previous year, and they were able to connect to market mainly using maritime routes that were not noticed by people over the course of the year,” Douglas said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The UN office also expressed concern that Cambodia has become “a key transit and to some extent production point for the regional drug trade.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It suggests that even though there has been consolidation of synthetic drug production in the Golden Triangle, that development may reflect “some diversification of production and &#39;hedging&#39; by organised crime.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Industrial-scale ketamine labs and facilities for processing and storing the substance were found across Cambodia, raising serious concern throughout the region, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Organised crime groups have adopted a supply-driven market expansion modality similar to the approach taken to expand the methamphetamine market in the region that started in 2015,” warns the report about the trade-in ketamine, which has legal use as an anaesthetic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Landlocked Laos, near both Shan State and northern Thailand, is another weak link in the fight against the drug trade, and “intelligence officials have come to the conclusion that supply is transiting the country with little resistance,” says the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report says that in addition to becoming an increasingly important route for drugs trafficked out of Myanmar, meth tablet production was also detected there in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It says that meth and other drugs produced in Shan State laboratories usually enter Laos by crossing the Mekong river from ports “under the control or influence of major non-state armed groups,” naming some of them: ethnic militias including the United Wa State Army, the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army, the National Democratic Alliance Army, “and their allies who work in partnership with transnational organised crime syndicates.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The case of Laos also illustrates the difficulties of blocking the ingredients needed to produce the drugs from reaching the illegal labs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Laos, it says, is becoming an increasingly important route for chemicals reportedly used in drug production in Myanmar, entering the country through Vietnam, Thailand, and China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Efforts to disrupt chemical flows into Myanmar&#39;s drug-producing areas also continue to be impeded by slow and bureaucratic inter-agency coordination, inadequate resources and personnel, and limited cross border cooperation,” the report says, and traffickers are finding alternatives for obtaining their supplies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The main chemicals needed to make methamphetamines are generally under tight international controls, so illicit laboratories in recent years have moved to using chemicals that are not so closely regulated. The report says that the logistics of obtaining such chemicals have also been expedited by online ordering, especially from suppliers willing to disguise the nature of the transactions.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Shangri-La Dialogue: US defence chief Lloyd Austin doubles down on security alliance push]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3222826/shangri-la-dialogue-us-defence-chief-lloyd-austin-doubles-down-security-alliance-push?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 09:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/03/4099efc9-c881-48e0-b066-1e9e2cb6d500_ef316a92.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;US Defence Secretary Lloyd Austin underlined US resolve to shore up alliances and partnerships in the Asia-Pacific in a speech to a key security summit in Singapore on Saturday morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stressing there was no room for intimidation, bullying or coercion, he said the US was doubling down on reinforcing its security alliances and partnerships.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our shared goals are clear: to deter aggression and to deepen the rules and norms that promote prosperity and prevent conflict,” he said at the Shangri-La Dialogue, a three-day defence summit run by the International Institute for Strategic Studies think tank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His speech to hundreds of officials and analysts is focusing on the United States&#39; views on hotspots in the Asia-Pacific, especially on Taiwan and the South China Sea, issues on which Washington has accused Beijing of using force – and sometimes falling foul of international law – to force its geopolitical interests onto other countries in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Beijing and Washington clash on Taiwan, compete on advanced weapons development and engage in close encounters in the South China Sea and elsewhere, the United States has shifted funds to its Asian allies and partners to shore up their defensive abilities and held joint drills with armed forces in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So we&#39;re stepping up planning and coordination and training with our friends, from the East China Sea to the South China Sea to the Indian Ocean,” Austin said. “That includes staunch allies such as Australia, Japan, Republic of Korea, the Philippines and Thailand.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US had reinforced deterrence to prevent conflict and stood for rule and norms that “protect us all”, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More to follow …&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its national security strategy released in October, the US described China as the only competitor with the intent and power to reshape the international order to become more accommodating to its authoritarian political system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Pentagon&#39;s national defence strategy, also from October, said the US military would focus on efforts to deter Chinese “aggression” against American interests and to “prevail in conflict if deterrence fails”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has often criticised the framing of US-China relations as a competition and has accused the US of containment with its system of allies in the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 09:20:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI, post-Covid work from home culture will reverse slump in world PC sales, Acer CEO says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3222770/ai-post-covid-work-home-culture-will-reverse-slump-world-pc-sales-acer-ceo-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.03 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/b87f40ac-f85b-4272-83b3-8186f924cafd_076f668a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A post-coronavirus work from home culture and rising unit prices will stop the long slump in PC sales caused by weak consumer confidence, the head of the world&#39;s sixth-largest vendor said this week during the Computex Taipei tech show.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sales of laptops and desktops have declined over the past 12 months because inflation and interest rates combined to hurt consumer sentiment, Jason Chen, the chairman and CEO of Taiwanese hardware and electronics firm Acer, told the Post said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the surge in PC purchases during the pandemic for remote working and home study means more machines than before will need to be replaced during the next so-called refresh cycle, Chen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A refresh cycle usually refers to business replacement of hardware and software every three to five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From the macro level, inflation has triggered interest rates, and the interest rates have triggered [weaker] consumer confidence, and because of that, the end-user demand made a drastic change about four quarters ago,” said 61-year-old Chen, who was appointed CEO in 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Interest rates have risen as central banks tightened monetary policy to combat inflation, which grew in much of the world last year due to rising energy prices and shipping costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Working from home, however, shows no sign of disappearing despite the end of Covid-19 controls, Chen added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said remote working and studying at home during the pandemic meant that every family member had a PC rather than sharing one.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Wow, what a view! China&#39;s &#39;digital nomads&#39; seek paradise while on the clock&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Around a third of workers with jobs that can be conducted remotely are working from home, the Pew Research Centre said in a survey released in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When we talk about refresh cycles, the numbers required will be higher because of the bigger installation base,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fields such as accounting and human resources “people get used to that working model and it&#39;s harder to get them back,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Consumers are already buying up PC accessories, such as docking stations and different kinds of connectors, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PC shipments across vendors reached 286.2 million units last year, down by 16.2 per cent from 2021, according to market research firm Gartner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shipments of just 55.2 million units in the first three months of 2023, representing a 30 per cent decrease from the first quarter of 2022, follow what Gartner describes as an “unfavourable combination of oversupply and continued low PC demand due to economic uncertainties”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Acer sold 3.523 million units in the first quarter, according to Gartner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rising average sales prices of PCs stand to increase overall sales revenues, Chen said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Consumers are often willing to pay more for PCs with strong computing power and parts made from recycled materials, he added, with the PC gaming market already “declining less”, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the next few years, the demand for generative chatbots such as ChatGPT will drive purchases of late-model PCs, Chen said, as phones are not suitable due to their lack of keypads and small screens.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Generative AI will become more popular and people will use it for productive purposes,” said Chen, who previously worked for 14 years at Intel and eight years at Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen said India and Indonesia are also taking increasing numbers of PCs because of their relatively large young population employed by burgeoning manufacturing sectors.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The next Bali? Taiwan city tries to lure remote workers amid talent shortage&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Market research firm IDC ranks Acer, which plans to expand sales and marketing in both countries, as the fourth-largest vendor in India.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In another boost to global PC sales, Chen said Chromebooks orders are also picking up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Acer, among other brands, make the lightweight notebooks together with Google.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;School districts in the US and Europe are placing orders, Chen said, and Acer is discussing sales with India and Japan.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 03 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>