<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Meet Japan’s millennials – they’re ‘sober’, trapped in dead-end jobs and never want children]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3224682/meet-japans-millennials-theyre-sober-trapped-dead-end-jobs-and-never-want-children?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 11:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/fbb4154e-8b5b-449f-8ffd-222182c0c4e1_0c9dbb5b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;36 岁的伊势诚终于觉得自己可以开始新的生活了。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;这位自由软件工程师和他的妻子，一位有抱负的厨师，还有几个月就可以清偿债务了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位高中毕业生，在日本南部沿海伊势市的鹿儿岛长大他的职业生涯始于一家零售店销售乐器，然后在一个小乐队里弹吉他，然后与一位音乐家同行创办了一家 IT 公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当该公司于 2019 年破产时，他发现自己背负着 35,000 美元负债累累，而他的妻子则借贷支付烹饪学校的费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Isechi 关闭了他的公司并决定成为一名自由网站设计师，通过观看 YouTube 视频和上网自学如何编码和使用 Photoshop培训班。在过去的三年里，他慢慢建立了一个客户群，现在每月收入 7,500 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在我们可以开始我们的未来了，”Isechi 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那个未来不会。这对夫妇来说不会有太大的改变。他的妻子正考虑从他们在大阪的三居室公寓搬到乡下开一家意大利餐厅，但他们没有生育孩子、拥有房屋或致富的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;像许多日本人一样作为千禧一代，Isechi 对现在的生活感到满意，当他们看着自己的国家忍受严重的经济危机和自然灾害时，乐于维持生计。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;日本错了——通货紧缩不是其经济困境的原因&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;美国皮尤研究中心智库将千禧一代定义为 1981 年至 1996 年出生的人，因此他们现在的年龄介于 24 至 44 岁之间。这意味着，虽然美国千禧一代可能在 2008 年大金融危机期间开始了他们的职业生涯，但他们的日本同龄人一生都在经济衰退中度过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 2700 万人 - 约占全球人口的五分之一国家的总人口——在日本是千禧一代。相比之下，美国有 7200 万千禧一代，而中国有大约 4 亿千禧一代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文采访了日本的三位千禧一代和两位经济学家。关于他们的职业抱负、消费习惯和财务决策的调查结果反映了日本典型的千禧一代，但并非那一代人的每一位成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;典型的日本千禧一代在财务上是保守的，已经成长看着他们国家的“失去的十年”遭受毁灭性的​​经济危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1990 年代初在日本南部城市鹿儿岛长大，Isechi 和他的弟弟看着他们的父母在抵押贷款和汽车付款上挣扎在日本近代最严重的经济危机中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我母亲经常告诉我们，&#39;永远不要为任何事情贷款，&#39;”Isechi 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Isechi 可能没有他听从了母亲的建议，但他说，他童年时期的经济痛苦至今仍在支配着他的心态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“日本的千禧一代在经济低迷时期开始了生活，当时泡沫破灭，他们的许多父母都受到了影响.因此，千禧一代在很多方面受到了同样或更多的影响，”静冈大学管理、信息学和创新研究生院院长 Seijiro Takeshita 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;祝福和日本疯狂低抵押贷款利率的诅咒&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;从 1986 年到 1991 年，日本经历了一场经济泡沫，期间资产和房地产价格大幅膨胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后日本的资产泡沫在 1990 年代初破灭.情况非常糟糕，日本基准日经 225 指数在 1989 年 12 月触及近 39,000 点的高位后，每年下跌 40%，而且在 30 年后仍未复苏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本经济1980 年代的平均增长率约为 4%，但自 1990 年代以来的大多数年份均下降至 1% 至 3% 左右。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特别是，从 1991 年开始的 10 年被称为日本的“失去的十年”，该国的失业率从 1991 年的 2.1% 翻了一番多，到 2002 年达到历史最高水平 5.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“日本经济陷入了持续 30 年的停滞，因此，千禧一代从未经历过非常好的经济形势，”野村综合研究所执行经济学家 Takahide Kiuchi 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些情况使他们在支出方面更加谨慎，在工作方式方面更加保守”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它并没有止步于失去的十年。日本千禧一代一生都在目睹一场又一场灾难——包括 1997 年的亚洲金融危机和 2011 年的地震和海啸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接二连三的灾难和这些事件造成的经济破坏塑造了日本千禧一代及其世界观，使他们“比他们之前的一代人更现实”，Takeshita 说，他们陶醉于该国经济的过度繁荣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但也有积极的一面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们不像前一代人那样，‘加油，加油，加油，努力工作’，工作到死——因为他们看到了太多的消极情绪，无论是在国际事务中还是在自然灾害中，”Takeshita 补充说，他指的是karoshi 的概念，或过劳死。 “他们不是从泡沫开始的，所以这是一件大事。他们很清醒。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本的大多数千禧一代并不关心买房，只有不到三分之一的人拥有房产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本的房屋自有率一直保持稳定根据 Statista 的数据，自 1970 年代以来，这一比例约为 60%。但年轻一代在房主中所占的比例正在下降。 2018 年，26% 的房屋由 30 至 34 岁年龄段的户主拥有，低于 1983 年的 46%。35 至 39 岁年龄段的户主的房屋拥有率从 60% 下降同期增加到 44%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我无法想象为自己买房，”Isechi 说。他从来没有觉得国家经济稳定到足以让他安全地买房，而且他认为自己缺乏选择好的房产的金融知识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与韩国的父母和同龄人不同，许多人日本千禧一代并不渴望拥有自己的房子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这几代人经历了资产价格刚刚跌至谷底的现实，拥有房子的地位并不像前几代人那么重要”静冈大学的 Takeshita 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，京都 37 岁的机械工程师 Jin Gujin 还是在日本的租赁市场上抢占了一席之地。去年，他借了 430,000 美元的贷款购买了两处房产，并将其翻新为合租屋，租户租用一个房间并分开厨房和浴室设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;分而治之：新加坡的房地产投资者通过共同投资获利living craze&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Jin一共可以招收12位租客，每人每月收费470美元，每月租金收入超过5600美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加上每月的贷款和支付的利息总计 1,000 美元，这些房子已经收回成本，尽管按照这个利率他需要大约 7 年的时间才能偿还债务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他住在他的两处房产中的一处，并说如果不是不是为了他的租赁业务，他会满足于在别人合租的房子里租一个房间。他说：“我认为日本人乐于一直租房到死。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为数字原住民，日本千禧一代的价值观往往比他们的前几代人更多元化，并且不认为拥有房产是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我猜是因为数字时代，他们能够以更广阔、更灵活的视角看待事物，”Takeshita 补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本的千禧一代可能不会工作到死，但他们仍然在工作很长时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在一个典型的工作日，Jin 在他的办公室工作 12 个小时，他一直在设计智能手机、相机和平板电脑过去 13 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当他晚上 10 点回到家时，他会通宵玩电子游戏或阅读漫画小说。他每晚大约睡四个小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;韩国的“FIRE 部落”在不确定的世界中寻求财务自由&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“由于我在办公室花费了大量的额外时间，我需要是我的爱好和人际关系的时间，”Jin 说。 “通常我会在凌晨 3 点或 4 点睡觉，然后在 7:30 起床上班。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我的公司，一周加班 20 小时是正常的。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Isechi 回应了这种观点。尽管他现在是一名自由职业者，每周工作 7 天，但他说他经常感到有压力，要在他以前的零售工作中加班加班并帮助他的高级同事（他称之为前辈）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但情况正在发生变化 – Takeshita相信千禧一代的员工开始拒绝加班文化，因为日本公司不再吸引这种业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我看来，这更多地与公司本身的基本情况有关在他们的时间里变得更加放松，因为他们不能像过去那样追求增长，因为我们的潜在增长率已经显着下降，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，日本人的工作时间一直在缩短根据政府间组织经济合作与发展组织 (OECD) 的数据，甚至在大流行病爆发前的工作小时数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019 年，日本工人的平均工作时间为 1,644 小时，减少了 5 小时根据经合组织的数据，2010 年的工作时间为 1,733 小时。相比之下，2019 年美国和韩国人的平均工作时间分别为 1,824 小时和 1,967 小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于日本的千禧一代一直担心经济，因此很少有人考虑组建家庭。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;首相的助手说，如果人们不生更多孩子，日本就会“消失”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;33 岁的东京居民 Suganuma Natsuki 于 2021 年辞去工作，重新开始她自己的微生物研究公司。她的一些同龄人有一两个孩子，但她和丈夫认为，在经营 Suganuma 的公司的同时组建家庭太困难了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府要求我们生孩子。但是大多数人没有钱照顾他们。生孩子太可怕了，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文采访的三位千禧一代都处于恋爱或婚姻中，但他们表示他们从不考虑生孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据日本卫生部的数据，日本的生育率在 2023 年降至每位女性 1.26 人，为 17 年来的最低水平。相比之下，根据世界银行的数据，美国的出生率为 1.7，而韩国报告的生育率在 2022 年为世界最低，为每名妇女生育 0.78 个孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本的出生率下降并不是新趋势.日本政府在其网站上称，二战后的几年里，该国的出生率在 1947 年达到 4.54，但在 1960 年左右开始急剧下降，直到 1970 年代该国经济蓬勃发展之前一直稳定在两倍左右. 1970 年代之后，这一数字继续下滑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该国一直试图通过为妇女生育创造有利环境并使其能够在没有育儿需求的情况下重返工作岗位来提高生育率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但该国的千禧一代没有孩子，因为这个保守的国家对未来没有信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济低迷加剧了不安全感，因为自 2000 年代以来实际工资没有上涨——尽管有些人由于通货膨胀，公司最近增加了工资。野村证券的 Kiuchi 认为这是一次性加薪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“年轻一代认为他们未来没有增加收入的前景，”Kiuchi 说。 “他们的收入有限，但仍然想享受生活，所以结婚生子就退居二线了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Isechi 说，他和妻子部分反对生孩子，因为他们喜欢搬到每隔几年，日本的许多地方都认为，如果他们开始了家庭，他们就必须安定下来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“生孩子是我们生活中的一个巨大变化，做一个好父母很难。我不知道我们什么时候可以准备好做出这样的决定，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本的千禧一代习惯于看到逆境打击经济，他们一贯是保守的消费者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 发推文称日本将“不复存在”，这触动了神经&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在日本资产泡沫破灭后，他们在受约束的环境中成长，这使得该国的千禧一代比之前挥霍无度的一代更加节俭&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们不像上一代经历过泡沫的大手笔消费者。他们更加现实，而且他们的消费模式也更加安全可靠，”Takeshita 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suganama 在她 5,700 美元的月薪中节省了大约 15%，同时还清了 60,000 美元的学生贷款。她的大部分闲暇开支用于欧洲和亚洲的背包旅行，她一共去过 35 个国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，去年年薪为 78,000 美元的 Jin 表示，他将 70% 的钱存起来了税后收入，他将其投入股票市场和比特币。他将大笔开支限制在日本各地的短途公路旅行上，但计划很快花 2,000 美元去美国西海岸旅行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Isechi 说，他和他的妻子几乎没有积蓄。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们尝试过，但没能存下来，”他说。 “现在这对我们来说是个大问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与他们的父母不同，日本的千禧一代不喜欢忙碌的企业生活。 Suganuma 刚刚创办了自己的公司，她说组建家庭对她和丈夫来说太费力了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在创办公司之前，Suganuma 在当地一家食品巨头工作了七年，研究酸奶对健康的影响产品。工作时间很难跟上——她的团队经常不得不在周末工作以检查他们的研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suganuma 也从未得到晋升——但她说她更喜欢这种安排。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我认为年轻人不想升职。大公司的首席执行官看起来并不喜欢每天的工作，他们看起来工作很努力，”Suganuma 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到 2021 年，她已经厌倦了公司生活。她辞去了工作，创办了自己的公司，研究肠道健康如何影响怀孕和整体健康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的梦想是让人们健康快乐，”她说。 “在我以前的公司很难，因为他们想生产很多食物以低价出售。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管在同一家公司工作了 13 年，机械工程师 Jin 也从未得到晋升.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;不认为值得去&#39;：日元疲软打击日本对外国工人的出价&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“在日本公司，人们工作非常努力，但他们不会得到更高的职位，”金说。他已经接受了这种安排，并说他在别处寻找成就感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin 梦想获得语言教师执照并移居海外——也许是泰国——成为一名日语教师。 “我想做一些新的事情。我想创建自己的公司，但我没有任何好主意，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有财产或孩子的 Isechi 说他认为自己的生活并不比他的前辈更好，那是应对 1990 年代金融危机的那一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为我也正在经历与我父母相同的痛苦，”他说。 “但我乐在其中！这是我的生活！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本文首发于&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong must embrace Middle East capital, mainland China culture, to bolster role as international financial centre]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/markets/article/3224684/hong-kong-must-embrace-middle-east-capital-mainland-china-culture-bolster-role-international?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 11:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/da78b6b5-6a8c-40f3-99e8-2c36fa327162_b3341e09.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在中美地缘政治紧张局势下，香港需要放眼美国以外的市场根据香港上市公司商会主席的说法，中东寻求巩固其作为国际金融中心的地位，并将中东作为资本来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为我们有一个问题在今天的香港，事实上尽管 [in the financial system] 有基础设施，但缺乏来自美国的资本流动，”Catherine Leung，她也是 MizMaa Ventures 的联合创始人兼合伙人，在一次周二的会议。 “[美国] 代表着世界上最大和最深的资本池。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果香港想成为国际金融中心，就需要积极寻找其他资本来源，并且不仅仅是金融中心，Leung 在瑞吉酒店举行的邮报中国会议的小组讨论中补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有一些来自美国的对冲基金资金，但不多，”她说。 “因此，我们陷入了这一切的地缘政治之中……我认为香港政府，如果我可以这么说的话，非常迫切需要制定中东战略。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府需要建立她说，在中东建立一个系统并努力发展长期关系，因为那里的资金来源不会只是“给你钱”，并补充说双向合作是首选。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港Asia Securities Industry &amp; Financial 董事总经理兼股票和交易后主管 Lyndon Chao 表示，也需要停止对北京在政策方面可能想要或不想要什么犹豫不决，而应该接受其作为开放金融中心的历史市场协会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基于最近与中国证监会（中国证券监督管理委员会）的会议，“大门是敞开的，监管机构非常有建设性，市场将继续开放”，Chao 说。&lt;/p >;&lt;h3>;中国和沙特官员发誓要改善商业环境&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“[北京]希望香港发展，他们希望香港成为资本主义国家，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是他说，现在取决于香港。他建议，与其考虑北京可能会怎么想，不如“做你自己”。 “成为你几十年来一直担任的国际金融中心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chao 认为，香港还必须继续接受英语，以保持其作为国际金融中心的地位，并指出在他的职业生涯中，他注意到香港该行业的英语使用率下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;EV 公司 Human Horizo​​ns 在阿拉伯-中国峰会上签署的 5.6b 美元交易&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“成为一个欢迎国际金融中心，你真的需要拥抱主导语言和两个最大的全球经济体。美国和中国，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金融服务发展委员会主任兼政策研究主管 Rocky Tung 表示，该行业必须超越单纯的语言理解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我相信香港成为国际枢纽不仅与金融有关，与企业在这里有关，还与人民有关，”他说。 “因此，我认为我们应该采用国际化的[视野]，我们不仅要讲语言，还要了解文化。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“毫无疑问”中国在中东经济上的发展，但政治上的“更多”复杂&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这也适用于中国大陆，Leung 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“香港人需要在中国，并了解如何在那里工作，”她说。该行业应该拥抱大陆同行，在区块链实施等一系列问题上像一个大家庭一样共同努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果我们提供这些巨大而繁荣的机会，钱就会来，”她说，并补充说在深圳和上海做生意不仅仅是要说普通话，而是要沉浸和了解文化。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港的 IPO 市场将缓慢复苏，2023 年的数量将超过 2022 年&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;被问及拥抱中东是否意味着永远远离美国，梁振英表示，资本是无国界的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只是因为我们现在可能会从美国转移到中东，因为地缘政治的变化并不意味着香港永远远离美国，”她说。 “[它] 只是转移到投资机会所在的地方。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港不应该选边站，Chao 同意。 “这是一个多极世界，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s John Lee warns against ‘hijack’ of July 1 celebrations, unveils wave of events and discounts to mark handover anniversary]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3224686/hong-kongs-john-lee-warns-against-hijack-july-1-celebrations-unveils-wave-events-and-discounts-mark?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 11:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/99a72f96-741e-416b-92db-9b86e3a4e801_86d149d2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二，香港特首警告不要“劫持”7 月 1 日庆祝活动这座城市回归中国统治的周年纪念日，将提供免费乘车等广泛的福利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市的博物馆也将免费开放，而电车和渡轮。超过1000家餐厅将为食客提供折扣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们有两年的7月1日被别人劫持，和平被打破，违法行为不断。所以，我们不能掉以轻心，”行政长官李家超说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在值得大家庆祝的日子，我们要尽量让大家开心度过， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2019 年反政府抗议活动最激烈的时候，数十名示威者于当年 7 月 1 日冲进了香港的立法会大楼，破坏了建筑物并喷漆了该市的会徽。&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;香港前公务员因敦促更多刺伤警察被判入狱 6 个月&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;反对派集团从 2003 年开始每年 7 月 1 日举行游行，直到三年前 Covid-19 大流行爆发，随后北京对香港实施国家安全法，改变了其政治格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李在周二强调，7 月 1 日举行的任何活动都应遵守法律，并指出即将到来的活动数量之多日期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在每周与执行委员会的主要决策机构的顾问举行会议之前，Lee 向媒体发表讲话，宣布将于 7 月 1 日推出的活动和免费赠品清单，这也标志着一周年&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国第一夫人彭丽媛将在香港与习近平一起庆祝回归 25 周年&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;信心和希望，政府将继续追求经济增长和发展，提升城市的竞争力，”他誓言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府和公共企业将率先推出一系列折扣和”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李说，居民可以在 7 月 1 日连续五天免费乘坐多条渡轮航线和电车。多间博物馆，包括位于西九文化区的 M+ 博物馆和香港故宫文化博物馆，将免费向公众开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;康乐及文化事务署营办的设施，包括大部分游泳池、 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港安全局局长为识别集会参与者的新措施辩护&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;超过 1,000 家餐馆将提供 29% 的折扣。该数字来自中文折扣的措辞——表示客户需要支付的金额，即 71%，即 7 月 1 日的“7/1”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更多详细信息Lee说，将由相关政府部门公布。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 11:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Intel to build US$33 billion plant in Germany with US$11 billion in subsidies as it seeks to regain chip dominance]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224680/intel-build-us33-billion-plant-germany-us11-billion-subsidies-it-seeks-regain-chip-dominance?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 11:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/10d6ae8e-daa9-4fbf-81e1-edb0822f2ec5_1043cc7b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;德国和英特尔公司签署了一项协议，让这家美国公司获得扩大的补贴方案据知情人士透露，该交易价值约 100 亿欧元（109 亿美元），用于前共产主义东部的一家半导体工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英特尔周一证实了该协议，但未提供具体的经济援助金额。它表示计划投资约 300 亿欧元用于马格德堡的“前沿晶圆制造基地”，总理奥拉夫·舒尔茨称这是“德国历史上最大的单一外国直接投资”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;连同英特尔在爱尔兰和波兰的工厂，新工厂——将由两个晶圆厂组成，被称为“硅结”——将创建一个端到端的半导体制造基础设施，支持欧盟推动更具弹性的供应链，英特尔该公司在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一家工厂预计将在获得欧盟委员会批准后的四到五年内投入生产，它补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国计算机公司 Powerleader 表示其 CPU 是与英特尔的支持&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“今天的协议对于德国作为高科技生产地以及我们的韧性来说是重要的一步，”Scholz 说，他与 Scholz 一起参加了在柏林总理府举行的交易签字仪式英特尔首席执行官 Pat Gelsinger。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议由 Scholz 的高级经济顾问 Joerg Kukies 和英特尔执行副总裁、首席全球运营官兼制造、供应链和业务部总经理 Keyvan Esfarjani 签署。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英特尔于 2022 年底购买了该项目的土地，并最初同意以 68 亿欧元的政府援助建设该设施，但由于经济逆风而推迟了开工建设。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;据知情人士透露，现在商定的增强型一揽子计划将包括以财政补贴形式提供的传统援助以及能源价格上限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英特尔表示，该网站预计将在此期间创造 7,000 个建筑工作岗位初始建设阶段，以及大约 3,000 个永久性高科技工作岗位和“整个行业生态系统”的数万个额外职位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Gelsinger 的领导下，英特尔开始了一项旨在重新夺回其以前在该行业的主导地位和关键部件的多元化制造中心，目前集中在东亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马格德堡在出价高于欧洲其他地点后成为这些计划的关键部分，但该项目在能源价格飙升后失败&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与大多数将通过欧盟芯片法案获得政府资金的项目一样，英特尔预计其成本的大约 40% 将得到补贴，知情人士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;根据 Scholz 的说法，继芯片制造竞争对手 Infineon Technologies AG 和 Wolfspeed Inc 推出重大项目之后，英特尔的投资只是科技巨头在德国的最新投资，而且可能不是最后一次投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英特尔将在以色列扩张新的晶圆厂以实现供应链多元化&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“其他人正在等待，”这位德国领导人周一在柏林的商业游说会议上发表讲话时说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果这些投资得以实施——我们正在为此努力——德国将成为世界主要的半导体生产地之一，”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“此类投资将使我们的供应链多样化，并使德国能够和欧洲公司在欧盟采购他们需要的芯片。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球最大的代工芯片制造商台湾积体电路制造公司正在与德国政府谈判，以获得高达一半成本的补贴。知情人士上个月表示，德累斯顿的一家工厂可能耗资高达 100 亿欧元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore Airlines’ fortunes are soaring. And Hong Kong’s Cathay Pacific?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3224673/singapore-airlines-fortunes-are-soaring-and-hong-kongs-cathay-pacific?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 10:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/20/e3263466-5bc8-41e1-9b4a-db9a3e77cab2_e0b948af.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;旗舰航空公司新加坡航空公司和国泰航空公司的命运亚洲两个最重要的金融中心，在大流行期间存在分歧，并在其后果中继续分化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它们的估值很能说明问题——新加坡航空公司 170 亿美元的市值几乎是国泰航空公司的三倍。四年前，这一差距仅为 20 亿美元左右。新加坡的载旗航空公司刚刚结束连续 12 天的涨势，这是自 2008 年以来最长的涨势，今年上涨了约 40%。国泰航空股价下跌 9.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然两家公司的处境都比新冠疫情最严重时要好，但新加坡航空的反弹速度要快得多，并且在持续不断的旅行需求浪潮中飞得更高。 Bloomberg Intelligence 分析师蒂姆·巴克斯 (Tim Bacchus) 表示，其股价反映了其作为“亚洲航空公司复苏的典型代表”的地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，国泰的重建受到香港政府不愿放弃病毒的严重阻碍-相关限制，它仍在努力恢复员工人数和服务。该航空公司预计要到明年年底才能恢复到大流行前的客运量水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Covid 封锁后对旅行的新鲜和永不满足的胃口并没有被令人瞠目结舌的机票所削弱.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这帮助许多航空公司复苏，因为他们的飞机上载满了愿意花钱进行所谓的“报复性旅行”的乘客。新加坡航空公布截至 3 月份的财年收入达到创纪录的 21.6 亿新元（16 亿美元），收入达到 178 亿新元，超过疫情前的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国泰航空的状况也在改善，但收入为 51 港元亿美元（65 亿美元）去年仍然不到危机前 2019 年的一半。至少，该公司现在产生的现金足以支付 6 月底应向政府支付的 15.2 亿港元股息。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着飞往中国、日本的预订量飙升，新加坡航空公司的利润创历史新高&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;新加坡航空公司的员工看到了好处——他们有资格获得相当于大约八个月工资的奖金。国泰航空的士气并不高，最近宣布的薪酬调整遭到了质疑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“飞行员士气低谷，”代表国泰航空飞行员的工会主席 Paul Weatherilt 上周表示在公司透露它正在改变其薪资政策之后。 “他们永久性地削减了我们的工资。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去三个月，新加坡航空公司是全球表现最好的航空公司股票之一，飙升 34%。只有台湾的 Eva Airways Corp. 表现更好，上涨了 56%。新加坡海峡时报指数在此期间上涨了约 2%。 Cathay has added 6.2 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singapore Airline&#39;s investors backed its effort to rebuild flight capacity, confident that it would lift earnings, said Jason Sum, an analyst at DBS Bank Ltd. Advanced bookings also look attractive as competitors like Cathay face resource constraints, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Singapore Airlines carried 2.8 million passengers in May, hitting 88 per cent of its pre-Covid capacity and advancing toward the 3.4 million high set in January 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cathay&#39;s passenger traffic was nearly 1.4 million in April, according to the most recent data available. The airline has said it will only return to 70 per cent of pre-pandemic operation levels by the end of this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While both airlines have been on a hiring spree, Cathay needs to climb out of a deeper trench. Its staff attrition over the pandemic was nearly 40 per cent. It also owes the government HK$19.5 billion that was extended in a rescue package.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From its position of relative strength, Singapore Airlines is cementing partnerships around the region with several other carriers, including Garuda Indonesia, Malaysia Airlines Bhd, Thai Airways International Pcl and Vietnam Airlines JSC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The flag carrier and its low-cost unit Scoot are flying to 114 destinations again, while Cathay and HK Express are only back to 70. Before the pandemic, they served 136 and 119 places, respectively.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singapore Airlines and Scoot have 195 planes, while Cathay has 222, some of which remain in storage.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore Airlines to roll out free Wi-fi for all passengers in rare move&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The speed at which Cathay can dust off its jets and bring them back into service will help determine its recovery to an extent, but it will be playing catch-up to Singapore Airlines for some time yet, regardless.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our journey of rebuilding Cathay for Hong Kong is on the right track,” Cathay Chief Executive Officer Ronald Lam said on June 6.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He didn&#39;t mention his rival based some 2,585km (1,600 miles) to the south.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 10:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Korea investigates secret Chinese ‘police stations’ after claims of 2 more being uncovered on Jeju Island]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3224646/south-korea-investigates-secret-chinese-police-stations-after-claims-2-more-being-uncovered-jeju?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/87326bf6-14c9-43b8-970f-6cf6c98cbaa7_9761b30e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;South Korean authorities are reportedly looking into alleged Chinese “secret police stations” in the country, as analysts say Seoul has apparently had enough of sovereignty transgressions by Chinese agents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Security authorities have uncovered two suspected Chinese secret police stations on southern Jeju Island, bringing the total number of such stations in South Korea to three, including one found in Seoul last year, Yonhap News TV reported on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spokesman at the Chinese embassy in Seoul slammed the allegations as “totally groundless”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is our firm official stance that there exists no so-called secret police stations set up by China in this country,” he told This Week in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Japan urged to root out secret Chinese &#39;police stations&#39; amid spying concerns&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s foreign ministry spokesman Wang Wengbin said last month that there were “no so-called overseas police stations” and that such accusations were “disinformation … smearing and discrediting China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said there were institutions helping Chinese nationals in other countries return home during the pandemic, but these were “not so-called police stations or police service centres”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to news reports, South Korean intelligence operatives reached a tentative conclusion last month that a Chinese restaurant in central Seoul was acting as a base for undeclared police operations for Beijing, the first example uncovered in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was no immediate comment from South Korea&#39;s National Intelligence Agency on the reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After opening in 2017, the restaurant in Seoul remained unprofitable before it shut early this year to carry out renovations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Owner Wang Haijun, 44, in December denied reports that his restaurant served as a “secret police station” for China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also rejected allegations he was involved in secret police activities, such as suppressing Chinese dissidents and forcibly repatriating them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We never forcibly arrested anti-Chinese people, it&#39;s not something we&#39;re involved in. We don&#39;t have the ability or authority to do so,” he told journalists at that time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang said he served as the head of the Overseas Chinese Service Centre in Seoul, which local news reports had accused of having links to the secret police.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What are China&#39;s &#39;secret police stations&#39; and is their role exaggerated?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said the organisation “helps Chinese people who die or are injured [in South Korea] due to unexpected circumstances such as illness, to return to China”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Safeguard Defenders, a Madrid-based human rights group, said in a report last year that the United Front Work Department – a Communist Party body that coordinates influence operations in China and abroad – was behind the “secret police stations” the NGO claimed to have found in 53 countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US State Department describes China&#39;s United Front Work Department as being “responsible for coordinating domestic and foreign influence operations, through propaganda and manipulation of susceptible audiences and individuals” for the interests of the Communist Party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, the Netherlands said two such police facilities found in Amsterdam and Rotterdam had been closed. Ireland also ordered another centre in Dublin to shut, according to news reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese authorities have previously said the facilities are run “voluntarily” to offer services such as renewing documents for Chinese nationals overseas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Safeguard Defenders believe the main function of the facilities is to pressure some Chinese dissidents to return to China to face criminal charges.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tools they use to do so, including “denying the target&#39;s children in China the right to education”, are “similar to the North Korean practice”, the group has alleged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its report said such police stations were operated out of four Chinese jurisdictions: Nantong, Wenzhou, Qingtian and Fuzhou. The one in South Korea is believed by the group to be operated out of Nantong, a city in China&#39;s southeastern Jiangsu province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Against this backdrop, Choi Jae-hyung, a lawmaker from South Korea&#39;s ruling People Power Party, last week introduced a bill to the National Assembly with a view to forcing all foreign governments&#39; agents in the country to register with the Justice Ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi said this would enable authorities to identify any instructions, orders and money that were delivered to such agents and help officials to detect influence operations designed to intervene in domestic policies or bend public opinion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cho Tae-yong, one of Seoul&#39;s top national security officials, said last week that South Korea would build a “healthy bilateral relationship with China” through a “self-confident diplomacy” in line with the country&#39;s increased national strength.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Relations between countries should be based on mutual respect,” Cho said last week at a seminar held to celebrate President Yoon Suk-yeol&#39;s first anniversary in office.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China-South Korea ties are low and could go lower, Chinese envoy says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Yoon administration has accused its predecessor, the government of liberal president Moon Jae-in, of being “submissive” to Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang Uk, a security expert at the Seoul-based Asan Institute for Policy Studies think tank, said South Korea had apparently reached its limit in “letting Chinese agents operate without restraints” as conservative President Yoon toughens his stance towards Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The two countries should address this issue quietly to avoid a vicious cycle of tit-for-tat in expelling each other&#39;s agents,” Yang said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee Il-woo, an analyst at the Korea Defence Network, said that in addition to the usual intelligence collecting activities, Chinese agents were suspected of using Chinese migrant workers and students in South Korea to influence public opinion online in favour of China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Korea Times&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 09:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Hubby, I’m wrong’: repentant Chinese woman begs ex to take her back with placard messages outside his home, divides online opinion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3224589/hubby-im-wrong-repentant-chinese-woman-begs-ex-take-her-back-placard-messages-outside-his-home?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/88774932-edb6-403f-90ea-2d757cb7685e_96222239.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A woman in China has gone viral on mainland social media for begging her ex-husband to remarry her while holding a placard in front of his home for hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unidentified woman from Shandong province in eastern China waited for her ex for more than six hours last Thursday to ask him for another chance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Star Video, the reason for their divorce was not clear, but the woman felt regret.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a viral clip filmed by a passerby, surnamed Zhu, the woman is shown standing in a car park and holding a small placard above her head while her lower body supports a large placard. She later knelt on the ground.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hubby, I am wrong,” the woman wrote on the smaller placard.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the large sign, she wrote: “All I want is to remarry and give our child an intact family. I will be here to wait for you to come downstairs to see me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu said he stumbled upon the woman when passing by in the afternoon. Despite the blazing sun, the woman insisted on staying in the car park.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman repeatedly called her ex-husband&#39;s name to attract his attention while raising the small sign. She then began kneeling and shouting to beg him to come down to the car park. She repeated the motions again and again without any response from her ex-husband.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“No matter what she did, her ex-husband didn&#39;t show up,” Zhu told Star Video.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu stayed at the scene for a while in an attempt to find out more about the situation. After asking a resident of the building, Zhu learned the woman had been waiting under the sun for more than six hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The woman regrets their divorce, and she wants to remarry her ex-husband,” the resident told Zhu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story sparked a flurry of reactions on Chinese social media, with 300,000 views and 7,292 comments at the time of writing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I take pity on her, but I do think she makes it difficult for her ex-husband,” said one social media observer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Who would beg to remarry in this manner? If I were the woman&#39;s husband, I wouldn&#39;t remarry her,” said another commenter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February, BJ News reported that 1.64 million couples had divorced in the first three quarters of 2022, an increase of 3.72 per cent when compared to the same period in the previous year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2021, the provinces of Henan in central China, southwestern Sichuan and Guangdong in the south, reported the country&#39;s highest number of divorces.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese military to get new rules to control top commanders’ social lives]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3224649/chinese-military-get-new-rules-control-top-commanders-social-lives?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/19/943af45a-1e18-4221-9d71-7271b0d0053b_edb86036.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s top military body has issued a new set of rules controlling the social activities of serving and retired senior officers from the People&#39;s Liberation Army.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new rules, recently approved by the Central Military Commission chaired by President Xi Jinping, were jointly promulgated by the political and disciplinary departments of the PLA in what analysts described as an effort to further tighten control.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A report published on the front page of PLA Daily on Monday said the rules included “specific requirements and concrete demands in eight areas” without giving further details.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese and Russian armed forces agree to hold more joint drills&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The rules set out a code of conduct for dealing with Communist Party officials, government bodies and state-owned enterprises, social organisations, the media, academic and research bodies, ethnic minority and religious groups, foreign institutions and family members as well as people they meet online, according to the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Political and disciplinary bodies will carry out their supervisory responsibilities, look out for and correct any problems that are in violation of the rules or the law,” the PLA Daily report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[They will] hold any of the leading cadres who have been found responsible for dereliction of duty and instil a strong sense of party spirit among them and encourage them to practice self-discipline so that [the leading cadres] will live a clean social life publicly, and among their families and friends,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The goal] is that their social life is principled, has boundaries and is based upon rules.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is an unprecedented move [for the PLA] to have a set of codes on social life for the senior cadres,” said Ni Lexiong, a professor of political science at Shanghai University of Political Science and Law. “This has not been done even in Mao Zedong&#39;s times.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But it has become necessary now [for the PLA] to keep up with changing times,” he said. “Corruption has remained a problem for the military.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ni explained that the rules were needed since engagement between PLA generals and retired officers with local party and government leaders, businesses and social bodies was inevitable and the influence of social media and the online world had grown significantly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For example, the consumption of heavy liquor was a tradition among some senior officers although it was banned after Xi became the head of the Central Military Commission in 2012,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I believe it will be spelled out in the new rules again that this is not allowed.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A PLA source said the new rules, which target leading cadres of the military, would also be applied to retired generals, who are known to wield considerable influence over the younger leaders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Many retired generals are active in religious and cultural groups, and their presence in these bodies can sometimes be used by others for profiteering, creating very bad social effects,” the source said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Chenming, a researcher with the Beijing-based Yuan Wang military science and technology think tank, said the new rules were likely aimed at eradicating the legacy of two disgraced former CMC vice-chairmen and generals, Guo Boxiong and Xu Caihou.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guo and Xu are the most senior PLA leaders purged by Xi in an anti-corruption campaign that started in 2013. The pair were accused of accepting bribes from other officers in return for promotions. Guo is serving a life sentence for corruption and Xu died in 2015 when he was under investigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Tight time, unfamiliar seas&#39;: PLA Navy destroyer tested on evacuation skills&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Zeng Zhiping, a law professor of Guangzhou College of Commerce, said the PLA would need to implement the rules transparently or it would face resistance from the generals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The best way is to allow the public to take part in the supervision so there will be a balance of power and supervision,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s rash of violent crimes may not be result of ‘copycat effect’, experts say, as one warns post-Covid stress could lead to more conflicts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3224656/hong-kongs-rash-violent-crimes-may-not-be-result-copycat-effect-experts-say-one-warns-post-covid?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/19/e6e87193-0f79-48dd-a39c-5e6bd54b7d64_f672d7f8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A recent spate of knife attacks in Hong Kong should not necessarily be attributed to perpetrators copying each other, experts have said, with one warning that pent-up stress among residents following the Covid-19 pandemic could lead to more conflicts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The remarks from experts on Monday followed a third incident this month, when a McDonald&#39;s employee on Sunday allegedly attacked his manager at work with a pair of knives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Police a day later laid a holding charge against the 29-year-old man with one count of wounding. He is expected to appear at the city&#39;s Eastern Court on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The force said the man had argued with the 38-year-old victim over his job performance before the incident. The suspect had no prior record of mental illness, they added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hospital Authority said on Monday the victim remained in serious condition.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Knife attack at McDonald&#39;s outlet leaves Hongkongers concerned for own safety&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Dennis Wong Sing-wing, a criminology professor at City University, said it was unlikely that the recent attacks were due to others attempting to imitate crimes reported by news outlets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the person has a risk factor, say a mental health problem, and feelings of frustration, anger or hatred, they may find a knife attack to be a good way to vent their feelings when they see someone else do it,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He added the theory only applied to those who imitated crimes without any other underlying motive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The criminologist argued copycat behaviour “could hardly be an explanation for crime”, instead it could only serve as a catalyst under certain conditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong mall stabbing: suspect fit for plea, psychiatrists confirm&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Knives were also a common tool in wounding cases, meaning there was no need to copy their use from other incidents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Professor Eric Chui Wing-hong, head of Polytechnic University&#39;s Department of Applied Social Sciences, warned those under huge mental stress and lacking the capacity to process such widely reported incidents were more likely to copy such crimes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When people read the news about those violent crimes, they can easily tell the consequences. But a mentally incapacitated person, or those under immense mental stress that cannot think critically, may simply follow suit blindly,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Chui stressed that only a small number of people might attempt to imitate violent crimes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong said he was concerned the city might experience record-breaking violent crime figures this year in the wake of a string of incidents over the past few months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two women were fatally stabbed at the Plaza Hollywood shopping centre in Diamond Hill earlier this month. The suspect, who has a history of mental illness, was charged with two counts of murder.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 27-year-old man was last week arrested on suspicion of attacking his former supervisor, 43, with a meat cleaver in an underpass connected to Choi Hung MTR station.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city recorded 2,249 incidents of violent crime during this year&#39;s first quarter, an increase of more than 20 per cent from the same period last year, police figures showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police arrest 27-year-old man after woman slashed in underpass&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Among the cases recorded during the first three months of this year, 890 were classified as wounding and serious assault. The figure was a 20 per cent rise from the same period the year before.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong said people&#39;s mental health could be more unstable amid the early stages of post-pandemic recovery and after three years of strict social-distancing curbs and high stress.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Some people will tend to vent their emotions and find it hard to deal with conflicts in a rational manner,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“People&#39;s emotions are running high in post-pandemic days. That is why they went revenge-shopping, travelling and dining … and they wanted to rush so much within a short period of time.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s labour shortage could also be another source of conflict for residents, as they would need to compete more fiercely for the limited services on offer, Wong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The academic advised Hongkongers to “stay calm and take things one step at a time”, and appealed to the authorities to allocate more resources to support the public during the post-pandemic emotional transition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong also asked media outlets that covered violent crimes to avoid excessively grisly details, which could affect people&#39;s emotions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chui called on the public to adopt a rational mindset when processing and sharing news online, arguing such behaviour could help to avoid creating a panic.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2 women stabbed to death in brutal knife attack at Hong Kong shopping mall&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Dr Ephraem Tsui Pui-wang, a registered clinical psychologist with the Hong Kong Psychological Society, said determining whether a crime was a copycat one depended on learning the perpetrator&#39;s motive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said assault cases were not uncommon in the city and, although offenders could be influenced by other incidents, any similarities between such crimes could be put down to coincidence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The way that a person perceives the news is very subjective. We would need to look into how he thinks, and why he chooses to express anger in that way, because not all people with risk factors will be affected and choose to hurt people,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China cuts mortgage-related rate to prop up economy. Is property loosening on the way?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224671/china-cuts-mortgage-related-rate-prop-economy-property-loosening-way?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 09:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/20/b86dde65-3597-4147-940f-2d363e0f8c00_8a64440d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China cut two benchmark lending rates on Tuesday, in the latest sign that Beijing&#39;s policymakers are aiming to lower the financial burden on households and also help stabilise the cooling property sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The five-year loan prime rate (LPR) – which is a reference rate for mortgages – was cut from 4.3 to 4.2 per cent at the June fixing, the People&#39;s Bank of China said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The one-year loan prime rate – the medium-term lending benchmark for corporate loans – was also cut from 3.65 to 3.55 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both key lending rates were last cut in August.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;6 takeaways from China&#39;s economic data as youth unemployment hit a new high&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The LPR has been considered China&#39;s de facto benchmark funding cost since 2019. The rate is decided by a group of 18 banks and is reported in the form of a spread over the interest rate of the central bank&#39;s medium-term lending facility.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Friday, China&#39;s State Council announced plans for “more powerful” economic packages to expand effective demand, strengthen the real economy and defuse risks in key areas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And many policy advisers and analysts have suggested more support for the property sector, which is seen as a major growth engine for the Chinese economy, is required.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Stabilising expectations and confidence is vital for the stabilisation of the property market,” said a research report by Tsinghua University at the weekend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Property is the largest source of both assets and liabilities for Chinese families, and has plagued financial regulators, developers, commercial banks and households over the last three years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The national average mortgage rate – considering the preferential rate for first homebuyers and the rate for buyers of more than one property – was 4.14 per cent in the first quarter, representing a fall of 1.35 percentage points from a year earlier, according to central bank data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Property investment in the first five months of the year fell by 7.2 per cent from a year earlier, an acceleration from a fall of 6.2 per cent in the first four months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Floor space sold also fell by 0.9 per cent, year on year, in the first five months of the year compared to a decrease of 0.4 per cent in the first four months.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;3 takeaways from China&#39;s price data as deflation worries rose&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Tsinghua University team, led by former central bank adviser Li Daokui, suggested Beijing should make it clear to public that in the short term it will not levy a property tax – that could help alleviate local-level government debt pressure and narrow the wealth gap – and instead implement city-specific policies to boost demand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese leaders have been discussing a first-of-its-kind tax on property since 2003 and a new pilot programme was mentioned in 2021. A national registration system is also in place after a decade-long effort to record all of the information on urban flats, villas, offices and rural houses, but Chinese households have expressed concerns that a US-like property tax would increase their costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local authorities have imposed a variety of restrictions – including on purchases, mortgages and financing for developers – given Beijing&#39;s overriding principle that houses are for living in and not for speculation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some cities have partially lifted purchase restrictions and increased quotas for mortgage loans.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s debt restrictions are debilitating at local levels, and Beijing should ease up, advisers urge]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224602/chinas-debt-restrictions-are-debilitating-local-levels-and-beijing-should-ease-advisers-urge?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.20 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/19/2f984657-3cf6-4103-a514-45b9bb3114ff_45a899ba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Beijing should be more tolerant of mounting debt among local governments while sharing their burden and allowing for more time to rectify the situation, Chinese policy advisers have said amid rising concerns over heavily indebted localities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The suggestions came as a looming local debt crisis has not only sparked widespread worries over the health of China&#39;s financial system, it is also threatening to curtail the effects of Beijing&#39;s stimulus plan – discussed by the State Council on Friday – to revive the faltering economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing should also consider postponing the deadline for local governments to defuse off-the-books debt, while raising the warning line for their debt ratio, said Zhao Quanhou, a researcher with the Chinese Academy of Fiscal Sciences, an affiliate of the Ministry of Finance.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As China&#39;s local governments struggle to repay debts, should Beijing help out?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The central government should raise the debt warning line to 150 per cent, the upper limit suggested by the International Monetary Fund (IMF), as many local authorities have already surpassed the current warning line of 120 per cent, Zhao said last week at a seminar in Wuxi, Jiangsu province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also urged Beijing to extend the time given to local governments to handle their hidden debts – referring to off-budget borrowings often occurring in financing vehicles or other state-owned firms – by three years, to ease their burden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By doing so, he explained, local governments would not be so preoccupied with repaying and defusing debt, and thus supportive fiscal policies could more effectively “stabilise investment and stimulate consumption”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Is China&#39;s local government debt a concern and what role do LGFVs play?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;There is no official data on the existing scale of hidden debt. Former finance minister Lou Jiwei said at a forum in January that the total was estimated to be between 30 trillion yuan (US$4.2 trillion) and 50 trillion yuan as of 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And in a report published in February, the IMF estimated that the total debt of China&#39;s local government financing vehicles had swollen to a record 66 trillion yuan this year, more than double an estimated 30.7 trillion yuan in 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past few years, Beijing has stepped up its supervision of local government debt in an effort to curb risks and has told local governments not to count on a state bailout.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its quarterly economic analysis in late April, the Politburo headed by President Xi Jinping called for strengthening local-government-debt management and strictly controlling increases in hidden debt.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How is China defusing its debt bubble, and what&#39;s the outlook?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The central government should take over some of the local government debt and issue special treasury bonds to transfer liabilities of those that are overly indebted, a research team led by prominent economist Li Daokui proposed over the weekend.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We suggest that the central government should work together with local governments to defuse existing debts,” said the team&#39;s report, released at a forum hosted by the Academic Centre for Chinese Economic Practice and Thinking under Tsinghua University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Internationally, the Chinese central government&#39;s debt ratio to GDP is relatively lower than other countries, so there&#39;s much room for that,” explained Lu Lin, a co-author of the report. “Repayment costs can be lowered when we issue lower-interest treasury bonds to swap local government debts, which have higher interest rates.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additionally, she said, the central government receives a “fairly big percentage” of the country&#39;s fiscal revenue but accounts for a “relatively low percentage” of expenditures.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>