<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[UK government vows massive recruitment drive for England’s National Health Service]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226184/uk-government-plans-massive-recruitment-drive-englands-national-health-service?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 21:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/e176abe3-f2f4-45ea-bd93-d43f29ee4181_85559084.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英格兰国家医疗服务体系 (NHS) 将在一项计划下招募超过 300,000 名员工政府周五宣布了一项新计划，旨在解决医生和护士长期短缺的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公共资助的 NHS 将于周三迎来成立 75 周年，预计到 2037 年将面临 36 万名劳动力短缺，因为人口老龄化、缺乏国内培训的卫生工作者以及留住员工的困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府的长期劳动力计划将包括减少医生在医学院的时间和培训更多本土员工，以改善低于欧洲平均水平的人员配置水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天，我们宣布对 NHS 的人员配置方式进行有史以来最雄心勃勃的变革，”总理里希·苏纳克 (Rishi Sunak) 在新闻发布会上表示。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一项为期 15 年的计划，旨在实现有史以来最大程度的扩大我们培训的医生和护士的数量……该计划不仅可以缓解当今的压力，而且可以保护这个宝贵的国家机构从长远来看，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指责前几届政府“几十年来一直回避挑战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英国卫生工作者发动 NHS 历史上最大规模的罢工&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;英格兰国家医疗服务体系 (NHS England) 目前有 112,000 个职位空缺，因为该机构正在努力填补大量因工资问题以及英国脱欧后更严格的签证规定而离开该服务部门的员工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国国家医疗服务体系 (NHS) 遭遇了前所未有的罢工。去年，员工抱怨工资过低和工作过度，因为他们难以清理冠状病毒封锁期间产生的积压工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府表示，该计划的主要目标是培训和留住更多员工并改革工作方式。他们希望到 2037 年再增加 60,000 名医生、170,000 名护士和 71,000 名卫生专业人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了留住更多员工，政府正计划改变养老金计划，并为员工的职业生涯提供更大的灵活性。它还将鼓励使用人工智能和“虚拟病房”等创新技术，以更好地利用 NHS 资源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府要求卫生部门负责人提出这些提案，NHS 英格兰负责人对此表示欢迎高管阿曼达·普里查德 (Amanda Pritchard) 称其为“历史性时刻”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在谈到下周的里程碑时，普里查德表示，“这项雄心勃勃且大胆的 NHS 计划的发布感觉比周年纪念日更重要”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是一个千载难逢的机会，可以通过将人员配备建立在可持续的基础上来改善患者护理”，她说。 “我们将对 NHS 历史上的劳动力进行最大胆的改革——我们将增加本土医生、护士和其他工作人员的数量”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该计划还将鼓励在其他背景接受过培训的人通过学徒转向医疗保健行业。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;作为招聘竞标的一部分，香港向英国医生提供了 130 多个工作机会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;反对党工党指责2010 年以来执政的政府采纳自己的想法但行动太慢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“保守党最终承认他们没有自己的想法，因此正在采纳工党的计划来培训医生和护士NHS 需要，”影子卫生部长韦斯·斯特里廷 (Wes Streeting) 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们应该在十年前就这样做，这样 NHS 今天就会有足够的工作人员。相反，医疗服务部门缺乏 15 万名员工，这一公告需要数年时间才能产生影响。”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医疗保健在英国是一个权力下放的部门，由苏格兰、威尔士和北部地区的政府负责爱尔兰在那里制定政策。英国政府负责监督英格兰的健康状况。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong, mainland Chinese police arrest 17 suspects in connection with 149 online fraud cases, including writers of scripted scam dialogue]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3226185/hong-kong-mainland-chinese-police-arrest-17-suspects-connection-149-online-fraud-cases-including?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 21:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/04c6645f-f1ab-45e0-a1ed-dedeb799056f_81026e08.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港和中国内地警方逮捕了 17 名涉嫌参与犯罪集团的成员至少149起网络诈骗案件中，包括为骗子提供脚本对话以欺骗受害者的作家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周四和周五在联合行动中被捕的嫌疑人包括12名年龄在18岁至57岁之间的香港人.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这 10 名男子和两名女子因串谋诈骗和洗钱 3500 万港元而被捕，其中受害人被骗金额总计 6820 万港元（870 万美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港企业发誓打击诈骗者，不通过短信收集客户数据&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据警方称，五名驻香港的嫌疑人被认为是该诈骗集团的主谋和主要成员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，边境执法人员捣毁了该组织的行动中心，并拘捕了五名年龄介乎21至28岁的内地男子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内地团队主要负责联系、勒索受害人以及提供技术支持，警察说。据信，这些人还编写了所谓裸聊诈骗的短信对话模板等材料，其中包括诱骗受害者在视频对话中脱掉衣服，然后向骗子勒索钱财。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但当地警方周五拒绝透露突袭地点，称可能会逮捕更多人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至少有 157 名年龄在 13 岁至 79 岁之间的受害者被卷入诈骗案件，并有补偿约会诈骗受害人损失逾千万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方亦检获84张提款卡、31部流动电话、34张预付SIM卡、六部手提电脑及平板电脑，以及两块手表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;网络安全及科技罪案调查科警司谭伟信表示，内地警方早前已通知警方，发现本市有针对受害人的裸聊诈骗运作中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相关组织Tam 说：“从 2022 年 11 月开始运营……直到现在。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他解释说，这些欺诈行为的方法和目标各不相同。其中，网上购物诈骗案占40起，其中32起与投资诈骗有关，27起与求职诈骗有关。已发现有偿交友案件多达20起，其中裸聊勒索案件14起，网络游戏诈骗案件10起，虚拟恋情诈骗案件6起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该团伙还被认为利用了更多手段。超过 100 个本地走狗银行账户，洗钱约 3,500 万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们相信我们已经成功打击了跨境有组织犯罪集团，”谭说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;洪香港警方拘捕25名嫌疑人，提醒长者提防电话诈骗&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;总督察郑泽恩表示，内地骗徒通过网上交友应用程序与受害者联系，并声称提供裸聊或有偿约会的机会。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;他们后来勒索受害者，强迫他们将钱存入傀儡账户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑解释说，香港同行负责洗钱、管理账户、将资金转换为资金。最大的受害者是一名 54 岁的男子，他通过 49 笔单独的交易损失了超过 1000 万港元。诈骗者通过一款声称提供有偿约会机会的智能手机应用程序与他联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最年轻的受害者是一名 13 岁女孩，她试图在社交媒体上出售自己的在线游戏帐户，损失了 2,300 港元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方逮捕25名嫌疑人后，警告老年人提防电话诈骗&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;郑表示，总收益的1％已作为佣金给一些集团成员。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;高级督察吴伯伟表示，去年裸聊诈骗案件已从 2019 年的 171 起增至 1,402 起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至 5 月，已记录了 657 起案件，增加了 10%与去年同期相比，损失超过1,100万港元，增加了30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谭表示，大多数旨在预防犯罪的法律也适用于互联网，居民不应测试极限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为避免成为骗子的目标，居民在与朋友在线互动时应保持谨慎，尤其是当这些人索要个人信息或试图借用银行账户时。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong inks cross-border data transfer deal for Greater Bay Area with China’s internet regulator following crackdown]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/policy/article/3226161/hong-kong-inks-cross-border-data-transfer-deal-greater-bay-area-chinas-internet-regulator-following?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 21:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/5f8f610c-d08e-4e53-9399-d6dee9a53023_94cbf062.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港和中国中央政府签署备忘录，简化跨境数据传输在大湾区内，这项协议可能会让这座南方半自治城市在处理来自中国的数据方面发挥特殊作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的数据监管机构国家互联网信息办公室 (CAC) 和香港据该机构周五发布的公告，香港创新科技工业局同意在国家数据安全管理框架下起草该地区（包括澳门和广东省九个城市）数据安全流动规则。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;虽然网信办没有透露细节，但表示该交易有望增强内地与香港之间的数据流动，充分发挥数据的利用作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;C2NET首先承认&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;香港前特首梁振英在 Facebook 上发帖称，这份备忘录是双方多年努力的“成就”和“突破”双方。同时担任中国最高政治咨询机构副主席的梁振英表示，该协议可以“平衡国家网络安全和跨境交流的需要”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港创新科技局局长孙东工信部在香港政府网站发布的另一则公告称，该备忘录将促进内地数据便捷有序地转移到香港，有利于香港建设全球数据中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“便利湾区数据流动是推动湾区一体化高质量发展、降低企业合规成本、带动香港数字经济发展、主动融入国家发展的重要举措该技术负责人在声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该交易是在中国近年来出台新法律加强对跨境数据传输的控制之后达成的。 2021年生效的《数据安全法》和《个人信息保护法》对未经授权收集、处理、存储和使用境内产生的数据行为进行了严厉处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，中国还对跨境数据传输实施了严格的新规定，要求从中国向境外目的地传输“重要”且大量的数据，并接受网络安全审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计该规定将使情况变得复杂化和大幅提高了许多国际企业在内地运营的合规成本，但没有具体说明内地与香港之间的数据流是否也涵盖在内。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据跨境数据传输规则规定，处理超过100万中国居民个人信息的企业必须经过安全审查，如果是“关键信息基础设施运营者”或需要转让“重要信息基础设施”的企业进行转让，则需要获得网信办的批准。 ”数据。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 ex-flight attendants at Hong Kong’s Cathay Pacific found guilty of accepting HK$78,000 in bribes to help travellers get discounted tickets]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3226181/3-ex-flight-attendants-hong-kongs-cathay-pacific-found-guilty-accepting-hk78000-bribes-help?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 21:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/7f90103a-1126-4e24-b6ae-38015c09b027_6196067b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;三名前国泰航空空姐因收受超过港币七万八千元被判有罪（10,000美元）帮助三名旅客获得优惠机票，给香港旗舰航空公司造成近86万港元的损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;区域法院周五将李宗辉和黄爱廷定罪凭借其前同事刘静雯的证据，被指控两项贿赂罪。刘静雯今年早些时候认罪后，在审讯中为控方作证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭获悉，三人滥用职权。 2018 年至 2019 年间，员工受益于国泰航空的同伴旅行计划，该计划为员工的家人和朋友提供高达 90％ 的机票折扣，如果他们的提名被航空公司接受。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lau，前航班事务长早些时候承认，她从一名越南时装设计师（在法庭上被指称 Trang Nha Le Do）收受了 1,500 美元，作为出售她的提名的奖励。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Le Do，又名 Mimi，购买了 20 张国泰航空门票只需港币 19,500 元，节省近港币 330,000 元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;设计师还寻求刘的协助，以 8,500 美元向当时的侍者 Lee 和 Wong 购买提名，送给她的男友 Marc Dambrines 和 Dambrines 的妹妹 Mariah Ernst .&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;国泰航空解雇3名员工，指其侮辱非英语人士&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;兄妹共购买29张机票，总价约港币35,000元，不足原价港币526,000元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刘承认三项串谋代理人接受利益的罪名，而李和黄则各自否认一项罪名。刘周五没有出庭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这三名旅客没有被捕，因为他们不在香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李告诉审判，他不知道所谓的阴谋并坚称他只是与刘讨论通过私下向乘客出售机上免税品来赚钱的方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，他提名丹布林斯是因为后者是他的情人。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;法官郭启安周五驳回了李的主张，并指出前服务员甚至不记得自己何时开始与该男子约会。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“高度关注”：香港国泰航空的疏散受到政府关注&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;Kwok 强调了从 Lau 的手机中恢复的消息记录，其中显示 Lee 向 Lau 提供 10% 的佣金，以将他连接到 Dambrines。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee 声称这笔回扣是为了让 Lau 建议赚取额外的费用通过在机上出售免税商品赚钱，但郭表示，机组人员从这种“高风险”活动中获利是不切实际的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官进一步判定黄有罪，黄没有出庭作证。 ，在拒绝了她的警告声明后，她从买家恩斯特那里收到的钱是机票预付款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法院撤销了黄的保释，但将李释放到下周四，以便他可以完成大学考试&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着航班数量的增加，香港国泰航空的新机组人员每月收入高达 20,000 港元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这是你不想看到的结果，但我可以告诉你们这不是世界末日，”郭告诉被告席上耻辱的两人。 “但就目前的情况来看，[贿赂罪]会被判处监禁。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辩护律师表示，两名被告愿意全额赔偿其前雇主遭受的损失。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;法院预计将于 9 月份对所有三名被告进行判决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在地方法院，串谋代理人接受利益的行为最高可判处七年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 21:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese travellers in visa rush for first post-Covid overseas summer holiday]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3226182/chinese-travellers-visa-rush-first-post-covid-overseas-summer-holiday?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 21:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/458a2830-7d73-4031-8e91-a0e8373afbba_d1eedc50.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国东部城市杭州的艺术家托尼·包 (Tony Bao) 计划拜访朋友今年夏天，他在荷兰自疫情大流行以来第一次见到他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他于五月初申请了申根签证，预计有足够的时间获得允许他入境的文件欧洲大部分国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他最早能预约的是8月15日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“三个月的等待时间太长了，但我真的很想见到我的朋友们欧洲，所以我可以接受。”鲍说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京，李海棠从 3 月份开始与伴侣申请美国签证，但得知她必须等到 6 月份才能获得签证面试时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李没有时间等待 - 她向一家公司支付了 1,500 元（约合 200 美元），帮助她将面试推迟到 4 月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的男朋友刚刚向我提议的。我们想庆祝生命中这个甜蜜的时刻，并在春天——一年中最好的时节——去美国旅行。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;签证代理表示，来自大陆的游客正在涌入。希望充分利用自中国政府一月份取消零新冠病毒政策并开放边境以来的第一个暑假。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近几周，美国和一些欧洲国家的签证申请激增唯一可用的预约是在几个月后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，周五通过美国大使馆网站尝试确保签证面试的时间（几乎所有中国游客都必须这样做）表明旅游签证申请人将在上海预约需要等待128个日历日，在北京预约需要等待119天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;等待时间最短的是在沉阳领事馆预约，等待时间为75天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;西南城市成都的签证代理人高安表示，西方国家的签证申请量“显着增加”——这是她在该行业工作五年来从未见过的需求。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“如果有人计划今年夏天去美国旅行，他们至少必须在四月份申请签证。现在申请已经太晚了，”高说，并补充说今年剩余时间的需求预计会很高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们可能要等到明年农历新年之后，那时每个人都可以申请。想要出去的人在需求减少之前就已经来回了。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;广州签证机构张朝阳表示，申请数量“史无前例”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “夏天忙碌对我们来说并不奇怪，但没有这样的事情，”张说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;想来一次野生动物园吗？非洲国家正在争夺大部分中国游客&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据申根签证规则，申请人必须在 15 天内收到决定，该期限可以延长至 30 天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但一些欧盟国家警告旅客等待时间较长，并提醒他们在获得签证之前不要尝试购买机票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府签证外包和技术服务专家 VFS Global 周三表示，丹麦驻广州领事馆的签证处理时间可能长达 30 天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国大使馆的外包签证机构 TLScontact 也表示，由于申请人数激增，申请人可能需要“更长的等待时间”。 “放宽Covid-19旅行限制”带来的申请。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 21:20:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s leaders and their social media strategies one year on: Thumbs up or down? Experts say they are not impressed]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3226175/hong-kongs-leaders-and-their-social-media-strategies-one-year-thumbs-or-down-experts-say-they-are?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/ffe270c2-9c7e-4e76-83c8-257b693bca65_7e1da428.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港领导人李家超及其政府一年前推出在线账户传播专家表示，他们的目的是为了利用社交媒体，但在利用社交媒体讲述更好的香港故事方面仅仅触及了表面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家们解释说，部长们倾向于专注于他们所做的工作或揭开面纱。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府官员也没有采取太多行动积极“出售”香港，尽管这已被定为他们表示，疫情后重新开放城市后，这是政府的优先事项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位部长的个性化内容策略引起了人们的关注，一位前高级政府助理表示，纳税人可能更愿意把钱花在&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 7 月 1 日，行政长官李家超上任仅几个小时，他就在他的第二个 Facebook 帖子中承诺，他将通过分享来加强与公众的联系&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一年过去了，在发布了 270 多条帖子后，Lee 的 Facebook 页面已经吸引了大约 40,000 名粉丝，获得了大约 22,600 个页面点赞，并积累了超过 530,000 次互动。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与李光耀大约同时进入社交媒体舞台的部长们受到了不同程度的关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港二号官员、布政司陈国基大约有大约3,300 名追随者。财政司司长陈茂波约有2,600人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;保安部长邓炳强是新人中的佼佼者。唐的 Facebook 粉丝数约为 30,000 人，页面点赞数为 21,000，与李的相差不远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浸会大学新闻系副教授 Rose Luqiu Luwei 博士表示，唐受益于以下策略：与李相比，他使用了更多的视频和幕后内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐的两个最受欢迎的帖子都是与妻子在音乐会上的自拍照。每个人都获得了大约 8,000 个赞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但唐最近发布的一个庆祝端午节的视频，其中他与保安局实习生分享粽子，在在线论坛 LIHKG 上引起了严厉的评论。一位用户写道：“他没事可做吗，他的新闻都是吃东西和拍视频。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;蜜月结束？香港领导人的微博粉丝对垃圾邮件提出批评&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;闾丘同意引人入胜的内容可以保持公众对高层官员页面的兴趣，但认为他们还应该通过提供更多个人见解和回应评论来促进社交媒体上的对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但其他专家表示，他们认为社交媒体平台不适合进行严肃的政策讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;传播顾问伊丽莎白说，人物塑造是社交媒体内容策略的典型目标。黄杰伟说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她解释说，邓的网页成功地传达了一个坚强但内心温柔的形象，他像普通人一样生活。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她说李的 Facebook 页面对她来说就像他的工作日记。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“已经过去了一整年了，我仍然无法说出关键信息是什么。我得到的唯一信息是他的日程安排得很满，经常出差。”黄说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;轻松的内容不一定是个人的，曾担任竞选记者的朱利安·罗永中 (Julian Law Wing-chung) 说道。前财政司司长曾俊华的行政长官竞选活动说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“让你喜欢香港政府或政府中某个官员的[策略]是有区别的。对于涉及公共资金的事情，我们可能不会期望它集中在一个人身上，”劳解释道，他现在经营着一家为包括政府在内的客户提供通信服务的公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还对官员将其影响力扩大到内地社交媒体平台的理由，而这些平台上没有多少香港居民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李、陈和唐在微博（一个类似于中国推特的平台）上开始了他们的账户，在过去的一年里。李曾表示，他希望自己在该服务上的首次亮相能够让内地人更好地了解这座城市并改善跨境关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年九月，唐成为第一位开设小红书账户的高级官员，该账户在年轻的内地人中很受欢迎因为其照片和视频内容较多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当他们与小红书合作时，他们面对的不是香港人，而是内地人，其中当然包括内地官员，”罗说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保安局目前为自己和唐管理着四个平台的六个页面。微博和小红书上的存在仅限于秘书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位发言人表示，该局在内地平台上的“增强存在感”将吸引游客，并“有助于吸引人才和企业，加强我们与大湾区的联系” 。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，在人们对纪律部队存在“巨大误解”的背景下，通过社交媒体培养公众对纪律部队工作的兴趣尤为重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公共事务顾问曾荫权前市长的宣传工作何安达表示，通过社交媒体改变公众想法的尝试不太可能取得成果，因为人们已经建立了坚定的信念。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;何说，面对一连串批评香港的外国政府报道，政府应该通过Twitter和Tik Tok（香港无法使用）接触西方受众，“告诉香港香港的故事很好”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在每次报道后发表新闻声明是不够的，”何坚称。 “千篇一律的言论作为表明立场的方式很好，但无助于影响他人的观点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港受到欧美的不公平攻击&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;前政府信息控制员呼吁他的前同事对网上对香港的怀疑发起挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将如何反击这些信息？我们知道这些人如何在抖音和推特上谈论香港吗？”他问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黄说，由于李所面临的政治环境比他的前任要少得多，因此他是时候采取更积极的内容策略并详细阐述他一直想讲述的“香港故事”了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为行政长官，他眼中的香港故事是什么？这是他的施政理念，也是他作为政治领袖的愿景。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以人为本的讲故事内容可以唤起部分香港人的情感，比上传的内容更容易分享她认为，去年在李的 Facebook 页面上访问过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong 表示，促进李的追随者基础的增长至关重要，因为这位城市领导人在受到美国制裁后无法支付费用并在 Facebook 上增加帖子。 2020 年，他因在执行北京实施的国家安全法中所发挥的作用而受到表彰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更广泛的受众也可能会带回不同的声音，并有助于官员评估公众舆论。Law（也是前财政部长的助手）曾俊华补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政长官办公室发言人表示，人们认识到社交媒体是吸引公众并评估公众对新政策感受的有效方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;发言人补充说：“我们会密切关注公众使用社交媒体的最新趋势，并适时检讨扩大社交媒体网络的需要。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[With Starlink, Japan ‘could buy more time’ in conflict over Taiwan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3226176/starlink-japan-could-buy-more-time-conflict-over-taiwan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/30/801b1f4d-ef27-45fd-89a4-7047859f1d9a_fd6d66a9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本军方决定将星链添加到其通信工具箱中，这将增强其防御能力并购买分析人士表示，为台北和华盛顿在该岛冲突中争取更多时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周二的一份报道中，《日本时报》援引日本防卫大臣滨田康和的话说，证实日本自卫队一直在测试&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“近年来，对不受限制地使用太空的威胁不断增加，通过使用多个通信卫星网络来提高卫星通信的弹性非常重要，”滨田说&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据《读卖新闻》报道，东京计划在下一个财政年度采用星链技术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自去年乌克兰军方采用该技术以来， Starlink 是美国亿万富翁埃隆·马斯克 (Elon Musk) 运营的先进宽带卫星互联网系统，以其稳健性和抗干扰性而闻名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰军方现在高度依赖该系统进行无人机飞行和炮击。俄罗斯军队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约哥伦比亚大学国际关系专家 Fumiko Sasaki 表示，在台湾问题上发生冲突时，解放军可能首先瞄准水下电缆和卫星，以中断台湾与台湾之间的通讯。 “就像俄罗斯在入侵乌克兰之前对 ViaSat 通信卫星进行网络攻击一样，”佐佐木说，他指的是总部位于加州的高速宽带服务&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本军队采用星链系统将使对台湾的攻击变得更加困难，成为对冲突的进一步威慑，她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;星链现在有近 3,700 个在近地轨道运行的小型卫星——仅占 SpaceX 目标数量的三分之一——其庞大的规模增强了其抗干扰能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“星链的使用将迫使解放军重新考虑佐佐木说：“调整其进攻战略，这需要时间，这将给日本更大的空间和更多的时间来加强防御。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但前台湾海军教官卢立石表示，马斯克的巨大商业利益在中国，可能会阻止这位亿万富翁在大陆和台湾之间的冲突中提供卫星服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“星链是民用用途，对马斯克来说是一项盈利业务，但它已变得至关重要乌克兰几乎是偶然，”陆说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“马斯克在美国以外最大的特斯拉工厂位于上海，去年交付了全球一半以上的特斯拉汽车，”陆说。 “大陆市场对马斯克来说至关重要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位亿万富翁对中国市场的浓厚兴趣在六月初访问大陆、会见中国高层官员并成为首批著名的西方商界领袖之一时就显而易见了。 to go to the country since the Covid pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think Musk would allow his Starlink to be used for the transmission of encoded military data if war happens over Taiwan,” Lu said.&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“In order to avoid political sanctions from China or the US, Musk might make Starlink strictly a commercial service as soon as the Ukraine war is over.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A businessman like him will never sacrifice a business interest even if he is a patriot.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sasaki said Japan would also improve the capacity and resilience of its advanced X-band defence satellite system, which was vulnerable to interference by China and Russia because of its limited number of satellites.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The SDF needs to diversify its defence communication network system. The use of Starlink in addition to its X-band system is one such effort,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macau-based military observer Antony Wong Tong said the PLA was working on ways to deal with Starlink.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It realised that a Taiwan attack should involve multi-domain and hybrid combat covering space, intelligence, communications, electromagnetic warfare, cognitive warfare and other areas,” Wong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That realisation was apparent in April when the Beijing Institute of Tracking and Telecommunications – part of the PLA&#39;s Strategic Support Force – said China must boost its anti-satellite abilities, including a surveillance system with unprecedented scale and sensitivity to track and monitor every Starlink satellite.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China also appears to be working on its own version of the system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February, China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation, the country&#39;s main space contractor, said its new Long March 5B heavy-lift rocket upper stage configuration could be used to help deliver a large number of satellites into space for its planned “Guo Wang” satellite internet mega-constellation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Guo Wang”, or “National Network” in Chinese, aims to be a low-Earth orbit broadband system with about 13,000 satellites.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Amid China’s AI investment fever, a debate on whether start-ups can make money from ChatGPT-style services]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3226107/amid-chinas-ai-investment-fever-debate-whether-start-ups-can-make-money-chatgpt-style-services?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/a98f3577-84de-49be-9dd9-ee27a95498fc_5056f310.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Is there still room for start-ups to profit from ChatGPT-style services in China? That question has stirred heated debate among Chinese entrepreneurs and investors after the launch of OpenAI&#39;s chatbot sparked a wave of artificial intelligence (AI) investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With ChatGPT and Google&#39;s Bard unlikely to be available in China due to the country&#39;s strict content regulation, local technology firms have been racing to introduce similar services.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of May, China had at least 79 large AI models with more than 1 billion parameters – a measure of the sophistication of a model – according to a recent report published by the Institute of Scientific and Technical Information of China, a government research agency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the jury is out on whether start-ups have a good chance of profiting from the new AI technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Allen Zhu Xiaohu, managing partner at GSR Ventures, a company that invests in early-stage start-ups, said in a conference in Beijing that ChatGPT may be a curse for AI start-ups, as the service is so powerful that it can perform better than many of their existing functions, according to Chinese media reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response, Fu Sheng, a well-known Chinese entrepreneur and CEO of internet company Cheetah Mobile, described Zhu in a comment as “fearlessly ignorant” about the business potential that ChatGPT can unlock.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu and Zhu did not immediately respond to requests for comment on this article.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The back-and-forth between the two industry veterans has caught the attention of China&#39;s tech community.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Yiran, an electrical and computer engineering professor at Duke University, said on Weibo that large language models (LLMs), the technology underpinning generative AI products such as ChatGPT, may be too costly for start-ups to build, but there are many opportunities for start-ups to develop applications based upon LLMs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hou Zhenyu, a vice-president at Baidu, said it is unsuitable for start-ups to develop LLMs from scratch because that is very expensive.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Money, graphics processing units and data are all challenges,” Hou was quoted as saying by Chinese magazine Caijing. “Baidu alone has bought tens of thousands of GPUs, which is a massive investment.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are already signs that China&#39;s generative AI industry is consolidating. Chinese food delivery giant Meituan on Thursday announced a buyout of Light Year, a four-month-old generative AI start-up founded by Meituan co-founder Wang Huiwen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deal involved a payment of US$28 million to the original investor HongShan, formerly known as Sequoia China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ChatGPT, the cutting-edge conversational bot developed by Microsoft-backed OpenAI, burst onto the scene last autumn, spurring a global AI arms race. Chinese firms, from tech giants to start-ups backed by venture capitalists and headed by big names in tech, have been joining their global peers in playing catch-up with the San Francisco-based start-up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These include Big Tech companies like social media and video gaming giant Tencent Holdings and e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding, owner of the South China Morning Post, and AI specialists such as voice recognition service provider iFlyTek.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Others that have jumped on the bandwagon include Modelbest and DeepLang AI, two of several start-ups affiliated with Tsinghua University&#39;s natural language processing project, and Baichuan, a start-up established by Wang Xiaochuan, founder and ex-CEO of search engine operator Sogou, with the goal of launching China&#39;s top LLM by the end of this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Dahai, chief technology officer at Chinese Quora-like website Zhihu and CEO at Beijing-based Modelbest, said in a recent interview with the Post that building a successful LLM is resource-intensive and involves a lot of uncertainties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When [OpenAI&#39;s] GPT-3 was released, everyone thought it was great … but there were not many application scenarios for the service,” he said. “Despite that, OpenAI remains committed to spending more money to develop other GPT models. This was a very different investment mindset.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Sheng, an investor with Beijing-based InnoAngel Fund, said there are different layers to AI investment opportunities in China, from underlying infrastructure that involves chips to large AI models to applications in which AI intersects and transforms other sectors. But he added that it is too late to jump into LLMs now.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you invested in [LLMs] last year or the year before, that&#39;s good … but now the opportunity is gone,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other experts seem to agree.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang Tiejun, deputy head at Peking University&#39;s Institute for Artificial Intelligence and research head at the Beijing Academy of Artificial Intelligence, told Tencent News that the world probably only needs three large AI models.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qu Kai, founder at Beijing-based financial advisory 42 Capital, said in an interview with the Post that 70 per cent of future investments are flowing into AI applications.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1 year of Hong Kong’s John Lee: what have been some of his more controversial moves?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3226168/1-year-hong-kongs-john-lee-what-have-been-some-his-more-controversial-moves?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/a38da329-0afa-4396-93d1-26c94962e2f4_9d819052.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Winning more than 99 per cent of the vote in the chief executive election in May last year, John Lee Ka-chiu came into office 12 months ago vowing to revive the city&#39;s international standing and reboot the beleaguered economy amid a prolonged shutdown due to the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From “light public housing” to a district council overhaul, the Post takes a look back at some of the headline-making measures taken by Lee&#39;s administration over the past year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;1. First interpretation of Hong Kong&#39;s national security law&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Lee last November sought Beijing&#39;s interpretation of the national security law after a failed bid in the city&#39;s top court to block London-based barrister Timothy Owen from representing media tycoon Jimmy Lai Chee-ying at his trial for allegations of collusion with foreign forces.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Beijing&#39;s ruling on Hong Kong national security law &#39;likely to be a one-off&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Instead of banning overseas lawyers from appearing in trials concerning state interests, China&#39;s top legislative body ruled the matter could be left to the city&#39;s leader and a committee to decide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But some legal academics expressed concerns about the interpretation, saying it had given the executive branch wide authority before the court.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government later also amended the Legal Practitioners Ordinance, which now allows local authorities to ban foreign lawyers from taking part in national security cases in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Justice Paul Lam Ting-kwok said it was not a total ban and overseas counsel could still work on sensitive cases in the city if the chief executive had determined that national security interests would not be compromised.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai&#39;s case has been scheduled for September this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What Beijing ruling on overseas lawyers in Hong Kong national security cases means&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;2. District council overhaul&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In a bid to “depoliticise” district councils and pivot their focus back to neighbourhood issues, Lee announced a shake-up of the municipal-level organisations in May which involves a reduction of democratically-elected seats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the plan, only about one-fifth of the 470 seats in the 18 district councils will be decided by popular vote. Authorities will appoint 179 members, while three government-appointed community committees will decide another 176, with a separate 27 seats reserved for rural leaders.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong district council reforms spark soul-searching on future of direct elections&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Candidates will also require nominations from members on the three community committees and are subject to a government screening procedure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee said the changes were meant to stop anti-China troublemakers and separatists from manipulating the district bodies as they did in 2019. But critics said the new structure would cut the connection between citizens and the councils, of which most of the seats were previously directly elected.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How will Hong Kong&#39;s district council overhaul change neighbourhood political life?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The government has said it hopes the Legislative Council can pass the District Councils (Amendment) Bill by early July to pave the way for the next elections at the end of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;3. Importing labour to address shortage&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s labour force shrank from 3.68 million in 2018 to 3.46 million in 2022. The government announced in June that it would import some 20,000 workers for the construction and transport sectors, and lift a ban prohibiting employers from bringing in people from overseas for 26 low-skilled jobs, such as clothing pressers, junior cooks and telephone operators.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following the move, unions accused the authorities of stripping the Labour Advisory Board of its say in vetting applications for importing workers. In a June 19 briefing session arranged by the government, the board&#39;s six labour-side members staged a walkout in protest, saying authorities had not consulted them before announcing the scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Officials said they had not intended to bypass the board and promised they would consult it periodically regarding the implementation of the schemes. They also denied the schemes would import cheap labour.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;4. Light public housing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;To cope with huge demand for public rental housing, Lee announced last October that 30,000 short-term light public housing flats would be built in five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plan, with an original price tag of HK$27.4 billion (US$3.5 billion), sparked concerns over cost-effectiveness. Authorities later decided not to include air conditioning in the flats to save about HK$1 billion. The government also sought funding from the legislature in two phases, instead of a lump sum amount as originally planned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A decision to build some of the homes in the prime urban commercial area of Kai Tak also led to controversy, with residents threatening to take to the streets in protest. The government did not back down, but promised the temporary homes would not stay beyond the five-year target and continue with planned commercial development for the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The scheme aims to help families in need who have waited for traditional public flats for three years or more.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong lawmakers approve first phase of light housing scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;5. Top Talent Pass Scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Launched last December, the scheme aims to attract high-earners and graduates from prestigious overseas universities. By the end of May, more than 32,000 applications were received, and about 21,000 were approved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The programme courted controversy in February after news reports emerged that controversial mainland Chinese biophysicist He Jiankui, who was once jailed for illegal medical practices, had been granted a visa.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong approves 361 applicants across 3 expanded talent schemes&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The government later revoked He&#39;s visa and amended the rules to require applicants to declare any criminal convictions. The requirement was later extended to several other talent recruitment schemes and further extended in June to cover people applying for work and student visas, including domestic helpers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee said in June that Hong Kong was well on its way to attracting nearly double the 35,000 workers annually targeted by various admission schemes rolled out by his administration to lure talent.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;6. A court injunction against “Glory to Hong Kong”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In a surprise move, the government on June 5 applied for a court injunction to ban the protest song “Glory to Hong Kong” – dubbed as the anthem of the 2019 anti-government demonstrations. The injunction targets those who use the song to advocate for the separation of Hong Kong from China, as well as anyone who uses the song to suggest that the city is independent or to insult the national anthem.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Glory to Hong Kong&#39; protest song to be banned? Government files court injunction&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The government seeks to ban all forms of the tune, sparking concerns about the freedom of speech and expression. Authorities have argued that the application is in line with the legitimate aim of safeguarding national security.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The court is expected to hear the case on July 21.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[France riots: State of emergency mulled by government over protest violence]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226170/france-riots-state-emergency-mulled-government-over-protest-violence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/edf1dee8-fefc-495e-a043-d0ccf7893db9_7952a9cb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;French Prime Minister Elisabeth Borne said on Friday that the government was considering “all options” to restore order, including declaring a state of emergency, after a third night of rioting over a police officer&#39;s killing of a youth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked by reporters if a state of emergency was a possibility, as some right-wing opposition parties have demanded, Borne replied: “I won&#39;t tell you now, but we are looking at all options, with one priority: restoring order throughout the country”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prime minister, who was visiting a police station in Evry-Courcouronnes south of Paris, is to attend a crisis security meeting chaired by President Emmanuel Macron at 1pm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A state of emergency would give authorities increased powers to declare localised curfews, ban demonstrations, and give police more freedom in restraining suspected rioters and searching homes.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;France riots: how teen&#39;s killing is focusing anger on police tactics&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Macron cut short a trip to Brussels for an EU summit on Friday and was said by an aide to be prepared to adopt new measures “without taboos”, though some ministers in the cabinet are known to be opposed to a state of emergency.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the nationwide urban riots in 2005, the right-wing government at the time declared a state of emergency after around two weeks of clashes, the first time the measure had been used in mainland France since the 1950s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are calling for a curfew initially, then the imposition of a full state of emergency and the mobilisation of all the forces of law and order in the country,” spokesman for the alt-right National Rally Sebastien Chenu told LCI television Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Right now we&#39;re at the bottom of a cliff and we need to be extremely tough,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The head of the right-wing Republicans party, Eric Ciotti, had called for a state of emergency on Thursday, saying “The nation cannot waver in any circumstances”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around 40,000 security forces were deployed on Thursday evening and 875 people were arrested overnight, according to the interior ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;France lived under a state of emergency for two years following the November 2015 terror attacks by jihadist gunmen that left 130 people dead at the Bataclan concert hall, restaurants and the national sports stadium.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many of the anti-terror provisions in the emergency law, including giving the government powers to close places of worship and restrain people without trial, were included in a new law passed in 2017 under Macron that was widely criticised by civil liberties groups.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An aide to Macron had played down the possibility of emergency law on Thursday, saying that there was “no need for an overreaction”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Housing and Urban Affairs Minister Olivier Klein also spoke out against it on Friday, telling France Inter radio that it would be “an admission of failure”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I think we still have other options,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Clamart, a suburb southwest of Paris, became the first area to declare a nightly curfew on Thursday, while public bus and tram services in the capital region were stopped at 9pm – a measure that will now be imposed nightly for an indefinite period.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China uses laser for 10 times faster satellite-to-ground communication in major breakthrough]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3226159/china-uses-laser-10-times-faster-satellite-ground-communication-major-breakthrough?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.30 20:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/30/0a8395a3-b008-4fe0-8c5b-35df0a2a8b45_8fa8405f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China has successfully deployed laser-based high-speed communication technology on commercial satellites, increasing space-to-ground data transfer speed tenfold to 10 gigabytes per second (Gbps).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Using a ground-based 500mm (19.7 inches) aperture, researchers received laser signals emitted from a transmitter on the Jilin-1 MF02A04 satellite,” the official Science and Technology Daily reported earlier this week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 108-strong Jilin-1 constellation in lower Earth orbit is the world&#39;s largest imaging satellite network, and sends back commercial remote sensing data for sectors including land resource survey, urban planning and disaster monitoring. The latest breakthrough is forecast to significantly enhance ground communication with the satellites.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Traditionally, satellite-to-ground links have primarily relied on microwave technology. However, as the range of microwave frequencies is restricted, so is the speed of data transfer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lasers, by contrast, have a much wider spectrum. Therefore, using lasers as data carriers can help pack more data into each transmission with the bandwidth potentially reaching several hundred gigahertz.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A team from the Aerospace Information Research Institute (AIR), under the country&#39;s premier research institute – the Chinese Academy of Sciences – set up a satellite-to-ground link using lasers, for what is formally known as “optical communication”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Their system, sent into orbit with the Jilin-1 MF02A04 in December, was successfully tested on Wednesday, opening the doors to more efficient data exchange.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China space laser zaps competition with data speed record: paper&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Li Yalin, the leader of the ground system at AIR, compared the technology to city roads.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Using the common microwave at 375 MHz is like driving on a single lane, and the emerging [technology of a] higher 1.5 GHz microwave would be a four-lane road,” he said. “Lasers, meanwhile, can accommodate hundreds or even thousands of lanes.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With [such] optical communication, it is possible to transmit a high-definition movie in one second, which is 10 to 1,000 times faster than the current microwave communication method.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first batch of data sent back to Earth by the Jilin-1 transmitter included a picture of Doha, the capital of Qatar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is the first ultra-high-speed [10 Gbps] satellite-to-ground optical communication test for business applications in China, and the single communication lasted for more than 100 seconds,” chief designer Chen Shanbo at Chang Guang Satellite Technology, the commercial company that launched the Jilin-1 MF02A04 satellite, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The highly concentrated energy of lasers also means the size, weight, and power consumption of satellite-borne laser transmitters are markedly less than those powered by microwave.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lasers also have strong anti-electromagnetic interference capabilities, which can significantly improve the security of ground-to-satellite communication.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Notably, Nasa has speeded up similar research, and teamed up with the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) researchers to achieve a downlink speed of 100 Gbps last June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The feat was achieved by the MIT-developed TeraByte InfraRed Delivery (TBIRD) system, which was taken into orbit by Nasa&#39;s Pathfinder Technology Demonstrator 3 (PTD-3) satellite. The system is named after the terabyte, a unit of digital data that equals 1,000 gigabytes or about 500 hours of high-definition video.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;PTD-3 is about the size of two stacked cereal boxes, and the TBIRD payload it carries is no larger than the average tissue box, according to Nasa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year, the US laser link doubled that data rate, reaching a record-breaking transmission speed of 200 Gbps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With optical communications, we&#39;re blowing that out of the water as far as the amount of data we can bring back. It is truly a game-changing capability,” TBIRD project manager Beth Keer said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Nasa record, however, was achieved on a demonstration satellite, which are usually more powerful than the commercial type.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Jilin-1 MF02A04 is a commercial satellite designed for practical use and a longer lifespan. It weighs less than 40kg (88 pounds) but the weight of its transmitter is not known.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Faster data transmission could drive development in many areas. Missions to collect important data on Earth&#39;s climate and resources, as well as astrophysical discoveries and military detection could all be boosted by this technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Laser communications is the missing link that will enable the science discoveries of the future,” Keer was reported as saying in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, when it comes to the technology&#39;s commercial application, China might have an edge. The Jilin-1 constellation is set to have 138 satellites in orbit this year and complete the second phase of construction by 2025, by which time it will have 300 satellites.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;The powerful Chinese megawatt laser &#39;small enough for a satellite&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The system&#39;s powerful remote sensing image capability will generate a large amount of data every day by then, feeding the growing demand for data transmission from satellite to ground and between satellites.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another Jilin-1 series satellite coded “02A” was successfully launched by Chang Guang Satellite Technology on June 15. It carries a new generation of optical communication payload to validate high-speed inter-satellite, and satellite-to-ground and back to satellite communication technologies, and aims to form a network with the others in orbit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the company website: “As the next step, Chang Guang Satellite Technology will carry out the normalisation and commercial trial operation of ground-to-satellite laser communication, providing a technical foundation for the subsequent large-scale application of 40 Gbps satellite-to-ground laser communication payloads.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>