<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Indonesian activist lifts lid on rape of Chinese women in May 1998 riots: ‘it was a new low’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/people/article/3221871/indonesian-activist-lifts-lid-rape-chinese-women-may-1998-riots-it-was-new-low?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 11:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/4641a887-d7a5-48d7-a63f-762ef2273938_1e78013f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;1998 年 5 月骚乱爆发时，印度尼西亚作家和主要女权主义者 Julia Suryakusuma 在雅加达首都陷入混乱，暴徒袭击和抢劫拥有印尼华人的企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在军事独裁者苏哈托统治 32 年后，印尼人猛烈起来抗议粮食短缺、大规模失业、腐败和经济危机，以及少数华人社区——长期受到歧视性政策的攻击并被指责偷工作——受到攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“鉴于经济危机，抢劫或许是可以理解的，但数百人的事实对我们来说，被强奸的中国妇女的数量创下新低，”Suryakusuma 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着印度尼西亚纪念 1998 年 5 月导致苏哈托下台的骚乱 25 周年，围绕着印尼华人妇女的性侵事件仍未被公开。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在台湾的印尼华人回忆起 1998 年骚乱后生活发生了怎样的变化&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ita Fatia Nadia，来自妇女性暴力受害者志愿者组织，表示在 5 月 12 日至 6 月 2 日期间，雅加达及其周边地区发生了 152 起针对印尼华人妇女的性暴力事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但全国的实际数字可能要高得多，因为骚乱也Suryakusuma 说，印尼其他主要城市也爆发了疫情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“并非所有受害者都选择挺身而出。羞耻、屈辱以及自我价值和尊严的完全丧失常常导致强奸受害者埋葬对恐怖和创伤的回忆。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suryakusuma 是妇女正义联盟的约 100 名女性活动家之一， 1998 年 7 月 17 日在国防部外抗议的民主人士。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们举着标语从雅加达的国家纪念碑游行到国防部大楼，向路人分发小册子并要求见部长，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抗议者要求会见当时的印度尼西亚武装部队国防部长兼指挥官 Wiranto 将军的请求被拒绝，但他们被允许提交一份请愿书，要求举行军方对其在 5 月骚乱中的作用负责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“第一手资料表明，军事特工挑衅者在现场煽动暴徒骚乱并袭击中资商店，”Suryakusuma 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“暴乱者大多对苏哈托和为他的政权服务的印尼华人大亨感到愤怒，但他们受到的保护太过严密，因此无法触及，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，暴徒被军方特工将他们的挫败感发泄在普通中产阶级印尼华人及其女性亲属等“简单目标”身上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;之后被杀。在骚乱中被强奸的八名妇女中有七名随后被谋杀，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;印度尼西亚的 Reformasi 改革 25 年后，佐科威领导下的民主正在瓦解吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但悲剧也变成了Suryakusuma 说，这是变革的催化剂。 1998 年对印尼华人妇女犯下的恐怖事件统一并激发了沿“世俗”和“穆斯林”路线两极分化的妇女权利团体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在骚乱发生后的同年，印度尼西亚还成立了全国暴力侵害妇女委员会 (KOMNAS Perempuan) 与政府合作并就打击基于性别的暴力向政府提出建议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，总统佐科·维多多正式“承认”1998 年 5 月的骚乱，以及其他 11 次事件，被认为是“严重侵犯人权”，他也对此表示“遗憾”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suryakusuma 表示，她希望维多多的声明将导致采取更具体的和解步骤。 “但如果不揭露军方在五月骚乱中参与的真实程度，就不可能发生这种情况；谁是主谋，谁是执行命令的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;维多多的姿态也未能令民间社会团体满意，国际特赦组织印度尼西亚执行主任乌斯曼·哈米德表示，它必须超越口头承诺。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“公开点名几起悲惨事件是远远不够的。总统甚至没有谈论 1998 年 5 月骚乱中系统性发生的性暴力，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; 1998 年 5 月的骚乱有力地提醒我们，印度尼西亚的妇女权利还有很长的路要走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“回到 1980 年代，我是第一个公开承认自己是女权主义者的女性。许多人对这个词过敏，”朱莉娅的圣战 (Julia&#39;s Jihad)、国家伊布主义 (State Ibuism) 和性、权力与国家 (Sex, Power and Nation) 等书籍的作者说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她承认，随着印度尼西亚人越来越多地转向宗教保守主义，当今的女权主义面临着相当大的挑战。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020 年皮尤研究中心对 34 个国家超过 38,000 名受访者进行的一项研究发现，98% 的印度尼西亚人将上帝和祈祷视为他们生活的重要部分，这使这个东南亚最大的国家跻身世界上宗教信仰最丰富的国家之列。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“女权主义在某种程度上已经成为一个肮脏的词。有时给自己贴上女权主义者的标签会导致强烈反对，尽管我现在改变我的想法已经太迟了，”Suryakusuma 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在当地媒体 Tirto 于 2021 年对 1,500 名男性和女性受访者进行的一项民意调查中，51 % 的女性受访者认为自己是女权主义者，但从未参加过行动主义。另有 35% 的人希望与这个词保持距离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管对女权主义的反应冷淡，但印度尼西亚在妇女权利方面继续取得进展，Suryakusuma 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“穆斯林女权主义者，例如来自印度尼西亚妇女乌里玛大会的那些人，现在站在我们斗争的前线，”她说，并补充说，她们在伊斯兰教和妇女权利问题之间充当桥梁的方式给她留下了深刻的印象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被问及她是否对印尼女权主义的未来充满希望时，她笑着回答：“我今年 69 岁了，我一直告诉人们我想活到 100 岁。如果我悲观，我就不会那样做关于即将发生的事情。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As ‘Blue Helmets’ turn 75, peacekeeping chief laments UN divisions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3221883/blue-helmets-turn-75-chief-laments-un-divisions?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 11:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/bbcf4efe-1109-4ef1-bdf7-f455c8e69c3c_d1186904.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;联合国维和行动负责人表示，分裂的安全理事会阻碍了周一迎来 75 岁生日的所谓蓝盔部队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jean-Pierre Lacroix 表示，一长串国家从“数百万在联合国旗帜下服役的男女”中受益这支部队于 1948 年成立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他补充说，一方面是美国、英国和法国与另一方面是俄罗斯和中国之间的瘫痪和冲突，这使得行动变得困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;负责联合国和平行动的副秘书长说：“我们的会员国存在分歧，这让我们深受其害。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位 63 岁的法国外交官补充说，联合国发现它“更难实现”维和行动的最终目标：部署、支持和平协议的实施，然后逐步离开”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管由 15 名成员组成的理事会定期更新维和行动的任务，但拉克鲁瓦呼吁更加团结，以便他们可以更好地“影响和平协议和政治进程的实施”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在刚果东部的反联合国抗议活动中丧生的 15 名印度维和人员中有印度维和人员&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;5 月 29 日是国际联合国日联合国大会于2002年设立维和人员，以纪念那些在冲突地区服务的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于下周一是美国的阵亡将士纪念日假期，联合国周四庆祝了维和人员75周年，为纪念自 1948 年以来“为和平事业牺牲的 4200 多名维和人员”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯为去年牺牲的 103 名维和人员默哀一分钟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国驻马​​里稳定特派团（马努斯马）部署了 12,000 名维和人员，是近年来伤亡人数最多的特派团。自 2013 年成立以来，已有 185 名成员死于敌对行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，来自 125 个国家的 87,000 多人被部署在世界各地的 12 项和平行动中。它们包括黎巴嫩、马里、刚果民主共和国、塞浦路斯、印度和巴基斯坦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lacroix 指出，“恢复稳定的国家名单很长”，例如科特迪瓦、利比里亚、塞拉利昂、安哥拉和柬埔寨在 1990 年代和 2000 年代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他认为，“当时国际社会更加团结，这些国家的政治进程是在我们积极和团结一致的支持下实施的成员国”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至于失败，他指出联合国维和人员未能阻止 1994 年的卢旺达种族灭绝，该事件导致至少 800,000 名图西人和胡图人丧生，以及 1995 年至少 8,000 名穆斯林的大屠杀波斯尼亚战争期间斯雷布雷尼察的男人和男孩，这是欧洲自第二次世界大战期间大屠杀以来唯一承认的种族灭绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国的声誉也因许多指控而受到玷污，这些指控称负责保护平民的维和人员性虐待妇女和&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰：荷兰总理说要从波斯尼亚的斯雷布雷尼察吸取教训&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;另一个引人注目的失误是海地的霍乱疫情始于2010 年，在联合国维和人员通过他们基地的污水径流将细菌引入该国最大的河流之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，国际危机组织联合国主任理查德高恩说：“联合国维和行动具有令人惊讶的体面从 1950 年代的苏伊士运河危机到 2000 年代的利比里亚，在平息危机、保护平民和重建破碎国家方面做得很好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lacroix 指出维和人员的其他挑战面临着：更加暴力和危险的行动环境、更加复杂的攻击以及虚假新闻和虚假信息，这些都是“对民众和维和人员的巨大威胁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以及新旧冲突驱动因素——包括跨国犯罪活动、贩运、毒品、武器、自然资源的非法开采，以及气候变化的影响加剧了牧民和农民之间的竞争——也产生了“绝对巨大的影响”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;危机组织的 Gowan 说很明显，联合国在马里和刚果等一些国家“受困”，那里没有足够的维和人员来制止暴力循环。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尼泊尔维和人员被指控在南部“令人发指”的强奸儿童行为苏丹&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;他说，包括马里在内的一些非洲国家政府正在求助于俄罗斯瓦格纳集团等私营安保提供商来打击叛乱分子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为我们应该警惕放弃联合国行动彻底，”高恩告诉美联社。 “我们从阿富汗这样的案例中学到了惨痛的教训，即使是全副武装的西方军队也无法实现和平。联合国的记录可能并不完美，但在动荡的国家中建立稳定方面，没有其他人能做得更好。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Elderly Malaysian man collapses and dies while trying to save pet from municipal dogcatchers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3221884/elderly-malaysian-man-collapses-and-dies-while-trying-save-pet-municipal-dogcatchers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 11:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/ba09dd37-5443-4e3e-a4b9-9aee5078215b_88c25705.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名 85 岁的马来西亚男子在据称参与的事件后死亡与前来带走他的宠物狗的文冬市议会的捕狗者发生拉锯战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Law Sei Kiew 独自带着他 7 岁的混种狗住在他位于 Taman Saga 的双层房子里在彭亨州的文冬镇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据 55 岁的邻居 Chan Poh Loong 说，事件发生在周三下午 5 点（当地时间），当时一群政府捕狗员来到住宅区。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“狗在大院里，但大门没有锁。”陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“捕狗人走到大门附近，狗就出来了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说 Law 非常喜欢这只狗，他从小就把它养大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它从来不被允许四处游荡。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;马来西亚活动家对dogcatchers 的“令人厌恶”的方法&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;显然，dogcatchers 在狗身上套了一个绞索，当 Law 听到骚动时，他冲出他的房子并恳求释放它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“捕狗人用绳圈和杆子拉住狗，想把它拖走，但罗抓住杆子不肯松手，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后发生了争斗，而捕狗者也拒绝让步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，罗随后倒下并掉进了附近的排水沟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;救护车被叫来，但救护人员宣布罗已经死亡&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 说，至于那只狗，它还在 Law 的家里，尽管它的未来不确定，因为 Law 的孩子在葬礼后已经回到了他们在其他州的各自家中。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;Law 的儿子拒绝接受媒体采访，称一家人希望一个人呆着。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;放火烧狗的马来西亚青少年的妈妈请求结束家庭的猎犬行为&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;文冬国会议员Young Syefura Othman探望死者家属并表示哀悼，并敦促地方政府发展部和全国所有地方当局立即明确说明处理流浪狗行动的过程。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“这是为了防止发生分歧等意外事件，这些分歧可能会变得更糟，并导致地方当局的执法人员与居民或喂养流浪狗的个人发生争执，”她在一份声明中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文冬市议会公共卫生部负责人 Norizam Saad 在联系时表示，市议会已就此事向警方报案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他拒绝详细说明，称他目前正在外出参加课程，尚未收到完整信息&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘They peed in my car’: 32-hour ride-sharing car ‘occupation’ by Chinese father and daughter ends with police detention]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3221395/they-peed-my-car-32-hour-ride-sharing-car-occupation-chinese-father-and-daughter-ends-police?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/23/50261cfc-3fcc-4173-bd99-5a214e591e89_b7edcc5f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一对父女上演了一段离奇的 32 小时“占领”旅程-共享汽车期间，其中一人或两人在车内小便已被中国东部当局拘留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这起令许多网友震惊的奇怪事件发生在两人与&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 20 日，浙江省杭州市警方通报，两人已被行政拘留 7 天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据据报道，5月17日下午2点至次日晚上10点，这名54岁的父亲和他25岁的女儿都姓于，拒绝下车，原因是司机王姓女子在接到命令后中断了他们的订单。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王某告诉当地消费者监督机构“1818黄金眼”，乘客在网约车应用程序上选择的上车点不允许停车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于事实上，当时下着大雨，王女士说她给他们扔了一把伞，并让他们步行到几米外的新接送点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，王女士说这个要求激怒了这对夫妇，他们开始尖叫在上车之前对她说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王某怒不可遏，决定中止服务，将他们送回原出发地，并告诉他们：“我宁愿死也不送你们。” ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警察报警但未能劝说两人下车，于是王某当晚开车送他们到她的住宅区，然后没锁车门回家，希望他们能在第二天早上离开.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，第二天，王某震惊地发现，两人不仅还在车里，还在车内撒尿，还用香水掩盖了异味。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王某开车送他们到附近的警察局，巧合的是，警察局在一条叫“刘霞”的街道上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女儿告诉消费者监督计划，他们决心在王完成他们的订单之前，或者向他们支付相当于 9 元车费（1.3 美元）的 10 倍的赔偿金之前，不得离开并占用汽车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在为我们的合法权利而战，”她说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名自称是来自上海的媒体工作者的女子称，当她向记者展示视频和一张泼水的照片时，王向他们泼了水，她说这“会成为病毒”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;王说她只是在“洗车”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方最初表示他们不能强迫两人下车，因为没有“肢体冲突”，最终32 小时后向他们发出传唤令，让他们别无选择，只能离开车辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内地社交媒体对警方的决定表示赞赏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们是糟糕的乘客。他们应该被拼车平台列入黑名单，”一位观察人士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一位开玩笑说：“如果他们在 7 天后也拒绝离开派出所怎么办？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“看来拼车平台也有责任，为什么要让他们选择不允许停车的上车点？” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拼车平台T3出行表示将向王某提供法律援助，帮助她追回损失的收入。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What are China’s ‘secret police stations’ and is their role exaggerated by foreign governments?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3221396/what-are-chinas-secret-police-stations-and-their-role-exaggerated-foreign-governments?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/22/24d0f51f-e088-476f-81e3-0a615a74ee6b_1b88149f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;西方国家再次呼吁关闭中国的“秘密警察局”欧洲和北美政府将焦点重新放在中国在海外的行动上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月 15 日，德国外交部表示，尽管北京早先做出承诺，但它认为中国仍在继续运营“非法海外警察局”它将关闭所谓的“服务站”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一天前，加拿大公共安全部长马可·门迪奇诺 (Marco Mendicino) 表示，在对两个调查展开数月后，全国可能会有更多“秘密警察局”在运作&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新的电话是在美国当局逮捕两名纽约华裔居民一个月后发出的，他们涉嫌在曼哈顿唐人街的一家商业办公室经营此类加油站。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;北京断然否认这些台站被用于域外执法或海外间谍活动，一些分析人士表示，这些台站的作用可能被夸大了。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;从 9 月开始，人权组织 Safeguard Defenders 发布报告称，中国公安部在多达 53 个国家/地区设立了 100 多个海外派出所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些据称早在 2016 年就开始运作的前哨站是在福州、南通、温州和青田等中国东南部城市的地方警察局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查发现，在华侨社区经常光顾的地区的企业和商业建筑外设有派出所。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Safeguard Defenders 表示，这些站点是该部门“劝返”行动的工具，目标是将生活在海外的逃犯（例如骗子或腐败商人）送回中国接受起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，这些警察局也与据称监视和威胁包括非中国公民在内的持不同政见者和民主活动人士有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;出于对间谍活动的担忧，日本敦促铲除中国的秘密“警察局”&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;虽然不是警察本身，但前哨站的人员被指控使用各种恐吓方法，例如在线骚扰和胁迫家人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些西方政府称被指控的行动“不可接受”和“令人愤慨”，指责北京在海外非法执法，违反国际准则，公然干涉他们的内政。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;北京一再否认这些台站是海外警察局。相反，它说它们被用来提供驾驶执照更新等官僚服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相关机构帮助了因大流行而无法返回中国的海外华人，”外交部发言人王文斌在5 月 15 日，补充说，所提供的服务已经转移到网上，而且车站已经关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京坚称，车站的工作人员不是警察或政府雇员，而是当地志愿者，他们希望帮助他们社区。美国和其他地方当局的调查证实了北京的一些说法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然中国外交部表示中国正在打击跨国犯罪，但它表示所有行动都符合国际法，西方的指控反倒是道听途说的“抹黑”和“造谣”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，电信和网络诈骗在中国十分猖獗。 9 月，中国通过了一项法律，赋予当局在国外追捕嫌疑人的权力，尽管法律规定必须与国际执法机构合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2014 年以来，中国还开展了“狐狸行动” Hunt”，即国家批准追捕金融犯罪嫌疑人或面临腐败指控的已逃离该国的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国始终坚持不干涉他国内政的原则，严格遵守王说，国际法和尊重所有国家的司法主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;对这些“警察局”采取的最引人注目的行动是逮捕纽约居民卢61 岁的建旺和 59 岁的陈金平于 4 月 17 日被美国当局起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们被指控“密谋充当中国政府的代理人”以及涉嫌“破坏证据”与公安部官员的通信有关。据称他们经营的车站在美国联邦特工搜查后于 2022 年秋季关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从英国到奥地利，越来越多的其他国家已经对“警察局”展开了自己的调查或调查”以及他们涉嫌的犯罪活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在加拿大，警方表示他们正在调查两个据称在蒙特利尔经营“秘密警察局”的华人社区团体，尽管后来当地媒体报道称这些团体继续运作。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;爱尔兰和荷兰外交部均表示，他们已直接与中国各自的大使讨论了此事。日本等国家的国内压力也越来越大，反对党呼吁日本政府公开更多有关这些站点的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;包括意大利和塞尔维亚在内的一些国家此前与中国建立了联合巡逻伙伴关系警察和地方部队。这些项目被宣传为帮助越来越多的中国游客前往海外旅游目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，意大利在 12 月宣布将停止该项目——该项目在 Covid-19 大流行期间暂停——根据 Safeguard Defenders 的报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;耶鲁大学法学院 Paul Tsai 中国中心的高级研究员 Jeremy Daum 称这些车站周围的叙事建筑“分散了注意力”北京采取的其他跨国行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为中国当局和极端民族主义公民的域外骚扰是一个真正的问题，[但]这些警察局在这方面的作用可能很小，”道姆说。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;在 Safeguard Defenders 报告首次发布后，Daum 强调说，这些站点在它们所在的社区中公开运作，基本上充当调解和其他服务的视频会议室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还指出，在纽约被捕后，美国司法部表示 Lu 和 Chen 的涉嫌行为与电视台本身之间几乎没有联系。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“猎狐”：美国指控 7 人涉嫌阴谋遣返美国居住在中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Daum 说，他担心对“海外警察局”的关注是“一种日益增长的趋势，即考虑每个与中国有联系的人，无论是民族传统、商业等……作为一个[中国共产党] 的潜在代理人”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治学副教授 Chong Ja Ian 说，无论它们是否被用于跨国执法，这场争议都进一步损害了北京在西方的形象新加坡国立大学的科学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管官方声明并非如此，但这种所谓的行动令人怀疑 [中国] 对法治和尊重主权的承诺的现实性，”Chong 说。 “即使前哨站是为了标准的行政程序，他们仍然需要某种登记。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chong 和 Daum 都表示，美国等地正在进行的司法程序应该“更加明确” &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周二，Safeguard Defenders 表示，自最初发布以来，它一直是涉及数万个虚假社交媒体账户的“长期”虚假信息宣传活动的目标9 月的报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 YouTube 和其他网站上，以与该组织原始报告相似的名称出现了数千个几乎相同的视频和博客文章，但其中包含 669 字的中国立场辩护。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Twitter 上，在大量可疑的机器人帐户触发社交媒体网站的反垃圾邮件过滤器后，暂时禁止引用这些报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Twitter 允许对其验证方案进行彻底改革该组织表示，数千个账户伪装成 Safeguard Defenders。据报道，虽然该社交媒体网站删除了多达 1000 个“冒名顶替”账户，但《南华早报》的搜索显示，该网站上仍有数百个使用与 Safeguard Defenders 相同的姓名、头像和简历的账户。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;该组织在一份新闻稿中表示，该活动“似乎旨在淹没 Safeguard Defenders 的消息传递和在线可见度”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它补充说，其之前关于中​​国的报道引发了类似的浪潮网络骚扰，但该组织并未将其称为国家协调行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个人在指挥它，”Safeguard Defenders 说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China and US trade officials exchange barbs during ‘candid talks’ but vow to step up communication amid rising tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3221879/china-us-trade-war-commerce-chiefs-both-sides-air-grievances-meeting-pledge-step-communication?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 11:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/26/568acf05-8e3b-4217-9b62-08f7f7d1a741_82f86acc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国和美国就贸易分歧交换了倒钩，但仍同意双方高级贸易官员在华盛顿会晤后加强沟通，以应对不断升级的冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国商务部长王文涛与美国商务部长吉娜·雷蒙多就双边贸易关系进行了“坦诚、专业和建设性”的交流中国商务部周五在一份声明中表示，“中国强调了对美国对华贸易政策、半导体政策、出口管制和海外投资审查的担忧。”中方表示，双方同意建立沟通渠道，就具体贸易问题和合作保持和加强交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国商务部发表的一份声明称，讨论是“坦诚和实质性”，他们谈到了“两国贸易和投资的整体环境以及潜在合作领域”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“雷蒙多部长还对中国最近对在美国经营的美国公司采取的一系列行动表示担忧中国，”美国的声明说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次会议是为保持开放的沟通渠道和负责任地管理两国关系而进行的持续努力的一部分。雷蒙多国务卿表示，她致力于在 2022 年 11 月在印度尼西亚巴厘岛继续加强拜登总统和习主席之间的接触。”后者于 2021 年上任——此前北京禁止美国美光公司在关键基础设施项目中使用半导体，美国在中国的咨询公司遭到国家安全突袭。美国商务部表示，对美光的禁令没有事实根据。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在亚太经合组织上，美国高级官员敦促贸易政策采取“以工人为中心”的方法&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Wang 的美国之行继上周七国集团领导人在广岛举行会议之后，来自富裕的七国集团国家的领导人在会上批评中国的“经济胁迫”，并表示他们将“去风险”而不是在所有方面与世界第二大经济体“脱钩”从芯片到矿产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京回应公报称，G7 国家不应滥用贸易和投资限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们希望 G7 成员将他们的声明付诸实践that they are not seeking to &#39;decouple&#39; from China, instead of saying that they are not seeking to &#39;decouple&#39; while abusing trade and investment restrictions to suppress and curb China&#39;s development,” said Shu Jueting, a spokeswoman with the Ministry of Commerce, at a media briefing on Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing also expressed opposition to Washington&#39;s move towards a new trade pact with Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The China-US meeting and subsequent pledge for greater communication were positive moves , according to He Weiwen, a senior fellow with the Beijing-based think tank Centre for China and Globalisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The most pressing issue for China and the United States is to establish a dialogue mechanism to clearly state their differences, and then discuss how to solve or ease them,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that such a dialogue mechanism should be restored to discuss not only commerce issues, but also culture, agriculture, energy management and technology for a vital signal by both Beijing and Washington to show their willingness to cooperate and manage differences.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US lawmaker demands action against Chinese chip firm CXMT after Micron&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“This is in the interests of the companies of both countries.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang, who is attending the Apec trade ministers meeting in Detroit this week, would meet the US Trade Representative, Katherine Tai, Shu said. Wang last met Tai in Thailand in November at an Apec meeting&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meetings will be a further attempt by the world&#39;s top two economies to re-engage after stalemates as bilateral ties soured in recent years.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US says North Korea to send more programmers  abroad to fund nuclear arms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3221873/us-says-north-korea-send-more-programmers-abroad-fund-nuclear-arms?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 10:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/26/8ec14650-3d6d-43ec-bba2-01b12614daec_6c2d6982.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;North Korea is ramping up efforts to deploy information technology workers overseas as it increasingly relies on cyberattacks and other online crimes to funds its weapons programmes, US and South Korean officials said, anticipating the easing of the isolated country&#39;s strict Covid-19 lockdown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is a growth industry, because as we see the DPRK potentially opening up borders, they could be dispatching additional labourers to all parts of the world to generate revenue,” said Jung Pak, the US deputy special representative for the Democratic People&#39;s Republic of Korea, the country&#39;s formal name. “We think it&#39;s actively getting worse.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This week, the US Treasury Department sanctioned four entities linked to North Korea&#39;s military and intelligence services, as well as one North Korean based in the Russian city of Vladivostok who received cryptocurrency payments from North Korean tech workers.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;North Korea steps up &#39;opportunistic&#39; cybercrime to fund nuclear ambitions&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Pyongyang, forced to shift tactics in response to sanctions programmes targeting its nuclear weapons efforts, is increasingly relying on thousands of North Korean programmers who were sent abroad, mainly to China and Russia, before the regime shut its borders during Covid-19, according to the US and South Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They say these in-demand workers can make as much as US$300,000 a year, working abroad – often remotely through freelance platforms with falsified or stolen identification – and can assist in enabling cyberattacks and cryptocurrency thefts that helped North Korea earn an estimated US$1.7 billion in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US efforts to sanction North Korea – including at the United Nations – have done little to halt leader Kim Jong-un&#39;s weapons programme, with the country launching more than 70 ballistic missiles last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the main reasons North Korea can continue these efforts is because China and Russia continue to protect North Korea in the United Nations Security Council, as well as host the bulk of the country&#39;s overseas information technology workers as they seek more revenues, Pak said, adding that Beijing should use its leverage to pressure Pyongyang.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The elephants in the room, obviously, are Russia and China,” Pak said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s extremely difficult to shape the DPRK&#39;s behaviour if Russia and China continue to shield it from overwhelming international condemnation of their ballistic missile and nuclear weapons activities.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Yoon steers South Korea away from China, Russia and towards US, Japan&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Although North Korea has also sent out manual labourers to work in sectors such as construction, Kim&#39;s government views cryptocurrency thefts and IT revenue as a “new frontier,” according to Lee Jun-il, the director general for North Korean nuclear issues at South Korea&#39;s foreign ministry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since they closed down their border, and their other revenue streams suffered, they have increasingly concentrated on making money out of cyberspace, and as the cryptocurrency market grows, they find more vulnerabilities in the sector,” Lee said in a phone interview from San Francisco, where he was meeting with Pak and other officials.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 10:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[TSMC in talks for German subsidies that could cover half of a US$10.7 billion fab in the country]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3221872/tsmc-talks-german-subsidies-could-cover-half-us107-billion-fab-country?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 10:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/26/2d9c0c91-14e6-4366-b329-6961f48e6f9e_481298b2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co, the world&#39;s biggest contract chip maker, is in talks to receive German government subsidies for as much as 50 per cent of the costs to build its new semiconductor plant in the country, people familiar with the matter said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government is in ongoing negotiations with TSMC as well as its partners on the project – Bosch Ltd, NXP Semiconductors NV and Infineon Technologies AG – the people said, asking not to be identified because the deliberations are private. No final decisions have been made and the final subsidy amount could still change. Any state aid must also be signed off by the European Commission.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The deliberations over the Dresden plant, which could cost as much as €10 billion (US$10.7 billion) to build, show how competition for semiconductor manufacturing capacity has intensified. The top end of the subsidies being discussed would put German government support for the fab on par with what Japan&#39;s offering TSMC to build a factory there. It would also outpace the 40 per cent maximum that most other chip makers are getting for their plants in Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The German Economy Ministry said in a statement that it&#39;s in a “close exchange” with TSMC “with the aim of jointly discussing prerequisites for an investment decision”. The ministry didn&#39;t comment on the subsidies beyond saying that the government could fund the project under the European Chips Act.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A spokeswoman for TSMC said that the company is evaluating the possibility of building a fab in Europe and declined to comment further. The chipmaker&#39;s chief executive officer CC Wei had said in April that the decision would be based on demand from customers and the level of government support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plant would be a big win for the EU&#39;s €43 billion Chips Act, which is aimed at increasing domestic output to avoid future supply chain disruptions. STMicroelectronics NV, GlobalFoundries Inc, Infineon Technologies AG and Wolfspeed Inc are among the chip makers that have announced new investments in Europe since it was first proposed last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The goal is to be close to our customers,” TSMC&#39;s senior vice-president Kevin Zhang said at an industry event in Amsterdam this week. TSMC&#39;s board will make a final decision about going ahead with the project as soon as August, he said. “If we do build a fab in Dresden, likely we would start at the 28-nanometre generation.” Such chips could be used for microcontrollers in cars and could be made smaller in future.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 10:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fake images of Elon Musk kissing ‘robot wives’ are sweeping social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3221875/fake-images-elon-musk-kissing-robot-wives-are-sweeping-social-media?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 10:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/26/dca4eac1-4dd0-4650-8118-6216e135173c_a1006c77.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;AI-generated images of Elon Musk in passionate embraces with so-called “robot wives” have spread on social media, with some users claiming such technology is close to being rolled out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The billionaire can be seen kissing and embracing female robots in various images posted by Daniel Marven, a Twitter user with almost one million followers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the post, Marven wrote that Musk has announced his “future wife” who has been “designed with artificial intelligence”. He then went on to clarify that the purpose of sharing these pictures is to flag the risks associated with AI.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another post by user Baboon Forest Entertainment said that Musk&#39;s company is in the final stages of making “Robot Wives”, a product that will be released in September 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It continued: “The man made Robot Wife will use batteries that last in accordance with menstrual circle. Batteries will only be charged for full three days and operate for a month. Sex with a Robot Wife will require a Password, Pattern or Fingerprint to avoid tempering!!!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Various posts about the robot wives have attracted thousands of likes with some calling them “sex robots”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The images, however, are AI-generated, and there is no suggestion that Musk, or anyone, is actually working on creating so-called “robot wives”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fake images created by AI of celebrities and public figures have gone viral numerous times on social media in recent months, with one picture of Pope Francis in a stylish white Balenciaga puffer coat receiving hundreds of thousands of likes on Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some are using a platform called Midjourney, which uses AI to generate images through textual descriptions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Henry Ajder, an AI expert and presenter who is on the European advisory council for Meta&#39;s Reality Labs, described the key ways to identify AI images to Business Insider. Ajder said that on Midjourney, especially, “a lot of the images have a very stylised, almost smooth kind of shiny, plasticky appearance”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Full Fact, which fact-checked the false claims about Musk and robots, noted that many of the fake images of Musk with robot wives have many of the hallmarks of AI-generated pictures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you look closely at some of the pictures used in the posts, some irregularities in hands and facial features quickly become apparent,” it wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 10:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: China’s top server makers stop orders of memory modules containing Micron chips, sources say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3221833/tech-war-chinas-top-server-makers-stop-orders-memory-modules-containing-micron-chips-sources-say?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/25/dcd1a8fa-b16d-4b3b-a01f-f2601c90a6c4_65a47183.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s top server makers, including Inspur Group and Lenovo Group, have asked suppliers to suspend shipments of modules containing chips made by US-based Micron Technology, after Beijing imposed a partial ban on the firm&#39;s products, according to a supplier with knowledge of the situation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DRAM chips used in memory modules for servers are a commoditised component that is commonly supplied by Micron and Samsung Electronics, said the source, who declined to be named to protect relationships with clients.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It would take some time for the suppliers to make technical adjustments for newly-sourced alternatives, the person added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lenovo and Inspur did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The halted orders highlight the immediate impact that China&#39;s ban, announced on Sunday, has already had on the United States&#39; largest memory chip maker.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese market has been one of Micron&#39;s major revenue generators, contributing about 11 per cent of the company&#39;s total revenue of US$30.8 billion in 2022. The firm expects low to high single-digit losses to its total sales as a result of the ban, which prohibits critical information infrastructure operators in China from buying its products.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inspur, which is under US trade sanctions, and Lenovo are among the biggest buyers of Micron products, according to Bloomberg data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ban also affects memory module makers and third-party suppliers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese memory module manufacturers would have to change their product portfolios as a result of the Micron ban, Huang Leping, an analyst at Huatai Securities, was quoted as saying in a report on Monday by Chinese magazine Caijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shenzhen Longsys Electronics, one of China&#39;s top memory module producers, counted Micron as its top supplier between 2018 and mid-2021, with purchases from the Boise, Idaho-based company exceeding 33 per cent of total procurement contracts annually during the period.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Cyberspace Administration of China (CAC) in March launched a national security probe into Micron products to “safeguard key information infrastructure supply chain security” and “prevent cyberspace security risks due to problematic products”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It marked the first time a foreign semiconductor company was put under a cybersecurity review, and was seen as retaliation for Washington&#39;s tightened export controls on advanced US semiconductor technology to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CAC did not disclose which products it tested or the methods it used to test them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US commerce department on Monday said the Micron ban and recent raids of international consulting firms by Chinese authorities contradicted the country&#39;s commitment to an open market and transparent regulatory framework.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese foreign ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning said at a regular press conference on Wednesday that the country&#39;s investigation into Micron was conducted in accordance with the law and the latest decision was based on facts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The review “does not target any particular countries or regions, nor does China seek to exclude technologies or products from any specific country,” she added.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong to honour young leaders’ contributions to city during pandemic at annual Student of the Year Awards]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/education/article/3221853/hong-kong-honour-young-leaders-contributions-city-during-pandemic-annual-student-year-awards?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.26 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/25/323de6ab-d85a-4792-8559-70af6b29a66e_7448ec83.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;As Hong Kong gets back on its feet after the Covid-19 pandemic, the 2023 Student of the Year (SOTY) Awards are an opportunity to recognise young leaders for helping the community through the tough times, the organisers have said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Entering their 42nd year, the prestigious awards continue their legacy to scout for the next generation of young leaders in the hope of helping them to further their cause and goals in life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The annual awards have chosen the theme “Take action to drive positive change” to recognise and support young leaders who make a difference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“SOTY is not just an award which accords laurels conferring status and prestige but a wholesome programme initiative that equips young leaders with skill sets that allow them to further succeed,” said Catherine So, CEO of the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Organised by Young Post and the Post and sponsored by the Hong Kong Jockey Club, the awards hope to give students a chance to tell their stories while reflecting on this year&#39;s theme. Nominations for the awards opened in April and have been extended to May 28.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On top of alumni sharing sessions and award ceremonies, where students connect and interact with fellow student leaders, this year, SOTY has taken engagement a step further and introduced a series of fireside chats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These fireside chats and tailor-made workshops with leading professionals from various sectors aim to broaden participants&#39; horizons while allowing them to gain insights and advice that will be invaluable later in life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There will also be a hackathon which aims to cultivate creativity and innovative thinking.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Everything in Chinese&#39;: Hong Kong&#39;s ethnic minority students hit a wall&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Nominations across the nine categories should show how well the students demonstrate their abilities and also explain how their extracurricular activities have helped drive positive change.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SOTY will continue its tradition of giving a school the Special Award for Most Nurturing Environment. This will go to the institution that shows a strong connection to its students and encourages them to realise their potential.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both school and self-nominations are welcomed, while a reference letter or endorsement is required if students apply through non-school and self-nomination channels.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Poor Hong Kong students given lift with free flight, mentorship programme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Forms Four to Six (Grade/Years 10 to 13) students in government-registered secondary schools during the 2022-23 academic year are qualified for nomination. The Grand Prize category is open for Forms Five to Six (Grade/Year 11 to 13).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The names of shortlisted students and finalists will be announced in June. They will be invited to individual interviews. The winners will be announced at the awards lunch in July.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 26 May 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>