<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden unveils 2024 election battle plan: ‘Bidenomics’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3225670/joe-biden-unveils-2024-election-battle-plan-bidenomics?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 11:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/f455d927-cd3d-4481-a0ba-b017f9b950c4_837ca9d6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登对美国经济下了很大的赌注，这将推动他重新崛起- 明年大选，本周将向选民推出“拜登经济学”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在继承了遭受新冠大流行蹂躏的经济，然后又受到挥之不去的通货膨胀和供应链困境的困扰后，拜登经历了一段艰难的时期是时候让美国人相信他做得很好了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国广播公司新闻/华盛顿邮报 5 月份的一项民意调查甚至发现，拜登丑闻缠身的共和党前任 — — 以及可能在 2024 年复赛的对手 — — 唐纳德·特朗普在支持率上领先 18 个百分点谁能更好地管理经济的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着本周以拜登周三在芝加哥的演讲为基础的品牌重塑启动，白宫认为它可以扭转局面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首席副新闻秘书奥利维亚·道尔顿 (Olivia Dalton) 告诉记者，“拜登经济学”就是这个词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它是“每日一词、每周一词、每月一词、年度一词”。白宫，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国将斥资 420 亿美元，到 2030 年普及互联网&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这句口号是对著名的“里根经济学”的故意运用和斥责。 ” 罗纳德·里根 (Ronald Reagan) 1980 年代的总统任期，当时“涓滴经济学”的理念被一些人认为点燃了美国的繁荣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫称拜登已经来埋葬“里根经济学”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫称拜登已经来埋葬“里根经济学”。国家经济委员会主任莱尔·布雷纳德 (Lael Brainard) 告诉记者：“他拒绝接受滴流经济学，即顶层减税会向下层层扩散的理论，我们所需要的只是政府让路。” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，道尔顿说，拜登将专注于“当我们发展中产阶级时我们就会发展经济”的信念。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登的主要主张是制定庞大的政府支出计划在他的第一个任期内将刺激长期扩张，从而重建美国的制造业实力并提升该国较不富裕的人口的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这不仅仅是一个经济论据，而且如果有效的话，这将是一个潜在的政治路线图在这场选举中，民主党和共和党将争夺少数摇摆州选民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登最引人注目的是他在过去两年中取得的一系列令人印象深刻的立法胜利。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;国会通过的主要法案向绿色能源技术、半导体投入了历史性的巨额资金，并投入不少于 5500 亿美元用于改造国家的道路、桥梁和其他基础设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布雷纳德说，里根时代涓滴理论导致美国工业城市因离岸外包和放弃雄心勃勃的基础设施升级而空心化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，她说，拜登的重税收工业政策正在利用政府资金作为“制造业建设领域私营部门支出繁荣”的催化剂。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乔·拜登发誓要对抗共和党的“极端”反堕胎议程&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她吹捧为宽带互联网扩张提供资金到美国的每一个角落，呼应富兰克林·罗斯福在 1930 年代实现国家现代化的史诗般的电气化计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到目前为止的问题是，选民并没有购买拜登必须出售的东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;民意调查显示，他因低失业率和总体乐观的经济而没有得到多少信任。尽管通货膨胀率连续 11 个月从大流行后的高点缓慢下降，但仍然是选民的一个主要担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;道尔顿表示，随着拜登计划资助的项目最终启动，美国人将对事情有不同的看法.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们看到铲子开工，我们看到私人投资回到我们的国家，我们看到创造了数百万个就业机会。因此，现在是时候了，在取得了所有这些成就之后，总统可以向美国人民传达这一信息，并说这就是拜登经济学，”道尔顿说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们才刚刚开始感受影响。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Not that great’: Brazil President Lula complains about palace food he got in Italy, France]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3225661/not-great-brazil-president-lula-complains-about-palace-food-he-got-italy-france?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 10:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/da714893-f65a-4b6c-8c04-9e8a04a04811_895a776f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦抱怨同行为他提供的食物上周在意大利和法国，批评了这些部分的质量和大小。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我与[伊曼纽尔]马克龙和[塞尔吉奥]马塔雷拉共进午餐，”卢拉周二说道，指的是最近与他的会面。法国和意大利的同行在巴黎和罗马。 “两种宫廷菜都不太好吃。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前工会领袖补充道，出差时，他总怀念有一个大托盘，想吃多少就吃多少。 “无论如何，我们都活了下来，”他在巴西利亚官邸的网络直播中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法国和意大利政府没有回应置评请求，也没有提供详细信息在为卢拉提供的菜单上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的评论——无论是严肃的还是轻松地开玩笑——永远不会在世界上两个对自己的美食感到无比自豪的烹饪之都得到很好的回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;这些言论还加剧了这位左翼领导人自重返全球舞台以来所使用的有争议的言论，包括他声称乔·拜登和弗拉基米尔·泽伦斯基对俄罗斯入侵乌克兰负有部分责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;br >;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/ a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese, Indonesians, Malaysians among 2,700 victims rescued in Philippines cyber scam raid]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225649/chinese-indonesians-malaysians-among-2700-victims-rescued-philippines-cyber-scam-raid?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 11:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/431f4aca-9ed3-42bc-bf11-c7f0338e2fa9_1a170f89.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;菲律宾警方在突击队的支持下表示，他们已从中国营救了 2,700 多名工人。菲律宾、越南、印度尼西亚以及其他十几个国家被骗为欺诈性在线游戏网站和其他网络犯罪团体工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从拉斯皮纳斯市的七座建筑物中获救的人口贩运受害者人数周二，马尼拉大都会发生了大规模夜间袭击，规模是今年迄今为止最大规模，这表明菲律宾已成为网络犯罪集团的主要活动基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;网络犯罪诈骗已成为主要的犯罪活动据报道，该地区及其他地区的人们被引诱到饱受冲突蹂躏的缅甸和柬埔寨等国家工作。然而，这些工人中的许多人发现自己陷入了虚拟的奴役之中，被迫参与通过互联网针对他人的诈骗活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月，东南亚国家联盟领导人在印度尼西亚举行的一次峰会上同意加强收紧政策边境管制和执法，并扩大公众教育，打击将工人贩运到其他国家、迫使他们参与网络欺诈的犯罪集团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;负责菲律宾国家警察反腐败行动的西德尼·埃尔尼亚 (Sydney Hernia) 准将网络犯罪部门表示，持逮捕令的警察在午夜左右突袭并搜查了拉斯皮纳斯市的建筑物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们救出了来自至少 17 个国家的 1,534 名菲律宾人和 1,190 名外国人，其中包括 604 名中国人、183 名越南人、137 名印度尼西亚人、 134 名马来西亚人和 81 名泰国人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有一些来自缅甸、巴基斯坦、也门、索马里、苏丹、尼日利亚和台湾的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前尚不清楚有多少可疑领导人该犯罪团伙的成员被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国敦促对被诱骗成为诈骗者的亚洲国民采取更温和的态度&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;警方突袭了位于邦板牙省北部马巴拉卡特市克拉克自由港的另一个涉嫌网络犯罪基地警方称，5 月，他们在马尼拉拘留了近 1,400 名菲律宾和外国工人，据称这些工人被迫进行加密货币诈骗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些工人告诉调查人员，当他们试图辞职时，他们被迫警方表示，出于不明原因支付巨额费用，或者担心自己会被卖给其他犯罪集团，并补充说，工人们还被迫为工作中的违规行为支付罚款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工人们被高薪诱惑。官员们表示，Facebook 广告中的广告中提到了理想的工作条件，但后来发现这些承诺只是一个诡计。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;负责政治、法律和安全问题的印度尼西亚部长穆罕默德·马福德 (Muhammad Mahfud) 5 月告诉记者，印度尼西亚和其他国家该地区国家发现很难与缅甸合作打击网络犯罪及其受害者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示，东盟需要在长期提议的区域引渡条约方面取得进展，该条约将有助于当局更快地起诉罪犯并防止网络犯罪进一步升级。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UK braces for new waves of Channel asylum seekers with barge and barracks plan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3225652/uk-braces-new-waves-channel-asylum-seekers-barge-and-barracks-plan?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 10:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/c4cdb8f1-1e4d-4aa9-86b7-4f97aa3a08fe_898fe52b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;英国预计将有数千名寻求庇护者乘小船抵达，并已宣布了多项计划，将无证移民转移到未使用的军事基地和大型住宿驳船。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国内政部数据显示，2023 年迄今已有超过 11,000 人穿越英吉利海峡，其中本月约有 3,300 人在温暖的天气下穿越英吉利海峡天气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6 月 11 日星期日是今年单日穿越人数最多的一天，有 549 人乘坐小艇和旧渔船冒险穿越英吉利海峡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寻求庇护者英国保守党政府承诺“截停船只”并将一些非法入境者送往卢旺达，但他们似乎并没有被吓倒。去年，据记录从法国穿越英吉利海峡的人数达到了前所未有的 45,755 人。这比 2021 年的 28,000 人和 2020 年的 8,500 人有所增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寻求来英国的人中约有一半来自冲突地区，其中阿富汗位居榜首。据内政部称，虽然去年阿尔巴尼亚人的激增有所下降，但印度人是最近抵达的人之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟是穿越地中海这一最危险的移民海域的寻求庇护者的另一个首选目的地&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;抗议者谴责英国阻止移民穿越英吉利海峡的计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在英国，数以万计的寻求庇护者住在临时住所，等待移民决定。索赔，这可能需要数年时间。住宿包括酒店，英国纳税人每天花费近 600 万英镑（750 万美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以阻止小船为旗舰政策，首相里希·苏纳克 (Rishi Sunak) 的政府希望结束对酒店的依赖以节省金钱并阻止更多寻求庇护者前来。如果 2023 年的数字与去年持平，那么到今年年底，自 2020 年以来到达海峡的游客总数将超过 125,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这些计划面临人权组织和地方当局的抵制。由于地方当局的反对，在利物浦附近为寻求庇护者停靠一艘游轮的提议被取消。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在伦敦皇家码头停泊一艘游轮的提议遭到皇家码头管理当局的反对后被取消和伦敦市长办公室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伦敦工党市长萨迪克·汗本月表示：“逃离可怕环境的弱势群体将无法获得他们所需的支持”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宣布了一项计划Bibby Stockholm 驳船将于 4 月份在英格兰南海岸的多塞特港停靠至少 18 个月，但由于该船正在进行改装，因此比原计划晚了几周。反恐警察在该船停靠的地方进行了不明原因的演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这艘驳船有 222 间卧室，可容纳 500 名单身男性寻求庇护者。该计划遭到了保守党管理的多塞特郡议会和当地保守党议员理查德·德拉克斯的反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当他们离开港口时——如果他们确实能出去的话，因为这艘驳船只不过是一个准监狱——当他们进入韦茅斯（最近的城镇）时，他们会做什么？谁来监视他们？”德拉克斯本月在 LBC 电台谈到寻求庇护者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寻求庇护者不得在英国工作或选择居住地。人权组织表示，驳船不适合逃离冲突或苦难的人们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将数千名移民转移到旧皇家空军 (RAF) 基地军营的计划也遭到了反对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;h3>;英国旨在通过“明确危险”广告活动来阻止阿尔巴尼亚难民&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“很明显，政府使用废弃的军营和空军基地是为了迎合最低限度的普通民众英国难民慈善机构 Care4Calais 的首席执行官史蒂夫·史密斯 (Steve Smith) 表示：办公室的提议是在巨大的帐篷里安置寻求庇护者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自由民主党领导的委员会正在试图阻止在林肯郡的皇家空军斯坎普顿建立设施的提议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些寻求庇护者已经住在埃塞克斯韦瑟斯菲尔德的英国皇家空军基地，在那里，愤怒的当地人在极右翼团体的支持下举行了示威活动。该地区的保守党议员、英国移民部长罗伯特·詹里克 (Robert Jenrick) 发现自己与威胁要起诉政府的当地党员意见不合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然这些废弃的军事设施曾经驻扎着英国军队，但它们长期以来一直被废弃。空置且年久失修，濒临废弃，”史密斯说。 “明显的安全措施、共享的居住区以及与更广泛社区的隔离相结合，导致住宿完全不适合战争、冲突、酷刑、贩运和迫害的幸存者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;庇护申请人的数量根据政府数据，截至今年 3 月 31 日，这一数字从 2020 年的 40,830 人增加到 133,607 人。反对党工党将庇护申请积压的主要原因归咎于内政部的裁员和招聘问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一个没有得到充分解决的根本问题是庇护申请积压，我们面临的情况是，庇护申请的数量牛津大学移民观察站副主任 Robert McNeil 表示：“等待批准或拒绝庇护的人数呈螺旋式上升。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;移民是导致 2016 年英国脱欧的一个主要问题，导致英国结束了来自欧盟的人员的自由流动。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英国计划在移民风潮中限制外国学生&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，随着学生人数激增和英国的发展，2022 年净移民人数达到创纪录的 606,000 人为逃离乌克兰战争的人和来自香港的英国国民（海外）护照持有者发放签证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两年前推出的伦敦快速居留计划已帮助至少 105,200 名香港人抵达英国据英国政府称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了阻止非法移民的流动，苏纳克的保守党政府提议将一些乘小船抵达英国的移民送往卢旺达，他们的庇护申请将在那里进行处理。获得庇护的人将留在非洲国家，而不是返回英国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非法移民法案目前正在上议院审议。它被难民委员会贴上“残酷和肮脏”的标签，并陷入法律挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国政府辩称，其驱逐政策将阻止偷运移民跨越英吉利海峡的犯罪团伙。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政策制定者承诺解决这些问题有点不诚实，因为他们没有解决这些问题的工具。这些都是棘手的情况，仅靠国家政策无法解决。”麦克尼尔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前往英国的航程往往是漫长而危险的旅程的最后一站，一艘移民船在英国海域沉没的悲剧凸显了这一点。 6 月 14 日，希腊海岸。这艘船离开利比亚后沉没，据信船上有数百人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;八天后，一艘从突尼斯出发的移民船在意大利岛屿附近倾覆。兰佩杜萨岛，造成 40 多人失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2014 年以来，联合国已记录地中海中部地区有超过 21,000 人死亡和失踪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布鲁塞尔将责任归咎于人口走私但许多非政府组织和人权组织指责“欧洲堡垒”政策，这些政策凸显了难民在欧洲寻求保护时缺乏合法途径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在英国，“小船”问题已成为最重要的问题。保守党右翼的心头大患。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 2022 年，欧洲有 21 个国家接收的寻求庇护者数量超过英国。英国（74,751 人）落后于德国（296,555 人）、法国（根据内政部的数据，英国（170,705）和西班牙（128,015）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“英国政府不能继续利用该国的岛屿地位来逃避保护难民的国际责任，”史密斯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“英国政府不能继续利用该国的岛屿地位来逃避保护难民的国际责任。” >;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[First US M&A reforms in 45 years will crack down on illegal mergers but also delay deals by months]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/companies/article/3225650/first-us-ma-reforms-45-years-will-crack-down-illegal-mergers-also-delay-deals-months?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 10:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/967d8934-dc86-4325-810f-484bbffb3af7_13aff7b2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国反垄断机构要求企业上交的交易信息比之前对合并规则进行了彻底改革，这可能会使交易延迟数月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所谓的哈特-斯科特-罗迪诺备案程序的改革，是司法部和联邦贸易委员会打击的举措据一项估计，有关非法合并的调查可能会使交易时间表增加两到三个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些机构表示，这是 45 年来的第一次全面改革，将使他们能够“更有效地周二发布的拟议变更将于本周晚些时候在《联邦公报》上公布，其中要求提供有关过去 10 年收购的详细信息以及有关公司高管、董事和高管的信息。董事会观察员，以及公司员工的数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各机构将在 60 天内就拟议的变更征求公众意见。新规则要等到联邦贸易委员会和司法部发布最终版本后才会生效，预计需要几个月的时间才能完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新文件还要求披露赠款和贷款等补贴某些外国政府，包括朝鲜、中国、俄罗斯和伊朗。国会于 12 月通过了一项法律，要求各机构开始收集有关外国政府补贴的信息，因为担心中国等国家可能通过向某些公司提供财务支持来扭曲竞争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联邦贸易委员会估计了这份 126 页的文件将使公司准备备案所需的时间增加 100 多个小时，他们表示目前需要大约 37 个小时才能完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，彭博资讯高级分析师 Jennifer Rie 表示公司可能需要比这更长的时间来汇编各机构现在寻求的所有信息和分析。 Rie 表示，如今，一家律师事务所可以在 7 到 10 天内完成寻求反垄断批准的公司合并的文书工作。她表示，拟议的变更可能会延长该流程数月的时间，从而使美国的合并申报制度更加符合欧洲的规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在考虑将流程从 10 天改为 2-在加入 Bloomberg Intelligence 之前，Rie 从事了 10 年的反垄断法工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;长江和记、沃达丰将合并各部门，组建英国最大的移动提供商&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;反垄断支持者称赞这些变化是急需的更新，将帮助执法者更好地调查交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去 45 年中，并购格局发生了巨大变化，HSR 备案流程是反垄断组织美国经济自由项目的克里斯塔·布朗 (Krista Brown) 表示：“合并审查应该反映这一点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据美国法律，价值超过 1.114 亿美元的交易必须通知 FTC 和 DOJ，并等待 30 天。关闭。绝大多数合并不会引起任何担忧，并在初始等待期结束后完成。但这些机构可以要求提供更多信息，从而引发对交易的深入调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2021 财年（各机构公布数据的最后一年）报告的 3,520 笔交易中，联邦贸易委员会和司法部要求提供其中 65 家（约 1.9%）的更多信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在阻止平安瓜分香港顶级银行后，汇丰银行下一步将何去何从？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;今天的文件大多需要一份- 以及两个词的回应，彭博社的 Rie 表示，而新提案将要求公司提供交易的叙述性摘要，并概述公司竞争的业务领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这增加了交易的可能性不会在雷达下飞行，”她说。 “你正在为他们安排竞争重叠。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位 FTC 官员表示，此次改革旨在帮助保护机构资源，并减少在前 30 天内要求提供更多文件或信息的需要。这位未获授权公开发言的人士表示，美国机构与包括欧盟、英国和加拿大在内的其他司法管辖区进行了磋商，以了解他们预先需要哪些有关交易的信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位官员表示，美国机构认为新表格不会改变引发深入调查的交易数量。但该人士表示，他们预计强化后的表格可能会减少所谓的“撤回和重新提交”，指的是一种常用的技术，即公司撤回其文件并再次提交，以便向联邦贸易委员会或司法部提供额外的 30 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，各机构转向分级收费制度，最小的交易需支付 3 万美元进行合并审查，而最大的交易则必须支付 225 万美元。 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Japan’s surprise state-backed buyout of chip materials maker JSR hints at further ‘protection’-minded acquisitions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3225586/japans-surprise-state-backed-buyout-chip-materials-maker-jsr-hints-further-protection-minded?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/aadef3f0-25dd-4e65-b7f8-85e55cb194a9_f0ff9896.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;本周突然宣布大型半导体材料制造商 JSR Corp 将被收购日本投资公司 (JIC) 是一家强大的政府支持基金，令行业观察人士措手不及。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但观察人士表示，在全球半导体行业紧张局势日益加剧之际，周一的发展是有道理的 - 而且很可能是许多类似交易中的第一个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JSR 在召开董事会会议讨论 JIC 的报价后确认了该交易，JIC 由贸易部监管。该基金的大股东是政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;媒体报道称，JSR 最初与该公司接洽时提出了该提案的概要，该提案周二对该公司的估值为 9,090 亿日元（63 亿美元），较之前的估值有了显着提高。截至周五晚间东京交易收盘，市场对其价值的估计约为 47 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;JSR 在日本和海外开展业务，占据全球光刻胶市场 30% 的份额光刻胶是一种对半导体制造至关重要的化学试剂，日本在这一领域处于世界领先地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;光刻胶应用于硅片，硅片用于集成电路并提高半导体的性能。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在周一晚间的新闻发布会上，JSR 首席执行官埃里克·约翰逊 (Eric Johnson) 表示，随着研发成本的增加和竞争对手的进步，公司一段时间以来已经认识到重组的必要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道作为一家政府支持的实体，半个多世纪前开始生产合成橡胶的 JSR 将能够进行必要的改革，同时也有助于更广泛地推动该行业的发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;芯片在英特尔 500 亿美元行动的带动下，这场竞赛引发了消费热潮&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;从日本政府的角度来看，此次收购完全符合保护国家现有先进技术和开发下一代能力的积极政策。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;随着美国和中国在半导体领域的对峙以及芯片日益成为对日本经济安全至关重要的战略商品，政府干预的必要性变得更加迫切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本首相岸田文雄6 月 21 日在东京举行的新闻发布会上表示，“确保日本半导体技术的工业基础至关重要，不仅是为了增强产业竞争力，而且从脱碳和经济安全的角度来看也是如此”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东京大学科技政策教授铃木一人表示，他认为这笔交易“让所有人感到惊讶，但是，当你仔细观察时，就会发现政府采取这一步骤的原因是可以理解的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“政府希望保护重要技术免遭潜在的外国收购，特别是来自中国的技术，并保护这些公司免遭商业投资者的潜在拆散，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道，JSR Corp 在全球光刻胶市场上占据如此主导地位，显然属于国家战略利益的范畴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府显然也希望保护和维持这种市场优势。” ，因此这不仅仅是保护技术的问题，也是保留市场份额的问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东京麦格理集团日本股票研究主管达米安·通 (Damian Thong) 表示，世界各国政府正在介入保护他们的半导体产业。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;不断上升的产业政策如何赋予亚利桑那州经济实力来获得台积电交易&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这一消息让我们感到惊讶，但我绝对认为将会有更多地关注这一领域的发展，特别是在某些瓶颈能力领域，”他说。 “想要加强这些行业的不仅是政府，还有投资者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充道，在关键技术领域，没有人能够承受落后的后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本政府于 6 月初更新了涵盖半导体和电子行业的战略，设定了将半导体产品国内年销售额增加三倍至超过 15 万亿日元（1,044 亿美元）的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东京还向国内外公司提供慷慨的财政支持，以建立制造工厂，台积电于 6 月初宣布将开始在日本南部的熊本建设第二家工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;政府正在为该公司在该县的第一家工厂提供 4,760 亿日元（33 亿美元）的资金援助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多其他开发项目也在进行中，包括去年建立的工厂半导体制造商 Rapidus Corp 的年度投资项目，并获得八家日本科技公司的额外资金，用于在北海道建设最先进的生产工厂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据本周协议的条款，JIC 将推出一位政府消息人士向《朝日新闻》透露，12 月将进行每股 4,350 日元（30 美元）的要约收购，JSR 将在下一财年从东京证券交易所退市。日本政府已采取行动确保一个组织能够履行重要的国家政策角色，这表明未来可能会发生更多类似的收购。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“下一轮很可能会看到政府采取行动保护那些生产先进半导体所需的材料，因为它需要保持其在市场上的优势。”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore jails Indonesian who filmed himself having sex with 76 women without their consent]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3225647/singapore-jails-indonesian-who-filmed-himself-having-sex-76-women-without-their-consent?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/28/a78e5253-0da4-4ec8-8a88-2cef32db6eb8_0b52cf45.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在使用约会应用程序认识新加坡的各种女性后，Johan Wijaya 拍摄了她们与&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在调查过程中，警方在约翰的设备上发现了 76 名女性受害者的录音，这些录音在五年内被拍摄。并非所有指控都针对印度尼西亚人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，32 岁的约翰是该城邦的永久居民，在承认五项偷窥罪后，被判处八个月监禁。量刑期间还考虑了其​​他十一项类似指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约翰在 Tinder 和 OkCupid 等应用程序上与这些女性见面后，他会在亲自与她们见面之前询问她们是否愿意建立随意的关系。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在与他在家里或经济型酒店遇到的女性发生性行为之前，约翰会打开隐藏在便携式充电器内的摄像机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女人洗澡或者上厕所的时候，他会把充电宝的充电器对着床。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于录音时充电宝没有发光，所以女人不会注意到。全程录制视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Johan 会将视频保存在他的笔记本电脑或硬盘上，并注明受害者的姓名以及拍摄日期，以便他稍后观看。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;h3>;电视节目临时演员拍摄了在新加坡入狱的演员的小便池照片&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据法院命令，受害者的姓名不得公开，以保护他们的身份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Johan，他的法庭文件中没有说明职业，也没有向第三方传播视频。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;副检察官秦金城准备的法庭文件称，2021年1月6日，Johan结识了一个25年的——通过约会应用程序与老妇联系后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两人决定几天后见面发生性关系，然后同意每周见面一次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这些会议期间， Johan 会在未经女子同意的情况下使用移动电源充电器中的摄像头记录他们的亲密行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这导致总共 16 个视频显示该女子全裸，脸部和生殖器可见。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;The woman was initially unaware of the recordings and had filed a police report in relation to a separate recording that Johan had made using his mobile phone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Court documents did not elaborate on what led to her discovery.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman found out about the other recordings only after the police extracted them from Johan&#39;s laptop that had been seized for investigations.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore jails Chinese man for trying to strangle landlord over slow Wi-fi&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A total of 391 videos were extracted, of which 336 contained voyeuristic elements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The videos also featured a total of 76 victims, which included the 25- year-old and four other victims whose treatment was the subject of the charges brought against Johan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Johan eventually admitted that the videos were recordings of his sexual activities with various sexual partners who did not consent to the recordings and were unaware that they were being recorded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also admitted that the power-bank charger with the camera was bought in 2017 to secretly record such videos.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For each count of voyeurism, Johan could have been jailed for up to two years, fined or caned, or punished with any combination of the three.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This article was first published by &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Catching insects instead of fish’: video of man fishing next to bed in flooded home after heavy rain goes viral delighting Chinese social media]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3225448/catching-insects-instead-fish-video-man-fishing-next-bed-flooded-home-after-heavy-rain-goes-viral?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/592741d3-0d4c-4a49-969c-a43853db354f_9f3b0b3b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A video of a man in China fishing off the side of his bed after his home was flooded has delighted mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unnamed man from Wuhan in central China&#39;s Hubei province began fishing next to his bed after recent heavy rains caused his home to flood, but instead of fish, he only caught insects, The Paper reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man&#39;s wife, surnamed Dong, filmed the video and shared the details online, saying they were at home when a downpour occurred earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Aiya, in an instant, our home was flooded,” Dong told The Paper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the flash floods, Dong said her husband got the idea to fish.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He is a fishing enthusiast,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man threw a line into the floodwaters to see what happened, but after many attempts over half an hour, he had not caught any fish.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We did not see any fish, but we did see quite a few insects,” Dong added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story has amused online observers in China, who praised the couple&#39;s positive attitude.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “People who have such a sunny attitude know how to live their life.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person wrote: “The man is lovely, and so is his wife.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwan to get tactical boost with Nato’s Link 22 and US SeaGuardian drones: analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3225627/taiwan-get-tactical-boost-natos-link-22-and-us-seaguardian-drones-analysts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/5b683d59-6c7a-4254-8845-d7646d57e54e_cf5fbe4a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s acquisition of Nato&#39;s Link 22 tactical communications system will bolster the island&#39;s defences, especially with the planned addition of four advanced surveillance and reconnaissance drones from the United States, military experts said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A senior Taiwanese defence official confirmed last month that the US would help the self-ruled island to acquire the advanced data link and radio system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan is also expecting to take delivery of powerful MQ-9B SeaGuardian drones in 2025 after the US State Department approved the US$600 million deal three years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts said that in a conflict with the mainland Link 22 would be a highly valuable defence communications asset for Taiwan, which does not have its own satellite system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Taiwan&#39;s acquisition of Nato&#39;s Link 22 will enable it to operate the MQ-9B SeaGuardian drones to be provided by the US,” Taipei-based military commentator Chi Le-yi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[The US] sale of four MQ-9Bs to Taiwan and its acquisition of Link 22 for support could be seen as a part of the US integrated deterrence strategy in light of the increasing risk of military conflict between Taiwan and the mainland.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Link 22 is the beyond-line-of-sight communications platform used by Nato members in joint operations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The SeaGuardian drones, which have a range of up to 6,000km (3,730 miles) and 40 hours of flight time, are expected to be a boost to anti-submarine operations and surveillance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Pentagon&#39;s integrated deterrence strategy emphasises the use of diplomacy, economic statecraft, and military power together to deter enemy forces from aggression.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Chenming, a researcher from the Beijing-based Yuan Wang military science and technology think tank, said Link 22 would help Taipei improve its ability to counter communications jamming in a conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Link 22 is for secure air and sea data transmission, and is mainly used for redundancy enhancement for sending bigger data like joint operational images,” Zhou said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s military already uses the US-built Link 16 system to connect its US-made weapon systems, but it is not compatible with non-US weapon systems such as the La Fayette-class frigates and Mirage 2000-5 fighter jets it bought from France.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Lu Li-shih, a former instructor at the Taiwanese Naval Academy in Kaohsiung, said Taiwan&#39;s acquisition of Link 22 did not mean that Nato would automatically allow Taiwan to join its communications system as some Taiwanese analysts had expected.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“According to the Nato&#39;s founding treaty, Asia is excluded under its principle of collective defence … and France, a core member, has expressed its opposition to expanding [the alliance] to Asia,” Lu said, adding that he did not think France and other Nato members would share their military operational codes with Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The US wants Taiwan to have Link 22 because it&#39;s the most convenient and lowest cost measure to operate the MQ-9B, which needs to connect with satellites, and Taiwan doesn&#39;t have its own satellite system.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lu said that while Taiwan could upgrade its Link 16 system to connect with the SeaGuardian drones, it would require the island to share its military operation codes with the US – something Taipei would be reluctant to do.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During a visit to Taiwan last month, retired US general Steven Rudder, who headed the marine air wing in the Pacific region from 2017 to 2020, said the US&#39; ultimate goal was to bring Taiwan into its C4ISR system, a mechanism for command, control, communications, computers, intelligence, surveillance and reconnaissance.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong leader John Lee has hit nearly every goal for his first year in office, but what do residents think of his performance?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3225646/hong-kong-leader-john-lee-has-hit-nearly-every-goal-his-first-year-office-what-do-residents-think?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 09:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/28/1abbba0b-4369-4f8e-b06d-972b1936ce8b_a3cb5c1a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s leader has delivered on nearly all 68 goals he vowed his administration would achieve during his first year in office, the Post has found, but observers have warned residents might still not be any better off as a result.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu campaigned on the back of a promise to bring a “result-oriented” approach to governing that would hold up to public scrutiny. In his October policy address, he set out almost 200 key performance indicators (KPIs) covering land and housing, economics, healthcare, welfare, youth development and civil service reform.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of the 194 KPIs, 68 were to be met by the middle of the year, another 55 by the end of it, and the remainder within two to 10 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A check by the Post found Lee&#39;s administration had met one-third of all KPIs while delivering on 66 out of the 68 short-term goals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he has yet to release an updated Civil Service Code to government workers for consultation. His administration has floated the idea of removing a requirement for civil servants to adhere to “political neutrality” to prevent the rule from being used to evade tasks and once suggested a draft for consultation would be out in the first quarter of this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But dropping the requirement could be holding up the consultation, suggested Leung Chau-ting, chairman of the Federation of Civil Service Unions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is very sensitive and involves a lot of details,” he said. “We are still waiting for the consultation paper if there will be one.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The other goal still to be achieved is the commercialisation of more than 50 per cent of the projects in the government&#39;s Fintech Proof-of-Concept Subsidy Scheme in 2022-23. In a reply to the Legislative Council on June 5, the government said it had approved 56 projects out of the 166 applications.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong&#39;s John Lee gears up for Asean trade trip as exports remain in slump&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;But Lee has been particularly successful in achieving goals related to attracting talent and business, as well as land and housing supply.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since December, the government has launched the Top Talent Pass Scheme, lowered some requirements under existing admission schemes and set up teams at its overseas offices to lure talent, as required by nine KPIs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official figures showed that various talent schemes had received about 84,000 applications, 49,000 of which had been approved, by the end of May. Lee earlier said the city was well on its way to attracting nearly double the 35,000 workers targeted annually.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 95 per cent of the visas granted through the talent schemes were to applicants from mainland China, according to the Immigration Department. The prevalence has sparked concerns over the city&#39;s ability to attract international candidates. It also remains unknown whether newcomers would stay in the city for a year as the government wants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for luring business, the government has established the Office for Attracting Strategic Enterprises and allocated HK$30 billion (US$3.8 billion) from the Future Fund to set up the “Co‑Investment Fund” – two KPIs considered the foundation for attracting companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The office told the Post it had met over 150 top-notch enterprises working in cutting-edge technologies such as artificial intelligence and life sciences since its launch in December.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong John Lee&#39;s first year in office: what did he achieve?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Most of these enterprises have shown interest in setting up business in Hong Kong, the office added. One KPI set for 2027 requires the government to attract at least 100 innovation and technology enterprises with high potential.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the Commerce and Economic Development Bureau, 186 mainland and overseas companies had decided to set up or expand their operations in Hong Kong since January, which is nearly 20 per cent of the goal to attract 1,130 businesses between 2023 and 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But lawmaker Duncan Chiu, who represents the technology sector, doubted many companies would come to the city because the state of the global economy made it difficult for businesses to expand.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have seen new policies coming out every month since last October,” he said. “But without policy continuity, development won&#39;t be fostered with just the numbers of the delivered KPIs.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While almost all of Hong Kong&#39;s ministers have visited mainland or overseas cities to promote the city&#39;s strengths since Lee took office, Allen Shi Lop-tak, president of the Chinese Manufacturers&#39; Association, said it was too early to assess the impact of such trips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Going out is better than staying home,” Shi said. “But I don&#39;t think it would yield fruits in the short term, and it still depends on whether such activities could be held regularly instead of just meeting a certain target, then nothing comes after.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even though most KPIs under land and housing are mid- and long-term, Lee&#39;s administration managed to meet all nine short-term ones. These include tabling bills to cut time for development procedures, launching schemes to boost cooperation with private developers in building subsidised flats and setting up a dedicated office to coordinate the development of the Northern Metropolis – a government flagship project.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government also told the public it had secured enough land to build 360,000 public housing flats in the next decade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The missing part of this rosy picture is how will all these development projects be financed,” said legislator Doreen Kong Yuk-foon who sits on the Legislative Council&#39;s panel on housing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regina Ip Lau Suk-yee, the government&#39;s top adviser in the Executive Council, earlier urged the administration to prioritise the Northern Metropolis plan over the Lantau Tomorrow Vision, a controversial project to create three artificial islands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The debate over the government&#39;s plan to build public flats on a Fanling golf course – reignited by the Hong Kong Golf Club&#39;s extensive lobbying efforts to block it – also drew scepticism on Lee&#39;s ability to achieve his goals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kong added that solving the housing problem would take more than just constructing flats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It should also come with building infrastructure and supporting facilities,” she said. “Will you live in a flat without any supporting infrastructure nearby?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;John Burns, an honorary professor at the department of politics and public administration at the University of Hong Kong, said people cared about more than meeting the KPIs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But now it may be too early to evaluate the outcomes of all these activities associated with the KPIs,” Burns said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong firms move to cut major deals in Middle East after John Lee&#39;s visit&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The political scientist also noted that with trust in the government still low, Lee&#39;s administration had to understand “results were co-produced” and needed people&#39;s cooperation and respect.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Engaging citizens is the key, not marginalising them,” he said. “Public consultation can build trust and legitimacy and lay the foundation for more stable state-society collaboration in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The government appears to believe that it doesn&#39;t have time for that, which is a dangerous position.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Natalie Wong&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Rocky US-China relationship could benefit from couples therapy strategies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3225473/rocky-us-china-relationship-could-benefit-couples-therapy-strategies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.28 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/27/1af16e30-bc17-4a2b-86ab-7471b2d4c375_4732fe69.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Conflict is inevitable in any long-term relationship. What really matters is whether partners can manage, resolve and move on from their disagreements and build a healthier bond over time. This insight applies to international diplomacy as much as to romantic relationships.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is fair to say the aftermath of the balloon incident in February was not a shining example of conflict resolution. Rather than communicate calmly and effectively, China and the United States got caught in a cycle of blame and recrimination, sending the relationship to its lowest ebb in decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thankfully, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken&#39;s successful visit to Beijing has opened a window of opportunity to establish a more constructive and harmonious US-China relationship. Both sides have a responsibility to seize this chance – as two of the world&#39;s foremost powers, their dynamic not only influences their own nations but the entire global landscape.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Blinken&#39;s visit, the first to China by a US secretary of state in five years, saw constructive meetings with Foreign Minister Qin Gang, top diplomat Wang Yi and President Xi Jinping, the last of which was by no means guaranteed. These positive interactions send a strong signal that, having veered dangerously close to the edge, both sides recognise they cannot risk a complete break and are committed to putting the relationship on a more steady footing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is now crucial for China and the US to work together to build a solid foundation for their relationship so future incidents cannot derail ties in the manner we have seen in the last few months. To achieve this, there are four principles from relationship therapy that can be adapted to help guide the development of stronger, more stable US-China relations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, open and regular communication is the cornerstone of any strong partnership. China and the US must get back to having frequent and transparent dialogue about their intentions, concerns and expectations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first priority is to step up high-level interactions to clear the way for a meeting between Xi and US President Joe Biden at the Group of 20 or Apec summits later this year. Hopefully Blinken&#39;s trip will be followed by visits by US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen, Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo and Biden&#39;s climate envoy John Kerry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regular contacts at lower levels of government should also be restored, as well as the bilateral dialogue that withered during the Trump administration. Collectively, these meetings can provide platforms to explore avenues for cooperation and address any brewing issues and defuse tensions before they snowball into larger conflicts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Second, any relationship needs robust mechanisms to manage and resolve conflict when it does occur. China and the US must establish channels for swift and effective communication during crises, as well as pre-established protocols to manage such events, to help de-escalate such situations before they become unmanageable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even at the height of the Cold War, the US and Soviet Union maintained channels for communication and crisis management, including a hotline between Washington and Moscow. China and the US lack those kinds of mechanisms.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Would a Cold War-style agreement help prevent China-US tensions from escalating?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Looking to the longer term, the third point a relationship therapist might emphasise is the need to develop mutual respect, empathy and shared interests. Couples going through a rough patch are often advised to try to understand the other person and engage in joint activities or hobbies to strengthen their bond.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a similar vein, nations can foster empathy through cultural exchange in areas such as education, research and tourism, helping to enhance mutual understanding and reduce the “us versus them” mentality. Cultural ties between China and the US have waned in recent years because of politics and the Covid-19 pandemic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is now open again, but the lack of enough flights to and from the US remains a bottleneck. Fewer than 6 per cent of flights between China and the US that existed in 2019 have resumed, according to a recent Nomura report, and flights that remain are expensive. Part of the issue is that restrictions on flying over Russian airspace add a significant cost to operating these routes. Both sides need to explore ways to increase the number of flights.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More broadly, both sides should strive to promote bilateral exchange across society. The number of US students in China dwindled to just around 350 last semester. Hopefully this number will begin to rise as students make new applications for next term. It would also be beneficial to promote academic exchange, including by reducing the red tape involved in having foreign guests participate in academic conferences in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the Fulbright China programme sent US scholars to China for more than four decades and sent their Chinese counterparts the other way. It was cancelled in 2020 but should be revived, as should the Peace Corps programme, which withdrew from China the same year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finally, shared goals and collaborative projects play a pivotal role in helping couples deepen their connection. Similarly, China and the US must identify areas of common ground and pursue joint initiatives that benefit both nations. This should extend beyond addressing immediate concerns and conflicts to encompass broader, more constructive themes such as climate change and global financial stability. Long-term collaboration and incremental achievements on such issues can help unite both nations under a common cause.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like successful couples, both nations must invest time and effort in nurturing their partnership. After Blinken&#39;s visit, there is a chance for China and the US to build a more solid foundation for their relationship so it is not derailed when the next surprise comes. As with any relationship, there will be bumps in the road, but these can be overcome with careful management.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>