<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Tencent’s ‘third-tier’ audio platform Penguin FM to shut down in September after lagging far behind rivals like Ximalaya]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3226668/tencents-third-tier-audio-platform-penguin-fm-shut-down-september-after-lagging-far-behind-rivals?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/e6790572-7698-4ce4-9943-2d64bcbe4607_a4b1fe99.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国社交媒体巨头腾讯控股表示将关闭其成立八年的公司在线音频平台企鹅FM于9月份上线，中国估值最高的科技巨头继续整合其内容业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;企鹅FM已停止新用户注册，现有用户无法再向其账户充值，该业务部门周三在其网站上发表声明称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;腾讯于2015年推出该平台，允许用户收听各种音频产品，包括音乐电台、书籍、新闻和聊天频道。该公司并未对这一决定做出具体解释，只是简单地将其称为“业务调整”。该公司在声明中表示，“与用户告别是一种遗憾。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;分析师看好汽车音响增长，喜马拉雅首次实现盈利&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国在线音频服务平台之间的竞争，在 2021 年出现了疯狂的新活动，当时美国的 Clubhouse 曾短暂流行，包括在中国，但几个月后就被屏蔽了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;喜马拉雅同样由腾讯支持的播客平台拥有最大的市场份额，每月活跃用户 (MAU) 超过 1 亿。根据中国研究公司 Selection Data 3 月份的一份报告，竞争对手蜻蜓 FM 和荔枝的月活跃用户数均超过 1000 万。该报告将企鹅FM列为“第三梯队”应用，月活跃用户数超过100万。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去一年，腾讯一直在整合多项业务，试图在经济形势严峻的情况下削减成本并削减无利可图的业务。逆风和收紧的监管环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 8 月，这家科技集团关闭了其内容创作应用看点，两个月前，该公司关闭了视频游戏流媒体平台企鹅电竞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;与其他中国大型科技公司一样，在北京于 2020 年底发起为期两年的行业整顿后，腾讯今年的财务业绩出现反弹。然而，世界第二大经济体的增长仍然低迷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;腾讯第一季度收入同比增长 11%，利润增长 10%，主要由广告和视频游戏销售推动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，由于预计经济放缓以及可能即将到来的经济放缓受经济衰退影响，全球大型科技公司在 2022 年底和今年裁员数万人。许多中国科技公司都参与了这一趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;腾讯在香港的股价周三收盘下跌 1.1%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[At China-led regional summit, India refuses to back Beijing’s infrastructure vision]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3226684/china-led-regional-summit-india-refuses-back-beijings-infrastructure-vision?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/d032dd8f-61fb-420a-87ed-d03192584ca8_2801dfc6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;尽管中国国家主席习近平提出倡议，但印度拒绝支持他的签名腰带和在印度主持的峰会上提出“道路倡议”，这是专家们所期待的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周二举行的上海合作组织（SCO）虚拟峰会上，习近平表示，该基础设施项目将促进区域合作、贸易和投资，他呼吁加强“一带一路”项目的协调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刚刚完成上合组织主席国一年任期的印度和新批准的正式成员国伊朗在一份联合声明中表示不支持“一带一路”战略。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“自从印度2017年成为上合组织正式成员以来，声明就一直如此。印度不太同意在联合声明中认可中国的[一带一路倡议]，并且它有自己的基础设施开发项目版本。兰州大学政治与国际关系学院教授朱永标表示，中国原本预计不会得到印度的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相反，该声明表明上合组织致力于求同存异” ，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡南洋理工大学国际政治暴力和恐怖主义研究中心高级研究员拉斐尔·潘图奇表示，印度有实际原因拒绝支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一带一路经过克什米尔与巴基斯坦有争议的领土……印度人试图通过一带一路倡议与上合组织接触总是面临着一种实际的困境。他们一向非常沉默寡言。他们总是说这是一个坏主意。”潘图奇说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪在峰会演讲中强调了合作打击地区恐怖主义的必要性，凸显了与北京和莫斯科的分歧。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国强调推动伊朗与巴基斯坦接触的共同威胁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“恐怖主义已成为对地区和全球和平的威胁……我们必须共同打击任何形式的恐怖主义以及任何表现，”莫迪说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人提出了更具体的呼吁。哈萨克斯坦总统托卡耶夫敦促加强能源合作，并表示上合组织成员国应设立投资基金。习近平再次呼吁建立上合组织开发银行&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯总统普京建议建立“支付基础设施”，以促进区域经济一体化并建立“独立的金融结构”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和俄罗斯都呼吁在上合组织成员国之间的贸易中更广泛地使用本国货币，以推动该集团内更深层次的经济一体化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但潘图奇表示，印度还有其他选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我不认为他们有同样的立场。他们有很多西方国家渴望与他们接触并发展自由贸易区和自由贸易关系，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于每个人想要做的事情并没有真正达成一致。并实现……[这成为]一个优先事项不同的问题。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当莫迪谈到国家面临的恐怖主义威胁时，他说“一些国家利用跨境恐怖主义作为其政策的工具并为恐怖分子提供庇护所”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“上合组织必须毫不犹豫地批评那些将支持跨境恐怖主义作为国家政策一部分的国家。莫迪表示：“在如此严重的问题上不应该存在双重标准。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然没有直接提及巴基斯坦，但上海国际问题研究院研究员李红梅表示，这是一个明显的问题。提到印度的邻国，莫迪希望上海合作组织共同向其施压。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国希望上海合作组织成为安全和经济合作的平台，但印度仍然更担心恐怖主义，自塔利班以来，恐怖主义日益恶化李说，中国接管了阿富汗。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国敦促巴基斯坦、阿富汗在 2021 年以来的首次会谈中帮助打击恐怖主义&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“莫迪的讲话中也提到了区域互联互通，[但]这是她说：“反恐是印度的次要关切或次要目标，而反恐是印度在上合组织中的首要目标。”她补充说，自2020年在加勒万河谷与中国军队发生致命边境冲突以来，印度经济已显示出“去中国化”的迹象。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管边界争端造成的紧张局势持续存在，潘图奇表示，新德里仍然积极参与该地区集团，并领导了多个工作组，其中包括专注于数字经济的工作组。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但它同样非常清楚的是，从印度的角度来看，由于他们与中国的敌对关系，并且他们喜欢提出一种更加不可知论的观点，因此从印度的角度来看，他们显然不愿意陷入太深的泥潭，而上合组织就是一个很好的例子。考虑他们如何做到这一点，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Monday was the hottest day ever recorded, Tuesday was even hotter as global temperatures continue to rise]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/3226689/monday-was-hottest-day-ever-recorded-tuesday-was-even-hotter-global-temperatures-continue-rise?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 22:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/a1125834-024b-4189-9438-776b5cad3ce3_b4ad9842.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;7 月 3 日和根据缅因大学气候再分析器项目科学家的说法，7 月 4 日天气更加炎热。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;连续两天，全球平均气温飙升至未知区域。在科学家们讨论了周一的酷热之后，周二的气温飙升了 0.17 摄氏度（0.31 华氏度），甚至更热，这对于全球平均温度和记录而言是一个巨大的气温跃升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样是缅因大学的气候计算器 –基于卫星数据和计算机模拟 - 预计周三的气温将达到创纪录水平，南极洲的平均气温将比 1979-2000 年的平均气温高出 4.5 摄氏度（8.1 华氏度）。&lt;/p>;&lt; 7月3日至4日，魁北克省、加拿大西北部和秘鲁的高温记录被打破。美国国家气象局气象学家扎克·泰勒表示，从俄勒冈州梅德福到佛罗里达州坦帕，美国各地的城市都在历史最高水平上徘徊。北京报告上周连续 9 天气温超过 35 摄氏度（95 华氏度）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“化石燃料的使用导致地球升温并不意外，早在 19 日就已预测到。毕竟是一个世纪，”德国波茨坦气候研究所的气候科学家斯特凡·拉姆斯托夫说。 “但这对我们人类和我们赖以生存的生态系统来说是危险的。我们需要快速阻止它。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每天但初步和非官方的高温记录是在“今年真正不真实的气象和气候统计数据”几个月之后得出的，例如在俄克拉荷马大学气象学教授 Jason Furtado 表示，北大西洋、南极洲海冰创历史新低以及厄尔尼诺现象迅速加强。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;专家怀疑，泰国鱼类大规模死亡是由气候变化造成的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这一全球记录并不完全是国家海洋和大气协会等黄金标准气候测量实体经常使用的类型。但这表明气候变化正在进入未知领域。美国国家海洋和大气管理局 (NOAA) 下属国家环境信息中心主任德克·阿恩特 (Deke Arndt) 表示，它合法地捕获了全球范围内的供暖情况，NOAA 在进行官方记录计算时将考虑这些数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在对于气候评估界来说，我认为我们不会像一个月或一年那样对单日观测给予如此重视，”阿恩特说。科学家通常使用更长的测量时间——数月、数年、数十年——来追踪地球变暖。此外，这一最热日的初步记录所依据的数据只能追溯到 1979 年，即卫星记录保存的开始，而 NOAA 的数据可以追溯到 1880 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 Arndt 补充说，我们不会除非我们正处于由温室气体排放和“强劲”厄尔尼诺现象爆发驱动的“一个可能非常温暖的时代”，否则我们不会看到任何接近创纪录温暖的日子。厄尔尼诺现象是太平洋中部部分地区的暂时性自然变暖，它会改变全世界的天气，总体上使地球变得更热。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人为造成的气候变化就像全球气温的上升自动扶梯，而厄尔尼诺现象阿恩特说，就像站在自动扶梯上跳起来一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周二，即美国独立日，地球平均气温飙升至 17.18 摄氏度或 62.9 华氏度，根据缅因大学气候再分析仪的数据，气候科学家经常使用的常用工具来了解世界状况。周二的气温比 1979-2000 年的平均气温高出近一摄氏度（1.8 华氏度），而 1979-2000 年的平均气温本身也比 20 世纪和 19 世纪的平均气温高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月 3 日，重新分析仪获得了该温度温度为 17.01 摄氏度（62.6 华氏度）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;重新分析器基于 NOAA 计算机模拟，旨在使用卫星数据进行预测。它不是基于报告的地面观察结果。因此，这份非官方记录实际上是使用了一种专为预测而不是保存记录而设计的天气工具。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月 3 日的全球日平均气温为 17.01 摄氏度或 62.6 华氏度。这个平均气温可能看起来不那么热，但这是该数据集 44 年来首次气温突破 17 摄氏度大关，然后甚至更高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“像这样的记录斯坦福大学气候科学家克里斯·菲尔德（Chris Field）没有参与计算，他说：“这是现在得到广泛支持的命题的又一个证据，即全球变暖正在将我们推向更热的未来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球平均温度更热气温对世界各地的人们来说都是残酷的条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国，高温警告本周对俄勒冈州西部部分地区、加利福尼亚州北部内陆地区、中部地区等超过 3000 万人生效。据国家气象局天气预报中心称，新墨西哥州、德克萨斯州、佛罗里达州和卡罗来纳州沿海地区。他们说，亚利桑那州南部和加利福尼亚州持续发出高温警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当高温达到峰值时，人类的健康会受到影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我们变得比平时更热时，就会出现更高的气温。状况？人们不习惯这样。他们的身体不习惯这种情况，”亚利桑那州气候学家、极端天气和气候事件专家 Erinanne Saffell 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Saffell 补充说，对于年轻人和老年人来说，这种风险已经很高，他们即使在正常条件下，他们也容易受到高温的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“重要的是要了解谁可能处于危险之中，确保人们补充水分、保持凉爽、不会在户外劳累并做好防护你周围那些也可能面临风险的人，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s quiet strides in the climate change fight are an example to all]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3226442/chinas-quiet-strides-climate-change-fight-are-example-all?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/f90b1019-353b-4556-ad91-a317364f7691_be582a9b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;瑞士大小的原始雨林去年被夷为平地，造成了无数的损失不可替代的生物多样性。加拿大的大规模野火释放了大量二氧化碳，加剧了全球变暖，同时也让北美各地的居民窒息。海狮和海豚在加利福尼亚州海岸以前所未有的数量死亡，全球范围内越来越频繁和严重的风暴、洪水和饥荒正在发生。抓住现实，在所有现有证据的情况下，不认识到世界气候正在发生危险的事情，并对所有生物产生严重的负面影响。它正在加速并创下记录——而且不是以一种好的方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多政府开始认真起来，发表了好话，甚至通过联合国气候峰会等机构采取了一些协调行动.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，出现了某种形式的民众起义，其中包括“停止石油”和“反抗灭绝”等团体。世界各国人民正在组织起来，要求其政治领导人对气候变化采取更大胆的行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，Covid-19 大流行、俄罗斯入侵乌克兰引发的可怕而残酷的战争以及全球生活成本危机、通货膨胀和其他相关问题在最糟糕的时刻让我们分心。这些事情正在转移我们的注意力，使我们无法集中精力采取紧急行动，以帮助解决地球面临的根本和生存威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们希望采取行动，但存在严重滞后。风险正在迅速增加，一切都太小、太迟了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界现在需要大胆的领导和模范举措，而不是明天。我们需要实际的例子来说明如何努力超越气候变化的临界点，而不是远远落后于它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在我看来，中国可以接受这一职责。当其他国家在世界燃烧之际争论、争论、推卸责任和武断时，中国实施了一系列广泛的项目来正面解决自己的碳足迹问题。其方法是多方面的、以技术为中心、可扩展的，并且以稳定、可持续的速度实施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一波行动正在中国展开。其中之一是最近批准在甘肃省沙漠城市武威建设一座 2 兆瓦液体燃料钍熔盐反应堆 (MSR)。这项技术的潜力几十年来已为人所知，并提供了令人兴奋的前景。它比铀基同类产品更清洁、更安全。它还拥有更容易获得和丰富的燃料储备以及更高效的动力源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果不是 20 世纪 50 年代以来核武器计划的需要，世界核电库存现在可能主要由更加环保的钍盐核装置。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国钍盐储量丰富。未来，它可以部署大量熔盐反应堆来利用这些资源。它们可以成为国家多管齐下解决方案的一部分，以消除燃烧化石燃料发电的任何需要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度也有一个活跃的钍盐反应堆计划，这些重要的地缘政治参与者之间的宝贵合作是可能的。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;另一个值得注意的项目是位于四川省雅砻江高原的光水混合发电厂的投产，每年可发电20亿千瓦时，相当于70万户家庭的用电量&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后是通过安徽合肥实验性先进超导托卡马克等设施进行聚变发电研究，以及中国在法国建设的国际热核聚变实验堆（ITER）聚变设施的国际合作。耗资 250 亿美元的国际热核实验反应堆 (ITER) 是世界上最大的国际聚变项目，当然也是最雄心勃勃的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国目前部署的太阳能已提供超过 225 吉瓦的可再生能源，这比比世界其他地区的总和还多。值得一提的是，中央权力机构能够在短时间内授权并实施如此重要的项目，造福所有人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，中国正在努力通过种植数百万美元来扭转荒漠化。的树木。联合国粮食及农业组织2021年报告指出，中国的森林覆盖面积已从1990年的1.57亿公顷增加到2020年的约2.2亿公顷。此外，作为2021年3月公布的中国“十四五”规划的一部分，到 2025 年将森林覆盖率提高到 24.1% 的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;树木是重要的碳汇。它们帮助调节我们的气候，过滤我们饮用的水，为其他植物、昆虫和其他野生动物提供重要的栖息地，当然，它们还释放氧气。这并不能弥补前面提到的原始雨林的损失，但这仍然是一件好事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后，中国正在快速引进电动汽车。它已取代日本成为世界上最大的汽车出口国，并在这一特定领域以及重要电池和太阳能电池板技术的研究方面处于领先地位。这意味着中国城市颗粒物污染有望减少，空气质量得到改善，汽油需求也将减少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，在没有大张旗鼓、认真刻意的情况下，中国在国内和国际上正在取得重要且不断进步的进步。解决气候变化问题。世界其他地区应该注意到并效仿这种大胆而深刻的举措。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;颜色：橙色&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US’ once exclusive ginseng crop – a TCM favourite in China – still withering under trade war despite a 5-year search for relief]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3226638/us-once-exclusive-ginseng-crop-tcm-favourite-china-still-withering-under-trade-war-despite-5-year?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 22:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/1c619917-4e38-48e8-8322-16e85ff1c83d_2bda4bc5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;自中国开始征税以来，江明涛位于美国威斯康星州的人参农场产量减半五年前，对这种因其健康益处而令人垂涎的植物征收高达 40% 的关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年，北京对中国消费者珍视的可增强免疫力和缓解某些慢性疾病的植物根采取了行动。随着美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普开始与中国的贸易战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于向中国批发不再有利可图，出生于中国的姜尝试改种胡萝卜和玉米，但这两种作物都无法带来足够的收入&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前医生一直想经营一家企业，他在马拉松县经营着一个农场，马拉松县是威斯康星州中西部的一个地区，也是大多数销往中国的人参的来源地。凉爽的气候和独特的表土成分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有什么可以种植的，”江说，他 14 年前首次移居加拿大攻读博士学位，然后在威斯康星州上医学院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我正在坚持政府的工资保障计划和政府提供的小企业贷款。”江可能认为自己是马拉松县的幸运者，该县拥有 138,000 人口，大约有 100 名农民沃索县城县长凯蒂·罗森伯格 (Katie Rosenberg) 表示，已经完全停止种植人参。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，通常价值 2000 万美元的农作物占该农业县经济的三分之一，其中乳制品和牛肉构成了该县经济的三分之一。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“以无益的方式攻击中国是很常见的，”罗森伯格说。 “与世界第二大经济体的关系不好让我们受到伤害。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关税已回落至 32%，但仍高于 2018 年前仅 7.5% 的水平.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京长期以来一直呼吁取消美国惩罚性关税，当美国财政部长珍妮特·耶伦从周四开始对中国进行为期四天的访问时，可能会提出这个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗森伯格补充说，中国驻芝加哥领事馆还必须对马拉松县出口的人参进行公证，中国入境口岸的文件记录也更加严格，这使得运输成本更高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人参出口商还必须使用标准化集装箱”，她说，这给出货量较小的农民带来了负担。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“似乎有很多文书工作阻碍了这一过程，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang 必须花费大量资金额外8000美元的包装材料费用，用于通过港口城市深圳运往中国终端市场的人参。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国内的人参市场，甚至当地商人已经开始生产的人参啤酒，都没有兴趣罗森伯格补充道，其他喜爱人参的亚洲国家可以在贸易战之前抵消对中国的销售。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;自 2018 年 7 月以来的中美贸易战关键日期和事件时间表&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;威斯康星州人参、大部分来自马拉松县，其品质与法国波尔多葡萄酒和日本和牛牛肉类似。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗森伯格、蒋和该县的其他种植者已瞄准华盛顿国会山敦促立法者解决贸易争端，这场贸易争端引发了针锋相对的关税上调，涉及价值 5500 亿美元的双边贸易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗森伯格还与美国贸易代表办公室进行了交谈，并向威斯康星州政府提出了要求&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但罗森伯格和帮助她宣传工作的农民发现，华盛顿对中国的不信任根深蒂固，立法者不会推动任何改变。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“我们需要进行外交，这就是我们在全球经济格局中取得成功的方式，但这并不受欢迎，”主张削减关税的罗森伯格说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我希望这些对话继续下去”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的人参消费者将其根源与中药联系在一起，许多人将西洋参视为“清热”的一种手段，繁忙的Crcare药店的一名工作人员表示。香港铜锣湾购物区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样位于铜锣湾的余仁生中药店以 69 港元（8.8 美元）的价格出售盒装加工威斯康星人参。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该店的一位女售货员表示，威斯康星州品种因其“浓而不苦”的味道而受到追捧。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国应提高可支配收入、买家信任度以支撑经济：美国报告&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;不过，她补充说，由于世界气候波动，西洋参的采购变得越来越困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普发起贸易战是因为他认为中国的“不公平”贸易行为，例如限制市场准入、知识产权盗窃和强制技术转让。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国会研究服务处表示，与 2017 年相比，中国提高关税使 2018 年美国农产品出口额下降了 53%，至 90 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;就美中贸易关系问题联系的议员办公室没有回复电话或电子邮件，其中包括参议员马可·卢比奥以及国会议员布拉德·谢尔曼和迈克·加拉格尔。总部位于威斯康星州的美国人参种植者协会贸易组织也拒绝置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美中第一阶段贸易协议是“历史性失败”吗？接下来会怎样？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在马拉松县，Will Hsu 拥有 50 年历史的家族式人参农场已裁员 40%，种植面积也减少了几乎相同的程度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国关税和更高的生产成本他说，马拉松县的人参种植者已经允许加拿大和中国的人参种植者占据市场份额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许说，他已经“与每一位愿意听我讲话的美国参议员和代表进行了交谈”，但被告知“我们不是在跟中国说话”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hsu 的业务已将重点转向中国的“高端消费者”，他们每公斤支付约 200 美元至 400 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾和台湾台湾血统的许说，越南市场最终也可能会扩大。他补充说，正常价格约为贸易争端发生前当前水平的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐的农场现在通过为其他农民晒参、销售用品和修理设备来维持经营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang计划保留他的人参作物，并希望最终降低关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他计划继续要求立法者提供贸易战救济，但与此同时，他已向韩国和日本发出了第一批货物.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人参因其健康益处在这两个国家享有相似的声誉，但两国都缺乏中国的市场规模。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在为我们的产品寻找其他分销途径， ”他补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/一个>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hongkongers’ trust in Japanese food could drop if waste water discharge plan goes ahead, catering sector says, as lawmakers call for tough response]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3226695/hongkongers-trust-japanese-food-could-drop-if-waste-water-discharge-plan-goes-ahead-catering-sector?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 22:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/07/05/e86e54ab-acae-4a48-941c-0cb25f213f67_cd067dd9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;如果国家排放经过处理的废水，香港人可能会对日本食物失去兴趣该市的一些餐饮业领导人表示，随着立法者加大对采取强硬措施的呼声，该市的一些餐饮业领导人表示，福岛核电站已进入海洋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本媒体周三报道称，该计划最早可能在 8 月份开始实施，一天前，国际原子能机构 (IAEA) 表示该计划“对人类和环境的放射性影响可以忽略不计”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工厂处理过的水在 2011 年的地震和海啸中受损，将用海水稀释并通过水下隧道释放。预计需要长达 30 年的时间才能处理掉这 137 万吨污水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该市的日本领事馆为该计划进行了辩护，称废水已使用“先进液体处理系统”进行了处理”并强调它不会损害农业、海洋或其他食品。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国监管机构称福岛废水超过 70% 未达标&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是 omakase 行政主厨 Eric Chan Tempura Taki 餐厅表示，一旦该计划实施，餐厅对日本料理的需求可能会下降多达 50%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这将比新冠疫情更糟糕，”他说。 “这是因为围绕这个问题的普遍情绪，并不是所有的食客都会知道餐厅到底从哪里进口食材。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的餐厅 90% 的食材来自九州，九州是日本的一个地区。他补充说，位于日本以南，距离福岛近 1,500 公里（932 英里）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 表示，即使产品被证明是安全的，他也没有考虑从福岛县进口产品，理由是他的顾客对此表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;立法会食品安全及环境卫生委员会主席陈海恩周三呼吁采取严厉措施，例如在日本实施该计划之前从福岛及周边地区进口食品。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;“放射性水将对食物链产生广泛且不可逆转的影响……日本的自私举动将使香港花费大量资金来确保粮食安全，”她在电台节目中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ko日本食品进口商力生控股集团执行董事俊杰对香港供应商的未来表示担忧，如果该国继续将废水排入大海。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果最坏的情况发生发生这种情况，意味着水的排放正在影响整个生态，这将影响整个世界，而不仅仅是我们的行业，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但如果进口真的受到影响，生计和数千家餐厅的生存，香港数万名员工将面临生命危险，政府必须巧妙应对。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港仍对日本放射性污水排放计划保持警惕， despite UN go-ahead&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ko said Nic Sang Holdings had stopped importing food from Fukushima and the surrounding area since 2011, with most of its goods sold in Hong Kong coming from Tokyo, Osaka, Hokkaido and Kyushu.&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Entrepreneur Ruby Wan, who has lived in Japan for five years, said she focused on food safety checks rather than its origin when sourcing produce to sell, arguing Hong Kong and Japanese inspections were to a high standard.&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“General consumers might not have an idea of where different Japanese prefectures are,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wan added that she was aware the Hong Kong government had begun stricter inspections of goods from the country over the past few months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Ko said his company had first-hand experience of what it was currently like to fly fresh produce into Hong Kong almost every day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The checks are tighter now. We&#39;ve always had checks, but in the past, we&#39;ve never had to wait for results before departing,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If a product was randomly selected for radioactivity tests, importers often needed to wait hours to get test results back, taking up “a lot of time” for fresh food, Ko added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s Environment and Ecology Bureau earlier said a task force was reviewing the IAEA&#39;s final report. The body would also conduct further risk assessments and seek more information from Japan about the waste water disposal plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also vowed that any control measures for importing such goods would be based on “scientific and risk-based principles”, as well as considering factors such as the report and the opinions of mainland Chinese experts.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong team unveils cheap &#39;artificial mussels&#39; to check for nuclear pollution&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Appearing on the same radio show as his fellow lawmaker, Luk Chung-hung accused Japan of acting irresponsibly and urged the Hong Kong government to ban more products coming from the areas affected by the 2011 disaster.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The scope of the food ban should be wider. On top of that, Hong Kong should also consider countermeasures, be it on the economy or other aspects, to ask Japan to pay for the price of the water release,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taiwanese presidential hopeful William Lai stresses cross-strait status quo in bid to appease US, Beijing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3226674/taiwanese-presidential-hopeful-william-lai-stresses-cross-strait-status-quo-bid-appease-us-beijing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/b20892cf-a31a-4d3b-8b8d-19cbc0d5e36b_03c34da0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Taiwanese presidential hopeful and vice-president William Lai Ching-te has stressed to international media that he has no plans to declare independence for Taiwan if elected the island&#39;s next leader in January.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts said the move was aimed at reassuring the United States that he would not cause trouble, while at the same time telling Beijing he would adhere to the status quo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an opinion piece published by the Wall Street Journal on Tuesday, Lai touted pragmatism and consistency as his top priorities if elected president of the island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai, 63, was nominated in April by Taiwan&#39;s ruling party, the independence-leaning Democratic Progressive Party, to run for the island&#39;s top post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I will support the cross-strait status quo – which is in the best interests of both the Republic of China, as Taiwan is formally known, and the international community,” he wrote.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I will never rule out the possibility of dialogue without preconditions, based on the principles of reciprocity and dignity,” he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How William Lai&#39;s &#39;deep green&#39; Taiwan politics became a red line for Beijing&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In the opinion piece, titled “My Plan to Preserve Peace in the Taiwan Strait”, Lai also offered to implement a “four-pillar plan for peace” to address the challenges the island faces and ensure continued stability in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The plan includes building up Taiwan&#39;s deterrence in the face of growing military threats from Beijing, ensuring the island remains a hi-tech powerhouse and a secure link in the supply chain, forming partnerships with democracies around the world and promoting steady and principled cross-strait leadership.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite political and economic challenges from Beijing, Lai said he would commit to working towards peace and stability “for the people of Taiwan and the international community”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A former dentist, Lai&#39;s political experience was forged in the southern DPP stronghold of Tainan, where sentiment leans towards independence. He has long been regarded as “deep green” – a reference to the more radical, pro-independence wing of the party.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When he was appointed the island&#39;s premier in 2017, Lai described himself as “a pragmatic worker for Taiwan independence”, raising concerns in the US and the international community that he might declare independence if elected leader.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taiwanese analysts said that by publishing the article on July 4 – American Independence Day – Lai aimed to tell the US there would be nothing to worry about if he won the top post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Lai knows clearly that previously identifying himself as &#39;a pragmatic worker for Taiwan independence&#39; could bring uncertainties to his race,” said Li Da-jung, a professor of international relations and strategic studies at Tamkang University in New Taipei.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li said Lai must repeatedly clarify his stance to assure the US he would adhere to the policies of outgoing Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen and maintain the cross-strait status quo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US, like most countries, does not officially recognise Taiwan as an independent state, but it opposes any unilateral change to the status quo by force.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Washington warned independence-leaning Chen Shui-bian not to cause trouble when he was elected president in 2000 and repeated the same message to Tsai when she challenged Ma Ying-jeou of the Kuomintang, then the ruling party, in the island&#39;s 2012 presidential race.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing regards Taiwan as its territory and has not renounced the use of force to bring it under its control.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li said although Washington, which views Beijing as its rival, does not want Taiwan to be taken under mainland China&#39;s control, it also does not want to see the island provoke a cross-strait war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li said this explained why Lai published the article in the Wall Street Journal to try to allay US fears over his stance on independence.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Super shock waves&#39;: Taiwan People&#39;s Party may shake up politics, poll shows&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“He also wanted to send the same message to the international community and Taiwan&#39;s like-minded partners to assure them there would be no changes if elected,” Li said, adding Lai also hoped to use that message to win support from neutral voters in Taiwan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It remains to be seen if such a message would convince the US and voters here that he would not bring Taiwan to a dangerous state,” Li said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Kung-yi, head of the Taiwan International Strategic Study Society, a Taipei think tank, said Lai&#39;s message was also directed at Beijing, which had repeatedly warned that pro-independence forces would fail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Beijing has long seen Lai as a deep-green figure and it is unlikely it would pay heed to what he touted,” Wang said, adding Lai must modify his stance on independence to win trust from both Beijing and Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After all, the US is seeking to alleviate its rivalry with Beijing, and it would not want the next leader of Taiwan to adopt a confrontational policy towards the mainland,” Wang said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 22:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese Apple Vision Pro suppliers stay largely quiet on report Apple has slashed initial production target]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3226675/chinese-apple-vision-pro-suppliers-stay-largely-quiet-report-apple-has-slashed-initial-production?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/0995a9e9-7443-488f-acce-6657358744e4_5adc36a3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;There has been scant response from Apple and Chinese suppliers of its Vision Pro headset after a Financial Times report this week that the US tech giant is cutting planned output of the US$3,499 augmented-reality device by more than half.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The California-based tech giant has slashed planned production of the new headset from an initial goal of 1 million units for the first year to 400,000 in 2024 due to complex design issues, according to the FT report, which cited unidentified sources from Apple and Chinese assembler Luxshare Precision Industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Investors in Apple suppliers closely watch production targets, as any change in order volume can influence, or even decide, business performance in the near-term. Luxshare closed 0.94 per cent lower in Shenzhen on Wednesday, and is up 3.82 per cent for the week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple and Luxshare Precision did not immediately respond to requests for comments on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Which mainland Chinese firms are part of Apple&#39;s Vision Pro supply chain?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Suzhou-based electronics firm Bozhon Precision Industry Technology, which is involved in the assembly of the Apple Vision Pro, said it had not been informed of any production cuts, according to a report by Chinese newspaper Securities Daily. However, a company official told the Post that it does not comment on such matters as client information is confidential.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bozhon shares fell 0.56 per cent on Wednesday, giving it a loss of 0.43 per cent for the week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to a report by Chinese media outlet ThePaper.com, Luxhare Precision said it could not comment on production plans as the information is confidential.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is set to become the manufacturing hub for the Apple headset, and hopes were high that production of the US tech giant&#39;s first major new product in a decade would open up a new source of revenue for Chinese manufacturers. Global demand for hit products such as Apple&#39;s iPhone helped spur the emergence of assemblers such as Taiwanese company Foxconn Technology Group, formally known as Hon Hai Precision Industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple CEO Tim Cook said the Apple Vision Pro, which allows users to experience digital content such as games and 3D videos overlaid onto any physical space, marked “the beginning of a new era for computing”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analysts, however, have been cautious about short-term market reaction to the new headset.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Apple has failed to “demonstrate the need to use the Vision Pro in everyday life”, and it remains to be seen “whether Apple can provide more attractive apps, content and an ecosystem before launch”, said Kuo Ming-chi, a TF International Securities analyst known for his accurate assessment of Apple&#39;s business, shortly after launch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dan Ives, managing director of Wedbush Securities, expects initial shipments to be roughly 150,000 units for the first year, and 1 million units in the second year at lower price points.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Financial Times report said Apple was only asking for parts for 130,000 to 150,000 units in the first year from two of its Chinese component suppliers, while plans for a cheaper version have been pushed back.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 22:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Popular Hong Kong singer-songwriter Coco Lee dies aged 48 after ‘suicide attempt’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3226686/popular-hong-kong-singer-songwriter-coco-lee-dies-aged-48?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 22:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/e9a14e9d-7385-436a-87a9-382a51f6462b_e64e8b88.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong singer-songwriter Coco Lee died on Wednesday after trying to take her own life at the weekend, her sisters announced on social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a Facebook Post, Lee&#39;s sisters Carol and Nancy revealed that the celebrity, who had been diagnosed with depression a few years ago, had attempted suicide at home on Sunday. Lee, 48, had been in a coma since then, they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her family expressed their gratitude to healthcare staff and fans for their support.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They also thanked the medical team for their efforts to save her life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sisters said their biggest responsibility now was to take care of their elderly mother and asked for everyone&#39;s prayers and space to heal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More to follow...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you have suicidal thoughts, or you know someone who is, help is available. For Hong Kong, dial +852 2896 0000 for The Samaritans or +852 2382 0000 for Suicide Prevention Services. In the US, call the 988 Suicide &amp; Crisis Lifeline at 988 or +1 800 273 8255. For a list of other nations&#39; helplines, see this .&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 22:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Okinawa governor Denny Tamaki traces historic Chinese links with visit to Beijing cemetery]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3226690/okinawa-governor-denny-tamaki-traces-historic-chinese-links-visit-beijing-cemetery?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 22:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/85b95d9b-a447-417d-96e5-c891db291706_39914f79.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Okinawa&#39;s governor Denny Tamaki visited a cemetery in Beijing on Tuesday to pay his respects to people from the Ryukyu Islands, who were buried there hundreds of years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cemetery in the city&#39;s Tongzhou district includes several graves of people from the historical Kingdom of Ryukyu, which included Okinawa island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tamaki will also visit Fujian, a coastal province with strong historic links to the Ryukyu island chain, during his trip to China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He is visiting with a delegation from the Japanese Association for the Promotion of International Trade, which is headed by former Japanese foreign minister Yohei Kono.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Wednesday, the delegation met Chinese Premier Li Qiang, who told the visitors that China looks forward to strengthening economic and cultural exchanges and cooperation with Japan, according to state broadcaster CCTV. He added that the two countries should be partners rather than threatening each other.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an interview with the Chinese tabloid Global Times before his visit, Tamaki said: “The long-standing history of friendly exchanges between Okinawa and China dates back over 600 years.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China stokes tensions, opposition to US bases in Japan&#39;s Okinawa&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“In 1997, the Okinawa prefecture established a friendly relationship with Fujian province, taking friendly relations to a new level.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trade and exchanges between Ryukyu and China flourished from the 14th century onward, and the kingdom became a tributary state to the Ming dynasty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ryukyuans, including officials and students, were sent to study in the Chinese capital and the kingdom adopted a similar governmental system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Japanese influence grew in subsequent centuries before Ryukyu was annexed by Japan in 1879 and became the Okinawa prefecture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last month Chinese President Xi Jinping raised eyebrows by discussing the kingdom&#39;s links to Fujian, where he used to be governor and party chief.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When I was working in Fuzhou [the capital of Fujian], I was aware of the Ryukyu-kan [diplomats&#39; house] and the Ryukyu cemetery there, and that Fujian had a deep connection with Ryukyu,” Xi said during a visit to a national history archive in early June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although Tamaki welcomed the comments as evidence of Xi&#39;s willingness to develop ties with the Ryukyu Islands, some Japanese media outlets expressed concern, saying it indicated China might play up the Okinawa issue in future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some Chinese academics have suggested that China should support autonomy for the islands, or even separatist movements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Okinawa is just 110km (68 miles) from Taiwan and has a heavy US military presence, which means that it would be a potential battleground in the event of conflict between China and the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Okinawa prefecture also governs the Japanese-controlled Diaoyu Islands – also known as the Senkakus – which are the cause of a long-standing territorial dispute between Beijing and Tokyo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tamaki has been a long-standing critic of the US military presence on Okinawa and has pushed for a reduction in troop numbers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Global Times interview, he said the rights of Okinawa&#39;s residents had been violated by a “military-first” approach.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also alluded to the bloody Second World War battle between US and Japanese troops on Okinawa in which around a quarter of the civilian population died, saying that “all Okinawans have a heartfelt expectation that &#39;Okinawa must never again become a battlefield&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tamaki also stressed that a war over Taiwan must be avoided at all costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese woman urged to &#39;buy&#39; Diaoyus after snapping up Japan island&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The governments of Japan and the US should make efforts to ease tensions, establish trust through peaceful diplomacy and dialogue, and take necessary measures to prevent any unforeseen incidents,” he told the newspaper.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[Tamaki] advocates friendly relations with China and has a strong local Okinawan identity, which is the reason why we pay attention to him,” Lian Degui, a researcher from Shanghai Institute for International Studies, said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he said the island&#39;s government was not able to do much about the US military presence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Because the US and Japanese governments have obligations under the Security Treaty between the United States and Japan, there is no way [Okinawa] can fundamentally change the fact of US-Japan military cooperation,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Xinlu Liang&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 22:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[France’s Macron faces backlash after calls to ‘cut off’ social media following riots from police shooting of 17-year-old]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3226678/frances-macron-faces-backlash-after-calls-cut-social-media-following-riots-police-shooting-17-year?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.07.05 21:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/07/05/5b518fe9-542e-4b6d-b8a2-4854dea3174a_bd5f4841.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;President Emmanuel Macron&#39;s government faced a backlash on Wednesday after the centrist leader called for powers to “cut off” social media in case of widespread violence like riots over the past week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have to think about the social networks, about the bans we&#39;ll have to put in place. When things get out of control, we might need to be able to regulate or cut them off,” Macron told a meeting of mayors on Tuesday according to media reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Macron and his ministers have singled out platforms like Snapchat, TikTok and encrypted messenger Telegram for their role in spreading images of the nights of violence following the June 27 police shooting of a 17-year-old teenager, Nahel M.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When [social media] becomes a tool for organising or for attempting to kill, it&#39;s a real problem,” Macron said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is worrying, when we reach the point of saying the only solution is cutting off social networks, you ask yourself what point we&#39;ve reached” in France, Greens leader Marine Tondelier told broadcaster France Inter on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other opposition politicians from left and right had attacked the proposal, with hard-left France Unbowed chief Mathilde Panot responding to Macron in a tweet with “Ok Kim Jong-Un”, referring to the leader of sealed-off North Korea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cut off social networks? Like China, Iran or North Korea? Even if it&#39;s a provocation to distract attention, it&#39;s in very bad taste,” conservative parliamentary chief Olivier Marleix also wrote on Twitter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some voices were even raised within Macron&#39;s parliamentary camp, with MP Eric Bothorel writing that to cut off social networks would mean “giving up on the idea that democracy is stronger than the tools turned against it. It would be a mistake.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Digital Transition Minister Jean-Noel Barrot&#39;s office on Wednesday told France Inter that cutting off social networks was “not on the table”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instead, the government wants to bring together lawmakers to discuss how best to alter an existing social-network bill currently under debate, cabinet spokesman Olivier Veran said after ministers met on Wednesday morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A working group would examine possible “legal tools” and “precisions” that could be added, he told reporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That could mean suspending features … for example some platforms have geolocation features allowing young people to meet at a certain spot, showing [violent] scenes and how to start fires,” Veran said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That&#39;s an appeal to organise hateful acts in public and we&#39;d have the authority to suspend it”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 05 Jul 2023 21:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>