<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China pledges support for Cambodia’s changing of the guard in meeting with Hun Sen and son]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231000/chinas-foreign-minister-wang-yi-pledges-support-cambodias-changing-guard-meeting-hun-sen-and-son?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 14:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/0114f89a-f09e-4cce-92c5-27d223575feb_40f6462e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中方愿同柬埔寨新政府一道，构建密切、高质量的关系”，外交部长王毅周日在会见柬埔寨下一任领导人洪马奈时表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，王毅祝贺执政的柬埔寨人民党在上个月的国家大选中取得“压倒性胜利”中国外交部声明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“由60多个国家代表组成的国际观察团一致认为，这次选举是公平、透明、依法的，选举结果反映了共同的愿望”。王毅在金边与即将上任的首相洪马内和即将离任的领导人洪森会谈时表示，“一些外部势力的喧嚣与人民的选择相比显得黯然失色。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;王毅表示，中方赞赏洪森为建设中柬关系、带领国家由乱走向稳定、由贫困走向繁荣作出的历史性贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金边越来越依赖中国的援助和投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国也重视柬埔寨作为东盟成员的战略意义。两国在南海存在争议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据统计，中国去年是柬埔寨最大的贸易伙伴，贸易额达116亿美元，其中中国出口额占比高达89.38%。柬埔寨海关和税务部门。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在美国制衡之际，柬埔寨洪森希望“回到北京轨道”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;美国长期以来声称柬埔寨云朗海军基地已成为海外前哨基地王毅是自洪森宣布将在任职 22 年后辞职以来第一位访问柬埔寨的外国外交官，这为他的长子铺平了道路。洪马内将于8月22日组建新政府。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中方愿同柬埔寨新政府密切联系，推动中柬新时代全面战略伙伴关系迈上新台阶，打造“高质量发展”据中国外交部声明，王说，“高水平、高标准的中柬共同体”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[中国将]坚定支持柬埔寨维护国家利益和民族尊严，坚定支持柬埔寨柬埔寨外交部在周日的一份声明中表示，中国支持“柬埔寨的主权、新兴政府的领导力和发展道路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柬埔寨外交部在周日的一份声明中表示，中国支持“柬埔寨的主权、新兴政府的领导力和发展道路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;据柬埔寨外交部称，洪马内对中国提供 Covid-19 疫苗以及对柬埔寨社会经济发展和基础设施的帮助表示感谢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国外交部表示，洪马内重申了中国愿意加强与中国的战略协调，承诺促进农业、制造业、经贸投资以及旅游、教育等务实领域合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;柬埔寨担心中国“一带一路”倡议加强监控&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;根据中方声明，洪马内强调政府在一个中国政策以及在台湾、新疆、西藏和香港问题上不干涉中国内政的“立场不变”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅会见周日，柬埔寨外长巴速坤会见洪马奈，讨论洪马奈对北京进行正式访问、出席在南宁举行的第二十届中国—东盟博览会、中国—东盟商务与投资峰会以及第三届“一带一路”高峰论坛的事宜。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 15:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US ‘Goon Squad’ officers admit racist torture of 2 black men]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231004/us-goon-squad-officers-admit-racist-torture-2-black-men?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 15:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/fcdab23d-f004-40a3-93e8-07d1e884789d_c7d786ce.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;预计六名前执法人员将于周一在美国认罪。最近在一项相关的联邦民权案件中承认有罪后，在种族主义袭击中折磨了两名黑人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官表示，密西西比州的警察都是白人，他们给自己起了个绰号“Goon Squad”，因为他们愿意过度使用武力并掩盖真相，包括以受害者嘴中枪告终的袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一月份，警察在没有搜查令的情况下进入一所房屋，给两名男子戴上手铐，并用电击枪袭击了两名男子、性玩具和其他物品。在 90 分钟的酷刑过程中，警察用种族歧视的语言嘲笑他们。然后，他们设计了一种掩盖手段，包括向其中一名男子植入毒品和枪支，这可能会让他入狱多年。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英国最大的警察部队“存在制度上的种族主义和性别歧视”&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;预计这些警官将对国家指控认罪，包括入室盗窃、妨碍司法公正和串谋阻碍起诉，以及对扣动扳机的警官进行严重攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法庭记录显示，男子达成了个人认罪协议，其中包括 5 至 30 年徒刑。州指控的服刑时间将与他们在 8 月 3 日认罪后预计 11 月在联邦法院接受的判决同时进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些人包括五名前兰金县副警长，包括布雷特·麦卡尔平 (Brett McAlpin)、亨特 (Hunter)、埃尔沃德、克里斯蒂安·戴德蒙、杰弗里·米德尔顿和丹尼尔·奥普代克，以及里奇兰市的一名警官约书亚·哈特菲尔德。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃尔沃德承认，他将枪塞进詹金斯嘴里，并在“模拟处决”中扣动了扳机。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;兰金县警察的公然暴力行为曝光后，一些居民指出了他们所说的警察文化，让警察可以全权滥用权力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者调查发现，自 2019 年以来，一些警察至少与黑人发生了四次暴力冲突，导致两人死亡、另一人持久受伤。司法部于 2 月份对此案启动了民权调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;兰金县以白人为主的郊区是白人逃离首都杰克逊的几个目的地之一，杰克逊是其中一名白人的所在地。文件称，美国主要城市中黑人居民的比例最高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文件称，官员警告詹金斯和帕克“回到杰克逊或珠江‘他们的那边’”。&lt;/p>;&lt;法庭文件显示，两名受害者迈克尔·科里·詹金斯 (Michael Corey Jenkins) 和埃迪·特雷尔·帕克 (Eddie Terrell Parker) 成为目标，因为一名白人邻居抱怨两名黑人男子与一名白人妇女住在家里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帕克是一名童年房主克里斯蒂·沃利的朋友。她从 15 岁起就瘫痪了，帕克正在帮助照顾她。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他是个幸运儿。每次我需要他的时候，他都会出现，”沃利在二月份的采访中说道。 “有时候我一个人住在这里，我不知道自己要做什么。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帕克和詹金斯已经离开密西西比州，不确定他们是否会回到密西西比州。状态较长一段时间。他们感到安慰的是，司法系统的至少一部分似乎发挥了作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过一点点斗争，经过大量斗争，你就能说出真相，”帕克一天后说道。宣布认罪。 “真相总是胜过你编造的任何谎言或故事。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在香港成为黑人和非洲人是什么感觉&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;詹金斯因受伤而说话仍然困难。枪声撕裂了他的舌头，打断了他的下巴，然后离开了脖子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“就正义而言，我知道我们会得到它，”詹金斯说。 “但我认为这可能需要更长的时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这些警官对联邦指控认罪后，司法部民权部门负责人克里斯汀·克拉克 (Kristen Clarke) 表示，他们在社区内煽动了不信任。本来应该服务的。密西西比州总检察长林恩·菲奇 (Lynn Fitch) 表示不会容忍滥用权力。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 15:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong police investigating 2 burglaries in Kowloon and on outlying island, amid 50 per cent rise in break-ins this year]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3231006/hong-kong-police-investigating-2-burglaries-kowloon-and-outlying-island-amid-50-cent-rise-break-ins?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 14:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/3236a7ce-a018-4c6f-8786-de74e8728003_67b531d4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港警方正调查两起发生在九龙市中心及离岛的入室盗窃案今年入室盗窃案增加了 50%。警方周一表示，窃贼在前一天袭击了两起不同的案件，其中一起涉及一名入侵者在租户及其家人回家前不到 20 分钟，他设法带着 10 块手表从大屿山愉景湾的一间公寓逃走。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些手表估计价值约 80,000 港元（10,230 美元）。据警方发言人称，总数。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港第一季度被捕的游客人数增加了三倍&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周日晚上 9 点 09 分，警员被传唤到愉景湾道的公寓52岁的住户回家后发现房间被洗劫一空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“监控录像显示，窃贼从窗户爬进公寓的主卧室，并于8.50左右从原路逃走。下午，”一位熟悉案件的消息人士称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方搜查了该地区，但没有逮捕任何人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;嫌疑人据信年龄在 40 岁至 50 岁之间，高约 1.7 米（5.6 英尺）。当时他戴着眼镜，身穿长袖衬衫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两小时后，警方又接到九龙一名44岁女子的入室盗窃报案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;晚上11时14分，她回到红磡黄埔花园家中，发现单位门开着，屋子被洗劫一空。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“初步调查发现，两条金项链和七对金手镯价值不菲。”发言人说：“该案共价值10万港元，连同16,800港元被盗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚未逮捕与此案有关的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方已处理572宗入室盗窃举报今年 1 月至 6 月期间，比 2022 年同期记录的 381 起案件增加了 50.1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;今年首 4 个月，香港盗窃案件猛增近 40%&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;据警方称，今年上半年，警员破获了 165 起案件并逮捕了 147 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方表示，入室盗窃报告数量比上半年下降了 27% 2019年，疫情爆发前，入室盗窃案件呈好转趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“入室盗窃案件的增加主要归因于涉及住宅的案件。警方上周五在一份声明中表示，据信窃贼会在人们恢复工作、上学和旅行时袭击无人看管的房屋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提醒居民正确锁好门窗并采取措施。防盗措施，以及不要将贵重物品放在家里。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 14:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong court grants bail to man charged over slapping 13-year-old boy during lesson at Islamic learning centre]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3230999/hong-kong-court-grants-bail-man-charged-over-slapping-13-year-old-boy-during-lesson-islamic-learning?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 13:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/192b1bdc-f07f-4e3f-b020-fd6321312bea_52a16c9e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周一，香港法院批准一名据称扇了 13 岁男孩耳光的失业男子保释本月早些时候，一名 35 岁的男孩在伊斯兰学习中心做志愿者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;35 岁的沙赫扎德·汗 (Shahzad Khan) 在东部法院出庭，面临与涉嫌袭击有关的非法和恶意伤人指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;在首席法官 Ivy Chui Yee-mei 询问后，检察官证实他是该宗教中心的一名志愿者，而不是一名受雇教师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可汗被指控在宗教中心打了这名少年耳光。据警方称，受害人因学习《古兰经》而导致眼睛受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检方申请休庭六周，以便警方进一步调查并获取受害人的医疗报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;崔先生批准了保释申请，但条件是汗不得与受害人及其姐姐联系，也不得返回中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他被要求支付 50,000 港元（6,395 美元）并向警方报到 3 次一周以获得保释。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港宗教教师被控在课堂上掌掴 13 岁男孩&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;法庭指控单显示 Khan 具有巴基斯坦血统，并持有担保书表格 – 一份临时移民文件，授予在香港居住但不得工作的权利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;听证会已延期至 9 月 29 日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方早些时候表示，有一份报告受害人家属于8月10日提出起诉，被告于次日被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;眼科专家发现男孩视网膜脱离，呈180度撕裂，并表示他需要两次手术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;这名少年已经接受了一次长达六个小时的手术，另一次手术计划在六个月内进行。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fire sale: Chinese teen who sells inherited US$139,000 property at half price to buy motorcycle has sale cancelled after mother’s legal action]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3230796/fire-sale-chinese-teen-sells-inherited-us139000-property-half-price-buy-motorcycle-has-sale?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/f3a50503-441e-4fe9-b70d-b48e5fb95cda_3c534849.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国一名18岁男子出售价值100万元的继承财产（139,000 美元）半价购买一辆摩托车，随后家人采取法律行动取消了这笔交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国中部河南省的一家法院审查了这名绰号为“小花”的青少年与两名房地产经纪人之间的交易据《Dacankao》报道，化名小武和小阳的小华发现这不公平并取消了出售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在父母拒绝给他买摩托车后，小华决定出售他从祖父那里继承的财产。 。在没有通知父母的情况下，他联系了经纪人小武。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名少年同意以市值一半的价格将房产以 52 万元（72,000 美元）的价格出售给小武。小武随后将其转售给另一位经纪人小阳，金额不详，但获利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当小华的母亲得知此事后，对这两名经纪人产生了怀疑，怀疑他们欺骗了这名少年。当她未能说服两名经纪人取消交易时，她向当地法院提起诉讼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法官何猛表示，小华应该为自己幼稚的决定负责。但母亲坚称这是不公平的交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法院审查了青少年与小武之间签署的合同以及谈话中的证据，向法院证明了这笔交易是合法完成的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，法官考虑到该青少年与经纪人之间的年龄和经验差异，并表示后者了解该房产的市场价值，诱使不成熟的青少年以低得多的价格出售该房产。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“小吴占了小华的便宜，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;法院推翻了交易，小华重新获得了房产的所有权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在撰写本文时，该故事的微博新闻已吸引了2000多条评论，其中许多人批评了这名少年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人说：“这是一个正确的判决，但我仍然认为男孩应该为自己的错误付出代价。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一人补充道：“他一定是被宠坏了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年 5 月，中国东部的一名男子想要偿还 31 万元（43,000 美元）的债务，于是卖掉了一套房子。以150万元继承价值200万元财产，后被债权人起诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2月，北京一男子在离婚协议书中将价值1200万元的财产赠与妻子； &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Myanmar crisis reflects East Timor’s ‘difficult balancing act’ in Asean accession bid: analysts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3230870/myanmar-crisis-reflects-east-timors-difficult-balancing-act-asean-accession-bid-analysts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/12/233f1393-d465-4a05-80ee-80f186f62c24_65a1d746.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;东帝汶表示，如果解决缅甸危机的努力失败，它可能会重新考虑加入东盟分析人士表示，这反映了该国在处理欧盟规范以及加入该集团的准备方面所采取的“艰难的平衡行动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理夏纳纳·古斯芒上周表示，东帝汶是亚洲最年轻的实行民主的国家2002年独立后，不能接受任何地方的军政府政权，也不能忽视缅甸的侵犯人权行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果东盟不能说服缅甸军政府，东帝汶将不会加入东盟”前独立斗士古斯芒表示，他的政党赢得了该国 5 月份的议会选举。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰国与缅甸会谈是破坏东盟中心地位的“无耻企图”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; 2021 年 2 月政变后，缅甸国防军镇压人民，但东南亚国家联盟 (东盟) 因其在追究军政府责任方面反应不佳且无效而受到批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管前景光明为了本月举行选举，军方以安全原因和该国持续发生的暴力事件为由推迟了这一行动。它延长了政变后实施的紧急状态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但东帝汶总统若泽·拉莫斯-奥尔塔周一表示，帝力加入东盟是“命运”，并指出“期待东盟全面解决复杂的缅甸危机是不公平的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雅加达战略与国际研究中心（CSIS）研究员穆罕默德·瓦法·卡里斯马（Muhammad Waffaa Kharisma）表示，古斯芒的言论很好地反映了东帝汶的现状准备加入东盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;穆罕默德·瓦法指出，东帝汶成为东盟正式成员还需要时间，他表示帝力“原则性强的民主、强有力的声音以及对民主和人权的倡导” “权利”可能会因东盟的规范（例如不干涉原则）而受到挫败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[该]原则仍然被如此严格地理解，”他说，并补充说古斯芒的评论也反映出日益增长的随着帝力距离成为东盟第 11 个成员国越来越近，人们担心是否有空间“发出民主声音”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十多年来，帝力一直寻求加入东盟，并最终获得最后批准。十一月。鉴于东帝汶仍处于国家建设过程中，该集团早些时候曾担心东帝汶是否有能力成为正式成员。 2021 年东帝汶的人均国内生产总值为 3,336 美元，使其成为亚洲最贫穷的国家之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 5 月于印度尼西亚举行的东盟峰会上，该集团最终确定了一份路线图，概述了各项步骤，包括政治措施、安全、经济和社会文化领域 - 让东帝汶成为正式成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帝力必须签署 66 项关键协议，包括东盟货物贸易协议和东盟全面投资协议，以获得正式成员资格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加州州立大学东湾分校政治学教授玛丽亚·奥尔图斯特表示，东帝汶在加入东盟方面面临着艰难的平衡，并指出这不是第一次当时帝力曾表达对缅甸人权和民主的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;注意到古斯芒在 2004 年呼吁释放民选文职领导人昂山素季的软禁，奥托斯特表示帝力有一段历史“要么以反对东盟的方式支持民主，要么采取更务实的做法”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“拉莫斯-奥尔塔采取了后一种做法，”奥托斯特说，并补充说，为了赢得东盟的支持作为会员国，帝力缓和了其人权声明，例如 2004 年，拉莫斯-奥尔塔对军政府当时的民主转型表示同情。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;东盟中的东帝汶可能会使该集团“更容易受到大国的攻击”&lt;/h3但奥托斯特说，帝力还必须应对国内舆论，例如四月份，民间社会要求拉莫斯-奥尔塔撤回对军政府代表的邀请，并邀请流亡民族团结政府的代表NUG，由政变期间被赶下台的议员组成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;NUG代表于7月访问了帝力，引起了缅甸军政府的抗议，“所以这对于东帝汶的外交政策来说确实是一个艰难的平衡” ”，奥托斯特说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东盟对其对待缅甸的态度仍然存在分歧，这意味着一些成员国可能会以此为“理由”反对东帝汶正式加入东盟，她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;东帝汶加入东盟一直受到关注，包括新加坡和老挝在内的一些成员国指出，东帝汶缺乏发展可能会影响区域经济一体化。新加坡和东盟其他创始成员国此前也曾表示，该集团在 1990 年代末从 5 个成员国扩大到 10 个成员国，使该集团变得更加笨重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南于 1995 年加入东盟，老挝和缅甸随后于 1995 年加入。 1997 年和 1999 年的柬埔寨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，穆罕默德·瓦法表示，印度尼西亚作为今年的东盟主席国可能会指出解决缅甸冲突的持续努力，并再次强调东帝汶最终加入东盟的重要性&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰国与缅甸军政府的非正式会谈暴露了东盟分歧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;雅加达哈比比中心的研究员马布达·哈伦尼萨·法吉里拉·西迪克 (Mabda Haerunnisa Fajrilla Sidiq) 表示，古斯芒的观点不一定得到其他领导人的认同，例如正如拉莫斯-奥尔塔所说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“那些持类似观点的人肯定不想为了获得加入资格而牺牲十年的辛勤工作，”她说，并补充说，长期以来，东盟成员资格一直是东方国家中的一员。东帝汶的外交政策优先事项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然经济和地缘政治考虑很重要，但“让东帝汶领导人习惯东盟达成共识的方式”也很重要，她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“妥协是是东盟决策的核心，这意味着协议往往并不理想。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Global Impact: US declares ‘emergency’ on sensitive tech in latest plans to restrict investment on China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3230970/global-impact-us-declares-emergency-sensitive-tech-latest-plans-restrict-investment-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 14:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/14/e4f189f6-8f3d-4150-91c1-812a5465e430_21bec6ef.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;《全球影响力》是一份每周精选的时事通讯，其中包含源自中国的新闻主题，具有重大意义对世界各地新闻播音员的宏观影响。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美中关系的现状和未来状况通常是通过入主白宫的政府所采取的行动来看待的。当然，中国政府的政策同样重要，但是，我们还是坚持华盛顿吧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前总统唐纳德·特朗普发起的贸易战，以及他的国务院对中国大陆和香港的诸多制裁本届政府期间，香港政府官员在该法案颁布多年后，继续使双边关系紧张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登政府在保留许多特朗普时代对华措施的同时，开始了一项战略：与印度-太平洋地区的亲密盟友进行密切接触，并向许多传统上不愿选边站的国家（印度和东南亚大部分国家）示好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被称为“奥库斯”和“印太”的三边军事伙伴关系太平洋经济框架（IPEF）是美国总统乔·拜登制定的众多举措中的两项，用政府的话说，这些举措旨在“塑造（中国）运作的战略环境”。北京有一个更简单的描述：“遏制”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但自从共和党控制众议院以来，国会——美国政府的另一个喧闹部门——更多地对拜登政府进行制衡。去年中期选举后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院的首要行动之一是成立中国共产党特别委员会，这标志着众议院外交事务委员会、国会及行政部门委员会等其他既定机构中国和美中经济与安全审查委员会的态度不够强硬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新委员会迄今已举行六次听证会，其中一些在晚上举行，目的是吸引更广泛的受众，主题包括“中国共产党中共正在进行的维吾尔族种族灭绝”和“如何反击中共的经济侵略”。该委员会的首次听证会由前副国家安全顾问马修·波廷格 (Matthew Pottinger) 主持，他在黄金时段活动期间声称，中国政府“最害怕的是自己的人民”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;预计拜登投资的影响将“有限”对中国量子技术的限制&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;虽然听证会不一定会转化为与拜登目标相抵触的法律，但它们可以在公共场合给政府官员带来巨大压力，例如密苏里州共和党众议员布莱恩·卢特克迈尔 (Blaine Luetkemeyer) ，指责美国商务部负责出口管理的助理部长西娅·罗兹曼·肯德勒 (Thea Rozman Kendler) 没有充分限制对中国的高科技出口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院委员会对中国的单一关注并没有限制其他国家对中国的出口。 ，历史悠久的委员会涵盖这一领域。特朗普政府期间负责国际贸易的商务部官员纳扎克·尼卡赫塔尔 (Nazak Nikakhtar) 今年 5 月向参议院外交关系委员会表示，大多数部门官员的心态仍然是“亲商”，她呼吁“彻底的文化转变”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;这种压力使得拜登在起草与中国相关的举措时更难留手，例如周三宣布的限制风险投资和私募股权投资进入中国高科技市场的行政命令。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;为何称中国国家主席习近平为“独裁者”的拜登会想要放轻松？他知道北京几乎肯定会采取报复措施，最终使他的工作变得更加复杂。典型的例子：北京上个月决定对用于制造半导体、通信设备和太阳能电池板的关键原材料实施出口管制。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国的科技限制是否会终结与中国改善关系的道路？&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;众议院委员会并不局限于通常由商务部、州政府和国防部管理的事务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约州北部的一所私立学校阿尔弗雷德大学决定关闭孔子学院该委员会启动了对其价值数百万美元的五角大楼高超音速导弹研究合同的审查后，该研究所。美国的国防授权法案 (NDAA) 禁止五角大楼资助设有孔子学院的高等教育机构，而孔子学院至少部分由北京教育部的一个部门资助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当听证会不举行时足以迫使拜登对中国采取更强硬的策略，国会可以以轻松的否决多数通过一些法律。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;例如，拜登无法阻止一项旨在禁止所有中国进口的法案中国新疆维吾尔自治区的这项措施由于供应链的复杂性而令美国海关官员头疼，并且让一些分析人士摸不着头脑，因为海关数据早期表明该立法并不有效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;拜登感谢国会领导人和该法案的起草者在这项两党压倒性的立法中发挥的“领导作用”，但他没有像总统有时对备受瞩目的法案那样举行签字仪式，这可能是矛盾的迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;拜登可能热衷或不热衷的数百项与中国相关的法案，包括一项可能关闭香港政府驻美国三个代表处的法案，已提交国会审议。该法案尚未在众议院或参议院进行投票，因此尚不清楚它是否会最终考验国会和白宫之间的意愿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它可能，然而，最终成为《国防授权法案》中的一项措施，立法者有时会提出一些与中国相关的条款，以提高其成为法律的可能性。今年的《国防授权法案》必须获得通过才能保持美国军事经费，其中有许多旨在对抗北京的条款，包括要求评估对中国的燃料封锁以及在台湾遭到袭击时的其他军事选择。&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;中国猛烈抨击美国在世贸组织的“双重标准”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当拜登本周签署《美国与台湾21世纪贸易倡议》时，这种不确定的国会与行政当局的意愿测试得到了充分展示《第一协议实施法案》，在两党的大力支持下在众议院和参议院获得通过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案旨在让国会在拜登政府的美国贸易代表办公室打算在其美国领导下达成的进一步协议中拥有发言权。 -台湾21世纪贸易倡议。它还需要通过法律才能实施此类协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登不情愿的一个更明显的例子是，他在签署后立即发表了一份声明，声称有权决定政府有义务分享什么内容与国会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;敬请关注结果如何。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;60 秒追赶&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;乔·拜登计划对美国在中国的投资实施新限制，包括香港在内，宣布对敏感科技采取“紧急状态”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国科技投资限制令中国严重担忧，本已萎缩的外国直接投资看起来吸引力更小&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国的限制措施针对的是中国公司，但随着科技战升级，双边关系可能成为最大受害者&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港政府称美国对中国科技的投资禁令“不合理”，但专家们对对该市初创企业的影响存在分歧&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国乔·拜登宣布限制措施后，芯片行业呼吁“至关重要”地进入中国市场&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师表示，美国新的投资限制对中国目标半导体、量子计算和人工智能行业的影响有限&lt;/p>;&lt; h3>;深入探讨&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据官方媒体报道，人工智能和超导领域的专家受邀参加中国领导层在北戴河的夏季度假会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;据官方通讯社新华社报道，截至周一，大约 57 名处于“国内技术前沿”的科学家与共产党最高领导人一起在北京东部的海滨度假胜地待了 7 天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阅读更多&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s chip-making capabilities remain highly reliant on imported parts for key semiconductor equipment, with even mature processes not completely free of US sanctions, according to industry experts attending a chip-manufacturing tool event in the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representatives from more than 600 Chinese semiconductor equipment companies including Naura Technology Group, Advanced Micro-Fabrication Equipment, and US sanctions-hit Shanghai Micro Electronics Equipment (SMEE) were in attendance at the three-day China Semiconductor Equipment Annual Conference 2023, which kicked off on Wednesday in Wuxi, eastern Jiangsu province.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China imported a total of 270.2 billion units of integrated circuits (IC) in the first seven months of 2023, down 16.8 per cent from the same period last year and showing a modest improving trend despite tougher trade restrictions imposed by the US and its allies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fall in IC import volume compared with an 18.5 per cent year-on-year drop in import volume in the first half, and a 22.9 per cent decline in the first three months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US lawmakers&#39; debate over how best to handle the US-China economic relationship was on full view at a congressional hearing on Thursday, with many Republicans arguing for a complete decoupling while some Democrats contended such a move would weaken American companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Representative Blaine Luetkemeyer, a Missouri Republican, took aim at Thea Rozman Kendler, assistant secretary of commerce for export administration, during her testimony before the House select committee on China.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US has established its first generative artificial intelligence task force, the Pentagon announced on Thursday, amid fierce competition with China in the domain that is vital to future warfare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Task Force Lima, as it is called, will assess, synchronise and employ generative AI capabilities across the Defence Department, ensuring that it remains at the forefront of cutting-edge technologies while safeguarding national security, according to a Pentagon statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China wants to develop the world&#39;s most advanced technology on its own as Western countries step up legal blockades aimed at cutting it out of the world technology trade.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing has unveiled a wide range of policies to boost tech self-reliance over the past decade, providing state funding to keep pace with the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden on Monday signed into law a bill that approves the first agreement negotiated under the US-Taiwan Initiative on 21st Century Trade and commits the administration to consult Congress for future agreements under the initiative.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The agreement, signed on June 1, covers streamlining customs procedures, combating corruption and helping small businesses navigate regulatory procedures in both markets. It broadly aims to strengthen the US-Taiwan trade and economic relationship, but does not include any market-access provisions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After months of combing through more than 1,000 amendments, the US Senate finally passed its version of the National Defence Authorisation Act last week – and as has been the case in recent years, it was ripe with measures to counter China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The NDAA, legislation that establishes the top-line budget and directs policy for the Pentagon for the coming financial year, is a “must-pass” bill because its enactment is required for members of the military to receive their pay and benefits on time. As a result, provisions not strictly tied to defence often make it into the bill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Read more&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Global Impact is a weekly curated newsletter featuring a news topic originating in China with a significant macro impact for our newsreaders around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sign up now!&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New Zealand ditches last remaining Covid rules: ‘we made sacrifices, we got vaccinated and we saved lives’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/australasia/article/3230994/new-zealand-ditches-last-remaining-covid-rules-we-made-sacrifices-we-got-vaccinated-and-we-saved?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 14:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/14/d4d28b0a-1a2a-46d1-a398-9a3fb3485333_d4ffe069.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;New Zealand&#39;s government will lift all remaining Covid-19 requirements from midnight on Tuesday, bringing an end to some of the toughest Covid-19 pandemic rules in the world more than three years after they were put in place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Minister of Health Ayesha Verrall said in a statement on Monday that from Tuesday people will no longer have to wear a face mask in healthcare facilities or isolate for seven days after contracting the virus.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While our case numbers will continue to fluctuate, we have not seen the dramatic peaks that characterised Covid-19 rates last year. This, paired with the population&#39;s immunity levels, means cabinet and I am advised we&#39;re positioned to safely remove the remaining Covid-19 requirements,” Verrall said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most of the restrictions were removed last year as vaccination rates reached high levels and the country&#39;s hospitals successfully navigated a winter without being overwhelmed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The decision to remove the requirements comes just two months out from a closely contested election.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the New Zealand government&#39;s handling of the pandemic was globally recognised for keeping infection and death rates at low levels, domestically it faced criticism for the extended lockdowns, school closures and closed borders.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Inexcusable&#39;: New Zealand justice minister quits after drinking, crashing car&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Prime Minister Chris Hipkins said the formal end of restrictions was a “significant milestone”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I believe that New Zealanders can be enormously proud of what we achieved together. We stayed home, we made sacrifices, we got vaccinated and there is absolutely no question that we saved lives,” he told his weekly press conference.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While no longer mandatory, the New Zealand&#39;s Health Ministry still recommends that people stay home for five days if they&#39;re unwell or have tested positive.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Waves of missile, drone attacks over Odesa repelled, Ukraine says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3231001/waves-missile-drone-attacks-over-odesa-repelled-ukraine-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 14:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/14/59960e9e-c66c-4ae0-963f-c053d3547312_9d2f03c6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ukraine downed three waves of Russian missiles and drones targeting Odesa, its army said early on Monday, the latest in a string of attacks in the southern region on the Black Sea coast.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The enemy attacked Odesa region three times during the night, using two waves of attack drones, a total of 15, and eight Kalibr-type sea-based missiles,” the Operational Command South wrote on Telegram.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Air defence forces repelled all the attacks, but falling debris damaged a student dormitory and a supermarket in Odesa&#39;s city centre, leaving three workers wounded, the army said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The blast wave damaged windows and balconies in several buildings, and damaged cars parked nearby”, it said, adding that firefighters were battling two blazes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Photos and videos shared by the army on Telegram showed firefighters trying to extinguish flames engulfing a multi-storey supermarket, with a large plume of smoke rising into the air.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russia and Ukraine have stepped up attacks in the Black Sea since Moscow exited a deal last month that had granted Kyiv&#39;s grain exports safe passage during the conflict.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since withdrawing from the agreement, Moscow has pounded ports in the Odesa region that were key for Ukrainian grain exports under the deal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The overnight missile and drone attacks come a day after Moscow said warning shots were fired from a Russian warship at a cargo vessel heading towards Izmail, a city on the Danube river in Odesa.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russia&#39;s Wagner boss will be killed by Putin or lead a coup, expert says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Russian ship spotted the Sukru Okan cargo vessel sailing under the flag of Palau and fired the shots after its captain did not respond to demands to stop.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After inspection, the cargo ship was allowed to continue its journey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On August 2, Russia struck port infrastructure in Izmail, one of the main export routes for Ukrainian agricultural products to neighbouring Romania.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 14:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[More than 100 Hongkongers seize last chance to buy subsidised flat under Home Ownership Scheme, despite falling property prices]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/hong-kong-economy/article/3230995/more-100-hongkongers-seize-last-chance-buy-subsidised-flat-under-home-ownership-scheme-despite?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 13:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/14/7b008606-86f9-4078-83e1-c29ff41bc6a8_ae7342c7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;More than 100 aspiring homeowners have seized the last chance this year to buy a subsidised flat, despite falling property prices, with fewer applicants to the government scheme compared with the previous round.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Interested buyers streamed into the Housing Authority&#39;s customer service building in Lok Fu on Monday to try their luck at securing one of the 9,000 flats on sale under the Home Ownership Scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many said they were looking to buy two-bedroom flats, with the Kai Tak area being the most popular choice because of its proximity to the commercial hub of Kwun Tong and the rest of Kowloon.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thomas Chiu, who showed up at 9am, was among the hopefuls. He said he wanted to buy a two-bedroom flat in Kai Tak for his family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re currently living in Tai Po in a one-bedroom flat. I sleep in the living room, while my wife and daughter stay in the bedroom,” the 57-year-old said. “My daughter is 16, so it&#39;s better if she can have her own room now.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said he came to submit his form on the last day of the application period, which started on July 31, because he was still deciding between buying a private flat or a public one.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Property developer CK Asset Holdings on Saturday sold all 626 homes at the Coastal Line II in Yau Tong for an average of HK$14,686 (US$1,880) per square foot, a seven-year low in prices for new flats in the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Home Ownership Scheme to bar property-owning Hong Kong public housing tenants&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The cost of some flats have dropped to HK$4 million, similar to that of a subsidised one.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chiu, who works in hospitality, said private property was unattainable for him, even at discounted prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It doesn&#39;t matter if private flats are becoming cheaper, there&#39;s still no chance for us. If a flat costs HK$5 million to HK$6 million, we can&#39;t even afford a down payment,” Chiu said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The only private flats we can afford are ones which will be ready in 20 or 30 years.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government scheme this year offered 9,154 flats across six sites in Kai Tak, Kwun Tong, Tuen Mun and Yuen Long at 38 per cent of the market price, lower than the rate in 2022.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two-block Kai Yuet Court complex in Kai Tak has more than 2,000 flats on sale, while three developments in Kwun Tong North are offering over 3,500 homes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prices for these flats, which are slated for completion between 2025 and 2026, vary between HK$1.49 million and HK$4.9 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung Man-kwong, deputy chairman of the Legislative Council&#39;s housing panel, said he did not expect there to be fewer than 110,000 applications for the subsidised homes as of last Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The figure is worse than what me and many others had expected,” he told a radio show on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He noted there were more than 200,000 applications last year, when the city was still struggling to cope with the Covid-19 pandemic and a weakened economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What to know about new Hong Kong public-private scheme to tackle housing crisis&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Leung said he had anticipated that demand for subsidised flats would be higher this year, as four of the six estates were located in urban areas, and more than 9,000 homes were available, including some larger ones.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The oversubscription rate, which refers to demand in relation to supply, of 10.9 for the latest round marks the lowest since authorities resumed selling subsidised flats in 2014.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Applications for last year&#39;s batch of more than 9,000 flats were oversubscribed by 27 times.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leung said he believed some people had decided not to apply because of a recent slump in property prices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When the application for subsidised flats began, overall property prices … were showing a downward trend,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There were also some new private flats being sold at prices which were similar to those of subsidised homes. People are wondering whether buying private flats will be an even cheaper option in the future.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Xiao Hai, who went to the customer service building on Monday with her husband and son to submit an application, said owning private property was the family&#39;s long-term goal, but they had decided to buy a subsidised flat in the meantime.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She applied for a two-bedroom flat in Kai Tak, saying transport in the area would make it easy for her son to commute to school.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We&#39;re here to try our luck. My main goal is to buy a private flat in the long-run, and our budget for that is HK$10 million, but for now we&#39;ll try getting a subsidised property as our sons grow up,” said the 42-year-old investor, who has two sons aged 9 and 13.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Elizabeth Cheung&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 13:50:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Lioness escapes farm in South Korea, shot dead by hunters]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3230991/lioness-escapes-farm-south-korea-shot-dead-hunters?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.14 13:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/14/3e692dda-2ba8-41dd-b811-b81ae472a381_e02a33e9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A lioness escaped from a farm in South Korea, touching off an emergency search before she was killed by a hunter on Monday, officials said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The owner of the farm in the southeastern county of Goryeong reported the escape after finding her cage empty. Authorities quickly sent police officers, emergency workers and civilian hunters to the area, Goryeong police said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People were banned from entering a mountain area where the lioness was believed to be before one of the hunters killed her near the farm, according to county and police officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Both county and police officials spoke on condition of anonymity because they were not authorised to speak to the media on the matter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were no reports of the lioness attacking anyone. The lioness had last been seen in her cage when she was fed on Sunday night and it wasn&#39;t known when she escaped.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The farm has no other lions or lionesses and mostly raises beef cattle.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese national&#39;s TikTok lion shows Cambodia&#39;s exotic pet problem&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The farm&#39;s owner told investigators the lioness had been handed over when the farm was purchased last year, Goryeong police said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It wasn&#39;t immediately known if the farm&#39;s previous owner had official permission to raise the lioness.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 14 Aug 2023 13:20:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>