<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China bans ‘one-size-fits-all’ approach to farmland reclamation amid food security drive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224490/china-bans-one-size-fits-all-approach-farmland-reclamation-amid-food-security-drive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/d6fc3967-34ed-4e6b-97fd-6a8db9bc99a1_b3a60bed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国最高土地使用监管机构警告地方当局不要草率地将土地重新分配用于农作物&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在上周的一项指令中，自然资源部表示“严禁”地方政府对土地使用采取“一刀切”的措施，包括推土机果园、苗圃和池塘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该命令是在对填海案件的一系列投诉之后发布的，其中包括成都市计划沿城市周边规划的绿化带开垦约 6,700 公顷（16,556 英亩）的土地，以&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，随着与西方的关系破裂以及乌克兰战争升级，粮食安全已成为国家的优先事项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的耕地总面积在快速增长的情况下减少近几十年来工业化和城市化，地方政府现在面临越来越大的压力来保证一定的农作物种植面积。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该部列出了地方政府不得采取的一些措施来满足中央政府的要求，例如将污染严重、生态脆弱或遭受严重水土流失或荒漠化的土地转变为耕地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新指令还禁止开垦坡度超过 25 度的土地，或位于主要水域之上的土地来源，坡度超过 15 度。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;极端天气威胁中国的粮食安全：部委&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该指示称，一些政府“只是在纸上追求耕地规模的平衡，而没有考虑如何实现耕地规模的平衡”土地在填海后被使用，再次造成土地流失。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国人民大学农业经济与农村发展学院教授郑奉天表示，最新的命令是对公众对不计后果的尝试的担忧的回应。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这也反映了国家将占用耕地用于商业开发与开垦配额挂钩的耕地保护计划，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据该计划，通过了在 2000 年代，如果一块农田用于非农业用途，则必须创建一块新的同等面积的农田。然而，这导致许多地方政府将良田用于建设，然后将贫瘠的土地或坡地转为耕地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;资源，并希望系统尽可能灵活，”郑说。 “但对于国家监管者来说，需要更具体的监管来保证新耕地的质量。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国社会科学院农村发展研究所原研究员党国英说。一个更好的解决办法是提高农作物的利润，而不是发布行政命令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我想说政府干预太多了。如果农民能从中赚到钱，他们就会在田里种更多的庄稼，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近几十年来，中国一直在使用补贴和激励措施来帮助扩大全国的耕地面积，但大多数年轻人劳动者仍然选择放弃田地，到城市寻找收入更高的工作，而不是从事农业。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s leader calls on technology and education sector to cultivate talent while youth drive city’s development]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3224515/hong-kongs-leader-calls-technology-and-education-sector-cultivate-talent-while-youth-drive-citys?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 21:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/3ccd1e8f-f77e-40c7-aab5-f74b75097cfb_5b1f9389.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港领导人呼吁教育、商业和科学界继续与香港合作政府通过在课堂内外提供更多元化的学习活动来培养创新科技人才。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在香港第二届香港科学展周日举行的颁奖典礼上，行政长官李家超还敦促青年成为创新科技增长和国家高质量发展的驱动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为教师提供 STEAM 教育培训，”Lee 说，指的是一种以科学、技术、工程、艺术和数学为切入点的学习方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我希望技术和教育部门继续努力与政府一起培养人才，而青年则可以参与香港发展成为国际创新科技中心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李说，香港的创新科技发展基础稳固，享誉全球，他指这座城市在 2023 年日内瓦国际发明展上获得了近 300 个奖项，是该市在 2017 年获得的奖项的五倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本次博览会于周六和周日举行，吸引了来自当地小学的 120 多支队伍和中学展示他们的科学项目，吸引了超过 20,000 名参观者。在参与的团队中，有 10 支团队因表现出色而被博览会评审团授予奖项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，财政司司长陈茂波在周日发表的一篇博文中写道，香港在&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，香港科技园共有 320 家公司入驻，比去年增加了 30%。该园区的科技公司还在 2022 年筹集了 7.8 亿港元（9,970 万美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，科技中心数码港现在拥有 1,900 多家公司。陈说，其初创企业自成立以来也筹集了超过 357 亿港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;财政司司长指出，政府的五个研发中心也取得了成果，共有 210 个研究项目从 2021-2022 财政年度开始，比上一财政年度高出 10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港计划在边境附近划拨 300 公顷土地用于 I&amp;T 目的&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 2021-2022 财政年度，这些中心共批准了 135 项专利，也比前 12 个月高出 16%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 还透露，政府吸引战略企业办公室会见了来自到目前为止，已有 150 多家公司，其中大多数是各自行业的领导者。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel’s Netanyahu to move ahead with contentious judicial overhaul plan after talks crumble]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/middle-east/article/3224516/israels-netanyahu-move-ahead-contentious-judicial-overhaul-plan-after-talks-crumble?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 21:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/109e5ca2-3712-4d71-a1f3-a3ea1fa0e222_3f6d504a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;以色列总理本杰明内塔尼亚胡周日表示，他的政府打算推进有争议的计划在旨在寻找妥协解决方案的会谈似乎破裂后，改变该国司法系统的计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府改革司法机构的计划使以色列在今年早些时候陷入有史以来最严重的国内危机之一。政府和反对党之间的谈判在一定程度上缓解了危机，试图就该国司法系统的拟议改革找到一个中间立场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，这些谈判因围绕负责挑选国家的法官。反对派领导人表示，在委员会成立之前，谈判将被冻结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在内塔尼亚胡周日举行的内阁会议上，内塔尼亚胡表示反对派没有本着诚意进行谈判，他的政府将谨慎推进大修。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“本周，我们将开始实际步骤。我们将以有节制、负责任的方式进行这些工作，但要根据我们收到的对司法系统进行纠正的授权，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在拜登总统的指责后，以色列的内塔尼亚胡对改革妥协持乐观态度&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;内塔尼亚胡在大规模抗议爆发后于 3 月暂停了改革。尽管计划暂停，但继续推进的决定可能会加剧紧张局势并加剧每个星期六继续示威的抗议运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抗议领导人表示，他们已准备好进行另一轮示威，这将使可以肯定的是，“任何损害以色列民主司法制度的企图都会失败。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对党领袖亚尔拉皮德表示，单方面推进该计划“将严重损害经济，危及安全”，他所在的政党一直在与内塔尼亚胡进行谈判并将以色列人民撕成碎片。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由极端民族主义和极端宗教政党组成的内塔尼亚胡政府在今年早些时候宣布改革计划时遭到强烈反对。主要经济学家、高级法律官员和前国防官员警告说，这会给该国的未来带来危险的后果。甚至以色列的主要国际盟友美国也表达了担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府表示，该计划对于恢复民选官员的权力是必要的，并削弱它所说的干预主义最高法院。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;批评者说，该计划将颠覆以色列微妙的制衡制度，并将该国推向威权主义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;任命法官的委员会——除其他外，该委员会批准最高法院的组成– 一直是改革计划的中心战场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;执政联盟和反对派传统上都在九人委员会中有代表。但改革的支持者要求联盟控制这两个职位，并指责内塔尼亚胡和他的盟友试图在司法机构中堆砌亲信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，议会任命了反对派代表加入委员会，但第二个空缺没有填补，导致委员会恢复工作的时间推迟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方都指责对方用委员会任命的结果破坏谈判。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Abby Choi murder: hundreds of mourners attend pink-themed Hong Kong funeral service for slain socialite]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3224514/abby-choi-murder-hundreds-mourners-attend-pink-themed-hong-kong-funeral-service-slain-socialite?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 20:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/562e81f4-291e-4714-9a1f-870d27cbb228_99d2131a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;数百名哀悼者参加了为遇害的香港社交名媛蔡慧玲举行的粉红色主题葬礼周日的天凤，粤语歌星郭富城等名人送上花圈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与传统的中国葬礼通常使用黑白两色表示哀悼不同，该仪式的纪念堂是整个大围宝福纪念堂铺满粉红色，据说是蔡氏最喜欢的颜色。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;整个大围宝福纪念堂地下铺满粉红色窗帘，并点缀着粉红色和白色的花朵。两张 1.5 米高（5 英尺高）的社交名媛和模特的照片被放置在入口的两侧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大厅内还摆放着几张社交名媛的巨幅肖像，上面挂着来自朋友和亲戚放在他们下面。其中包括朋友 Moka Fang 和她的巨星丈夫郭富城、流行乐队 Grasshopper 的歌手蔡逸智和他的妻子，以及广播公司 TVB 的高级行政人员 Virginia Lok Yee-ling。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Choi&#39;s 2 月下旬，在这位 28 岁的男子失踪三天后，在大埔的一所村屋里发现了部分遗骸。她的前夫 Alex Kwong Kong-chi、他的父母和兄弟已被指控与杀人有关。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;被杀的 Abby Choi 的朋友、合伙人否认香港慈善机构曾洗钱&lt;/h3>;&lt; p>;下午4点开始的葬礼闭门举行，只有至亲和朋友才能参加。殡仪馆工作人员在警力密集的情况下在入口处检查哀悼者的身份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》观察到，从下午 4 点 30 分到下午 5 点 30 分，八辆大巴在殡仪馆旁边的一个停车场送走了至少 400 名哀悼者。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡某的亲友曾一度在会所外排队等候进入会所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方在对面的沙田法医中心旁设立了一个可容纳至少40名记者的新闻发布区&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位熟悉情况的消息人士早些时候表示，葬礼将涉及佛教仪式。次日早上，在遗体被送往大屿山宝莲寺火化之前，将举行仪式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月 24 日，警方发现了蔡的头骨、腿部，这起可怕的案件曝光以及大埔龙尾村一栋三层村屋底层公寓的几根肋骨断裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港 Abby Choi 的子女面临 3 亿港元遗产的“5 年等待”&lt; /h3>;&lt;p>;尽管警方在新界堆填区和将军澳坟场进行了广泛搜查，但仍未能找到蔡女士的任何其他身体部位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的家人于 4 月取回了她的遗体来自富山公众太平间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡的前夫，28 岁的 Alex Kwong，他的父亲，65 岁的 Kwong Kau，和 32 岁的哥哥 Anthony Kwong Kong-jit，因共同谋杀而被还押&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kwong 的母亲，63 岁的 Jenny Li Sui-heung 被控在案件中妨碍司法公正，她在上个月第二次尝试保释失败后也被还押.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 20:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Beijing’s trade deals tempt Taipei’s allies in Latin America – but not the Pacific]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224453/why-beijings-trade-deals-tempt-taipeis-allies-latin-america-not-pacific?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/17/55ce0f1e-27a8-4f64-bb97-9edf8a9bafe7_aeb55f69.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京对自由贸易协定和基础设施合作的承诺可能是一个更大的诱惑分析人士称，台北在拉丁美洲的剩余外交盟友比在太平洋地区的外交盟友要多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该评估是在洪都拉斯总统西奥马拉卡斯特罗上周在北京接受红地毯款待之后进行的，这是她自从洪都拉斯总统以来首次访问中国大陆今年 3 月与台北建立外交关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在会晤期间，中国国家主席习近平称赞卡斯特罗在履行选举承诺时表现出的“历史性果断”和“强烈政治意愿”，将效忠对象从台北转移到台湾。北京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方在“一带一路”建设、农业、科技等多个领域签署了17项协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双方还表示，正式会谈旨在实现自由-贸易协定将“尽快”开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洪都拉斯只是台湾与北京之间长期外交争端中最新一个改变承认的国家——中国将这个自治岛屿视为它的领土。包括美国在内的大多数国家都不承认台湾是一个独立国家。然而，华盛顿反对任何以武力夺取该岛的企图。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2016 年台湾总统蔡英文当选以来，北京将台北仅存的几个外交盟友从其轨道上撤离的运动才有所增加她倾向于独立的民进党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从那时起，九个国家放弃了台北，只剩下 13 个正式盟友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗马教廷和非洲国家除外eSwatini，台湾剩下的外交盟友是少数拉丁美洲国家和四个太平洋岛国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其中危地马拉，伯利兹和巴拉圭的拉丁美洲国家与洪都拉斯一样，以出口为导向加勒比进步研究所创始人兼首席执行官 Rasheed Griffith 表示，伯利兹和危地马拉的主要出口产品之一是香蕉和咖啡豆，就在卡斯特罗与习近平会面一天后，中国宣布批准从尼加拉瓜进口商品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国也是世界上最大的大豆进口国，大豆是巴拉圭的主要作物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Griffiths 说，即使是像圣基茨和尼维斯以及圣卢西亚这样依赖旅游业和服务业而非出口的加勒比国家，也将从廉价中国商品的流入中获益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我看来认为经济计算将变得过于压倒性，”格里菲斯说。 “未来五年，台湾不太可能在该地区拥有任何正式盟友。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但北京的经济诱惑在太平洋地区可能不会那么有效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国政府向那些将对台北的认可转向北京的政府发出信号，表示他们将获得贵宾待遇，这是标准程序，”夏威夷东西方中心高级研究员丹尼·罗伊 (Denny Roy) 说，他指的是人民政府&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但在某些情况下，这还不够。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特别是马绍尔群岛和帕劳长期以来一直是美国的强大盟友。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;两国都签署了美国的自由联合协定，帕劳上个月扩大了其成员资格。包容带来许多好处，包括财政和发展支持，以换取美国出于军事和国家安全目的使用他们的土地和水域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果站在美国好的一边很重要，承认台北而不是北京是一个优势，”罗伊说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;图瓦卢也一直是台北的坚定支持者。去年，由于“民主、真理和人权”的共同价值观，这个太平洋岛国的总理 Kausea Natano 重申他打算不顾地缘政治压力与台北“站稳脚跟”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瑙鲁澳大利亚太平洋安全学院战略参与副主任 Henry Ivarature 表示，由于共同的价值观，它也表示愿意与台北保持关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有时，这些国家希望表明他们可以对抗超级大国，即使它们是世界上最小的国家，”Ivarature 说。 “中国很难影响他们转变。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，台北应该停止“徒劳地”与北京争夺发展中小国，而应专注于发展“非官方关系” East-West Centre 的 Roy 表示，与日本和美国等国家的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Griffith 表示同意，称缺乏外交承认并不是对该岛的“生存威胁”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“希望外交盟友问题将很快被淡化，”他说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 20:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Key Asean members skip Thai-hosted Myanmar talks amid criticism]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3224513/key-asean-members-skip-thai-hosted-myanmar-talks-amid-criticism?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 19:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/c5aa05ac-ef91-4814-9a56-f45308bf5147_21b101f4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;泰国看守政府在非正式地区和平会谈中接待了缅甸执政军政府的外交部长周日，由于主要的东南亚同行没有参加引起尖锐批评的会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到目前为止，只有柬埔寨正式确认它打算参加会谈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;缅甸的将军们一直将近两年被禁止参加东南亚国家联盟（东盟）的高级会议，原因是未能履行与反对者开始谈判的协议，这些反对者与现在被监禁的诺贝尔奖获得者昂山素领导的被罢免的文职政府有关Kyi。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，泰国总理本人首先在军事政变中掌权，邀请缅甸军政府任命的外交部长丹瑞与东盟 10 国集团的其他外交部长一起参加会谈，两个了解会议情况的消息人士称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日未能联系到缅甸军政府发言人置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国外交部对究竟谁参加了为期两天的会议守口如瓶在度假胜地芭堤雅举行集会，即将离任的外交部长唐·帕穆威奈 (Don Pramudwinai) 就在会议开始前四天发出了邀请函。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;泰国是否寻求与缅甸军政府全面重新接触以推动和平？&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;Don 周日告诉当地新闻媒体 Matichon，非官方倡议旨在补充而非取代东盟领导的努力，成员可以自由参加或不参加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前的情况已经改变很多。缅甸境内现在有更多的战斗，”引述他的话说。 “缅甸也有通往选举的路线图……这些事情让我们有必要继续与缅甸互动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 2021 年 2 月 1 日政变以来，缅甸一直饱受暴力袭击，军方在多条战线上作战，试图镇压为响应镇压而形成的武装民主抵抗运动。军政府表示，它正在与旨在摧毁该国的恐怖分子作战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国倡议的批评者表示，它有可能使缅甸军政府合法化，并且是不合适的，因为它不属于官方的东盟和平倡议，即所谓的“五个国家” -point consensus”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人质疑为什么泰国现在召集会谈，因为在亲军联盟在 5 月 16 日的选举中被进步和民粹主义政党彻底击败后，泰国预计将在 8 月组建新政府.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柬埔寨政府周五在一份声明中表示，柬埔寨外交部长 Prak Sokhonn 将出席会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他东盟成员国拒绝了泰国的邀请，包括今年的轮值主席国印度尼西亚，以及新加坡，其外交部长 Vivian Balakrishnan 周五表示，“在峰会层面甚至外交部长层面与军政府重新接触还为时过早”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nantiwat Samart，秘书据国家电视台泰语网站报道，周日致泰国外交部长的信为会谈辩护，称缅甸不应完全孤立或脱离东盟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南政府表示，其外国两位知情人士表示，部长“由于事先约定”将不会出席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚也不会出席。菲律宾在周末没有回应问题，被视为坚定地站在孤立缅甸将军的阵营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由昂山素季被罢免政府的支持者组成的缅甸反对派民族团结政府谴责泰国倡议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“邀请非法军政府参加这次讨论无助于解决缅甸的政治危机，”它在周六的一份声明中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;81 个缅甸国家集团激进组织周日发表了一封公开信，谴责“秘密倡议”，称这与东盟将军政府官员排除在高层会议之外的政策“公然矛盾”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要求看守泰国政府立即取消这次会议，”信中说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore doctors concerned about increase in cheap botched aesthetic procedures]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3224510/cheap-botched-aesthetic-procedures-rise-singapore?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 18:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/18/152d7a5d-b2d7-4aa1-b402-8d3d19fee7e1_37cf41c2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一些新加坡人被居家“美容师”宣传的低价所吸引，最终在程序出错时支付更多费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他们求助于合格的从业者，他们说他们看到越来越多的人寻求纠正这些无证操作员执行的拙劣程序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最近一名妇女因进行无证家庭唇部缩小手术而被判入狱一周的法庭案件引起了人们对提供美容服务的未经授权经营者的小型行业的关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当患者在法庭案件没有受到手术的不良影响，有些人就没那么幸运了，不得不付出代价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通常矫正手术的费用比初次手术本身要高，因为重建手术的费用很高Dr Leo Aesthetic Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery 的整形外科医生 Leo Kah Woon 博士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国女演员分享“噩梦”隆鼻照片&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Woffles Wu 美容外科和激光中心的整形外科医生 Woffles Wu 博士说：“他们中的一些人非常绝望，他们意识到……[这是]一件愚蠢的事情，他们不仅没有节省成本，反而不得不花更多的钱来纠正它。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡医学委员会指南关于医生美容实践的声明指出，美容程序，无论是否是侵入性的，都只能由持照医​​生在注册诊所或手术室进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;私立医院也禁止这种做法，并且Medical Clinic Act，规定任何用于医疗保健目的的场所都必须获得许可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在家经营的企业无法获得此类许可，这些企业在在线平台上提供侵入性和注射治疗。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;《今日报》的一名记者接触了 3 家宣传保妥适和唇部填充剂等服务的企业。这三人都声称拥有执业执照和证书，但当被要求出示文件或照片时，他们都拒绝了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后，这些操作员通过提供“证据”向记者保证侵入性手术是安全的，例如他们“获奖”的 Facebook 帖子，声称他们在医疗领域拥有多年经验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还声称拥有私人有限公司注册，并且他们的产品在皮肤上比其他产品更柔软-现成的，不会引起感染。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们对记者的保妥适和唇部填充手术报价从 138 新元（103 美元）到 238 新元（178 美元）不等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Adrian Ooi 博士是 Polaris Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery 的顾问整形外科医生兼医疗主任，他说同样的手术可能花费 200 新元（150 美元）到 2,000 新元（1,500 美元），具体取决于注射量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leo 博士说，居家经营者通过声称产品含有天然成分等方式歪曲了他们所推销的产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说这会给患者带来“一种​​错误的安全感”，甚至尽管实际上使用这些由无证操作员管理的产品存在很高的感染风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leo 博士举了一个特殊案例，该案例涉及一名患者在中国社交媒体上找到该服务后接受了拙劣的程序，并在 e -商务平台小红书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leo 医生说，当患者看到他们的朋友没有经历不良结果时，也存在同伴影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，所有受访的三位整形外科医生都警告说，它患者冒着感染风险继续进行这些手术是不值得的，有些极端病例甚至会导致死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴博士说很难取缔这种做法，因为政府机构没有资源监控非法经营者，因此他们依赖于投诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在大多数情况下，“人们只是太羞于谈论它”，他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;完整故事可在今天在线获取.com&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Blockchain-based securities are emerging in Hong Kong, further expanding distributed ledgers in local financial markets]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-trends/article/3224400/blockchain-based-securities-are-emerging-hong-kong-further-expanding-distributed-ledgers-local?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/16/170a04b6-0f6f-4f99-80b6-722b11f0568e_76f45441.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;新的基于区块链的安全产品正在香港涌现，为投资者提供各种在与加密货币等虚拟资产截然不同的领域，利用该市不断发展的 Web3 行业的方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着瑞银和中国银行香港总部上周宣布基于区块链的结构化票据投资部门，自推出新的加密许可制度以来，该市现在在公共区块链上拥有第一个私人安全产品。它加入了 2 月份宣布的由政府支持的绿色债券，该债券将在高盛的私有区块链平台上发行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些产品反映出人们对发展香港 Web3 行业的兴趣，而不仅仅是加密货币，而加密货币一直是人们关注的焦点&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这有助于巩固香港作为促进亲区块链生态系统的金融中心的形象，特别是因为发行是在公共区块链上进行的，”该中心副院长 Allen Huang 说。香港科技大学 (HKUST) 商学院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了成为加密中心，香港本月对虚拟资产实施了新规定，要求交易所获得许可并限制零售投资者购买具有大市值的代币，如比特币和以太币。但重要的是，证券和期货合约被排除在该市对此类资产的定义之外。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，投资者正在了解基于区块链的证券将如何在该市发挥作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国银行在香港的以太坊区块链上发行证券&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国银行国际控股 (BOCI) 的产品是独一无二的，因为它是在以太坊上提供的，以太坊是仅次于使用的第二大最受欢迎的区块链对于比特币。以太坊的主要创新是智能合约，这一理念在 2021 年推动了不可替代代币 (NFT) 的繁荣。这标志着一家总部设在中国大陆的银行罕见地涉足公共加密货币产品，那里严格禁止加密货币。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;虽然传统票据由中央证券存管处 (CSD) 持有，但中银国际和瑞银产品是作为智能合约创建的，并直接在以太坊网络上注册，不涉及 CSD，瑞银发言人周五告诉邮报.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说，使用公共区块链可以实现“不同市场参与者之间更好的互操作性和连接性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相比之下，金管局 2 月份发行的代币化绿色债券是根据香港金融管理局 (HKMA) 的说法，在获得许可的区块链上发行，整个债券生命周期——从发行到二级交易结算和到期赎回——都在链上进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然公共区块链可以香港科技大学的 Huang 表示，通过提供更高的透明度来增强股东信心，但他们不强制执行受监管金融所需的隐私功能，因此一些信息可能会保留在链下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中银国际副首席执行官 Ying Wang 在本周早些时候的一份声明称，该产品“专为亚太地区的客户设计”。据瑞银发言人称，瑞银客户可以使用法定货币购买该产品，而瑞士银行则担任该产品的托管人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新项目可被视为中国银行区块链努力的延伸, said Jack Poon, professor of practice for fintech and entrepreneurship at the Hong Kong Polytechnic University. He noted that BOC, a state-owned bank, participated in HKMA&#39;s tokenised green bond offering. The fact that it is now working with a Swiss bank in financial services and innovation is “quite significant”, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It means that there is a will to continuously explore this over time,” Poon said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s new blockchain research centre will train half a million industry workers&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Some questions about public blockchain security tokens, such as the costs of issuance and whether they will be accessible to retail investors outside of licensed exchanges, remain unanswered, Poon said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At this stage they may just want to show that yes, we can do this,” he said. “But I think the real need comes from when you can actually lower the cost.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;BOCI and UBS have not said what kind of payouts investors can expect from the new note or detailed how it is structured. The government&#39;s green bond, on the other hand, has specified a yield of 4.05 per cent with a one-year maturity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the new products are being touted by some as another signal of Hong Kong&#39;s forward-looking approach to Web3, the SFC regulates all securities the same – whether they are on a blockchain or not.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Much of the hype around Hong Kong&#39;s push to become a crypto hub revolves around its new regulations that went into effect this month. Those rules primarily apply to cryptocurrency exchanges and define virtual assets as those that are used “as a medium of exchange”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By virtue of being issued on a blockchain, these security products are still being seen as another way Hong Kong is expanding its Web3 footprint.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We see China definitely poised for driving innovation in digital financial assets,” said Ralf Kubli, board member at the Casper Association, the Switzerland-based non-profit organisation that operates the Casper Network blockchain. “With its digital-first mindset, and strong cross-border trade economies, it is only a matter of time until digitally native financial assets are commonplace.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Local cadres blamed over mouse head meal at college canteen in China]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3224505/local-cadres-blamed-over-mouse-head-meal-college-canteen-china?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 19:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/18/99b87ab0-00ad-4886-b6e5-301e4633d2f3_41923ffe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The mouthpiece of China&#39;s Communist Party has taken aim at “grass-roots cadres” after a task force concluded that a “foreign object” found in a school meal was a mouse head and not duck neck as previously claimed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A commentary in People&#39;s Daily on Sunday said the case exposed the failure of local cadres to face problems, their ignorance of the rule of law, and lack of awareness about the power of the internet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Failure to face up to problems will only trigger bigger problems … the more the truth is concealed, the greater the crisis of confidence will happen,” the commentary said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[This incident] shows some grass-roots cadres not only have a minimum awareness of the rule of law but also lack understanding [of the influence of] the internet and public opinion.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reprimand came after a student at Jiangxi Industry Polytechnic College in Nanchang posted a video of “an object with teeth, eyes and nose” in his rice dish at a college cafeteria on June 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The college repeatedly denied the dish had vermin and posted a notice from the Gaoxin District Market Supervisory Bureau declaring the material to be “duck neck”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another video posted online showed a Nanchang inspector agreeing with the duck neck conclusion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The issue reignited public concerns about food safety, with internet users calling for an investigation of the “cover-up”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Normal people can tell easily from the picture what it is,” one commenter said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another said: “An investigation has to be done to reveal who is behind it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Provincial inspectors then weighed in, concluding that the initial assessment of duck neck was “wrong”, People&#39;s Daily reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Based on the pictures and video footage taken by the student who found the &#39;foreign object&#39;, the country&#39;s leading animal experts ruled it is the head of a rodent,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report said canteen staff had thrown away the suspicious object so the provincial inspectors&#39; conclusion was based on a field study, surveillance footage and interviews with witnesses, including canteen staff and students.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The food business licence of the canteen owner was revoked and the maximum penalty imposed, the report said without detailing the punishment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The college has since removed the Gaoxin bureau&#39;s assessment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;Treated like livestock&#39;: school in China caught washing kids&#39; plates in urinal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Alfred Wu, an associate professor at the Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy at the National University of Singapore, said the “rat-headed” saga may be “the tip of the iceberg” in terms of poor governance at the local level because local cadres could cover up scandals for each other.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Food safety is a regular source of public concern in China. In December, a woman in southwest China attracted attention on mainland social media after revealing that she washed her dishes in pigswill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, a private foreign language school in Chengdu, in the southwest province of Sichuan, reportedly used suspected expired frozen pet food to cook student meals, according to video clips shared online by parents.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Bad vibes’: pub in China slaps customers with US$42 ‘punishment fine’ for ‘not creating vibrant’ atmosphere]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3224313/bad-vibes-pub-china-slaps-customers-us42-punishment-fine-not-creating-vibrant-atmosphere?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/18/e31fa44e-f90e-42be-b68e-61c27d76bb72_8d509ae2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A woman in China who was charged an extra 300 yuan (US$42) because she and her friends were “not creating a vibrant enough vibe” in a pub has shared her experience on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The unidentified woman was with friends at the Boom Shake bar in Hangzhou, Zhejiang province, eastern China, earlier this month and had booked a VIP booth with a minimum spend of 3,800 yuan (US$535), local media reported.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the group arrived, they discovered that the booth they were given was too small but they decided to stay, according to the woman.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, when the bill for 4,988 yuan arrived, they were surprised to find an extra bottle of wine and a mystery charge of 300 yuan added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Staff told them the extra charge was a “punishment” because the atmosphere around their booth was not good enough.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“He said we were fined as the vibe around us during the last hour there was not vibrant enough,” the woman told news site Pear Video.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I was speechless. We went there as consumers, not to work to create a vibe. Why should we be penalised?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She added that they only ordered four bottles of wine but were “mysteriously” charged for an extra bottle which cost more than 1,000 yuan (US$140).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman complained and was told by themanagement that the “vibe fine” was meant to be imposed on staff, not customers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I guess the waitperson was unhappy with this, so he charged the fine back to the customer,” the management representative told the woman.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, she then claimed the charge was nothing to do with the bar as the waiter, surnamed Li, was working on commission through a third-party sales company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is the problem of the waitperson, not our company,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An argument ensued over who was ultimately responsible, the bar management stood firm and eventually the group settled the bill.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After repeated complaints to the company that owns the bar and to the local market supervision authority, Li, the waiter who added the charge, repaid 1,480 yuan to the woman for the “vibe fine” and the extra bottle of wine they had not ordered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The incident happened because I am naive and not mature enough,” Li told the woman in an apology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident triggered an online discussion about consumer rights in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am lucky to see this kind of extremely incredible news,” one person said on Weibo.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At first, I thought it was the worker being fined. Then I confirmed the consumer was fined, and I didn&#39;t believe it was true. What a rare case!” said another person.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s obviously a robbery,” commented a third.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Consumer rights violations are common in China and have become a source of news and discussion online.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April this year, a man in eastern China who bought his friends dinner at a restaurant said he was overcharged by 1,000 yuan. The restaurant denied this until surveillance footage revealed the number of dishes they had consumed and the bill was rectified.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Africa’s minerals giants push for bigger battery bucks as China and the West vie for clean energy resources]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224365/africas-minerals-giants-push-bigger-battery-bucks-china-and-west-vie-clean-energy-resources?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.18 18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/16/8e347595-3d7e-4724-9d62-36a1da939741_d3de2879.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Some of Africa&#39;s top mineral-producing nations are banning the export of raw battery minerals and instead want the metals processed locally as rivalry between China and Western nations over the critical resources intensifies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Namibia, the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) and Zimbabwe have significant deposits of lithium – an essential component used to make rechargeable batteries for electronic devices, electric vehicles and other clean technologies – and want their minerals processed locally so they can get better value from the resources.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the world transitions to green energy, they are capitalising on rising demand for the minerals, especially lithium and cobalt which many countries are banking on to achieve clean energy ambitions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Namibia last week banned the export of unprocessed lithium and other critical minerals because it wants its economy to benefit more from them. The country&#39;s cabinet last week approved the ban on the export of unprocessed lithium ore, cobalt, manganese, graphite and rare earth minerals – all critical in the global green energy transition.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The southwest African country has significant deposits of lithium as well as rare earth minerals such as dysprosium and terbium used to make magnets in the batteries of electric cars and wind turbines. It is also one of the world&#39;s largest uranium and diamond producers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, Namibia&#39;s deputy minister of information and communications technology, Emma Theofelus, said smaller quantities of the minerals might be allowed for export at the discretion of the minister of mines and energy, subject to cabinet endorsement.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Toyota&#39;s top scientist says the world lacks resources to go all-EV&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China is the dominant player in global lithium processing, accounting for more than half the world&#39;s total. Meanwhile, the United States and Canada refine less than 5 per cent each, according to Benchmark&#39;s lithium forecast. But the US and some other Western nations are not letting China go unchallenged.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, the European Union signed a deal with Namibia to secure rare earth minerals under the bloc&#39;s bid to cut its reliance on China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US is also angling for the battery metals and last year signed a memorandum of understanding with Zambia and the DRC to bring funding and expertise into their mining industries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;TechMet, a company in which the US International Development Finance Corporation (DFC) is the second largest shareholder, partnered with Life Zone Metals in Tanzania to build a new facility to process nickel and other critical minerals mined in Tanzania, with the goal of delivering battery-grade nickel to the global market as soon as 2026, according to the White House.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most mineral-rich African countries have little or no capacity for lithium processing or refining and their ore or mineral concentrate is usually exported to countries such as China for value adding to make lithium-ion batteries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the DRC, President Félix Tshisekedi said China had agreed to help the Central African nation develop supply chains for battery metals. Tshisekedi told China Media Group last week that the DRC&#39;s focus had been on mere mineral extraction, which was not enough to develop the economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today, we realise that without added value, these minerals are virtually worthless especially when compared to the level of development we aspire to achieve in our country,” Tshisekedi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The DRC is by far the world&#39;s largest exporter of cobalt, accounting for about 70 per cent of global production. It supplies China with 60 per cent of its cobalt. It is also rich in dozens of other metals, such as copper and lithium.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tshisekedi said Chinese companies planned to build a battery-making plant, which would export to the US and Europe, and create a “mutually beneficial industrial chain”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today, it is high time we process the minerals extracted here within the DRC. This will add value and, most importantly, create wealth and jobs in the DRC,” Tshisekedi said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are on the cusp of a promising venture in the manufacturing of power batteries in Manono. There, we bring together the Congolese government, Chinese companies and American and European companies as end users.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Lithium supply volatility, price war pose risk to EV makers&#39; financials&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Manono in the southeast of DRC was estimated in 2019 to have the world&#39;s largest untapped lithium deposit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chris Berry, president of commodities advisory firm House Mountain Partners in New York, said: “Officials in those countries know how to read price charts and realise that they are losing a great deal of value in allowing the export of raw ore.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is much more profitable to export refined concentrate or high purity materials. Having more of the supply chain in your country also creates jobs and tax revenue,” Berry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said it would take time for these countries to start to integrate vertically but it was not impossible. They needed capital, legal certainty and technical talent, Berry said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In December, Zimbabwe barred exports of the lithium in its raw form as part of efforts to have it processed locally, allowing only concentrates to be shipped out. Zimbabwe is estimated to have the largest unexploited reserve of lithium in Africa, attracting many Chinese companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, three Chinese companies – Zhejiang Huayou Cobalt, Sinomine Resource Group and Chengxin Lithium Group – have acquired lithium projects in Zimbabwe worth a combined US$679 million, amid the worldwide race to go green.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huayou Cobalt and Chengxin Lithium are already developing processing plants. Huayou Cobalt acquired the Arcadia hard-rock lithium mine outside Harare for US$422 million from Australian company Prospect Resources last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Saliem Fakir, executive director of the African Climate Foundation, said Namibia and other resource-rich nations had realised they could not operate in the way as they had done in the past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are concerns that raw ore gets exported or partially processed – and given the high price critical minerals are fetching – little value remains in the country where the mineral resides,” Fakir said. He said Indonesia had a ban on exports of raw nickel. It too wanted beneficiation, or to improve the value of the ore, within the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Countries with valuable critical minerals ought to exploit the monopoly they have over some of these minerals, like the DRC, and bargain for better deals,” Fakir said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Recycling key to China&#39;s self-sufficiency ambitions for the &#39;new oil&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;He said there was immense competition for these resources from rival major economies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These countries have become wise to the fact that they have a better position to bargain, and why not? Why not change the status quo before it is too late,” Fakir said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fakir said it made sense to produce batteries in countries where the key minerals were but “we need to ensure that battery demand grows beyond the DRC and other countries – that demand is an important stepping stone to ensuring sustainable manufacturing of batteries and greater value-add in Africa”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 18 Jun 2023 18:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>