<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[South China Sea: as Philippines hosts US-Japan-Australia drills, will external players’ presence escalate tensions?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3231960/south-china-sea-philippines-hosts-us-japan-australia-drills-will-external-players-presence-escalate?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/23/5f1c0844-2499-4d54-a231-5375ebc24709_71f0e67d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;本周的一系列军事活动可能预示着华南地区的新事态分析人士表示，在资源丰富的海域，“外部参与者”的存在增加了因误算而引发武装冲突的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周，美国、日本和澳大利亚正在开展联合海军演习菲律宾安全官员表示，在中国最近在争议海域表现出侵略行为后，菲律宾将在菲律宾西部附近的南海举行演习，以强调他们对法治的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;演习内容包括三架飞机和直升机航母一起航行展示武力，同时进行联合演习，指挥官随后将在马尼拉会见菲律宾同行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾周二完成了对驻扎在生锈的世界上的部队的补给二战时期的船只——BRP Sierra Madre——停泊在南中国海的一个珊瑚礁上，之前中国海岸警卫队船只向几艘菲律宾船只发射高压水枪，中国阻止了一次令人担忧的遭遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;日本东京国际大学国际安全研究副教授杰弗里·奥丹尼尔表示，只要“最大、最强大的声索国不满足于现状”，争议水道的紧张局势就会持续升级。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;他指出，最近发生的仁爱礁事件只是中国“通过强制手段改变现状”的一系列努力的一个例子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;菲律宾和几个西方国家，包括美国在内的一些国家批评中国在此次事件中使用高压水枪的做法是“危险的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，北京方面表示，其海岸警卫队在距离最近的海南岛 1,000 公里处开展行动，是“专业且专业的”克制”，并敦促菲律宾移除 1999 年故意在浅滩搁浅的马德雷山脉。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;水下珊瑚礁如何成为南海热点&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;奥丹尼尔说自 1999 年以来，马德雷山脉在珊瑚礁上的存在以及定期轮换部队和补给任务一直是“现状”，东南亚国家以及中国都通过 2002 年《关于各方行为宣言》做出了承诺。南海——“保持自我克制，不进行导致争端复杂化或升级的活动”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“简而言之，他们承诺不扰乱现状。中国阻止马尼拉的轮换和补给任务，扰乱了现状并加剧了紧张局势，违反了 2002 年[宣言]的精神。”总部位于外交政策研究所的奥丹尼尔表示，马尼拉明白自己无法独自抵御压力，并补充说，本周的美日澳联合演习旨在表明对菲律宾行使其权利的支持国际法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[演习]是中国在海上不良行为的后果。通过胁迫美国的条约盟友，北京在南海看到更多的西方海上力量，而不是更少，”奥丹尼尔说，但他补充说，马尼拉和小费迪南德·马科斯总统需要“重新调整”他们的政策。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;在前总统罗德里戈·杜特尔特 (Rodrigo Duterte) 的领导下，马尼拉适应了北京在南海问题上的许多政策偏好，包括搁置了 2016 年仲裁庭做出的有利于菲律宾的裁决，并驳回了中国对争议水道的大部分主张。&lt;/奥丹尼尔说，上届菲律宾政府也淡化了北京的胁迫，并探索在有争议海域寻求共同开发的方法。 “[然而]，中国没有做出回应……也没有表现出妥协的意愿。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于马尼拉的亚太进步之路基金会智囊团研究员卢西奥·布兰科·皮特洛三世 (Lucio Blanco Pitlo III) 表示通过联合巡逻或演习，盟军空中和水上资产在战略水道上的存在不断增加，这将增加“危险冲突的幽灵”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京的“高压手段”可能会迫使马尼拉加倍行动皮特洛表示，不愿与盟友和伙伴合作，并指出这样做也将加强马尼拉在任何海上争端谈判中的地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然菲律宾不会参加本周的演习，但它持开放态度菲律宾官员表示，未来将成为参与者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国可能会在南海加大对菲律宾的压力，以挫伤马尼拉重振与华盛顿联盟关系的热情，特别是因为它承担着南海问题的责任。”皮特洛说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在美国在亚太地区的五个条约盟友（其中包括澳大利亚、韩国、日本和泰国）中，菲律宾距离台湾最近。美国增加对菲律宾军事基地的准入预计也会对台湾海峡的任何冲突产生影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京将台湾视为一个叛离的省份，需要将其置于大陆的控制之下，必要时可以使用武力。包括美国在内的许多国家并未正式承认台湾是一个独立国家，但反对使用武力改变现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际发展与安全合作组织常驻研究员约书亚·伯纳德·埃斯佩尼亚 (Joshua Bernard Espeña) 认为马尼拉的坦克表示，由于各方都拒绝动摇其做法，南中国海的紧张局势可能会变得更加激烈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国在该海域的“无情”和破坏性活动已导致菲律宾陷入困境他说，“我已经受够了”的态度，而北京可能将马尼拉对美国、澳大利亚和日本等外部参与者的支持视为“破坏稳定”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国对外部影响发出警告在南海行为准则谈判之前&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;埃斯佩尼亚表示，马尼拉继续试图向仁爱礁运送物资将导致东南亚国家感到不安。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这可能会导致他说，东南亚国家联盟采取更积极主动的方式来缓解马尼拉与北京在南海的紧张局势，如果前一种选择不起作用，甚至可能采取单方面行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[前者] 只有在中国接受东盟中心地位的情况下，这种选择才会奏效。”埃斯佩尼亚说道，他指的是东盟的基石原则，即东盟必须成为克服共同挑战以及与外部势力接触的主导区域平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr >;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 09:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Disappearing ducks: astonished vets open up bulldog in China and find 11 swallowed rubber toys, solving owner’s vanishing waterfowl mystery]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3231795/disappearing-ducks-astonished-vets-open-bulldog-china-and-find-11-swallowed-rubber-toys-solving?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/328196b7-bff5-45ee-8a33-73ade3817305_fdfbd0ff.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一个中国女人的故事，她对为什么她的玩具橡皮鸭一直困惑不解她带着自己的宠物斗牛犬做CT扫描后，失踪事件被澄清，在内地社交媒体上引发热议和讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;狗的主人来自上海，姓刘，她告诉星视频，她经常收到小橡皮鸭作为免费礼物，并送给她的狗玩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然而，它们似乎突然消失了。考虑到之前还有一些玩具也神秘消失，我开始怀疑可能是被狗吞掉了。”刘女士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CT扫描证实了她的怀疑，宠物主人立即选择进行手术&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当狗被打开时，兽医惊讶地发现它的胃里有 11 个橡皮鸭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当我看到 CT 扫描时，我以为只有 5 个，当他们发现这个数字的两倍多时，他们大吃一惊。”刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;术后图像显示，许多橡皮鸭保留了原来的形状和亮黄色。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这只斗牛犬已从花费约 8,000 元人民币（1,100 美元）的手术中完全康复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事在大陆社交媒体上引起了宠物主人的共鸣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位在线观察者说：“这只宠物就像我家里的傻狗一样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很多人称赞刘女士对这只狗的喜爱，并准备花这么多钱做手术：“主人很对她的狗很慷慨！” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人猜测这些鸭子是某个柠檬茶品牌赠送的免费赠品，并开玩笑说：“喝完柠檬茶后，记得把小鸭子放在够不到的地方。”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;这样的故事并不是第一次引起社交媒体的关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年 7 月，一只狗在舔了不小心掉落在地上的有毒野生蘑菇后出现了幻觉，并开始咬一根想象中的骨头。据星视频报道，该楼层由其所有者拥有。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Despite Luna-25 spacecraft crash, China expected to continue working with Russia in race for moon base]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3231901/despite-luna-25-spacecraft-crash-china-expected-continue-working-russia-race-moon-base?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/6e6fd7ab-1cbd-453e-8f6a-d2e2adbffa3e_c19840c9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;尽管 Luna-25 航天器坠毁，俄罗斯可能仍将是中国的主要建造伙伴一位太空政策研究人员表示，尽管这次挫折可能会让美国主导的阿尔忒弥斯计划在自己的基地项目上取得进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯的机器人探测器原定在月球上着陆。俄罗斯航天局局长尤里·鲍里索夫周一对官方媒体表示，本周初，月球南极地区在周六降低轨道准备着陆的机动过程中遇到了发动机故障。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“而不是计划中的84秒，发动机工作了127秒。这是航天器坠毁的主要原因，”鲍里索夫在俄罗斯航天局分享的一次采访中告诉 Russia-24。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luna-25 是俄罗斯计划执行的一系列任务中的第一个。国际月球研究站（ILRS）是由中国和俄罗斯发起的项目，计划于2030年代中期在月球南极建立基地，旨在利用那里丰富的水冰资源进行长期勘探和定居。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，当被问及任务失败后中国是否仍将俄罗斯视为重要合作伙伴时，外交部发言人汪文斌表示，ILRS“向所有感兴趣的各方开放”，并且中国将始终“推动”阿拉巴马州蒙哥马利的独立太空政策学者纳姆拉塔·戈斯瓦米 (Namrata Goswami) 表示，Luna-25 的丢失不太可能导致&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“ILRS是两国之间的战略伙伴关系。中国国家主席习近平已将俄罗斯视为主要合作伙伴，因此这不会影响两国关系。”戈斯瓦米说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，“这向世界证明，中国是拥有经过验证的月球技术的国家，并且将必须支持俄罗斯的月球技术开发和融资，”她说。 “这与20世纪60年代、1970年代和1980年代的情况不同，当时苏联是主角，中国在后面。 Goswami 表示，随着俄罗斯 Luna-25 的失败，印度的 Chandrayaan-3 任务现在需要在与 Luna-25 计划相似的纬度着陆，风险很高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goswami 说。 >;&lt;h3>;美国宇航局局长警告月球南极可能成为“另一个南中国海”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;月船 3 号曾被描述为与 Luna-25 进行竞赛，于周六成功降低了轨道，预计将于周三进行首次着陆尝试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次着陆将得到西班牙和澳大利亚地面站的支持，这些地面站是美国宇航局深空网络的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果印度如果着陆成功，它将成为第一个登陆南极的国家，也是第一个登陆月球的阿耳忒弥斯签约国。由于俄罗斯作为 ILRS 合作伙伴的失败，这将使阿尔忒弥斯阵营领先。”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度于 6 月成为第 27 个签署美国主导的《阿尔忒弥斯协议》的国家。美国宇航局的商业月球着陆器 Nova-C 已被推迟，目前计划于 11 月发射。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goswami 表示，希望印度航天局从月船 2 号月球着陆器坠毁的事件中吸取教训。 2019年，由于制动系统故障，它在准备再次尝试月球表面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在太空中，失败并不罕见，在月球上软着陆并不容易。在过去十年的七次尝试中，只有中国的嫦娥三号、四号和五号任务成功到达月球表面，而印度、以色列、日本和现在的俄罗斯的航天器都坠毁了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;本月，日本日本宇宙航空研究开发机构(JAXA)计划发射其月球勘测智能着陆器(SLIM)，主要是探索如何将小型飞船精确着陆在月球上。日本也是《阿耳忒弥斯协议》的签署国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下一个 ILRS 任务将是 2024 年中国的嫦娥六号任务，它希望成为第一个从月球背面返回样本的任务。根据 6 月份《自然天文学》上发表的一篇论文，在阿波罗盆地附近选择了三个候选着陆点，以深入了解太阳系的早期历史以及月球的地质演化。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国公布2030年载人登月任务的首批细节&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国的嫦娥四号、六号和七号以及俄罗斯的月球25、26和27号任务被列为ILRS第一阶段的计划任务，根据中国国家航天局和俄罗斯航天局2021年发布的合作指南。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ILRS建设的第一阶段目标是月球侦察、选址和验证安全、高精度着陆技术。&lt; /p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Only a third of Hongkongers who recently moved to UK found full-time jobs, despite most being highly educated, survey reveals]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3231956/only-third-hongkongers-who-recently-moved-uk-found-full-time-jobs-despite-most-being-highly-educated?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 09:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/71397c25-df50-4bb7-a1d6-4c33de22c7a6_f3a003ba.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;近年来移居英国的香港人中，只有三分之一的人找到了完整的一项针对 BN(O) 签证持有者的英国大学调查显示，尽管大多数人都受过高等教育，但他们仍从事全职工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管拥有良好的教育背景，但许多移民仍难以充分利用其专业知识利物浦大学进行的在线调查显示，他们对移居后的专业知识有所了解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该大学对 1,310 名香港人进行了调查，其中大多数人在 2020 年国家安全法实施后移居英国。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几乎所有受访者都是英国国民（海外）签证持有者，只有不到 6% 的受访者持学生签证入境、寻求庇护或持有英国护照。该调查于去年11月1日至12月15日进行，结果于6月公布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有30%的人找到了全职工作，而18%的人从事兼职或自由职业者。大约18%的人失业，15%的人称自己是家庭主妇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查发现，78.4%的受访者接受过高等教育，其中30%拥有硕士学位或更高学历。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该研究的作者Ricci Yue pak-hong表示，结果显示，“大量”来自城市的农民工可能不得不从专业或管理职位转向第一产业或基础工作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;属于该类别的工作包括非技术或半技术工作，例如收银员、零售助理和货物运输。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;北京抨击伦敦为香港 BN(O) 提供签证快速通道）&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;岳补充说，一些农民工抵达后就失业了，而另一些人则完全离开了就业市场，成为了家庭主妇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这凸显了人力资本和劳动力资源的潜在浪费。岳说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他强调，应努力确保城市移民在过渡过程中获得机会和支持。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;从 2021 年 1 月推出至今年 3 月，约有 172,500 名香港居民申请了该签证计划，其中 96%（即 166,420 人）获得批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;保守党政府介绍这是回应北京实施国家安全法的途径，该法禁止分裂国家、颠覆、恐怖主义和与外国团体勾结的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在该市 750 万人口中，估计有 540 万人符合资格。该计划允许成功的申请人及其家属在英国生活、工作和学习长达五年，之后他们可以申请公民身份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查受访者认为政治原因是最重要的影响他们决定离开香港的因素，98% 的人表示担心集会和言论自由，以及对政府的信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在英格兰学校就读的香港学生人数激增 400%两年内&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;受访者中30至49岁的香港人占58%，29岁或以下的占13.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女性比例也较高高于所有年龄段的男性，比例为 75.5-100。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约 72% 的人已婚或同居，一半以上有孩子。大约五分之二的人与至少一名家庭成员一起移居英国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查发现，23.4%的香港人居住在英格兰东南部地区，其次是伦敦，占22%，北部地区占17%。西英格兰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查还发现，大多数香港社区聚集在英格兰东南部的伦敦和雷丁等主要城市周围。他们还定居在利物浦、曼彻斯特和邻近的沃灵顿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;移民居住最多的三个城市是伦敦、雷丁和曼彻斯特。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作者岳表示，这不是第一次移民1989 年天安门广场镇压后，约 30 万人离开香港，引发了对北京的恐惧。但数十万人在获得外国公民身份后返回。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港人对英国计划提出抗议表示担忧BN(O)费用、医疗附加费&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;当移民被问及是否打算在可预见的未来永久返回城市时，61%的人表示无意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只有2.1%表示有计划在获得英国公民身份后返回香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岳表示，这个数字表明最近的移民潮与以往不同，因为只有一小部分人的移民计划在可预见的未来返回香港。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 09:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong developers line up home sales at heavy discounts to clear unsold stock, fearful of further price cuts in a watchful market]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3231938/hong-kong-developers-line-home-sales-heavy-discounts-clear-unsold-stock-fearful-further-price-cuts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 08:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/24d744c9-8d1c-4e16-8986-a408213060e4_f3cbaaee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港一些最大的开发商已按修订后的价目表安排销售住宅项目以近期价格为基准，吸引谨慎买家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;港岛、九龙、新界三个项目合共293伙将于本周末推出。&lt;/p>;&lt;利嘉阁地产研究主管陈德瑞表示：“在油塘海岸线项目之前，房地产市场一直非常平静。” “开发商现在正在以接近或低于市场价格的价格来测试购房者的胃口，并以海岸线为参考。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;折扣将是他们清理库存的首选策略，他补充道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李嘉诚的房地产旗舰公司长实集团凭借降低定价策略取得了成功，在海岸线出售的 886 个单位中售出了 832 个单位，收入达 53.6 亿港元（6.84 亿美元）正在进行中。单位平均售价为每平方尺15,530港元，是七年来最便宜的，吸引了数千名购房者，他们在8月12日开盘首日购买了二期的全部单位，一期的95% &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长江实业周二公布了 35 套优质单位的价格表，其中包括 28 套复式单位和 4 套错层单位，销售将于周六进行。单位折扣后售价介乎798万至1,290万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年香港楼市明显放缓。根据仲量联行的最新报告，上半年竣工的 7,600 套公寓中，截至 6 月底仅售出 55%，低于过去五年 78% 的平均售出率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港仲量联行高级总监诺里·李 (Norry Lee) 表示，大多数买家采取观望态度，不愿购买公寓，因为他们预计价格会进一步下跌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新的大规模住宅项目必须提供更大的折扣来吸引买家，”李说。 “油塘海岸线就是一个例子，价格对买家有吸引力，标志着价格战的开始。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周一，嘉华置业信和置业开发的日出康城 Villa Garda III国际联手招商局置地公布第二批108伙售价：折算后平均每平方尺港币16,938元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该批包括98个两房单位及10个三房单位，介乎港元最高折扣15%后，售价为716万至1,270万港元，即每平方英尺15,884至17,681港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Villa Garda III的开发商上周四将首批130个单位定价为每平方英尺16,938港元折扣后平均每平方英尺售价比去年二期的每平方英尺18,378港元低7.8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据信和置业称，这238个单位预计将在周末发售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;h3>;“永远第一”：长实集团预言房地产衰退的历史&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;恒基兆业地产公布鲗鱼涌The Holborn 42个单位的价单，首20个单位单位将于本周六发售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;单位包括19个一房及1个两房单位，面积介乎255平方尺至413平方尺，售价由港币577万元至港币11.85元万元，折扣后每平方尺22,609港元至28,687港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Holborn的最新价目​​表比第一批低了近20%，”美联物业行政总裁Sammy Po表示。香港及澳门住宅分部。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恒基地产自7月中旬以来已售出56个单位，售价约3.7亿港元。自 2021 年推出以来，The Holborn 的 206 套公寓中的 93%（即 192 套）已找到买家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与该地区的新项目相比，开发商将其项目的价格降低 5% 至 10%利嘉阁的陈表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;仲量联行的李表示同意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们预计一些开发商将在今年晚些时候降价，而其他开发商可能会放慢项目启动速度，”他说。 &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 08:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[As China’s property crisis plagues its economy and financial system, is a ‘Lehman Moment’ looming?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3231900/chinas-property-crisis-plagues-its-economy-and-financial-system-lehman-moment-looming?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 08:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/22/294533d2-e361-4956-ac8b-be77dd3b5921_9f9de1ce.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;两年后，中国最大的房地产开发商之一创造了第一笔债券违约随着冲击波的冲击，北京方面关于一切都在掌控之中的承诺越来越难以向投资者推销。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年夏天，随着陷入困境的开发商中国恒大集团报告称其合计亏损达 8120 亿元人民币（1120 亿美元），人们的担忧进一步加剧。 ）2021年和2022年的收入——这一数字高于该公司自1996年成立以来的总收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司上周向美国法院提交的破产保护申请也引起了中国社交媒体的广泛关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;第 15 章请愿书提到了香港和开曼群岛正在进行的重组程序，也向北京提出了许多问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它如何安慰数十万民众？正在为尚未交付的房屋支付抵押贷款？如何安抚那些回避中国股市的忧心忡忡的投资者？它如何扭转越来越多的人对中国金融体系及其经济增长的悲观看法？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球投资者、中国购房者和经济学家现在都在屏息以待，看看下一个倒下的多米诺骨牌是哪一张，以及北京可以使用哪些工具来防止所谓的雷曼时刻——这一阶段源于 2008 年末全球投资银行雷曼兄弟的破产，用于描述系统性风险爆发的触发因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;债务时间目前，中国五大开发商之一的碧桂园正处于债券违约的边缘，预计 2023 年上半年的损失将在 450 亿元至 550 亿元之间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的数十家私人开发商也可能效仿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为不会出现雷曼时刻，”牛津大学中国中心研究员乔治·马格努斯 (George Magnus) 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为不会出现雷曼时刻。” >;&lt;p>;“在国家银行体系中，当局可以在金融体系中转移负债，并使用“扩展和假装”会计来确保大银行不会倒闭，并且小型银行可以在必要时得到改善或合并。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，他警告说，高连通性的多次故障将考验北京防止疫情蔓延的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果有人预计单一突发事件会导致银行业几近崩溃《红色资本主义：中国非凡崛起的脆弱金融基础》一书的合著者弗雷泽·豪伊 (Fraser Howie) 表示：据估计，该行对房地产行业的敞口很大，主要由中国工商银行、中国建设银行、中国银行和中国农业银行等四大银行控股。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;然而，Howie 补充道，“压力会以不同的方式发挥作用”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了地方债务和小银行压力之外，房地产是中国最突出的风险，因为它根深蒂固。融入国民经济，影响到从铁矿石开采商到钢铁和水泥生产商、家居装饰企业、家用电器制造商、建筑工人和数百万购房者。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国是否面临日本化的危险？它能做些什么来避免失去的几十年？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;它也被认为在全球范围内具有系统重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;17年前的美国次贷危机——其中涉及向受损的潜在借款人提供抵押贷款信用记录——被复杂的金融包装放大，最终演变成一场全球金融危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雷曼兄弟倒闭后，华盛顿救助了 AIG 和高盛等公司，而英国政府也将北方银行收归国有。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;房地产泡沫的破裂也加剧了 20 世纪 90 年代的日本危机，并导致了所谓的“失去的几十年的停滞”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国具体情况的一个挑战伦敦经济学院系统性风险中心主任乔恩·丹尼尔森 (Jon Danielsson) 表示：“非常高的增长可能会掩盖大量问题，而当增长放缓时，这些问题就会暴露出来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“就像湖水位下降，我们看到了很多我们不知道存在的东西。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丹尼尔森著作《控制的幻觉：金融危机为何发生以及我们能做什么》的中文翻译(and Can’t) Do About It，最近由中国财政部副部长廖敏翻译后引起关注。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丹尼尔森特别警告了“未知的未知风险”，这是超出政府了解和应对的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“教训是，危机事件的触发因素可能会突然出现，就像[美国]次贷[危机]一样，并且存在政府当局不可能了解所有这些情况，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“重要的是它如何应对危机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[但是，]当政策制定者和政府在没有事先计划或考虑所有角度的情况下在最后一刻做出反应，通常是因为他们希望事情会变得更好，这种情况的代价尤其高昂。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国的开发商享受了黄金时期这是自前总理朱镕基在 1998 年作为扩大内需计划的一部分启动住房私有化以来的时期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;住房私有化已成为支柱产业，在 2010 年代的鼎盛时期对国家经济增长的贡献率超过四分之一.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“坚持现金”：中国的潜在购房者选择等待房地产市场低迷结束&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;房价上涨也引发了更多的投机，迫使北京采取各种购买措施，销售、抵押贷款和信贷限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国人民银行2020年初的调查，房地产占家庭财富的59.1%，占家庭负债的四分之三。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;中国的房地产危机最初始于 2020 年初，当时冠状病毒导致主要开发商的现金流停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京的回应是在 2020 年 8 月划定了三条红线，以确定借款门槛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初推出这些政策的目的是认为房地产行业是中国最大的“灰犀牛”风险，并回应了习近平主席“房子是用来住的、不是用来炒的”的警告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At政府数据显示，截至6月底，房地产行业的银行贷款余额同比增长0.5%至53.37万亿元人民币（7.4万亿美元）。其中包括13.1万亿元的房地产开发商贷款和约38万亿元的抵押贷款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据中国数据提供商Wind对132家国内上市开发商的计算，去年销售收入合计下降了8.3%—— 2005年以来首次，而2022年其负债率为78.99%，仅略低于2019年的79.03%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，该数据不包括恒大等香港上市公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;Their return on equities registered the first decline on record of 3.78 per cent, and the domestically listed developers reported a combined loss of 66 billion yuan (US$9.1 billion) – also the first loss since the data became available.&lt; /p>;&lt;h3>;As China&#39;s debt risks mount, the spectre of looming local crises rears its head&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;They also had a new cash outflow of 285.6 billion yuan from their fundraising activities – a sign that the sector is struggling to seek external funding from banks, investments or bonds.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the problems have not significantly spilled over into the financial system.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The non-performing loan ratio in the property sector was 1.4 per cent when it was last released in 2020, the highest since 2010 but lower than 9.2 per cent in 2005 and 3.35 per cent in 2008, according to data provided by the National Financial Regulatory Administration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, though, has not updated the non-performing loan ratio for the property sector since 2020.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the overall non-performing loan ratio for commercial banks was just 1.62 per cent by the end of June, lower than 1.81 per cent four years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“State ownership provides Chinese banks with a degree of protection against problems elsewhere in the financial system and there are currently few signs of any strains in the interbank market,” said Julian Evans- Pritchard, chief China economist at Capital Economics.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“But even if a wider financial crisis is avoided, shadow bank failures are likely to result in tighter credit conditions for subprime borrowers.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Zhongzhi Enterprise Group, one of the country&#39;s largest private wealth managers, have reportedly failed to repay some maturing products under more than 1 trillion yuan of assets that the company manages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In late July, Zhongzhi reportedly hired professional services firm KPMG to conduct an audit of its balance sheet.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The next few weeks are crucial, as the clock is ticking for some of the major developers,” said Larry Hu, chief China economist at Macquarie Capital, who attributed the ongoing property woes to a downward spiral between confidence and sales.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now the game changer is a package of policy measures, which is strong enough to turn around the market expectation and pull the housing market out of the current downward spiral.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The one-way bet on property is now waning as the myth that China&#39;s property prices will keep rising has been broken.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The value of property sales in the first seven months of the year fell by 1.5 per cent to 7.05 trillion yuan, while the floor space sold dropped by 6.5 per cent from a year earlier to 665.6 million square metres (7.1 billion sq ft), government data showed.&lt;/ p>;&lt;h3>;Are China&#39;s houses for speculating? Beijing lets real estate off leash&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;After China&#39;s Politburo, headed by President Xi, removed the sentence that “houses are for living in, not for speculation” in July, markets have been expecting further policy relaxation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June, the central bank extended 200 billion yuan of relending quotas to ensure completion of unfinished property units and allow commercial banks to roll over maturing loans after the Evergrande crisis, extending the policies until the end of next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Different from Western bailouts, Beijing tends to allow state-owned players and banks to help absorb troubled companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the case of Evergrande, authorities dispatched special teams to the company to ensure the delivery of property units, the management of debt repayment and to ensure overall social stability.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a de-risking conference on Friday, China&#39;s central bank, as well as its banking and securities regulators, pledged to optimise credit policies and enrich tools to defuse local debt risk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must firmly defend the bottom line of preventing systemic risk,” they said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bridgewater founder Ray Dalio said that China is better positioned than many other countries because debts are largely in yuan and they are largely owed to domestic citizens and institutions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There is an obvious need for a big debt restructuring of the sort that Zhu Rongji engineered in the late 1990s, just much bigger,” he said on Friday, referring to Zhu&#39;s move to set up four national asset management companies to split bad loans from state banks.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;As China signals property revival, can &#39;risky&#39; real estate still drive growth?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The legendary fund manager&#39;s “beautiful deleveraging” theory, which balances deflationary defaults and restructurings with debt monetisation to spread out the burden, has attracted significant attention from high-ranking Chinese officials in the past five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the government has tools to change the dire economic situation then they either aren&#39;t using them or they are not working,” added Howie.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The best scenario is muddling through where the government manages a slew of chronic economic problems and hopes they don&#39;t become acute ones which could have significant shocks or cause panic, ie allowing localised bank failures but ensuring the state banks in big cities don&#39;t see [bank] runs.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A likely outcome, according to Magnus, is that the real estate waves are likely to last a long time and the only viable solution is by allocating the costs of the crisis to someone – government, banks or homebuyers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In China&#39;s case, this might mean the resocialisation of much of the housing sector,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t think anyone should think there&#39;s a free lunch out there or that this won&#39;t be a painful experience.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[To win over global talent, Hong Kong must show its freedoms aren’t lost]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231786/win-over-global-talent-hong-kong-must-show-its-freedoms-arent-lost?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/67a122ba-41e3-4129-b4a9-61bc472e98ec_ffded105.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Much has been made concerning the dearth of talent coming to Hong Kong after the exodus following years of social unrest, the Covid-19 pandemic and negative perceptions about what Hong Kong has become. This triple whammy of bad headlines has percolated around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We were a beacon of free trade, stability and liberal values. The city sat well with large numbers of high-quality expatriates who came to Hong Kong to answer the call for top-tier talent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first two issues have largely passed into history, and harmony has returned to the city, but negative perceptions linger. This is an ongoing push factor despite many strong pull factors remaining: a globally significant fintech sector, robust economy, strong regulatory and compliance infrastructure, world-leading universities, and vibrant nightlife.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even given these advantages, a replacement influx remains elusive. Our global city needs global talent, today – even if our overall population has edged up 2.1 per cent in a year, thanks to the border reopening and largely mainland response to talent schemes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, what can Hong Kong do to get back its mojo, restore faith and regain its place at the top of the class in business, banking, fintech, investment and its other strengths?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is no reason to be passive and just hope things will return to the “good old days”;我们可以积极主动。新加坡等竞争对手正在为人才招聘提供激励措施，我们也应该这样做。一半量的产量少于半满的玻璃杯。 A revitalised government committee could focus on this issue while ensuring key sectors&#39; voices are heard.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;How Hong Kong can look within to nurture the talent it needs&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Officials could consider a number of schemes, for example: placing ads in target countries extolling the opportunities and lifestyle Hong Kong offers;一套更新的宣传视频；由政府支持的关键行业企业路演前往大城市吸引新人才； and a support scheme for talent that provides incentives in key areas such as subsidies, advice and sharing information.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Surveys of foreign workers who left Hong Kong could be carried out to discover the underlying reasons for their departure; we should learn from their responses and address their concerns to reduce the push factors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city could seek to diversify its talent pool by embracing emerging sectors and smart-city industries as befits the vision for the Northern Metropolis. It should also address concerns about Hong Kong&#39;s press freedom, judicial independence, legal protections and regulatory resilience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One important issue is the global perception of Hong Kong&#39;s national security law, a topic that has emerged as a strong push factor.感知一旦形成，就会成为一股强大的力量，而且一旦发生，就很难改变。 This is something that can happen in any field, including science.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One recent story that could help quell concerns about the national security law and judicial independence is the Court of Appeal quashing one of two charges against Jimmy Lai Chee-ying and six former opposition lawmakers for their roles during the 2019 protest movement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whether you agree with the court&#39;s decision is not the important thing. Rather, it sends a signal to the world that Hong Kong&#39;s legal system allows such outcomes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These developments run counter to the perception that Hong Kong is not able to apply its own laws to local matters.强化积极信息的故事必须广泛传播。如果政府想玩聪明的政治，就不会对法院的判决提出上诉，而是大方地接受判决。 Justice will be done.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is no shortage of reports in foreign media that feed the perception that dissent is stifled in Hong Kong, that Beijing is running everything and that the freedoms the city once enjoyed are a thing of the past. These are exaggerated, but the perception generated by these reports persists.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We are at a crossroads on this important issue that gives talented people who might be drawn to Hong Kong reason to think twice.更清晰的领导和方向，也许在幕后明智的建议的帮助下，将使真相变得显而易见。 This will help restore Hong Kong to its place as a beacon that attracts the cream of the world&#39;s talent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 08:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Canada’s Deputy PM Chrystia Freeland, who does not own a car, fined for speeding]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231969/canadas-deputy-pm-chrystia-freeland-who-does-not-own-car-fined-speeding?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 07:27&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/269453e2-a352-4a8a-a6ad-e6e22566e636_d1c16fc6.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Canadian Deputy Prime Minister and Finance Minister Chrystia Freeland, an avid cyclist who says she does not own a car, was fined C$273 (US$200) for speeding in her home province of Alberta, a spokesperson said on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Freeland was caught driving 132km/h (82mph) between the towns of Grande Prairie and Peace River and has paid the ticket in full, her spokeswoman Katherine Cuplinskas said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The news was first broken by the Counter Signal website.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cuplinskas did not say when the incident occurred and what the speed limit had been on that stretch of road.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The maximum speed limit on Alberta highways is 110km/h.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Freeland is a legislator who represents a parliamentary constituency in central Toronto, Canada&#39;s largest city, and is often photographed on her bike.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trudeau names Canada&#39;s first woman finance minister amid ethics scandal&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“A fact that still shocks my dad is that I don&#39;t actually own a car,” she told reporters last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I walk, I take the subway. My kids walk and ride their bikes and take the subway – it&#39;s actually healthier for our family,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s gloomy economic outlook has taken the fizz out of consumer spending, PwC says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3231935/chinas-gloomy-economic-outlook-has-taken-fizz-out-consumer-spending-pwc-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/06e7d054-5848-4e4f-b8e0-ef324724d833_9d23f18b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Chinese consumers are adjusting their spending habits to account for the country&#39;s less-than optimistic economic outlook, according to global advisory firm PwC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The crisis in China&#39;s real estate sector and high youth unemployment are among concerns weighing on consumer spending, it said in a report published on Tuesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Although the degree of financial concern felt by Chinese consumers is less acute than global counterparts, consumers have been holding back on non-essential spending,” said Michael Cheng, PwC Asia-Pacific consumer markets leader.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The recent weakness of the yuan together with poor real estate and equity performance, coupled with a record-high youth unemployment rate, has dampened consumer spending. Consumers feel the pinch of financial uncertainty, which has further undermined consumer confidence and heightened risk of deflation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PwC report is significant because Beijing has been trying to encourage domestic consumption as a way of driving and growing its economy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report, which has been published twice a year since 2021, surveyed about 9,000 consumers in 25 countries.报告发现，消费需求的减少和对未来的普遍不确定性导致中国的消费更加精明。 Consumers are less likely to make impulse purchases and are focusing on quality and value as well as promotions, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Chinese consumers wary of parting with hard-earned money amid slowdown: study&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;An area that is likely to see more spending is travel, the report showed, with Chinese consumers willing to spend more on their itineraries than any other nationality polled. About 62 per cent of the Chinese consumers surveyed said they would increase their spending on travel related activities slightly or significantly, compared to a global average of 40 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than half of the Chinese respondents said they were extremely likely to travel internationally in the second half of the year, compared to a global average of 44 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But a sense of caution prevails here too. A separate report published by Economist Intelligence Unit on Tuesday said the number of international flights in operation during the summer holidays in China was only half of the levels seen in 2019. The country&#39;s tally of outbound tourists is not anticipated to exceed pre-pandemic levels until 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At home, consumption in the first half of the year was driven mainly by catering services, luxury goods and apparel and footwear. Spending on catering services increased by 21.4 per cent year on year, while luxury goods increased by 17.5 per cent, and apparel and footwear increased by 12.8 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese consumers are being smarter about where they buy their essential items, by using WeChat groups and live-streaming promotions to get the best deals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the most significant changes in consumer behaviour has been a shift towards more pragmatic and rational decision-making, the PwC report said. Consumers are caring more about the price to value and quality, said Nicole Sun, PwC China M&amp;A advisory partner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On the other hand, other consumers purchase luxury goods to make themselves feel good after Covid-19,” Sun added. China&#39;s ultra-rich consumers are still spending a large portion of their disposable income on luxury brands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mainland Chinese tourists&#39; spending habits in Hong Kong have also changed, with more visitors from the mainland opting to spend on cultural activities now, said Cheng.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The launch of duty-free shopping in Hainan has significantly boosted tourism to the island province at the cost of Hong Kong. Promotions on luxury goods on the island combined with a strengthening Hong Kong dollar have also hurt the city&#39;s price advantage for high-end goods.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Alibaba chief strategist says small business &#39;more important&#39; in slowing economy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China has been trying to get mainland consumers to buy luxury goods domestically, which has been taking a toll on Hong Kong&#39;s luxury retailers, Cheng said. “But while there is still a price advantage in Hong Kong – whether its 5, 10 or 15 per cent – the city will always have an advantage.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luxury brands are still “ready to develop their position in the city and expand their presence”, Cheng added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong should diversify by attracting the emerging middle classes in Southeast Asia, as visits and spending by mainland tourists, the key driver of Hong Kong&#39;s retail sales, have not yet bounced back to pre-pandemic levels as expected, Cheng said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;China&#39;s Gen-Z consumers prep for bout of &#39;revenge&#39; spending on personal care&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;By the end of the year, mainland tourist arrivals should rebound to about 60 per cent of pre-Covid-19 levels, reaching an expected 25 million visitors over the year, according to PwC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Hong Kong&#39;s retail sales grew by 20.7 per cent in the first half of 2023, driven by the government&#39;s consumption voucher schemes. PwC, however, expected the second half to be lacklustre, with retail sales for the total year forecast to grow by 17 per cent to HK$408 billion (US$52.05 billion).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Hong Kong residents too opt to spend more on travel, there will be less spending at domestic retailers.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 07:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[First Donald Trump allies in Georgia election subversion case surrender]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231968/first-donald-trump-allies-georgia-election-subversion-case-surrender?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 06:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/23/db5f29f2-adcc-46a8-bb0e-2c2a9e48819c_f2f39f12.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The first of Donald Trump&#39;s co-defendants in Georgia&#39;s criminal case accusing the former US president and his associates of subverting his 2020 election loss surrendered at an Atlanta jail on Tuesday, according to county records and a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump&#39;s former lawyer John Eastman and Republican poll watcher Scott Hall both surrendered to the county sheriff&#39;s office, two days before Trump himself was set to turn himself into face his fourth criminal indictment this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump, the front-runner for the Republican 2024 White House nomination, has lambasted all the prosecutions as politically motivated and continues to claim falsely that his 2020 loss to Democratic President Joe Biden was the result of fraud.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eastman said in a statement he would surrender, the day after agreeing to a US$100,000 bond agreement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am here today to surrender to an indictment that should never have been brought,” Eastman said in the statement. “It represents a crossing of the Rubicon for our country, implicating the fundamental First Amendment right to petition the government for redress of grievances.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hall, a Republican poll watcher in Georgia&#39;s Fulton County, was booked by the county&#39;s sheriff&#39;s office on Tuesday and has not yet been released, the jail records showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hall previously agreed to a US$10,000 bond deal requiring that he report to pre-trial supervision every 30 days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump on Monday agreed to post a US$200,000 bond and accepted bail conditions that would bar him from threatening co-defendants or witnesses in the case.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Trump says he will be arrested on Thursday over Georgia election case&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In a 41-count Georgia indictment unveiled last week, Trump and 18 other defendants were charged with racketeering and other crimes over their efforts to reverse Trump&#39;s loss in the state to Biden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prosecutors are seeking a trial in March, but the number of defendants and complexity of the case could lead to delays.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mark Meadows, Trump&#39;s former chief of staff, sought last week to move the case to federal court and dismiss it on the grounds he is immune from prosecution for actions he took as a federal official.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meadows asked to delay his surrender until after a hearing in federal court on Monday but was rebuffed by Fulton County District Attorney Fani Willis, who told his lawyers she will seek his arrest if he does not turn himself in by Friday afternoon, court records showed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump and the rest of the defendants are likely to raise similar arguments, which could cause delays as their lawyers spar with prosecutors in pretrial litigation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trump faces indictments in three other separate criminal cases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has been charged in Washington over his efforts to overturn the election, in Florida over his handling of classified documents upon leaving office, and in New York over a hush money payment to a porn star.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fintech giant Ant Group, back in Beijing’s good graces, uses Alipay+ to burnish Hangzhou’s tech image for Asian Games]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3231903/fintech-giant-ant-group-back-beijings-good-graces-uses-alipay-burnish-hangzhous-tech-image-asian?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.23 07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/22/ce69c8fc-b1b6-4f57-86ff-3a4e695d25d3_184deb0c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ant Group, which was forced to pull its US$40 billion initial public offering at the last minute in 2020, is regaining the government&#39;s favour as its payment service Alipay is promoted as a key element to a successful Asian Games, the biggest public relations event for the city of Hangzhou this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the downtown centre of the capital city of eastern Zhejiang province, where Jack Ma started Alibaba Group Holding and later its spin-off Ant, nearly all stores now prominently display their digital payment codes, promoting Hangzhou as a cashless society. Alibaba owns the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to the usual codes for Alipay and WeChat Pay, from rival Tencent Holdings, which are ubiquitous across China, an increasing number of stores in Hangzhou include signs in English reading, “pay with your home e-wallet”, with the logos of other Asian digital wallet services displayed on the sign. This is part of Ant&#39;s efforts to improve the experience for foreigners travelling in the city, particularly for the Asian Games, which were postponed from last year and run from September 23 to October 8.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I put this notice on the wall one or two months ago after [Ant employees] came to the store and introduced this to me,” said Wu Linfeng, a 64-year-old who runs a street stall selling local Hangzhou food on Zhongshan South Road in the city centre. “Foreign visitors can just scan and pay.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Ant Group&#39;s Alipay widens support for Visa, Mastercard, other major credit cards&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Ant has worked with other companies to make its quick-response (QR) codes compatible with a number of different digital wallets, meaning many visitors from around Asia can use whatever apps they already have on their phones to pay for goods. Merchants do not need to change anything, according to Alipay+, the global cross-border digital payments and marketing solution from Ant, which facilitates the payments and converts the currencies from overseas wallets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The success of Alipay and WeChat Pay has made China a global model for the shift to mobile payments as cash has all but disappeared from many shops and street stalls in recent years.然而，这让许多无法使用装有人民币的本地数字钱包的中国游客感到困难。 In another bid to help remove this barrier, Alipay has recently expanded support for foreign credit cards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing once hailed China&#39;s Big Tech firms like Alibaba and Tencent as part of a long tradition of innovation in the country that includes inventions like gunpowder and the compass. However, an abrupt shift in policy three years ago cast a pall over the tech industry.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, Chinese authorities sought to curb the influence of internet platforms in the name of reining in the “irrational expansion of capital”, wiping trillions of dollars in value from tech stocks.几周前马云发表有争议的演讲后，北京方面挫败了蚂蚁金服备受期待的首次公开募股，从而开始了打击行动。 Ant was later told to follow the same regulatory rules as conventional banks, putting limits on how big it could scale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The crackdown eased at the end of 2022 as Beijing again shifted its attention to economic growth, hoping Big Tech could help the country recover from strict zero-Covid policies that had curbed a lot of commercial activity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In January this year, Ant overhauled its shareholding structure, diluting the voting power of founder Ma to make China&#39;s largest fintech company more “transparent and diversified”. Last month, the financial regulators fined the fintech giant a total of 7.1 billion yuan (US$984.3 million) for breaking rules related to “corporate governance and financial consumer protection”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ant&#39;s latest efforts in Hangzhou are illustrative of how tech giants are starting to spread their wings again. Wu, the merchant, said Ant employees had stopped by her stall at least two or three times to promote Alipay+.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ant is also competing with its Shenzhen-based rival.腾讯的微信现在允许香港和马来西亚的用户使用自己的货币设置本地钱包。 Like Alipay, WeChat Pay has also expanded support for international debit cards and credit cards from Visa, Mastercard and others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The connection between Ant and Hangzhou runs deep. In May, the fintech firm and the municipal government signed a wide-ranging collaboration that is expected to speed up the city&#39;s digital transformation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Asian Games marks one of the most important events for the Hangzhou government in recent years. The city, which had just three subway lines when it won its bid in 2015 to host the games, now has 12 lines running throughout the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Lu, director of cross-border business in Greater China at Ant&#39;s International Business Group, said the company&#39;s support for the games comes mainly through facilitating services and payments. “Now that we already have supported local wallets from Malaysia, South Korea and Hong Kong, under instruction from the central government, we are aiming to support 10 digital wallets before the Asian Games kick off,” Fu said in an interview last week.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Visitors coming from a country that does not have an e-wallet connected through Alipay+ can download the mainland Alipay app and connect their home bank cards to the app, Fu added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to expanding payment options, some shops see the Ant&#39;s new services as helping them modernise in other ways. Florasis, a beauty brand known for its cosmetics, set up the Alipay+ service for its flagship store near West Lake.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For us, the set-up cost is very low,” said Kun Ni, the head of branding at Florasis. “这也是我们进行跨境营销的一个很好的工具。 For example, sales information can be sent through the app.”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 23 Aug 2023 07:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>