<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[International outcry as Uganda’s anti-gay bill signed into law]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3222246/international-outcry-ugandas-anti-gay-bill-signed-law?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.30 05:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/30/a852a62e-3189-46d9-93e1-03a7668f1747_146975bd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;乌干达周一宣布总统约韦里·穆塞韦尼签署了严厉的反同性恋新措施被描述为世界上最严厉的措施之一，引发了人权和 LGBTQ 群体以及西方大国的谴责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔拜登呼吁立即废除他抨击为“对普遍人权的悲惨侵犯”的措施权利”，并威胁要削减对这个东非国家的援助和投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;穆塞韦尼的办公室表示，《2023 年反同性恋法案》是总统周日签署成为法律的六项立法之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;立法者本月早些时候通过了新的立法草案，誓言抵制他们所说的外部干涉，他们努力保护乌干达的价值观免受西方不道德行为的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;修订版说，将身份识别为同性恋不会被定罪，但“从事同性恋行为”将被判处无期徒刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管穆塞韦尼曾建议立法者删除将“严重同性恋”定为死罪的条款，但立法者拒绝了这一举措，这意味着尽管乌干达已经多年未执行死刑，但累犯可能会被判处死刑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个人权组织周一晚些时候宣布，它已向乌干达高等法院提出法律质疑，称该立法“公然违宪”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过将我们称之为成年人之间自愿的同性行为定为犯罪，它违反了宪法的关键条款，包括平等和非歧视权利，”Adrian Jjuuko 说，人权意识和促进论坛执行主任。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“大门终于敞开”：斯里兰卡法院为将同性恋合法化铺平了道路&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;拜登说他已要求他的国家安全委员会评估法律对“美国与乌干达交往的各个方面”的意义，包括提供艾滋病救济和其他援助和投资的服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，政府还将考虑对乌干达实施制裁，并限制进入&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟外交政策负责人 Josep Borrell 表示，乌干达政府“有义务保护其所有公民并维护他们的基本权利”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“如果不这样做，将破坏与国际伙伴的关系，”他在一份声明中警告说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;英国是乌干达的前殖民大国，在其统治期间将同性恋定为犯罪行为，称这是“感到震惊”，并称这项法律具有“严重的歧视性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“它将增加暴力、歧视和迫害的风险，将阻碍与艾滋病毒/艾滋病的斗争，”英国发展和非洲部长安德鲁·米切尔 (Andrew Mitchell) &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国人权高专办的专员沃尔克·特克在 3 月份称该法案是“世界上同类法案中最糟糕的”，也谴责该法案成为法律。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“这是系统性侵犯 LGBT 人群和更广泛人群权利的良方，”该办公室在 Twitter 上表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;英国 LGBTQ 退伍军人遭受转变治疗，政治迫害：报告&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;人权观察组织非洲副主任阿什瓦尼·布杜-舒尔茨 (Ashwanee Budoo-Scholtz) 表示，这是“歧视性的，是朝着保护乌干达所有人人权的错误方向迈出的一步”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大赦国际组织还表示，签署这项“深度压制性的法律是对人权的严重侵犯”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这项立法在乌干达得到了广泛的公众支持，乌干达是一个基督教徒占多数的国家，一直在推行一些最严厉的反非洲的同性恋立法，那里大约有 30 个国家禁止同性恋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们坚定地捍卫我们人民的文化、价值观和愿望，”议会议长 Anita Among 是该法案的主要支持者之一，他说在一份声明中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;议会对该法案的讨论充斥着仇视同性恋的诽谤，穆塞韦尼本人将同性恋者称为“越轨者”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Frank Mugisha，性少数群体执行董事乌干达表示，该法律将对该国已经受到迫害的 LGBTQ 社区“带来很多伤害”。 “我们感到非常、非常、非常担心，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;修订后的法案规定，“被认为或被指控或怀疑是同性恋者，未与他人发生性行为的人同性，不犯同性恋罪。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;较早的版本还要求乌干达人向警方报告涉嫌同性恋活动，否则将面临六个月的监禁。立法者同意修改该条款，取而代之的是报告要求仅涉及涉嫌对儿童和弱势群体的性犯罪，刑罚提高至五年监禁。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌干达严厉的新反同性恋立法遭到了联合国、人权组织&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;任何“故意宣扬同性恋”的人都将面临最高 20 年的监禁，而被判犯有鼓励同性性行为的组织可能面临 10 年的禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在穆塞韦尼 (Museveni) 多年的专制统治之后，乌干达民间团体的反应变得平淡无奇。但欧洲议会在 4 月投票谴责该法案，并要求欧盟国家向穆塞韦尼施压，要求其不要执行该法案，并警告说，与坎帕拉的关系岌岌可危。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发起该法案的国会议员阿苏曼·巴萨利瓦 (Asuman Basalirwa) 表示削减援助是意料之中的事，议会议长 Among 已经被告知她的美国签证已被吊销。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据乌干达的一份声明，该法案还有可能破坏乌干达在抗击艾滋病毒/艾滋病方面取得的进展联合国艾滋病规划署、全球抗击艾滋病、结核病和疟疾基金以及美国总统艾滋病紧急救援计划 (PEPFAR)。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自英国脱离英国独立以来，从未有人对双方同意的同性性行为定罪1962.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US says China declined request for defence chief Li Shangfu to meet Pentagon head Lloyd Austin]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222245/us-says-china-declined-request-defence-chief-li-shangfu-meet-pentagon-head-lloyd-austin?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.30 04:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/30/f2888ed2-0687-4f68-8b7b-0d6d04f04f37_afcdcfd2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国要求国防部长劳埃德·奥斯汀会见国防部长李尚福，中国拒绝了本周在新加坡，五角大楼称之为“不愿”参与军事讨论的部分原因。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国国防部“坚信保持开放的军方沟通渠道的重要性五角大楼新闻秘书帕特莱德准将在周一的一份声明中表示，华盛顿和北京之间的关系，以确保竞争不会演变成冲突。定于新加坡举行的香格里拉对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国要求美国解除 2018 年对李强实施的制裁，原因是他在监督从俄罗斯购买武器方面发挥的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据彭博新闻社早些时候报道，中国曾辩称，如果继续实施制裁，李克强将无法与奥斯汀平起平坐。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国外交部长秦刚与美国特使打破外交僵局&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;此次拒绝是美国加强与中国军事交流努力的最新回绝，尽管在今年早些时候据称中国间谍气球飞越美国领土后，两国正在采取试探性措施使双边关系重回正轨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;莱德说，美国的制裁指定“并不妨碍奥斯汀国务卿在处理美国政府公务的过程中与他会面”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why DeSantis is no match for Trump in the race for the Republican presidential nomination]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3221989/why-desantis-no-match-trump-race-republican-presidential-nomination?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.30 03:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/28/6f06370c-7b44-49cc-ba65-b6970d2daec6_0f604666.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Ron DeSantis 上周在 Twitter Spaces 上以灾难性的形象宣布了他的美国总统候选人资格。对许多人来说，德桑蒂斯是唐纳德特朗普七年来共和党总统候选人提名的第一个严肃挑战者。但他更有可能遭遇与杰布·布什、马可·卢比奥和特德·克鲁兹相同的命运——他们在 2016 年的提名中都输给了特朗普。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，德桑蒂斯获胜，结局再好不过了他在 11 月的连任中以近 20 个百分点的优势当选，而其他大多数共和党人在关键的中期选举中表现不佳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯在 Covid-19 大流行期间或多或少地保持佛罗里达州的开放，从而获得了超越他所在州的支持，同时大多数其他州都关闭了。有那么一刻，当福克斯新闻几乎宣布他是被选中的人时，他甚至看起来在人气方面将超过特朗普，导致他在民意调查中名列前茅，与特朗普进行假设的对决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为什么不是？他的政策对大多数保守派来说是天赐之物。他不仅放宽了枪支法并更容易判处死刑，而且还是共和党最著名的文化斗士，他采取了反觉醒行动，包括禁止在小学讨论性取向。&lt;/p>;然而，自连任以来，德桑蒂斯经历了艰难的几个月，这引发了他是否已准备好迎接黄金时段的问题。他犯了一个失礼，称俄罗斯对乌克兰的战争是“领土争端”，同时建议美国停止支持基辅。巨大的反弹，甚至来自党内的强烈反对，迫使他掉头——这只会让他看起来更糟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后他决定在佛罗里达州六周后签署堕胎禁令，不是国家舞台上的政治赢家。最后但并非最不重要的一点是，他的迪士尼传奇永无止境，最终导致这家娱乐公司取消了在佛罗里达州耗资数十亿美元的开发计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，这些进展在美国总统竞选中并不少见。德桑蒂斯只是经历了在他之前的其他候选人所经历的：面对全国的聚光灯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在小池塘里做大鱼是一回事，但一旦候选人成为全国聚光灯下的焦点，突然间就完全不同了提出共和国的愿景，同时被赶出他们的舒适区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鲁迪·朱利安尼 (Rudy Giuliani) 在 2007 年参加共和党竞选时是“美国市长”，在该领域遥遥领先，但他未能在早期初选中的糟糕结果之后进入超级星期二。得克萨斯州州长里克·佩里 (Rick Perry) 在 2011 年也领先该领域，但在他开始出现在全国辩论舞台后令人印象深刻地弃牌了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯现在甚至没有领先。根据民意调查，高达 20% 的共和党选民希望提名德桑蒂斯，但 58% 的人会投票给特朗普。德桑蒂斯必须弥补很多不足，他的选择有限。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;批评者称特朗普是自恋者、俄罗斯资产、臭名昭著的骗子和对美国民主的威胁，但即使是他最著名的批评者也不能忽视他富有魅力的个性。他是票房娱乐，一种让人无法抗拒的自然力量。他的出现让支持者兴奋不已。就像 2016 年一样，他的政策不连贯，有时根本不存在，这在共和党初选中无关紧要。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯不具备这些品质。他受过高等教育，可能对宪法了如指掌，并且与特朗普不同，他可以命名、理解和解释政策。但他很冷漠。当他不得不与选民互动时，他显得木讷，甚至有些笨拙。他在辩论舞台上的露面不会改变现状。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他决定不在欢呼的人群面前而是通过 Twitter Spaces 发起竞选活动，这完美地说明了这一点。它还显示了另一个让德桑蒂斯对特朗普付出沉重代价的主要缺点：他不是一个有统治力的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果说在总统竞选中有一个时刻必须投射权力和支配地位，那就是当宣布跑步。但德桑蒂斯在埃隆·马斯克的阴影下进入 Twitter 泡沫，从而削弱了自己。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德桑蒂斯从不厌倦表现得像个强人，愿意并且能够与“精英”或“社会主义者”较量。但是，在他政治生涯的最关键时刻，他寻求世界上最富有的人之一的保护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的竞选信条“永不退缩”，考虑到德桑蒂斯只在他严厉打击，例如当他对戴口罩的学童大喊大叫时，让移民上公共汽车去玛莎葡萄园岛或叫米老鼠时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在初选中，只有一个真正的问题：谁是卑鄙的足够强硬来对抗特朗普？到目前为止，答案不是德桑蒂斯。特朗普称德桑蒂斯是假特朗普，并发起了其他攻击，这些攻击基本上没有得到回应，德桑蒂斯既不愿意也不能直接攻击特朗普。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共和党基地仍然爱特朗普。 28% 的共和党初选选民表示，即使他以独立候选人身份参选，他们也会支持他。难以想象特朗普的支持者会为了一个没有表现出几乎相同的权力和恶毒的人而集体抛弃他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在共和党初选中，获胜者基本上通吃，为黄金时间做好准备；德桑蒂斯不是，特朗普将尽情享受他的形象和缺乏统治力，直到获得提名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 03:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[LGBTQ Russians flee to Argentina seeking refuge from discrimination, Ukraine war]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3222218/lgbtq-russians-flee-argentina-seeking-refuge-discrimination-ukraine-war?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.30 03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/465c31fc-1b5a-4794-a0a5-9a9bfbdd0330_333a0f89.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;阿纳斯塔西娅·多米尼 (Anastasia Domini) 和她的妻子安娜·多米尼 (Anna Domini) 在最近一个阳光明媚的日子里手拉手散步阿根廷首都布宜诺斯艾利斯，他们的四个不安分的孩子在附近玩耍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在同性婚姻合法化十多年的国家，同性伴侣随处可见。但这对去年初抵达这座城市后不久就结婚的夫妇仍然记得他们离开俄罗斯后第一次决定在公共场合牵手时的恐惧，俄罗斯在 2020 年明确禁止同性婚姻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这真的很可怕，”阿纳斯塔西娅说，但“我们环顾四周，真的，真的没有人在看”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于 Dominis，他们改了姓氏，这样他们就可以更有说服力地假装作为俄罗斯的姐妹，这次散步证明了她们搬家后生活发生了多大的变化，加入了越来越多的 LGBTQ 俄罗斯人的行列，他们决定离开自己的祖国并在阿根廷定居，以逃避歧视和与乌克兰的战争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在过去十年中，作为 LGBTQ 社区的一员在俄罗斯公开生活变得越来越困难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 12 月，俄罗斯总统弗拉基米尔·普京签署了一项法律，大幅扩大了对被视为促进 LGBTQ 的活动的限制权利，建立在自 2013 年生效的法律之上，独立研究人员称该法律导致针对性少数群体的暴力行为激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，克里姆林宫甚至将 2022 年 2 月对乌克兰的入侵定为部分原因作为捍卫保守价值观反对西方促进同性恋和变性人权利的一种方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自战争开始以来，阿根廷 LGBT 联合会收到了大约 130 份来自俄罗斯人的询问，他们有兴趣在阿根廷寻求庇护，比任何其他国籍的人都多.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“俄罗斯和乌克兰之间的冲突加速了许多已经处于脆弱境地的人的决定，”该组织国际关系部门负责人 Maribe Sgariglia 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; LGBTQ 社区的成员并不是唯一前往阿根廷的俄罗斯人。根据政府数据，1 月份有 4,523 名俄罗斯人进入该国，是去年同月抵达的 1,037 人的四倍多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年，约有 22,200 名俄罗斯人进入阿根廷，其中包括大量孕妇飞往该国分娩，部分原因是为了获得打开更多大门的护照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至少对于一些抵达阿根廷的俄罗斯人来说，该国不是他们的第一选择。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马克·博亚尔斯基 (Mark Boyarsky)，一名 38 岁的跨性别男人，在俄罗斯开始入侵乌克兰后不久，他带着妻子和两个分别为 5 岁和 8 岁的孩子离开了莫斯科，他首先搬到了尼泊尔，以期获得英国签证。经过几个月毫无结果的几个月后，他们决定在 9 月搬到阿根廷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Boyarsky 说，“我在这里感觉很安全”，并指出他还没有告诉他的孩子他是跨性别者，因为“感觉太过分了”考虑到人们普遍认为“俄罗斯没有同性恋”，知道这一点对他们来说是危险的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2010 年，婚姻平等在阿根廷成为法律两年后，国会批准了开创性的性别认同法律规定了跨性别者的权利，包括无需医学评估即可更改姓名的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;乌克兰战争推动了对 LGBTQ 权利的推动，但它会持续下去吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Boyarsky作为独立摄影师工作，经常在涉及俄罗斯移民的同性婚礼上拍照。根据阿根廷 LGBT 联合会的数据，2022 年至少有 34 对俄罗斯同性伴侣在阿根廷结婚，今年到目前为止有 31 对。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近，Boyarsky 拍摄了 22 岁的 Nadezhda Skvortosova 和 Tatiana 的婚礼29 岁的 Skvortosova 在搬到布宜诺斯艾利斯后不到一个月就结婚了。这对夫妇还在俄罗斯更改了她们的姓氏，这样她们就可以假装是姐妹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这对我们来说是一个非常重要的时刻。娜杰日达·斯克沃尔托索娃在布宜诺斯艾利斯民事登记处结婚后说，我们等了很长时间才正式成为一家人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多抵达阿根廷的俄罗斯人在搬家之前对这个国家知之甚少。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“探戈、切·格瓦拉和那是西班牙殖民地，”26 岁的男同性恋尼古拉·舒什潘开玩笑说，他在 10 月搬到阿根廷首都，当时他开始担心自己会被征召入伍&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shushpan 现在和他在约会应用程序上认识的俄罗斯同胞 Dimitry Yarin 在布宜诺斯艾利斯市中心合租一套公寓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;21 岁的 Yarin 说他早就计划搬家到一个更宽容的国家，但“战争加速了这一决定”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于他们在国内面临歧视，许多抵达阿根廷的俄罗斯人申请难民身份，这一过程可能需要长达三年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年年底在斯洛文尼亚逮捕了两名持有阿根廷护照的俄罗斯间谍后，当局最近加强了对俄罗斯移民的控制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，Shushpan 过着公开的生活第一次作为同性恋者。回到家，总是有紧张感和“可能会发生什么事”的感觉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我唯一没有这种感觉的国家就在这里。你不必一直担心。唯一需要担心的是价格，”Shushpan 说，他指的是阿根廷的通货膨胀率——世界上最高的通货膨胀率之一——大约 110%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在阿根廷呆了一年多之后，多米尼人也有这种如释重负的感觉。在俄罗斯西北部城市彼得罗扎沃茨克，34 岁的阿纳斯塔西娅和 44 岁的安娜几乎没有告诉任何人他们的关系以及两对双胞胎，年龄分别为 3 岁和 6 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们一直担心当局会采取他们的行动阿纳斯塔西娅·多米尼 (Anastasia Domini) 说，孩子们会被带走并送进孤儿院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，他们的生活不必担心有人会带走他们的孩子或将他们关进监狱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们完全习惯了我们已婚妇女的身份，我们是很多孩子的父母，我们可以在这里自由自在，”她说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden and Kevin McCarthy push for votes on spending deal as US debt default looms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222242/joe-biden-and-kevin-mccarthy-push-votes-spending-deal-us-debt-default-looms?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.30 03:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/30/45fca0c5-ae81-4be0-bb1b-ab4955bbd674_b15b6f54.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;白宫和共和党国会领导人加紧游说活动以赢得交易批准避免美国违约，因为环保主义者、国防鹰派和保守派强硬派谴责让步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统乔拜登的内阁成员和白宫高级工作人员已经在周一清晨之前分别向至少 60 名众议院民主党人发出游说电话，以一位民主党官员说，敦促他们投赞成票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登和共和党众议院议长凯文麦卡锡都表示相信他们会获得必要的选票。批准获得了各方温和派和实用主义派别的重要成员的早期支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案为到 2025 年的联邦支出设定了路线，并将暂停债务上限至 2025 年 1 月 1 日，这可能会推迟另一场斗争超过联邦借款授权直到那年年中。为了换取共和党人投票支持暂停，民主党人同意限制未来两年的联邦支出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫对上限的解释是告诉立法者，该协议将在未来两年内减少约 1 万亿美元的支出十年，而共和党人则认为支出削减是两倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国股指期货周一小幅上涨，10 年期国债期货上涨，降低了隐含收益率。在谨慎乐观的情况下，国家将避免违约。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;犹他州共和党参议员米特·罗姆尼是共和党温和派领袖，他周一在推特上发表声明表示，他将支持该协议，称它可以防止违约“并且随后的金融危机”和限制支出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由温和派众议院民主党组成的重要团体新民主党联盟领导团队也支持该协议，新罕布什尔州主席安妮库斯特表示这将避免“经济崩溃” ，同时“防止削减关键计划”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;分析师表示，尽管美国有可能达成债务协议，但中国仍面临风险&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但众议院民主党领袖哈基姆杰弗里斯，其党团成员包括和顽固的进步派，截至周一中午尚未发表任何公开声明表示支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 6 月 5 日可能违约之前，该交易的支持者只有一周的时间通过国会达成协议&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡锡周日表示，他预计大多数共和党人会投票支持新法案，并辩称这是一项旨在控制联邦支出的“变革性”举措，尽管“也许它不会为每个人做每一件事”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发言人表示他至少要等到星期三才能进行众议院投票，并遵守一项要求立法文本提前 72 小时公布的规则。参议院民主党领袖查克·舒默 (Chuck Schumer) 的参议院接下来将采取措施，他警告参议员们准备好在周末工作，如果持不同政见者设置程序障碍来推迟投票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共和党总统候选人罗恩·德桑蒂斯 (Ron DeSantis) 继续说道《Fox &amp; Friends》周一早上批评了这笔交易。 “我们的国家仍将濒临破产，”他说，并贬低了批准“大量支出”的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前总统唐纳德特朗普是德桑蒂斯在共和党 2024 年提名中的竞争对手，他没有公开表示自交易宣布以来，他就对该交易发表了评论，尽管他此前曾敦促他所在政党的国会领导人不要妥协，而是冒着违约的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国最著名的环保组织之一塞拉俱乐部 (Sierra Club) 于周一敦促反对意见，引用将加快批准横跨西弗吉尼亚州的天然气管道的规定，以及将对能源项目的环境审查施加时间限制的规定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“任何试图加快水力压裂天然气山谷的交易该组织的执行董事本·杰罗斯 (Ben Jealous) 在一份声明中表示，输油管道会削弱基本的环境保护措施，并让本已苦苦挣扎的工人和家庭的生活更加艰难，这对国家来说是一项糟糕的交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯发出逮捕令就乌克兰言论向美国参议员提供授权&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;国会议员劳尔·格里哈尔瓦 (Raul Grijalva) 是众议院自然资源委员会的高级民主党人，他表示该协议“为污染者提供了保护伞，不可避免地使本已无法接受的现状进一步恶化。”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;一位共和党国会助手表示，该党的国防鹰派也在酝酿不满。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南卡罗来纳州参议员林赛格雷厄姆周日在福克斯新闻上谴责国防开支增加 3.3%该协议是不充分的，因为它低于当前 5% 的年通货膨胀率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“低于通货膨胀率的支出并没有为军队提供充分的资金，”格雷厄姆说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议将不适用- 明年的安全支出将降至大致当前水平或更低。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案为 2024 财年的安全支出设定了 8860 亿美元的上限，为非安全国内支出设定了 7040 亿美元的上限。这些数字将会上升到 2025 财年分别达到 8,950 亿美元和 7,110 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于这些数字究竟如何加起来存在争议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫表示，通过预算调整，上限相当于为退伍军人服务以外的国内机构提供 6370 亿美元——仅比当前水平低 10 亿美元。但共和党表示，这个数字将是 5830 亿美元，降幅要大得多。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[G7 must stop meddling in other nations’ affairs – including China’s – and accept it is no longer relevant]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3222145/g7-must-stop-meddling-other-nations-affairs-including-chinas-and-accept-it-no-longer-relevant?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.30 01:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/05/29/f1ce3572-b302-42d6-ab90-9786f51a2d52_12339556.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;七国集团 (G7) 领导人齐聚日本广岛，来自5 月 19 日至 21 日举行峰会，期间他们发表了一份联合公报，读起来就像一个世界政府发表的宣言，窥探他国事务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界和平和全球秩序受到围攻随着 G7 依附于美国的心血来潮，已经沦为一个带有深刻意识形态偏见和冷战思维的地缘政治工具，旨在遏制中国，加剧政治和经济集团之间的对抗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着弱化代表世界的经济分量已成为 G7 的一项艰巨任务。七国集团成立于 1970 年代，占全球经济的近 70%。然而，根据国际货币基金组织的数据，随着发展中国家和新兴经济体的崛起，其在全球国内生产总值中的份额持续下降，预计今年将降至 30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A世界银行报告显示，从2013年到2021年，七国集团对全球增长的贡献率仅为25.7%，低于中国的38.6%。美国仅贡献了 18.6%，不到中国份额的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着七国集团在世界经济中的份额缩小，其相关性也随之下降。今天的七国集团既没有能力也没有意愿解决任何全球政治、经济或安全问题，其领导人必须适应其影响力正在减弱的现实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;七国集团的“经济胁迫”罪名反对中国是没有道理的。美国将单边制裁、长臂管辖、脱钩、供应链和产业链断裂，将经贸关系政治化和武器化，实际上是“经济胁迫”的根源和主要推动者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从 2000 年到 2021 年，美国政府对外国实体的制裁增加了 933%。到2021年，美国已经对全球数十个国家实施制裁，影响了世界上很大一部分人口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国也打着“去风险”的旗号，谋求与中国脱钩。为维护自身利益，华盛顿滥用职权，以牺牲众多跨国公司为代价，在重点行业打压中国企业。其他G7成员应敦促美国反思其错误行为，而不是听华盛顿的“经济胁迫”的帮凶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;G7干涉中国内政是公然违背事实。 G7公报还提到了台湾和香港，其遏制中国崛起的意图暴露无遗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;台湾问题的历史底蕴很清楚。台海两岸同属一个中国。一个中国原则是国际关系的基本准则，也是中国与世界各国建立和发展外交关系的政治基础。然而，七国集团一直试图挖空一个中国原则，与支持台独的势力勾结，对台海的和平与稳定构成严重威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港是中国的一部分，不是少数外国势力进行政治操弄的舞台。香港事务纯属中国内政，不容许七国集团插手。香港进入新阶段，由乱走向稳定繁荣，前景更加光明。炒作香港问题攻击中国，骗不了香港市民，也骗不了国际社会的正义人士。相反，这种行为只会暴露集团的虚伪和霸权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;G7国家在国内面临着许多经济和社会问题，包括日益扩大的贫富差距和忽视底层人民的基本权利在美国和其他国家引发抗议和罢工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近几个月，美国银行业的担忧加剧，民主党和共和党在债务上限期限问题上陷入苦战，这有可能将世界经济推入危机。如果 G7 在面对这些困难时仍然执着于冷战思维和居高临下的态度，它可能会失去所有尊重。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;扩大 G7 嘉宾名单暗示全球秩序会更好、更公平&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;中国走和平发展道路，奉行互利共赢的开放战略，为全球性问题提供解决方案。它维护以国际法为基础的国际秩序，反对任何霸权霸权行径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着七国集团领导人齐聚广岛，重点维护其对世界秩序的主导地位和对全球经济的垄断，中国－中亚峰会在西安开幕，中国与中亚五国共商共同发展，构建更加紧密的命运共同体。 Unlike the G7, the summit in China sent a cooperative signal to the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a Chinese poem says, “Thick mountains cannot stop the river from flowing into the sea.” Long gone are the days when a handful of countries could freely meddle in others&#39; internal affairs and manipulate global issues. In the 21st century, the international community – China included – will not accept Western rules that are imposed by the US. The G7 countries should realise they cannot stop this trend; ultimately, those blocking the path of others will find themselves in a dead end.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russian ‘spy’ whale surfaces in Sweden]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3222241/russian-spy-whale-surfaces-sweden?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.30 01:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/30/fe82674d-bc58-4b30-94e3-737ac597ebd4_e5bbb094.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A harness-wearing beluga whale that turned up in Norway in 2019, sparking speculation it was a spy trained by the Russian navy, has appeared off Sweden&#39;s coast, an organisation following him said Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First discovered in Norway&#39;s far northern region of Finnmark, the whale spent more than three years slowly moving down the top half of the Norwegian coastline, before suddenly speeding up in recent months to cover the second half and on to Sweden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Sunday, he was observed in Hunnebostrand, off Sweden&#39;s southwestern coast.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We don&#39;t know why he has sped up so fast right now,” especially since he is moving “very quickly away from his natural environment”, said Sebastian Strand, a marine biologist with the OneWhale organisation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It could be hormones driving him to find a mate. Or it could be loneliness as Belugas are a very social species – it could be that he&#39;s searching for other beluga whales.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Believed to be 13-14 years old, Strand said the whale is “at an age where his hormones are very high”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The closest population of Belugas is however located in the Svalbard archipelago, in Norway&#39;s far north. The whale is not believed to have seen a single beluga since arriving in Norway in April 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Norwegians nicknamed it “Hvaldimir” – a pun on the word “whale” in Norwegian, hval, and a nod to its alleged association to Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Whale with broken spine travels almost 5,000km doing breaststroke&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;When it first appeared in Norway&#39;s Arctic, marine biologists from the Norwegian Directorate of Fisheries removed an attached man-made harness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The harness had a mount suited for an action camera and the words “Equipment St Petersburg” printed on the plastic clasps.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Directorate officials said Hvaldimir may have escaped an enclosure, and may have been trained by the Russian navy as it appeared to be accustomed to humans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moscow never issued any official reaction to Norwegian speculation he could be a “Russian spy”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Barents Sea is a strategic geopolitical area where Western and Russian submarine movements are monitored. It is also the gateway to the Northern Route that shortens maritime journeys between the Atlantic and Pacific oceans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strand said the whale&#39;s health “seemed to be very good” in recent years, foraging wild fish under Norway&#39;s salmon farms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But his organisation was concerned about Hvaldimir&#39;s ability to find food in Sweden, and already observed some weight loss.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beluga whales, which can reach a size of six metres (20 feet) and live to between 40 and 60 years of age, generally inhabit the icy waters around Greenland, northern Norway and Russia.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 01:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong security chief accuses ex-district councillors living overseas of involvement in wave of withdrawals from city’s organ donor scheme]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3222239/hong-kong-security-chief-accuses-ex-district-councillors-living-overseas-involvement-wave?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 23:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/71047de4-416b-4570-b26a-5a618a11f41b_1e6ccc87.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s security chief has accused former district councillors who live overseas of involvement in a wave of withdrawals from the city&#39;s organ donation scheme and pledged possible arrests as criminal investigations are launched into suspected abuse of the register.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Security Chris Tang Ping-keung on Monday highlighted the case of four-month-old Cleo Lai Tsz-hei, who last December became the first Hongkonger to get a heart donated from mainland China, which sparked the examination of a transplant mutual aid scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There were people intending to endanger our safety and deliberately distort this act of kindness who claimed that if someone did not apply for a withdrawal of organ donation, they would automatically be included in the list of registrations,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“These people include some former anti-government district councillors who fled to foreign countries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We believe that some people maliciously used others&#39; names to make these withdrawals to create an illusion that a lot of people are dissatisfied with the proposal.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang emphasised that organ donation was “a very noble act” that prolonged the lives of others.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Wherever life is, it is still life,” he said. “I very much despise people who deliberately made these positive acts into negative things for the sake of their own political interests, which could affect those who are waiting for a transplant.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang was speaking just days after the government highlighted “abnormalities” in the number of withdrawals from the register since last December - about 3,000 of them made by people who had never opted in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said criminal investigations had been launched into the use of “deliberate and illegal methods” to make registration withdrawals for people who had never opted in as donors in the first place.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We will make arrests when evidence is found and file charges when there is enough evidence,” Tang warned.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What&#39;s behind wave of withdrawals from Hong Kong organ donor register?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The increase in withdrawals came after the city at the end of last year started to examine the feasibility of an organ transplant mutual assistance mechanism with the mainland in the wake of the Lai transplant.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The system would act as a second-tier response if transplant patients could not find a match on their side of the border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Health Bureau said last week 5,785 withdrawal applications were made on the Centralised Organ Donation Register website between last December and April, a “significantly higher” number than in the past.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than half of them - 2,905 applications - were invalid because they were filed by people not on the donor register.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Police to target organ donation rumour mongers, Hong Kong health chief warns&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The percentage of invalid withdrawal applications was as high as 74 per cent in February alone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The authorities earlier condemned the “utterly irresponsible behaviour” and said they suspected that “a small number of people” had produced the applications with the aim of “disrupting the representativeness” of the register and overloading its administration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Health Lo Chung-mau on Sunday said the government was considering asking organ donors to verify their identities and appealed to the public to stop spreading “rumours and false claims” about the proposed cross-border donor scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Department of Health also announced a new feature for the register, which allows users of the “iAM Smart” electronic identification system to check their registration status.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China’s C919 timeline 2008-23: first commercial flight 15 years in the making]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3222192/chinas-c919-timeline-2008-23-first-commercial-flight-15-years-making?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.30 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/d1a4e37b-1335-4439-ae41-e9b085073ff4_3cd5ba44.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The Commercial Aircraft Corporation of China (Comac) was formed in 2008 to develop the C919 narrow-body passenger jet, which eventually completed its maiden commercial flight in May 2023.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But how did it take 15 years for the C919 to take the two-hour commercial flight from Shanghai to Beijing?&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China forms the Commercial Aircraft Corporation of China (Comac) in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Comac announces it will develop the C919 narrow-body passenger jet. State media reports the C919 is expected to have its maiden flight in 2014 and will be delivered to airlines in 2016.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Comac unveils a model of the C919 aircraft for the first time at the Asian Aerospace Expo in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;CFM International, a joint venture between GE Aviation from the United States and France&#39;s Safran Aircraft Engines, is selected by Comac to supply the LEAP engine to the C919.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Civil Aviation Administration of China (CAAC) accepts Comac&#39;s application for a type certificate – the airworthiness of an aircraft design – for the C919.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Comac says at the Zhuhai air show that the development of C919 is going according to plan. It also says it has received 380 orders.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Local media report the C919&#39;s maiden flight will be delayed by a year until 2015, pushing the first delivery dates to around 2017 or 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Comac begins the assembly of the C919 at its Pudong base.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Reuters reports that the C919 would have to delay its maiden flight for a year and that it will also have to postpone its first delivery for two years.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;CFM International delivers the first LEAP engine for the C919 in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Comac unveils the C919 for the first time in a ceremony attended by some 4,000 government officials and guests at a hangar near Shanghai&#39;s Pudong International Airport.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Shanghai-based China Eastern Airlines announces at the Zhuhai air show that it will be the first C919 customer.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;C919 makes its maiden flight in Shanghai.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and CAAC agree to recognise each other&#39;s regulatory systems with respect to the airworthiness of aviation products and articles.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;US President Donald Trump says that he will support sales of hi-tech products to China after media reports suggested Washington may block the export of the LEAP engine to Comac.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;US government includes Comac on a military blacklist, banning US investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;China Eastern Airlines signs a firm order for five C919.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The US and the European Union agree to a truce in their near 17-year conflict over aircraft subsidies to Boeing and Airbus and to set up a working group to address “non-market practices” in other countries, most notably China.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Biden administration adjusts its military blacklist to remove Comac.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;C919 receives a type certificate from CAAC.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Comac says it has secured orders from seven leasing firms for 300 C919.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Comac delivers the first C919 jet to China Eastern Airlines in Shanghai and it begins a reported 100 hours of test flights.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Bearing the symbolic number MU9191, the flight operated by China Eastern Airlines and carrying more than 130 passengers travels between Shanghai and Beijing.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Russia issues arrest warrant for US senator over Ukraine comments]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222240/russia-issues-arrest-warrant-us-senator-over-ukraine-comments?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.30 00:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/18cdfc1f-eb45-4de4-817c-722deb85757e_35449667.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Russia&#39;s Interior Ministry on Monday issued an arrest warrant for US Senator Lindsey Graham following his comments related to the fighting in Ukraine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an edited video of his meeting on Friday with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky that was released by Zelensky&#39;s office, Graham, a Republican from South Carolina, noted that “the Russians are dying” and described the US military assistance to the country as “the best money we&#39;ve ever spent”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While Graham appeared to have made the remarks in different parts of the conversation, the short video by Ukraine&#39;s presidential office put them next to each other, causing outrage in Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russian President Vladimir Putin&#39;s spokesman Dmitry Peskov commented on Sunday by saying that “it&#39;s hard to imagine a greater shame for the country than having such senators.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Russia puts US Senator Lindsey Graham on wanted list&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The Investigative Committee, the country&#39;s top criminal investigation agency, has moved to open a criminal inquiry against Graham, and the Interior Ministry followed up by issuing a warrant for his arrest as indicated on Monday by its official record of wanted criminal suspects.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Graham commented on Twitter, saying that “to know that my commitment to Ukraine has drawn the ire of Putin&#39;s regime brings me immense joy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I will continue to stand with and for Ukraine&#39;s freedom until every Russian soldier is expelled from Ukrainian territory”, he tweeted. “I will wear the arrest warrant issued by Putin&#39;s corrupt and immoral government as a Badge of Honour”.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[9,500 Hong Kong drivers sign up for scheme to drive in mainland China, nearly 7 times quota limit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3222238/9500-hong-kong-drivers-sign-scheme-drive-mainland-china-nearly-7-times-quota-limit?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.05.29 23:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/05/29/52016f57-ad1f-44c2-bda4-faa209d6d37c_df333ebe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;About 9,500 Hong Kong drivers signed up for an expanded scheme to drive to mainland China via a mega bridge when registration opened on Monday, nearly seven times the quota set for the first week of its launch in July.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who win a quota slot via a ballot will each need to pay up to HK$3,000 (US$383) for the relevant documents, inspection fees and insurance policy and meet certain criteria before they can drive across the border, according to transport officials.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Known as “Northbound Travel for Hong Kong Vehicles”, the scheme will allow residents to drive into Guangdong province via the Hong Kong-Zhuhai-Macau Bridge with permits which will be valid for up to one year starting from July 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 9,500 applications were received as of 5pm on Monday when the two-day registration period opened for those hoping to get the cross-border driving licence in the first week of the launch, according to transport authorities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Authorities have fixed a quota of 200 cars a day in the first week and 300 daily in the second to ensure a smooth start.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although a motorists&#39; group had called for an expanded quota, transport officials on Monday said time would be needed to observe how the scheme was working.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As proficiency in operations improves, we will consider ramping up the daily processing capacity,” the Transport and Logistic Bureau said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What Hongkongers need to know about driving into mainland China under new scheme&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Results for the first ballot will be announced on Wednesday. Applicants who fail to secure a slot can register again between June 5 and 8 via a designated website, .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post attempted to register half an hour after registration opened at 10am on Monday and the system showed more than 2,000 users waiting in the queue and that it would take about 20 minutes to access the registration page.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Transport Department said some vehicle owners were not able to register for the online ballot in the morning because of a software glitch, but the issue was fixed by 1.30pm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Drivers successful in the ballot will need to file a formal application for the cross-border driving licence and submit documents in digital format, including the vehicle registration document, Hong Kong identity card and mainland travel permit. A certificate of roadworthiness issued by the city&#39;s designated car testing centres will also have to be filed if the vehicle is aged six years or more.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2 roadblocks facing plan to let more Hong Kong drivers cross mega bridge: experts&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;To qualify for the scheme, a vehicle also has to be cleared by the China Inspection Company – a testing, certification and appraisal agency approved by the State Council. The only recognised facility in Hong Kong able to examine cross-border vehicles is located in Yuen Long.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company has increased its daily inspection quota from a reported 300 to 700 cars and the bureau said it was discussing measures to further enhance arrangements.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Applicants also need to obtain a mainland driving licence in person in Guangdong in advance and meet the insurance requirements in both the city and across the border.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, the bureau said it had noted that the scanning system of car park gates in Guangdong was not able to read Hong Kong licence plates at present.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it said it had submitted different samples of Hong Kong car plates to mainland authorities for reference and expressed confidence the problem could be resolved by July 1.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lawmaker Professor William Wong Kam-fai, an associate dean at Chinese University&#39;s faculty of engineering, said: “Modifying the existing recognition systems in the mainland&#39;s car parks is not complicated. It can be done promptly as long as the mainland authorities request the car park operators to do so.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong gears up for safe cross-border driving&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The scheme also requires private car owners to buy mainland motor vehicle traffic mandatory liability insurance, with a coverage limit of 200,000 yuan (US$25,525) and which provide third-party protection against injuries and property losses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fellow lawmaker Chan Pui-leung, who is also general manager of China Taiping Insurance Hong Kong, said owners should also consider topping up the premium with commercial motor insurance to cover their damage and third-party liability with a maximum coverage of 10 million yuan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He reminded vehicle owners to call police, take photos and contact the insurer immediately to arrange a local full claim service if they encountered an accident on the mainland.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 29 May 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>