<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[UN rights chief slams Niger coup: ‘very notion of freedom’ at stake, he warns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3231615/un-rights-chief-slams-niger-coup-very-notion-freedom-stake-he-warns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 23:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/bcd5f71a-97b6-4375-a2b3-80b36c0afe08_c64a0278.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;联合国周五猛烈抨击在尼日尔夺取政权的将军们“ ”，并使该国进一步陷入苦难，要求立即恢复宪法秩序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尼日尔的自由概念正处于危险之中，”联合国人权事务高级专员沃尔克·特克在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尼日尔的自由概念正处于危险之中。” “将军们不能一时兴起违抗人民的意愿，”他说。 “枪治在当今世界没有立足之地。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的评论是在上个月的政变推翻尼日尔民选总统穆罕默德·巴祖姆之后发表的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴祖姆，63 岁，于7 月 26 日，总统卫队成员发起政变，这是尼日尔自 1960 年脱离法国独立以来第五次政变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内陆国家尼日尔因此与邻国马里和布基纳法索一起成为三年内第三个发动政变的萨赫勒国家。经历政变。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国高级外交官会见尼日尔政变领导人，进行了“艰难”的会谈&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;特克强调，尼日尔已经是世界上最贫穷的国家之一，近一半的人人民“陷入赤贫”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他警告说，政变使局势进一步恶化，边境关闭、贸易停滞、严重断电和粮食价格上涨，并呼吁“全面和人道主义援助的自由准入。”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特克感叹道，“他们选出的那些为结束贫困而开辟道路的人，却被违反宪法秩序的武力驱逐，并被政变领导人拘留。”他&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“必须立即释放他们，恢复民主。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特克对政变领导人宣布起诉巴祖姆的决定表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说：“这一决定不仅出于政治动机，反对民主选举的总统，而且没有法律依据，因为民主机构的正常运作已被搁置。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还描述了“对公民空间的压制” ，”指出有关恐吓记者和禁止国际媒体的指控“非常令人担忧”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 23:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Boy, 12, allegedly abandoned in Hong Kong hospital by mainland Chinese mother returns to family, welfare authorities say]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3231616/boy-12-allegedly-abandoned-hong-kong-hospital-mainland-chinese-mother-returns-family-welfare?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 23:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/665b1f90-da48-473b-a749-cb68dcf3341b_50976e47.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一名 12 岁男孩据称被中国大陆母亲遗弃在香港该市社会福利部门周五透露，根据法院命令，上个月的孔医院已被归还给他的家人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“社会福利署的社工已为该男孩制定了适当的福利计划”该部门在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前，该男孩已按照法院命令恢复由家人照顾。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港警方指控母亲将 12 岁的儿子遗弃在医院&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;该部门补充说，其社会工作者将与家人保持密切联系，以确保他得到照顾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该案件于7月21日，陈姓男童在油麻地广华医院急症室被发现独自徘徊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈出生于香港，持有香港身份证，男童被送往屯门儿童青少年院，警方搜寻其来自内地的父母。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警方初步调查显示，男童被指示告诉医院职员他有咳嗽。并出现腹泻，咨询后告知护士被遗弃。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;12岁弃婴的母亲“愿意回港”接他&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;男孩被发现后不久，警方联系了已经返回河南省的他的母亲。一位消息人士称，警方调查显示，她抛弃了儿子，希望他能在这座城市接受“更好的教育”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市领导人李家超谴责了这位母亲的行为，并警告说男孩的父母可能会因抛弃他而面临法律后果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名37岁的母亲于7月29日返回香港时被捕，并被指控虐待或忽视儿童。&lt;/p>; >;&lt;p>;两天后，市法院准许她保释，但被勒令交出旅行证件，直至 9 月 11 日恢复审判。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 23:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Country Garden to drop out of Hang Seng Index as Hong Kong’s stock benchmark adds Sinopharm in quarterly recalibration]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/3231513/sinopharm-join-hang-seng-index-quarterly-review-while-country-garden-be-dropped?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 21:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/4c68e12d-c4f7-46c4-a0a5-dee01c22285c_34d18d9b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;国药集团将于下个月在最新季度审核后被纳入恒生指数恒生指数编制者在盘后声明中表示，这将使成分股数量保持在 80 只不变，而房地产开发商碧桂园控股将在成为细价股后被剔除。周五关闭。这些变化将于 9 月 4 日起生效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;继 2 月份没有添加新成分股后，指数编制者已连续第二个季度向恒生指数添加了新成分股，这令投资者感到惊讶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从恒生指数于 2021 年宣布全面改革恒生指数（最终将有 100 只成分股）的计划以来，恒生指数在扩大基准方面已经落后于计划。在上次调整中，在线旅行社携程集团和黄金生产商紫金矿业集团等四家公司被纳入指数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调整后，恒生指数将覆盖 64% 的股票声明称，与目前的 65% 相比，香港市场的整体价值下降了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为恒生指数系列季度审查的一部分，Trip.com 将加入 50-声明称，该指数是在香港交易的中国公司的恒生中国企业指数成员。碧桂园旗下的物业管理公司碧桂园服务控股公司将被从指数中剔除。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;由于中国债务危机和人民币贬值，香港股市录得 3 月份以来最糟糕的一周&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周五，国药控股股价下跌 0.5%，至 21.20 港元，全年涨幅回落至 6.9%。碧桂园股价下跌 1.4%，至 0.76 港元，由于房屋销售下滑和流动性紧缩，今年其股价下跌了 72%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恒生指数在香港股市成分多元化方面取得了一些进展。股票基准。编制者上个月表示，在与市场参与者进行了两个月的咨询后，以香港作为主要上市地点的外国公司将有资格在 11 月份的下一次调整中成为恒生指数成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这为意大利奢侈品生产商普拉达 (Prada) 和美国箱包制造商新秀丽国际 (Samsonite International) 的加入铺平了道路。根据恒生指数，海外公司的总权重将被限制在该指数的10%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恒生指数今年已下跌超过9%，成为表现最差的指数之一随着中国在 Covid-19 后的经济复苏缓慢以及与美国的贸易战持续不断，该指数在全球范围内执行关键股票指数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该指数于 1969 年推出，市值为 11.4 万亿港元（ 1.5 万亿美元）。根据彭博社数据，香港股市是亚洲第三大股市，市值达 5 万亿美元，仅次于中国（9.9 万亿美元）和日本（5.8 万亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恒生家族据编制者称，截至去年底，被动基金跟踪指数，全球管理资产达 576 亿美元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Unmakeable in America? China-targeted tariffs forcing US manufacturers to relocate abroad]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3231588/unmakeable-america-china-targeted-tariffs-forcing-us-manufacturers-relocate-abroad?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/666a7bf5-d83d-4b2b-94b3-7111f016377d_8ad7157f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;当美国音频扬声器设计师和制造商 Misco 总裁 Dan Digre 时，六月份在佛罗里达州奥兰多举行的一次行业聚会上发表主题演讲时，他毫不掩饰地谴责华盛顿对中国商品征收进口关税的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关税阻碍了美国扬声器公司在美国生产产品。迪格雷对同情的观众说，这破坏了“本届政府在美国建设更多工厂的政策”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Misco 是一家小型家族企业，于 1949 年在明尼苏达州明尼阿波利斯成立，而其他制造商则留在原地不动。离开该国，前往中国追逐更便宜的劳动力和更低的成本。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在竞争激烈的环境中生存并蓬勃发展后，Misco 难以跟上，并将其部分业务转移到了中国。现在，它正在努力将其余产品留在美国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;扬声器的应用广泛：吉他、商业航空公司、军事应用和医疗设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最初决定留在美国美国认为扬声器是一项核心技术，应该在美国制造，但现在Misco处于竞争劣势，因为“在美国制造扬声器的公司支付的关税是完全在中国制造的公司的三倍”， Digre 告诉《华盛顿邮报》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是因为从中国进口扬声器零部件的关税为 25%，而成品扬声器的关税为 7.5%。简而言之，从中国进口最终产品对商品制造商来说比在美国制造更有意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“关税的目的是保护美国工业，而不是降低其竞争力， ”迪格雷说道。 “但这就是关税的影响。这使我们的成本更高，从而降低了我们的竞争力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管将部分成本转嫁给客户，Misco 认为“不在美国生产更多产品，但具有讽刺意味的是，最终具有商业意义” ”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;拜登限制美国对中国科技的投资，做出“紧急”声明&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;作为对中国采取强硬态度的承诺的一部分，美国前总统唐纳德·特朗普宣布了四笔投资自 2018 年起征收关税。前两项，即众所周知的清单 1 和清单 2，分别于当年 7 月和 8 月对价值至少 500 亿美元的中国商品征收 25% 的关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接下来的几个月，清单3对另外价值2000亿美元的中国商品征收10%的税。这个数额后来被提高到25%。 2019年，特朗普宣布了清单4a，对价值至少1200亿美元的中国商品征收15%的关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在2020年，中美贸易战让全球市场陷入困境后，特朗普签署了一项清单与北京达成的第一阶段协议，允许一定程度的减税，以换取在两年内购买大量美国出口产品并对中国经济做法进行结构性改变的承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议对清单进行了减税扬声器、转盘、电视、投影仪和其他电子产品等 4a 商品的税率从 15% 降至 7.5%。不过，清单 3 中的 25% 关税保持不变，其中包括制造扬声器所需的零部件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年入主白宫的美国总统乔·拜登在很大程度上维持了特朗普政府的关税水平。地方。自去年5月以来，美国贸易代表办公室一直在审查关税的必要性和影响。其评估预计将于秋季结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国贸易代表 Katherine Tai 表示，关税变化可能即将到来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为本次审查的一部分，我们正在考虑现有的关税结构，以及如何根据对美国经济部门的影响以及增加国内制造业的目标使关税更具战略性，”她的办公室在7月回应美国参议院财政委员会的询问时表示。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明称，美国贸易代表办公室将考虑是否需要采取额外的关税排除程序，以及“如何改变未来的排除以使其更有效”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;超过 300 项排除已生效，每项预计将于 9 月 30 日到期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着地缘政治不确定性的升温，中国的出口蛋糕是否正在融化？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在一封公开信中由 170 个贸易协会组成的联盟美国促进自由贸易组织 (Americans for Free Trade) 于 7 月 27 日向美国贸易代表办公室 (USTR) 发布了一份报告，敦促戴“及时”宣布继续实施现有的排除条款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该组织成立于 2018 年，“团结一致”据其 X（前身为 Twitter）社交媒体账户称，“我们正在对抗关税”。美国自由贸易协会代表制造商、农民和农业综合企业、零售商、技术公司、服务供应商、天然气和石油公司、进口商、出口商和其他供应链利益相关者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该组织表示，在过去的五年里，多年来，“美国进口商，包括我们联盟的成员，已经支付了超过 1830 亿美元”的关税，而美国贸易代表办公室关于排除的“最后一刻”决定破坏了政府“确保供应链弹性的既定目标”。&lt;/该联盟补充道，“美国家庭、工人和企业继续面临前所未有的、不确定的经济挑战”，并称自己是“对关税和需求的持续负面影响发表评论的数百个团体和公司之一”。寻求新的战略方法来解决中国的不公平贸易行为”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;华盛顿在美中贸易问题上的鹰派两党分歧日益扩大&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;与此同时，低迷的制造业继续对那些支持美国的人来说是一个坏兆头行业非营利组织供应管理协会的数据显示，7 月份美国制造业活动连续第九个月收缩，这是自 2007 年全球金融危机以来最长的收缩期。 2008年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，上个月采购经理人指数为46.4，较6月的46.0略有上升，为2020年5月以来的最低水平。读数低于50表明活动正在下降。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，由于陷入困境的企业为了维持生存而削减员工人数，7 月份美国工厂就业人数降至三年来的最低水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调查涵盖的 18 个行业群体中有 7 个报告称产量下降以及六月份的就业情况。这些制造商的范围从纺织厂到电气设备，从塑料到电器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国自由贸易组织在致众议院中国问题特别委员会主席、威斯康星州共和党议员迈克·加拉格尔的一封信中表示，关税已经美国“抑制了制造业”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这封信提到了 Misco 的经历，并援引该公司的话说，它认为自己“因在美国生产扬声器而受到了惩罚”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国人为自由贸易组织还为专家组指出了其他受中国针对关税影响的企业，例如一家 IT 公司表示，该公司每年为清单 3 和 4a 中指定的零部件支付了超过 3.5 亿美元的费用。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;美国芯片公司需要进入中国：半导体贸易组织&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但在多次尝试获得排除以及重新配置其供应链和削减成本后，该公司“现在正在考虑是否将其制造转移到中国”墨西哥，然后将产品免税进口到美国，这将导致 1,300 个美国就业岗位处于危险之中”，据该联盟称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Digre 表示，Misco 和另一家扬声器公司的产品排除请求遭到了美国政府的拒绝美国贸易代表办公室在特朗普执政期间没有做出任何解释。他批评排除审查不透明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有人知道这个过程是如何运作的。没有人知道标准是什么。没有任何证据，也没有给出任何解释，说明为什么排除请求被拒绝，”他说。迪格雷表示，他认为拜登政府应该重新考虑审查程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国自由贸易协会的美国贸易代表办公室在致加拉格尔的信中没有就政府的关税审查举行公开听证会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们认为美国贸易代表办公室必须迅速采取行动，宣布与其审查相关的决定，”该联盟写道，并认为审查必须“公平和透明”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些分析师也猛烈抨击关税适得其反。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿智库卡托研究所的克拉克·帕卡德和斯科特·林西科姆表示，政府对北京国际贸易和投资行为问题的反应“在过去一直严重不足”他们在 5 月份的美中贸易报告中表示，“无论是关税还是国内补贴，都不足以应对在 21 世纪超越中国的严峻任务”，并将该政策描述为&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美中关系取得缓慢但关键的进展：美国企业家&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据该报告，穆迪分析估计，中美贸易战已导致导致美国失去约 30 万个就业岗位，而纽约联储的一项研究称，关税导致“投资放缓导致企业市值损失约 1.7 万亿美元”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Digre 表示，官员们“尽管政府意识到其政策带来的挑战，但仍处于瘫痪状态。他表示，美国有关对华政策的政治讨论“非常两极分化”和“非常有害”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于一个政治家来说，说出任何可能被视为对中国软弱的言论都是失败的论据，”他添加。 “我认为拜登政府害怕做任何政治反对派可能会说的事情，‘好吧，你刚刚让中国人受益’。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我不知道他们会做任何事情，”Digre 说道，并指出 2024 年美国总统竞选的争夺正在进行中。 “我当然认为他们不会在选举前采取任何行动。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 23:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Longer Hong Kong storage time for eggs, sperm and embryos unlikely to boost birth rate, say reproductive medicine experts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3231613/hong-kong-reproductive-medicine-experts-say-longer-storage-time-eggs-sperm-and-embryos-unlikely?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 22:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/3d8370c3-5806-49c4-8e38-1049d243668a_34df544d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港卵子、精子和胚胎的储存时间由10天延长专家表示，将年龄延长至 55 岁无助于提高香港的出生率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们周五解释说，建议的新时间跨度“不切实际”，也不适合香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;玛丽医院生殖医学部前主任吴鸿宇教授表示，立法会议员叶刘淑仪提议的延期对解决香港低出生率问题影响不大，因为没有实际需求储存期超过10年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴解释说，大多数储存生殖材料的人会在四年内使用它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“确实有人​​希望冷冻10年以上，但这不是主要问题，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们不建议女性高龄生育，这会增加并发症的风险，例如”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他是在关键决策行政会议召集人、新民党主席叶议员建议将这一改变纳入行政长官李家超第二次政变后发表上述言论的。施政报告预计将于十月发表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;叶问周四向媒体表示，拟议的延期将增加夫妇生育孩子的灵活性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，她的建议符合与英国合作，英国于 2022 年将储存期限从 10 年延长至 55 年，以便人们更好地控制生育。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港 10 年最长储存期限的费用可能高达 200,000 港元（25,500 美元） &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;叶问的提议是在计划生育协会警告香港无子女夫妇的数量已达到“惊人”水平之后提出的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平均数量也下降至创历史新低，为每对夫妇 0.9 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新人口普查统计数据还显示，截至 6 月的一年中，新生儿出生人数仅为 32,600 人，低于去年同期的 35,100 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;随着每个家庭的出生人数降至 1 人以下，无子女的香港夫妇数量在 5 年内翻了一番&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是 Ng 表示，目前的最高限额对于那些尚未决定其生育计划的人来说已经足够了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，55对于任何想要使用自己的生殖材料的人来说，几年都太长了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“10年已经很长了。如果患者真的希望生孩子，他们会在10年内生孩子，”他说。 “如果患者想要孩子，他们不会等到太老了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ng 说，如果冷冻中心长期与患者失去联系，多余物质的积累可能会增加。导致存储问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他补充说，较长的存储限制可能对年轻的癌症患者有用，他们可能会因为治疗而失去自然分娩的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;博士妇产科医生陈奕诗补充说，患者在冷藏10年后取出生殖材料的情况并不常见，并怀疑建议的改变是否有效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港大学社会工作及社会行政学系也认同这样的观点，即较长的储存期无助于提高出生率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生育与不孕不育咨询专家陈女士表示，海外研究表明研究表明，冷冻卵子的使用率低至10%至30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们的研究经常发现，人们选择是否要孩子是基于社会的社会经济环境以及他们的生育能力。”她解释道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;将香港卵子、精子和胚胎的储存时间提高至55年：叶刘淑仪&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;陈建议免费进行3次体外受精周期（对于有生育问题的夫妇来说，体外受精（IVF）治疗可能更有效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，在海外国家有超过一百万个胚胎，没有人会声称拥有。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从宗教或道德角度来说，有些人可能会将这些胚胎视为生命，”她说。 “对于诊所是否可以处理它们，存在很多争议。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时担任国际不孕不育咨询组织中国和香港协调员的陈表示，香港没有记录冷冻的中央系统。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果在香港实施延期，政府将需要认真考虑对储存系统的监控，”她补充道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;她表示，延长储存期限会涉及伦理、身体和社会心理方面的困境，而且这个过程不仅仅是金钱和夫妻喜好的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈表示，她相信英国政府选择将期限延长至55年，因为卵子、胚胎和精子捐赠在当地更为常见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，英国女性可以将卵子捐赠给储存库，但香港没有类似的机构系统和人们必须自己寻找捐赠者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“拟议的延期可能会打开另一扇门，”她说。 “我们可以允许女性将未使用的冷冻卵子捐赠给银行供其他夫妇使用吗？这可以是一个选择。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US slaps tariffs on solar panel companies dodging China duties by finishing products in Southeast Asia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3231614/us-slaps-tariffs-solar-panel-companies-dodging-china-duties-finishing-products-southeast-asia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 22:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/1388eae7-faa4-4b58-8ce4-28c57827b91f_dad9e263.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国将于周五敲定对太阳能电池板制造商征收进口关税的决定据商务部一位高级官员称，这些公司在东南亚国家完成产品，以避免对中国制造的商品征收关税。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一决定在很大程度上反映了该机构 12 月做出的​​初步调查结果，但遭到了来自中国的反对。太阳能电池板的买家依靠海外制造的廉价产品来提高其项目的竞争力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这对于美国小型太阳能制造业来说是个好消息，该行业多年来一直在与中国产品竞争，并正在享受由于美国总统乔·拜登具有里程碑意义的气候变化法的补贴而重新投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;美国众议院投票废除拜登对 4 个东南亚国家的太阳能关税豁免&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;商务部调查发现，中国公司比亚迪、天合光能、隆基绿色能源和阿特斯阳光电力通过在柬埔寨、马来西亚、泰国和越南进行小加工来完成产品，然后再运往美国市场，从而规避美国对中国太阳能电池和电池板征收的关税。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;这些国家约占美国面板供应的80%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该机构还将对新东太阳能征收关税，因为它拒绝配合对其柬埔寨业务的现场审计这位官员表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这些国家运营的其他公司有能力寻求认证程序，以证明他们没有规避关税。要获得认证，太阳能电池和电池板必须包含非中国晶圆和其他三种关键部件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;商务部调查后，美国对中国制造的太阳能产品征收反倾销税已有十年发现中国公司接受不公平的政府补贴，人为地压低价格。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些公司和其他公司将面临美国已经对其中国制造的产品征收的相同税率。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;然而，由于美国总统乔·拜登的两年豁免，它们要到 2024 年 6 月才会启动，该豁免旨在确保国内制造业增加的同时确保充足的面板供应。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong pre-war cinema to be turned into restaurant celebrating Cheung Chau’s history and culture]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3231608/hong-kong-pre-war-cinema-be-turned-restaurant-celebrating-cheung-chaus-history-and-culture?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 21:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/18/584e37ab-9c71-4d72-abff-88c6b2b04f97_87d1c320.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港仅存的两家战前电影院之一将活化为一家餐厅，将于2025年开幕，纪念长洲历史文化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;废弃已久的长洲戏院于1931年落成，被政府列为三级历史建筑，设有600个座位该场馆放映粤语和西部电影，直至 1997 年关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长洲文化公司于周五宣布了这一改造项目，作为振兴计划第二阶段的一部分，该计划的两个阶段都吸引了数百名观众投资数百万港元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为第一阶段的一部分，电影院旁边的多元文化公园将于下周一开放，而电影院的主楼将改造成中式主题餐厅和将于2025年推出。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;逍遥游：香港最好的离岛宾馆&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“由于很少有大餐厅可以同时容纳许多住客，所以我们决定更换电影院改造成一家餐厅来满足岛上的需要。”公司首席执行官江俊伟说。 “我们希望这个新景点能够带动更多游客涌入长洲。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司表示，在电影院修复过程中，工人们发现了距今 5000 年前的陶器碎片，导致三-一年的勘探，出土了3000多件物品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当时所需的人力和物力，导致我们在这个项目上额外花费了八位数的资金，”蒋说。 “文物的保护需要先进的技能，否则它们可能会很快被侵蚀或损坏。因此，我们作为一个私人机构想要展示真实的陶器并不容易。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司首席执行官表示，他希望通过与当局的合作，能够使用 3D 打印技术复制这些文物，并且可以将复制品复制出来。两年后公开展示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chiang表示，当局在修复过程中提供了协助和专业建议，并补充说该公司计划在2025年盛大开业后申请政府资助。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;他补充说，该公司还花费了大量资源来加固建筑物的结构并保留其原有的外观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chiang 表示，该项目旨在通过组织与电影相关的活动来恢复电影院昔日的辉煌。一位姓黄的岛民表示，他记得只支付了 3 港元（38 美分），以表达对改造的支持。男孩和朋友一起去电影院看李小龙电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没有这家电影院，我很难适应生活……但我还是会去餐厅尝试一下，”61 岁的渔民&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;长洲海盗袭击：1912年袭击的真实情况&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“这将是我与邻居聚会的好地方，”另一位居民萧说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首席执行官蒋还指出，该公司最初打算开发该土地用于住宅用途，但后来申请将其留作商业用途。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创建了多元文化公园该计划的第一站占地3,530平方米，包括一个文化中心、信息中心、广场和一个提供工作坊和户外电影放映等活动的工作室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;活动门票价格为香港试用期间价格为 128 至 268 港元，之后价格为 180 至 348 港元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Forget world domination, India won’t catch up with China any time soon]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/comment/opinion/article/3231449/forget-world-domination-india-wont-catch-china-any-time-soon?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_opinion/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/08/17/8fddfa34-22b3-4e36-808e-0dc9b6cd88c3_b0fd427a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;去年，纳伦德拉·莫迪总理庆祝印度脱离英国统治独立 75 周年他呼吁国家“主宰世界”。本周早些时候，他再次在红堡唤起了“阿姆里特·卡尔”——一个机会之门打开的关键时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的“改革、执行、变革”口号涉及远大的梦想。他可能梦想着 1870 年之前的太平日子，当时印度和中国是世界上最大、最强大的两个经济体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但梦想并不能制定计划。 And in the nine years since Modi came to power, his plans to propel India to the top table of the world&#39;s most powerful economies remain largely that – plans.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Harvard University&#39;s Graham Allison reminded us in a recent Foreign Policy report that about a decade ago, the late Singapore leader Lee Kwan Yew had said India would never catch up with China and would always remain “the country of the future”. Lee said: “Do not talk about India and China in the same breath” – throwing the gauntlet down to those who see India biting at China&#39;s heels and cheer India on in hopes of hobbling China&#39;s ascent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To be fair to Modi, his government&#39;s economic performance is respectable after decades of stagnation and disappointment. India&#39;s gross domestic product has grown by about 6 per cent every year on average since 2014, reaching an all-time high of 9.1 per cent last year – impressive in light of the upheavals of the Covid-19 pandemic and recession in many parts of the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But a wide range of structural reforms are needed if India is to escape the shackles of its economic past. These include the grip of caste, bureaucratic friction, impenetrable tax rules, still-chronic protection of local business magnates and import tariffs that are among the world&#39;s highest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Any country rising from such a low base must recognise that it will take many decades to achieve anything the late Lee would regard as parity with China – and that this is nothing to be ashamed of. Goldman Sachs predicted last month that by 2075, China would become the world&#39;s largest economy (US$57 trillion), with India (at US$52.5 trillion) overtaking the US (at US$51.5 trillion).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Columbia University&#39;s Arvind Panagariya has similar projections, calculating recently in Time magazine that if India&#39;s real GDP grew at 8 per cent a year into the 2040s and 5 per cent after that, and if the US continues to grow on average by 2 per cent a year, India would overtake the US in 2073.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These are big “ifs”, even for those brave enough to make forecasts a half-century away. And huge bodies of data point India towards a more humdrum trajectory. According to Allison in Foreign Policy, back in 2000, China and India had economies worth less than US$2 trillion each. It took China five years to pass the mark and India 14 years. Last year, India&#39;s economy was worth US$3.4 trillion – a fraction of China&#39;s US$18.3 trillion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It will take many years of stellar economic growth for India to begin matching China in economic importance, and no amount of miraculous thinking or “China plus one” investment is likely to accelerate that.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Also, many other important economic indicators remain problematic. India accounted for about 1 per cent of global manufacturing in 2000, compared with 7 per cent for China. By last year, India&#39;s share had grown to 3 per cent against China&#39;s 31 per cent. In 2000, India accounted for just 1 per cent of the world&#39;s exports, and China 2 per cent. By last year, China accounted for 15 per cent of global exports against India&#39;s share of 2 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India enthusiasts celebrate the youthfulness of India&#39;s population, but ignore the reality that this is a problem rather than an advantage when they are poorly educated or even illiterate. To accommodate them, India must produce an estimated 90 million new jobs before 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Allison reminds us that China produces twice as many STEM-qualified (in science, technology, engineering and mathematics) graduates as India, spends almost three times the percentage of its GDP on research and development, and produces 65 per cent of the world&#39;s artificial intelligence patents (vs India&#39;s 3 per cent).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Bloomberg noted in April: “India is far behind China in key aspects important for manufacturing that include infrastructure, bureaucracy, attention to detail and even a sense of urgency.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Talk of &#39;Indian century&#39; is a dangerous myth masking real issues&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Supporters of India in search of a “hobble China” narrative have been encouraged by companies such as Apple and its main Taiwanese manufacturer Foxconn, which have made tentative steps to build investments in India, but ignore the challenges they have faced, and the reality that China remains their main manufacturing base.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They have ignored the withdrawals of companies like the Royal Bank of Scotland, Harley-Davidson and Citibank, and the many other companies with plans on hold. They have tended to celebrate the deliberate obstacles to prospective investment in China, even where China is a natural partner and the benefit of collaboration is huge.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rather than harbouring dreams of dominating the world, India&#39;s policymakers would benefit us all by opening up their economy and recognising that even if India does not surpass China, it can still be a huge driver in the global economy. China and India together account for one third of the world&#39;s population, one third of the global consumer class, and a quarter of all consumer spending in purchasing power parity terms.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 21st century may not be India&#39;s century, but it is almost certainly Asia&#39;s. Washington needs to come to terms with that, and perhaps New Delhi does too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Turkish Cypriot forces assault UN peacekeepers on buffer zone that separates Greeks from Turks]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3231609/turkish-cypriot-forces-assault-un-peacekeepers-buffer-zone-separates-island?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 22:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/4d6d804b-9e70-4530-9b0c-d879cc9e07bb_9c53ee85.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Turkish Cypriot forces assaulted UN peacekeepers on Friday as they attempted to block the construction of a controversial road in the buffer zone that separates the island from the Greek side, the UN mission on the island said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident occurred in Pyla, a village in the UN-patrolled Green Line that slices between the internationally recognised Republic of Cyprus and a breakaway Turkish Cypriot statelet in the north.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United Nations mission had on Thursday warned the Turkish Cypriot authorities against “unauthorised construction activities inside the UN buffer zone”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it said its peacekeepers had come under attack on Friday as they tried to block the construction of the road that encroaches on the buffer zone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The United Nations Peacekeeping Force in Cyprus condemns the assaults against UN peacekeepers and damage to UN vehicles by personnel from the Turkish Cypriot side this morning,” UNFICYP said in a statement.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said the incident occurred inside the buffer zone near Pyla, outside the southern coastal town of Larnaca.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Threats to the safety of UN peacekeepers and damage to UN property are unacceptable and constitute a serious crime under international law which will be prosecuted to the full extent of the law,” the UN mission said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An official said Turkish Cypriot police and military in plain clothes had punched a peacekeeper and assaulted a dozen others by “pushing them back violently”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Cyprus presidential vote goes to second round&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;A tractor was used to drag a UN vehicle out of the way and major damage had been caused to three vehicles, said the source who spoke on condition of anonymity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In its statement, the UN mission urged the Turkish Cypriot side to “respect the mission&#39;s mandated authority inside the UN buffer zone, refrain from any actions that could escalate tensions further, and withdraw all personnel and machinery from the UN buffer zone immediately”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UNFICYP said it was determined to block any construction work and would remain in the area. “The mission is monitoring the situation closely and remains committed to ensuring calm and stability are maintained in the area,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cyprus government spokesman Konstantinos Letymbiotis accused the Turkish side of trying to create new “faits accomplis” at Pyla by constructing a road connecting the “occupied village of Arsos with a forward illegal military outpost”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said it was “an attempt at a very serious violation of the status quo”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;European Union member Cyprus has been divided since 1974 when Turkish forces occupied the island&#39;s northern third in response to a military coup sponsored by the junta then in power in Greece.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The statehood of the Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus that Turkish Cypriot leaders proclaimed in 1983 is recognised only by Turkey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Efforts to reunify the eastern Mediterranean island have been at a standstill since the last round of UN-backed talks collapsed in 2017.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong national security law ‘casts doubt on the state of the rule of law’, EU warns]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3231611/hong-kong-national-security-law-casts-doubt-state-rule-law-eu-warns?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 22:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/718079d4-8e04-4e90-b67b-2f0d197a0fef_55fd7ecc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;The European Union has criticised the “continuing erosion of Hong Kong&#39;s high degree of autonomy and of rights and freedoms that were meant to be protected until at least 2047”, in an annual report released on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report for 2022 described at length the “far-reaching implementation of the national security law”, which it said had encroached on academic and media freedom, rights of assembly and association, and “cast doubt on the state of the rule of law in Hong Kong – a cornerstone of its economic success”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It summarised the major events in Hong Kong last year, including the unchallenged appointment of John Lee Ka-chiu as Chief Executive in the “patriots-only” election, the 25th anniversary of the handover from Britain, the visit of Chinese President Xi Jinping, and the Covid-19 restrictions which saw “around 10 per cent of EU nationals” abandon the city.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it was dominated by the roll-out of the security law, imposed by Beijing in July 2020, which has led to hundreds of arrests, the annihilation of political opposition, and a crackdown on many forms of expression and dissent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EU pointed to the “intensification” of trials under the national security law, which by the end of last year had led to the arrest of 236 people, some “held in custody since January 2021, in some cases in solitary confinement”, the detention of minors, and the invocation of a colonial era sedition law.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report says that on November 1, an EU national was arrested under the sedition law. “At a later stage, the authorities claimed that the man was a Chinese national and that, therefore, he was not allowed consular assistance,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Disquiet in EU ranks as &#39;de-risking&#39; strategy for China pushes ahead&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The detainee is believed to be Portuguese national Joseph John, also known as Wong Kin-chung, who was arrested for “allegedly publishing seditious articles online disparaging Beijing and local authorities”. The EU confirmed he is still being detained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report noted the high-profile cases of activist lawyer Chow Hang-tung, media tycoon Jimmy Lai Chee-ying and the arrests of those involved in the 612 Humanitarian Relief Fund – former lawmaker Cyd Ho Sau-lan, singer Denise Ho Wan-see, scholar Hui Po-keung, barrister Margaret Ng Ngoi-yee, 92 year-old Cardinal Joseph Zen Ze-kiun and the fund&#39;s secretary Sze Ching-wee.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At the time of his arrest, Hui was leaving the city to take up a teaching post at a university in the EU,” the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It described the purging of critical voices in the Law Society and Bar Association as “a negative impact on key parts of the legal community”. It noted the ongoing barriers to freedom of assembly, including the fining of attendees at a small protest against Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine and the continued outlawing of commemorations of the 1989 Tiananmen crackdown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Academics have been targeted by pro-Beijing media for “their perceived political stances, forcing some of them to leave their positions”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In one case, the government rejected a foreign researcher&#39;s visa application and neither the scholar nor the school was officially informed about the reasons behind this refusal,” the EU said, adding that political scientists had postponed sensitive research and some universities closed these departments altogether and removed human rights from the curriculum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It pointed to the increasingly long-arm of the security law, including the blocking of the Hong Kong Watch website and a police warning issued to the same group. The report also said exiled members of civil society had started receiving warnings from authorities and were blocked from accessing Hong Kong-based assets.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The EU also documented an increasingly harsh media environment. As well as the shuttering of outlets such as Citizen News and Factwire, editors of the previously closed Stand News faced sedition charges, and the Foreign Correspondents&#39; Club cancelled its annual human rights reporting awards, citing “legal red lines”.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Belgian university disputes Chinese account of meeting with top officials&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Instances of self-censorship cited by the bloc included a TV channel “apologising after receiving complaints that its reports &#39;incited hatred&#39;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The journalist in question had asked government officials “about the procedure for handling complaints against mainland medical professionals who came to Hong Kong to assist in controlling the pandemic”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite all this, the EU continues to ramp up its engagement with the Hong Kong government this year. Last week, the bloc&#39;s top diplomat in the city Thomas Gnocchi joined other EU consuls general at a luncheon hosted by the chief executive. Lee used the lunch to pitch Hong Kong as “the ideal gateway between East and West” for companies seeking to expand in the region.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just two months earlier, the European Parliament adopted by a landslide a motion calling for sanctions on Lee over the “alarming deterioration” of fundamental freedoms in the city. China&#39;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Hong Kong said the resolution was a “despicable act” and a “publicity stunt”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But elsewhere in Brussels, Hong Kong has largely fallen off the agenda. It has not been an agenda item at leaders&#39; or foreign ministers&#39; summits since early 2021, when the bloc failed to implement new measures on Hong Kong in response to the security law after being blocked by Hungary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Previous measures adopted by foreign ministers in 2020 included monitoring national security law trials in Hong Kong courts, ramping up engagement with civil society, and entering into no new negotiations with the Hong Kong government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report says that the EU&#39;s office and its member states in Hong Kong conducted 71 trial observations in 2022, however sources said that not all members have stepped up to the plate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One Brussels source told the Post that Hungary, Romania, Finland, Poland, Greece, Spain and Portugal have a diplomatic presence in the city but have been “laggards” on trial observations.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore’s presidential polls attract ‘same set’ of candidates, George Goh says after missing the cut]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3231600/singapores-presidential-polls-attract-same-set-candidates-george-goh-says-after-missing-cut?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.08.18 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/08/18/2c59c060-8b64-4e6a-804e-c67ae001fa9b_3cd72ce8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;George Goh, the Singaporean businessman who was deemed by authorities to be ineligible to contest the September 1 presidential election, has criticised the decision as a “setback” for the country.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goh was the first to declare his intention to run to succeed the incumbent, President Halimah Yacob.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Against the backdrop of the six-year presidency of Halimah, a former MP from the ruling People&#39;s Action Party (PAP), and her predecessors&#39; strong links to the establishment, Goh had pitched himself as the sole independent candidate.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Singapore set for three-way presidential contest on September 1&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Goh is the chief executive officer of Harvey Norman Ossia, a large furniture and electronics firm, and was previously Singapore&#39;s non-resident ambassador to Morocco.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Elections Department on Friday granted certificates of eligibility to three out of six candidates who had applied to stand for election: the ex-PAP stalwart Tharman Shanmugaratnam; Tan Kin Lian，NTUC Income 保险公司前首席执行官； and Ng Kok Song, a former chief investment officer of the state investor GIC.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former minister Tharman qualified based on his track record as a senior public official, while Ng and Tan were deemed to have met the criteria based on their private sector records.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am very disappointed at the decision of the Presidential Elections Committee to reject my application for a certificate of eligibility,” Goh said in a statement, referring to a five-person panel that was tasked by the government to assess if presidential hopefuls met the critieria set out in the constitution.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goh said the committee had taken a “very narrow view” of the requirements and had not explained its rationale.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Elections Department said in a statement earlier on Friday that it would not release details on why candidates were disqualified, as that would deter future candidates from stepping up for fear of being embarrassed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This decision has deprived Singaporeans of a wider choice to select who the next,” Goh said. “It is a setback not just for me, but for Singapore.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said in a press conference that he had a team consisting of accountants and lawyers, among others, to ensure that he could qualify.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That&#39;s why I was very confident [that I could qualify],” said Goh. “这群人是新加坡最顶尖的人。你说他们都错了？ Cannot be.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an interview with This Week in Asia earlier this week, Goh said he decided to run in this year&#39;s polls after parliament passed amendments to the constitution in 2016, which effectively raised the bar for potential candidates from the private sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To qualify as a candidate, former public officials must have held top senior positions for at least three years – as a minister, chief justice, or permanent secretary, among other positions in the last two decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Private sector candidates must have served an equivalent period as the chief executive of a company with at least S$500 million in shareholders&#39; equity and generated profit after tax throughout the entire period.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The PAP government earlier had amended the constitution to effectively reserve the 2017 vote for Malay candidates, citing the need for the role of president to be regularly rotated among the major ethnic groups. The republic had not had a Malay candidate since the 1965-1970 tenure of its first president, Yusof Ishak.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goh in the interview noted that Singapore&#39;s last four presidents had all been from the public sector: the president elected in 1993 was former PAP minister Ong Teng Cheong;他的继任者是前间谍头子兼外交官SR Nathan； and 2011&#39;s vote was won by Tony Tan Keng Yam, another ex-minister from the PAP.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former public officials, such as Tharman – who was for years Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong&#39;s finance tsar – would have difficulty serving as an independent president, Goh said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You have a lot of baggage to consider, your ex-colleagues to consider,” he said, adding that it would be “very hard” for a former establishment member to have an “independent mind” overnight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goh also suggested that candidates from the public sector belonged to the “same set” of people from government, which may result in an imbalance of power if elected president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Singaporeans have reached … a point [where they want] transparency, accountability.他们希望总统也发挥制衡作用，”他说。 “他们厌倦了这个系统。 Maybe in the past, people could accept [it] because they didn&#39;t understand the presidential role.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 18 Aug 2023 21:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>