<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[China, Mongolia to fight sandstorms amid calls to curb economic and ecological harm]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3224051/china-mongolia-fight-sandstorms-amid-calls-curb-economic-and-ecological-harm?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 13:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/2e40274d-4d85-412d-a68b-726613c52541_c4688157.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;北京和乌兰巴托加强联合努力，防止早些时候席卷中国北方的沙尘暴根据邮报获得的信息，今年，中国代表团将于本月晚些时候访问蒙古，共同研究解决方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个代表团率领环境和绿色发展政策顾问 Nyamosor Batkhuu 到应国家林业和草原局的邀请，蒙古国总统乌赫纳阿·呼日勒苏赫和林业部部长比亚姆巴苏伦·奥云萨纳于5月初对中国进行了为期6天的访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此行期间，两国签署了谅解备忘录。在中国内蒙古自治区进行的讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个中国研究小组现已应邀于 6 月 25 日至 7 月 10 日访问蒙古，以评估蒙古的荒漠化问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A据《华盛顿邮报》获悉，届时将成立联合工作组，以促进在蒙古建立中蒙防治荒漠化合作中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我们已做好准备”：蒙古总理向全球求助投资者&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;中国林业部门也将安排中国专家在该中心工作，由两国共同管理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国际开发合作署将支持捐赠计划、示范中心、荒漠化监测站、联合研究和中心能力建设培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国家林业和草原局没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国部生态与环境部此前将严重的沙尘暴——通常在春季袭击首都及周边地区——归咎于蒙古。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周，在访问内蒙古期间，习近平主席要求采取紧急行动，在 3 月和 4 月的春季强沙尘暴笼罩北京和中国北部地区，甚至影响包括上海在内的东部地区之后，中国“保持领先地位”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“荒漠化、沙尘暴，以及水土流失，造成生态破坏，制约 [中国] 北方地区的经济发展，”习近平说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去两年，中国北方经历了更多的沙尘暴，因为到气候变化的影响。长期、艰巨、不确定的防控工作刻不容缓，我们需要走在前列。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒙古科学院国际问题研究所客座研究员苏米亚楚鲁恩巴特尔表示，他表示，中国在内蒙古、宁夏、新疆等自治区以及甘肃省一直在防治荒漠化和沙尘暴，北京和乌兰巴托有必要加强合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“短缺水资源制约着蒙古的发展，特别是南部戈壁地区矿业发达，对水资源的需求很大，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国几十年的南水北调经验Chuluunbaatar 补充说，该项目——涉及从南部河流抽水并将其供应到干旱的北方——也将与蒙古相关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chuluunbaatar 还表示，碳排放交易系统是另一个潜在的合作领域，因为这是蒙古尚未开发的地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒙古戈壁沙漠地区植被生长不良导致沙尘暴，可能导致蒙古国民生产总值损失 0.27%根据拜访诺丁汉大学研究员 Hayatullah Ahmadzai 的一篇学术论文，由于农作物收入下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“沙尘暴频率的增加可能会使农业生产力降低 1.5% 24% 到 24%，具体取决于作物，”他在 2 月份发表的论文中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了与中国的共同努力外，蒙古政府还与矿业巨头力拓合作– 该国最大的外国投资者 – 到 2024 年将拯救 11 亿棵树木，因为该国正在与气候变化和荒漠化作斗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为期三年、耗资 230 万美元的健康森林项目于 2018 年启动到 2022 年，将创建能够抵御落叶并提高对害虫的适应能力的“弹性森林”，从而“通过提供长期健康的森林资源促进可持续经济发展”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，沙尘暴中国北方也笼罩着从韩国到日本的天空，给东京带来了自 2021 年以来的第一场黄沙。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内蒙古工业大学经济与管理学教授杨新吉乐图在一项研究中说7 月发布的论文指出，沙尘暴会降低道路能见度，导致交通事故，同时还会传播灰尘和花粉中携带的有害物质，引发健康问题，此外还会导致农作物减产。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Spotify confirms removal of ‘Glory to Hong Kong’ protest song, points to action by tune’s creator-distributor]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3224152/spotify-confirms-removal-glory-hong-kong-protest-song-points-action-tunes-creator-distributor?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 13:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/ef1bd95f-e0a0-495a-96b3-803f7ac5e895_77acaa66.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;音乐流媒体服务 Spotify 周四表示有争议的抗议歌曲“Glory to Hong Kong》已被发行商下架，这与前一天晚上歌曲创作者的声明相呼应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这首歌在 2019 年反政府骚乱期间受到抗议者欢迎的粤语和器乐版本已无法使用星期三向 Spotify 和其他音乐流媒体平台（包括台湾的 KKBox、香港的 Moov 和 Apple Music）的用户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港政府一周前向法院申请禁令禁止这首歌，防止那些怀有犯罪意图的人“以任何方式”“广播、表演、印刷、出版、销售、要约销售、分发、传播、展示或复制”该曲调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Spotify 发言人周四在提供给邮报的一份简短声明中说，这些歌曲是由发行商而不是平台删除的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创建和发行相关版本的“ThomasDGX &amp; HongKongers”曾表示正在处理技术问题与流媒体平台无关的问题，并为暂时的服务中断道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港抗议歌曲的流行版本从音乐流媒体平台上消失&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;所面临的“技术问题”的性质然而，中断的原因和持续时间仍不清楚。截至周四上午，同一创作者上传的“荣耀归于香港”的音乐视频仍在 YouTube 上播放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;邮报已与其他流媒体平台 KKBox、Moov、Apple Music 以及谷歌接洽拥有 YouTube 的公司征求意见。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港法院推迟就政府禁止抗议歌曲的听证会&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;政府已提前公布传票令和其他与拟议禁令相关的文件定于 7 月 21 日举行的听证会，呼吁任何反对者在 6 月 21 日之前到湾仔警署领取相关文件，并在 7 天内以书面形式提出反对。海外体育赛事错误播放《光荣归香港》而非中国国歌《义勇军进行曲》。大多数错误源于谷歌上“香港国歌”的热门搜索结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这家总部位于加利福尼亚州的科技巨头拒绝改变它所说的由算法决定的结果，这引发了北京方面的警告公司有义务传播正确的信息。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Investors need more details on Hong Kong’s mega San Tin technology-park project in Northern Metropolis, Colliers says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3224139/investors-need-more-details-hong-kongs-mega-technology-park-project-northern-metropolis-colliers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 13:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/545b74c2-cc37-4370-ab5b-b17e50f9aaae_0286f5f7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;房地产咨询公司 Colliers 表示，投资者在很大程度上仍对潜在机会一无所知新界北部占地 627 公顷的雄心勃勃的新田科技城项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被提议作为北部大都市大规模开发的旗舰项目，该场地被香港政府吹捧为一个创新和技术中心将推动城市的发展，并促进与大湾区的更紧密融合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个占地 300 公顷的项目可能需要 10 到 15 年才能实现，涉及开发建筑物预计总建筑面积达 7,000 万平方英尺的设施和设施，创造 120,000 个工作岗位，并为 6,400 名专业人士提供住房。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考虑到这些惊人的数字——仅土地总面积就相当于上环的总面积、中环、金钟和湾仔——高力香港资本市场和投资服务联席主管 Thomas Chak 表示，该开发项目为开发商和投资者提供了巨大的机会，但仍缺乏细节。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “投资者希望看到可靠的计划，以便他们能够真正开展承销模式，”高力国际的查克周三表示。 “如果没有这些坚实的计划，投资者甚至都很难开始计算，即使他们喜欢这个倡议，他们喜欢这个方向，他们也想参与进来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我敢肯定将会出现很多投资机会，但此时此刻，投资者很难迈出第一步。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“如果资金在 2 个大型项目上的使用不当，香港将面临金融危机”&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;Chak 表示，该项目的成功取决于完整生态系统的发展，该生态系统将支持预计将在那里设立基地的技术公司的需求，包括为员工和住户提供的住房和设施。&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;他说，目前对该项目的咨询通常来自在靠近中国大陆边界的新界区北部都会区附近拥有土地储备的开发商。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;周一，发展局宣布成立北方都会协调办公室 (NMCO)，以协调该项目的规划工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时宣布，前副部长邱卓恒来自该局的，将担任NMCO负责人，而前住房官员Pecvin Yong Pui-wan被任命为副主任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该项目以技术和研发为主要重点，并且靠近大陆Colliers Hong Kong 的研究主管 Kathy Lee 表示，在中国，受益于香港强大的金融和法律背景以及税收优惠的科技公司可能会发现该开发区是一个有吸引力的基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&#39;香港Kong must do more to ensure technopole success, learns from the past&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Northern Metropolis 的独特地位是吸引香港和中国大陆社区，而不是与新加坡等国际竞争对手竞争大公司Lee 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该项目还有望让香港的创业社区受益，一旦潜伏期结束，他们可能需要永久住所，他们不再有资格获得各种帮助Colliers 亚洲估值和咨询服务执行董事 Dorothy Chow 表示，该城市的科技园区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Northern Metropolis 项目最初是由时任首席执行官林郑月娥于 2021 年提出的-ngor 称其为“未来 20 年香港城市发展和人口主要增长的最具活力的地区”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Donald Trump’s arraignment took 45 minutes, but path to trial may take a couple years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224149/trumps-arraignment-took-45-minutes-path-trial-may-take-couple-years?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 13:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/cf202610-8d50-46c6-b4f4-9d8894ddee14_0699888e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周二在迈阿密联邦法院，唐纳德特朗普的传讯仅用了 45 分钟，前者总统一直保持沉默，但他的历史性机密文件案可能需要一年多的时间才能开庭审理——甚至可能在 2024 年 11 月总统大选之后。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现年 77 岁的特朗普拒不认罪通过他的律师，有权在被正式指控故意向美国政府隐瞒国家安全记录后的 70 天内获得“快速”审判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但速度不会成为描述路径的关键词法律专家表示，尽管佛罗里达州南区享有“快速审理案件”的声誉，法官通常会迅速审理刑事案件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“特朗普文件案不会很快就会进行审判，并且可能不会在 2024 年春季之前准备好进行审判，”曾在南佛罗里达州司法部有组织犯罪特别工作组工作的迈阿密律师约瑟夫·德玛利亚 (Joseph DeMaria) 说。 “但即便如此，如果法官在审判前批准任何辩护动议，政府也会上诉，这会占用更多时间。然后你会看到 2024 年夏天总统大选在即。它很容易被推迟到 2025 年。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;审判日期及其地点——迈阿密或西棕榈滩——对特朗普来说可能是一个关键因素，特朗普是众多候选人中的领跑者。共和党总统候选人提名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;首先，前总统的辩护团队预计将质疑基于选择性起诉特朗普而非其他同样拥有机密记录的政客的起诉书；提出动议以压制政府证据和证人证词；并争辩说审判将在西棕榈滩举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;自被起诉以来，特朗普已为 2024 年的竞选筹集了 700 万美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这接近于违反《间谍法》的罪行，阻挠据称，在特朗普位于棕榈滩的海湖庄园中，正义和对联邦调查局特工撒谎的行为在特朗普的海湖庄园展开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当司法部检察官在特别检察官杰克·史密斯的带领下于上周四提出起诉时，他们检查了西棕榈滩分部作为案件所在地——尽管迈阿密联邦大陪审团驳回了对特朗普和前总统助理沃尔特·诺塔的指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最重要的是，特朗普的案件从根本上说是关于非法保留政府国防文件的– 在 37 项指控中，恰好有 31 项指控涉及该罪行 – 因此双方都必须通过安全审查，并且可能会指定一名合法保管人通过审判来处理敏感材料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后最后，特朗普在纽约市的州审判定于 2024 年春季进行，罪名是伪造商业记录，同时向一名色情明星支付封口费，以阻止她在 2016 年竞选总统时公开他们涉嫌的婚外情。该案件可能会先进行审判，然后在南佛罗里达州进行联邦审判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;悬在特朗普文件案上的另一个关键问题是联邦法官在西棕榈滩分部被随机分配给谁&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国地区法官艾琳·坎农（Aileen Cannon）——曾被广泛报道为负责监督特朗普的传讯和保释听证会的法官，这项任务最终由治安法官乔纳森·古德曼（Jonathan Goodman）处理——被提名为前总统的联邦法官，就她的经验而言是一个相对新手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在特朗普失去 2020 年 11 月大选几天后加入法院系统担任法官的坎农实际上是在西棕榈滩以北的皮尔斯堡区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以上诉和写作技巧着称的前美国检察官办公室检察官坎农，因处理前总统民事案件的挑战而受到广泛批评FBI 去年夏天从海湖庄园没收了机密文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;应特朗普的要求，Cannon 任命了一名独立的特别主管，审查在 2022 年 8 月 8 日搜查特朗普总统时发现的 100 多份机密材料棕榈滩住所——尽管她发现司法部检察官和联邦调查局特工在进行搜查时是出于善意。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;特朗普起诉书中缺失的一环：他为什么这样做？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p >;上诉法院，包括其他特朗普提名的法官，发现她任命特别主管的理由有缺陷，得出结论认为她没有这样做的权力，并发布了一项严厉的裁决，推翻了她对前总统有利的决定。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;几位法律专家表示，可能没有法律理由取消坎农继续处理特朗普案的资格。但他们质疑坎农作为法官几乎没有审判经验，当然也没有涉及国家安全事务的案件，是否准备好应对挑战并保持开放的心态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然，坎农法官可以回避没有任何解释，但如果她不这样做，她拒绝这样做是不可上诉的，”美国检察官办公室前检察官、长期担任迈阿密辩护律师的马克·施纳普 (Mark Schnapp) 说。 “当然，这不是一般案件，但政府（检察官）此时要让她脱身并不容易。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南区首席联邦法官佛罗里达州的塞西莉亚·阿尔托纳加 (Cecilia Altonaga) 可以将文件案件重新分配给另一位联邦法官，她所在的迈阿密法庭曾被用于传讯特朗普。但这将是不寻常的，施纳普和其他律师说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果坎农下台，特朗普案将再次随机分配给西棕榈滩分庭的其他三名联邦法官之一：罗宾由巴拉克·奥巴马总统提名的罗森伯格、由比尔·克林顿总统任命的唐纳德·米德尔布鲁克斯或由乔治·W·布什总统提名的肯尼斯·马拉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坎农不会是唯一的法官在聚光灯下。西棕榈滩分部的治安法官布鲁斯·莱因哈特 (Bruce Reinhart) 将处理 Cannon 的审前动议和其他事务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莱因哈特在前总统的民事挑战中发现在发现海湖庄园犯罪的可能原因后，地方法官批准了联邦调查局的搜查令。据报道，莱因哈特曾受到生命威胁。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 13:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Twitter hit with US$250 million copyright lawsuit from music companies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224143/twitter-hit-us250-million-copyright-lawsuit-music-companies?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 12:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/31038c8a-5bac-49bb-9399-48590c70fd7d_220b0880.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;音乐出版商联盟，包括环球音乐出版集团、华纳查佩尔音乐和索尼Music Publishing 就涉及公司各自音乐目录的“大规模版权侵权”起诉 Twitter。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有 Drake、Taylor Swift 和 Adele 等艺术家音乐权利的 17 家音乐出版商联合提起诉讼在田纳西州联邦法院提起诉讼。他们要求对近 1,700 项版权的侵权索赔超过 2.5 亿美元。每件被侵权的作品以及其他损害赔偿金将达到 150,000 美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有 Twitter 的 Elon Musk 的 X Corp 是唯一的被告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Twitter 是唯一的被告全国音乐出版商协会首席执行官大卫·伊斯雷特在一份声明中表示：“最大的社交媒体平台完全拒绝为其服务中的数百万首歌曲提供许可。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Twitter 非常清楚每天都有数十亿人在其平台上泄露、发布和播放音乐。它不能再躲在（数字千年版权法）背后并拒绝向词曲作者和音乐出版商付款。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列指责 Twitter 将泄露的音乐、受版权保护的音乐视频和其他材料作为平台。根据 DMCA 规则，Twitter 和其他社交媒体网站受到保护，不会因用户上传的材料而受到版权攻击，前提是它们努力删除侵权材料并惩罚违规用户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，诉讼辩称 Twitter 未能做到&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Twitter 进一步声称，它会根据有效声明迅速删除内容，几乎总是在最初报告后的几小时内，如果不是在几分钟内，”诉讼中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “但现实情况是，Twitter 经常忽视已知的重复侵权者和已知的侵权行为，拒绝采取 Twitter 可用的简单步骤来阻止它知道的这些特定侵权事件。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;17 位发布者起诉 Twitter 的公司有 ABKCO Music、Anthem Entertainment、Big Machine Music、BMG Rights Management、Concord、Hipgnosis、Kobalt、Mayimba、Peer、Reservoir Media Management、Sony Music Publishing、Spirit Music Group、Royalty Network、Ultra Music Publishing、环球音乐集团出版、Warner Chappell 和 Wixen。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了回答有关诉讼的问题，Twitter 的新闻部门发送了一个大便表情符号的自动回复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Twitter 长期以来一直引起音乐界的愤怒出版商，甚至在马斯克于 2022 年 10 月购买该网站之前。在美国参议院司法小组委员会 2020 年的听证会上，美国唱片业协会指责 Twitter 没有采取任何行动来阻止其网站上的“工业规模盗版”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《纽约时报》报道，Twitter 最近曾考虑从三大唱片公司获得音乐授权，但在马斯克接管公司后谈判告吹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bloomberg 的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US nears deal to build fighter jet engines in India ahead of Modi’s White House trip]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3224138/us-nears-deal-build-fighter-jet-engines-india-ahead-modis-white-house-trip?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 12:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/05c82215-db05-4a78-ae80-1defe91a02e8_a87dc716.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国和印度可能同意在南方联合制造战斗机发动机印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪 (Narendra Modi) 下周将访问华盛顿，这标志着两国将在中国日益强硬的情况下加强军事合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据知情人士透露，该协议已接近尾声知情人士要求匿名，因为细节属于机密。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计白宫将批准总部位于马萨诸塞州的航空航天制造巨头通用电气公司的提议，以生产知情人士说，印度斯坦航空有限公司为 Tejas 轻型战斗机提供发动机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪将于 6 月 21 日开始他的首次正式国事访问。乔·拜登总统将主持他的国宴，印度领导人也将在美国国会发表讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“情况正在发生变化”：印度、美国加强与俄罗斯、中国的防务关系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;莫迪的一些成果美国国家安全顾问杰克沙利文周二在新德里的一次会议上说，访问“不仅仅是一页纸上的要点”。 “它们从根本上旨在消除我们每个国家在国防贸易、高科技贸易和投资方面的障碍。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sullivan 本周将在印度与印度高级官员会面，届时莫迪将出席会议&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫迪访问之际，拜登政府正在努力深化与对应对其认为中国日益增长的威胁至关重要的国家的关系。在加深与印度的关系时，美国似乎也愿意忽视其民主倒退，因为它试图将这个南亚国家从俄罗斯的势力范围中拉出来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国和印度之间的关系随着新德里智库政策研究中心高级研究员苏珊特·辛格 (Sushant Singh) 表示，尽管“价值观和愿景领域”存在重大差异，但对中国的担忧有所增加。 “这些目前正被利益所凌驾。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;喷气发动机协议需要美国的技术转让，需要得到美国国会的批准，印度寄希望于两国关系和两党关系的普遍好转支持清除剩余障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总部位于班加罗尔的 Hindustan Aeronautics Ltd. 和印度外交部没有立即回复置评请求。美国国家安全委员会未予置评，通用电气拒绝置评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;喷气发动机协议将符合莫迪更广泛地促进当地国防制造的努力，但与热衷于吸引新能源的国家建立技术合作伙伴关系随着俄罗斯在乌克兰的战争拖延到第二年，德里进入他们的轨道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本月早些时候，德国蒂森克虏伯公司的海军陆战队和印度的 Mazagon Dock Shipbuilders Ltd. 签署了一项初步协议，共同为印度海军建造潜艇...由于这些国家正在努力寻找一种不违反西方制裁的支付机制，向印度提供的军事供应已经停止。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着中国的发展，印度向东南亚提供高端、低成本的武器bolder&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;GE 发动机的国内生产将加强印度的战斗机计划及其空军，其快速老化的俄罗斯战斗机机队需要更换。这也将提升莫迪的形象，因为他考虑在明年的全国大选中连任第三个任期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度和美国也可能在其他国防问题上更接近达成协议，包括印度购买超过数十架武装无人机可以成倍地提高其海上和陆地防御能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;知情人士说，其目前的无人驾驶飞行器只能用于监视和侦察。随着 2020 年夏季与中国的边境紧张局势升级，新德里从美国借用了两架无人机 MQ 9B。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无人机与总部位于圣地亚哥的通用原子公司的交易陷入了官僚主义的繁文缛节多年。此外，两国还将讨论在印度联合建造八轮装甲运兵车——Stryker。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 12:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Sudan war displaces over 2 million, UN says as fighting rages in Darfur]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/africa/article/3224135/sudan-war-displaces-over-2-million-un-says-fighting-rages-darfur?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 11:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/f8b1dbcd-2e96-4f64-b944-15128d31e0ce_06cfd19e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;联合国表示，苏丹的冲突导致超过 200 万人流离失所，一名联合国官员警告说，在达尔富尔市不断升级的袭击可能构成“危害人类罪”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自 4 月中旬军方与其竞争对手准军事组织之间长达数月的紧张关系以来，苏丹陷入混乱快速支援部队在首都喀土穆和这个非洲东北部国家的其他地方爆发了公开战斗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;星期三，首都部分地区和达尔富尔西部地区的战斗有增无减，双方都看到了一些最糟糕的战斗。据追踪平民伤亡情况的苏丹医生辛迪加称，截至 6 月 12 日，至少有 959 名平民丧生，另有约 4,750 人受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;残酷的冲突已迫使超过 160 万人离开家园根据国际移民组织的说法，苏丹境内更安全的地区。该机构表示，还有大约 53 万人逃往埃及、南苏丹、乍得、埃塞俄比亚、中非共和国和利比亚等邻国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该医疗组织表示，考虑到这一点，伤亡人数可能会高得多无法考虑在西达尔富尔省首府赫纳纳持续不断的冲突中伤亡的人员。该组织表示，自 4 月份爆发战斗以来，该市的医院一直停止服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苏丹的 18 个省份都经历了流离失所，喀土穆位居榜首，约 65% 的人都流离失所。根据国际移民组织的流离失所者追踪矩阵，流离失所者总数紧随其后，西达尔富尔州超过 17%。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;180 具身份不明的尸体在苏丹激烈的战斗中被掩埋&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在 Genena，据当地活动人士和联合国官员称，在西达尔富尔省省会，RSF 和盟军阿拉伯民兵过去一周在该市肆虐，造成数百人伤亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Genena 的活动人士和居民报道数十名妇女在家中和试图逃离战斗时遭到性攻击。几乎所有强奸案都归咎于快速支援部队，而快速支援部队没有回应多次置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西达尔富尔省省长 Khamis Abdalla Abkar 指责快速支援部队和同盟民兵袭击当地社区穿过 Genena。在周三接受沙特阿拉伯电视台 Al-Hadath 的电话采访时，他敦促国际社会进行干预，以保护他所在省份的平民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在他接受电视台采访几小时后，阿布卡尔被绑架达尔富尔地区州长米尼·阿尔科·米纳维 (Mini Arko Minawi) 说。 Abkar 被绑架和杀害的情况尚不清楚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三晚间在社交媒体上流传的一段视频片段显示，一群武装人员拘留了 Abkar，其中一些人穿着 RSF 制服。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一段夜间录像——画面过于生动，无法播放——据称显示阿布卡尔躺在地上，脖子和脸上都有伤口。枪声响起，人们用阿拉伯语大喊：“这是州长”，“上帝是伟大的”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国驻苏丹特使沃尔克·佩尔特斯 (Volker Perthes) 周二表示，杰纳纳 (Genena) 的战斗已经结束被视为“种族层面”，阿拉伯民兵和身穿 RSF 制服的武装人员显示出“一种新出现的针对平民的基于种族身份的大规模有针对性攻击的模式”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此类攻击，“如果得到证实，可能构成危害人类罪，”他警告说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国防止种族灭绝问题特别顾问爱丽丝·怀里姆·恩德里图 (Alice Wairimu Nderitu) 也谴责了杰纳纳发生的“令人震惊的暴力事件”。 She warned in a statement Tuesday that such fighting could turn into “renewed campaigns of rape, murder, and ethnic cleansing amounting to atrocity crimes”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Darfur had been the scene of genocidal war in the early 2000s, when ethnic Africans rebelled, accusing the Arab-dominated government in Khartoum of discrimination. Former dictator Omar al-Bashir&#39;s government was accused of retaliating by arming local nomadic Arab tribes, known as Janjaweed, who targeted civilians.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Janjaweed later evolved into the RSF.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Additional reporting by Reuters&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 12:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘Such a mother-in-law still exists’: pregnant woman in China heatwave nearly loses baby after in-law banned air conditioner]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/environment/article/3223928/such-mother-law-still-exists-pregnant-woman-china-heatwave-nearly-loses-baby-after-law-banned-air?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/9b893730-4bbe-4539-8c1e-26cd517e2527_e6210145.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A woman in China who is 20 weeks pregnant nearly lost her baby during a severe heatwave after her mother-in-law banned using the air conditioner and has trended on mainland social media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingdao Broadcasting reported that the unnamed woman from Guangdong province in southern China and her baby were out of danger after emergency treatment in a local intensive care unit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a viral video shared with the news story, the woman is seen lying on a gurney with her pregnancy bump visible as a doctor conducts a medical check.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman said that because of her poor health, her husband suggested she stop working when she became pregnant. She said that they lived with her mother-in-law whom she accused of being a “controlling bully” who resented her presence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When temperatures reached 38 degrees Celsius on June 10, the woman found the heat increasingly unbearable. When she went to turn on the air conditioner, her mother-in-law stopped her. The older woman allegedly told the mother-to-be that she did not deserve comfort because she was not the person paying the bills.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“All the food, clothing and daily necessities are provided by my son,” the mother-in-law reportedly said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You only know how to spend money.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pregnant woman said she soon could not breathe properly and started sweating profusely before she passed out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She called the emergency hotline and was taken to a nearby hospital. She was immediately taken to intensive care for emergency treatment. When she regained consciousness, she was told by a doctor she would have lost her baby if she had not received treatment in time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have such panic and fear, and I won&#39;t forgive her. I will move out,” the pregnant woman said afterwards.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story has gone viral on Chinese social media, with many people shocked by the mother-in-law&#39;s behaviour.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person said: “Such a mother-in-law still exists?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another person added: “If I were the woman, I wouldn&#39;t listen to the mother-in-law. Why should I?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Summer heatwaves are common across much of mainland China. In July last year, a 58-year-old man in central China, who did not use air conditioning during the height of summer, suffered acute renal failure.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2017, a woman in Shanghai died during a heatwave after she declined to use air conditioning during her post-partum confinement.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why has Hong Kong launched a new public-private partnership scheme to help tackle the housing crisis?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3224092/why-has-hong-kong-launched-new-public-private-partnership-scheme-help-tackle-housing-crisis?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_explainer/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/ea8c67e9-3939-4fd6-9a58-05447e1a0e00_6e37f9cb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Housing authorities in Hong Kong have unveiled the Private Subsidised Sale Flat – Pilot Scheme, designed to restart a public-private partnership with developers to build affordable homes for middle-income buyers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Post looks at why the administration has embraced the private sector again and how the new scheme differs from similar attempts at cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;1. Why invite private developers to help?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The pilot programme was announced by Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu in his 2022 maiden policy address.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee said at the time that Hong Kong needed to tap into market forces and promote public-private partnerships.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary for Housing Winnie Ho Wing-yin explained on Tuesday that working with private companies could help boost construction capacity and efficiency, as well as unleash the development potential of private land.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three government sites have been identified under the new scheme and two, in Tung Chung and Chai Wai, will be put up for tender by the end of the financial year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Private developers can also apply to build subsidised flats on their own rezoned land.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A concessionary land premium, set at one-third of market value, will be offered for the domestic portion of any development under the new public-private scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Flats built as part of the programme have to be sold at about 65 per cent of market value. The discount is similar to the 62 per cent of market value for the latest Home Ownership Scheme flats.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;2. What response has the pilot scheme generated?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Stewart Leung Chi-kin, the chairman of the executive committee of the Real Estate Developers Association of Hong Kong, gave the new scheme a cautious welcome.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said developers should be interested in taking part, but more assessment of the market and the scheme&#39;s terms and conditions would be needed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Legislator Chan Hok-fung, also a spokesman for housing affairs for the Democratic Alliance for the Betterment and Progress of Hong Kong, said setting the sale price of flats at 65 per cent of market value was too rigid.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong needs golf course for business networking, ex-minister Fred Ma says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Home Ownership Scheme flat prices are set based on prevailing market data when the flats are about to be put on sale. But now the flats built under the pilot scheme are sold at a preset 35 per cent discount,” Chan said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If the market situation changes, the flats could become unaffordable to buyers, despite their eligibility to apply to purchase.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ryan Ip Man-ki, vice-president and co-head of research at the Our Hong Kong Foundation think tank, said encouraging more public-private partnerships was a good move. But he warned the complicated requirements could discourage developers from bidding on projects.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;3. How is the scheme different from previous ones?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The government introduced the Private Sector Participation Scheme in 1977. Under the initiative, private developers were invited to tender for housing sites on which they were required to build flats that met specifications laid down by the government.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If flats were unsold at the end of a preset period, the Housing Authority was obliged to buy them at a guaranteed price.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But under the new pilot scheme, developers will be responsible for putting all the flats in a development up for sale. The authority, the city&#39;s major public housing builder, will not buy back any unsold flats from the developers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ho said the change could be an incentive for developers to ensure they provided good-quality flats.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Subsidised flats built by Hong Kong developers to sell at 65 per cent of market price&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“I cannot see how developers would make big investments and sacrifice quality to a point where they wouldn&#39;t be able to sell or profit from them,” she told a radio programme on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The flats offered by private developers should be no less than 279 sq ft and at least 70 per cent of those for sale at each project must be bigger than 374 sq ft. The government will also specify the minimum number of units to be built.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Private Sector Participation Scheme and Home Ownership Scheme were halted in 2002 as part of a government bid to shore up the private property market amid a slump that left many homeowners with negative equity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 40 housing estates were built under the Private Sector Participation Scheme.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Home Ownership Scheme restarted in 2011.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;4. How is the existing Land Sharing Pilot Scheme doing?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong in 2020 launched an initiative allowing privately built housing sites to have a higher development density on the condition that at least 70 per cent of the additional gross floor area gained should be used for public or subsidised housing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Introduced by then leader Carrie Lam Cheng Yuet-ngor, the Land Sharing Pilot Scheme required land owners to carve out part of their sites and hand it over to the government for housing development, with the rest used for private housing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Think tank vice-president Ip said some developers might not find the terms attractive, which would explain the lukewarm response from the private sector. The scheme had only received six applications as of June.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three were granted approval in principle. These involved development sites in Yuen Long and Tai Po, which are expected to yield about 21,600 homes, including about 15,100 public housing flats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rezoning procedures are expected to start by the end of the year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Development Bureau last month announced the scheme would be extended by a year to May 5, 2024.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;5. What is Hong Kong&#39;s housing supply situation?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The government has said land supply between 2019 and 2048 will be more than 7,000 hectares (17,297 acres), surpassing the estimated demand of about 6,000 hectares.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The projected demand for public housing in the next 10 years will amount to 301,000 flats.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government said it had identified enough land to build about 360,000 flats, but emphasised the production stream for new public housing would be uneven.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only about a third of the units would be ready between 2023 and 2028, while the remainder would be completed between 2028 and 2033, it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong aims to cut wait for public flats to 3 years: housing secretary&lt;/h3>;&lt;h3>;6. What is Beijing&#39;s stance?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Beijing has described Hong Kong&#39;s housing shortage as a “deep-rooted problem” which should be tackled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The director of the State Council&#39;s Hong Kong and Macau Affairs Office, Xia Baolong, earlier said he hoped Hong Kong could “bid farewell” to subdivided flats and cage homes by 2049.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since taking office, city leader Lee has pledged to make “breakthroughs” in housing supply and come up with solutions to address the housing shortage.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Chinese couple charged with murder of South Korean influencer in Cambodia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3224132/chinese-couple-charged-murder-south-korean-influencer-cambodia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 11:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/15/7dc82909-4d1c-4e55-89eb-68fc282b86ae_62a587b2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A Cambodian court has charged a Chinese couple with murder after a popular South Korean influencer&#39;s body was dumped in a pit on the outskirts of Phnom Penh, a prosecutor said on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese couple, who run a medical clinic, were arrested last week after the body of BJ Ahyeong was found, according to a Cambodian police report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lai Wenshao, 30, and Cai Huijuan, 39, testified to police that they abandoned the woman&#39;s body after she had seizures and died while receiving treatment at their clinic on June 4, the report said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prosecutor Plang Sophal said that Lai and Cai were charged on Tuesday with “murder accompanied by torture”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They face life imprisonment if convicted of the charge.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Bali police suspect Chinese tourist killed girlfriend before taking own life&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;BJ Ahyeong was an influencer for AfreecaTV, a South Korean video streaming service, with more than 250,000 followers on Instagram.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to South Korean media, her real name was Byun Ah-yeong and she was 33 years old.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She posted on social media in March that she was giving up her influencer persona and was going to “live as a normal person for the time being”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On Tuesday, Lim Soo-suk, spokesman for South Korea&#39;s foreign ministry, said local authorities were investigating the “unfortunate incident”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The foreign ministry is providing necessary consular assistance to the bereaved family in a timely manner,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 11:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Premature baby with heart problems dies in Hong Kong hospital after tube blockage leads to delayed drug infusion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3224124/premature-baby-heart-problems-dies-hong-kong-hospital-after-tube-blockage-leads-delayed-drug?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 10:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/15/08f8e5da-7b93-4747-bf8d-e52f7655a29d_01063268.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A premature baby with heart problems died after delayed treatment at an intensive care unit in a Hong Kong public hospital, authorities have revealed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The case centred on a closed supply valve that had obstructed heart medication from reaching the infant&#39;s body for nearly an hour until equipment alarm sounded. The baby died 12 hours after the incident.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Disclosing the case late on Wednesday night, the Hospital Authority said the chief executive of Prince of Wales Hospital in Sha Tin and its clinical team had explained the problem and apologised to the family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“A root cause analysis panel would be set up to investigate the incident thoroughly. The case has been referred to the Coroner for follow-up,” the authority said in a statement, without indicating the child&#39;s gender.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The baby, born on June 12 after less than seven months in the womb, had been sent to the hospital&#39;s Neonatal Intensive Care Unit for premature birth and congenital heart issues, with doctors determining it needed ventilation care and inotropes medication – a drug that helps control heart contractions.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Newborn girl&#39;s heart stopped beating in suspected hospital blunder&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;According to a hospital spokesman, the infant&#39;s intropes dosage was adjusted at around 3am on Tuesday morning, but staff did not realise the stopcock had failed to open until 50 minutes later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Healthcare workers quickly fixed the issue, but the baby&#39;s condition continued to deteriorate until it died at 4pm on the same day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The hospital extended its deepest condolences to relatives,” the spokesman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Removal of patient&#39;s spleen was &#39;not a blunder&#39;, claims accused doctor&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The hospital said it had preliminarily reviewed the case and adopted immediate measures to prevent similar incidents, including reminding staff to be vigilant when performing drug infusions on newborns, as these involve very small dosages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The hospital would also liaise with the supplier on the feasibility of enhancing the safety procedure for infusions on newborn babies, it added.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 10:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>