<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s uniqueness under ‘one country, two systems’ doesn’t contradict patriotism, no need for ‘overcorrection’: top government adviser]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3222890/hong-kongs-uniqueness-under-one-country-two-systems-doesnt-contradict-patriotism-no-need?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 13:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/926b4e3b-cd90-43a3-b53b-3e8aeb5e664f_775942f0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;一位香港政府高级顾问表示，这座城市应该在“一个国家，两种制度”的执政原则，警告在促进爱国主义的努力中不要“矫枉过正”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行政会议主要决策机构成员唐家华在周日的电台节目中说计划认为这座城市的独特性与爱国主义并不矛盾，国家不需要另一个上海或深圳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国需要一个国家、两种制度下的香港。一个说英语的人，一个在法治和普通法下运作的人，一个拥有自由、开放和多元化的社会的人，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tong 补充说，这些属性并不与爱国主义相矛盾，爱国主义他说，在 2019 年的反政府抗议活动之后，由于情绪的反击而上升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前立法会议员指出，在任何情况下都不应该因为爱国主义而忽视一个国家、两个制度，例如最近的当局采取行动，将被视为敏感的书籍下架在公共图书馆的书架上。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“受质疑的书籍”席卷了香港图书馆的书架，但商店呢？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我不”我不同意这些类型的意见……有时矫枉过正不一定是好事，”他说，但没有进一步详细说明或具体说明他认为哪些标题不应该被删除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港经历了北京-在 2019 年社会动荡之后实施了政治改革，并于 2020 年颁布了国家安全法，以禁止分裂国家、颠覆国家政权、恐怖主义和与外国势力勾结的行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;政府顾问为香港警方使用煽动叛乱法辩护&lt;/p>; h3>;&lt;p>;政府后来改革了选举制度，以创造一个“仅限爱国者”的政治格局，大幅削减立法机关普选的席位数量，而立法机关现在由亲北京的立法者控制。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市政府也在各行各业，尤其是在教育领域推动爱国主义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，唐还表示，他同意保安局局长邓炳强对思域的呼吁该党主席兼联合创始人 Alan Leong Kah-kit 将对他在 2019 年抗议活动中的行为负责。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tong 是该党的联合创始人之一，但他于 2015 年辞职，转而追求更加中间派的立场政治道路，后来成为行政议员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“听我的前党员说暴力可以解决问题，或者进监狱会让生活更有趣，我感到非常心碎，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我觉得保安司是对的，我们不是要你跪地磕头认错，但你要清楚，当有大事的时候，从侧面为人们欢呼，你是在宽恕不法分子，你是在美化他们的行为，”他警告说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 13:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US, Chinese buyers flock to Japan flea market apps to snap up Hello Kitty, Pokemon toys due to weak yen]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3222884/us-chinese-buyers-flock-japan-flea-market-apps-snap-hello-kitty-pokemon-toys-due-weak-yen?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 13:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/7ce4c7f9-c4c8-44ba-a195-7d5d0c6a2a74_7e5358e1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;最近几个月，日本跳蚤市场应用作为二手日语吸引了更多海外用户人偶和交易卡等玩具在日元走弱的背景下吸引了更多来自美国、中国和其他地方的买家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;跨境交易越来越受欢迎，跳蚤市场应用程序运行Mercari Inc.、Yahoo Japan Corp. 和 Rakuten Group Inc. 的跨境交易，因为日元贬值为寻求保存完好的日本玩具的海外买家提供了更大的购买力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mercari 表示其跨境交易在由于日元疲软以及合作伙伴经营电子商务网站的增加，海外买家可以使用这些网站购买 Mercari 跳蚤市场应用程序上列出的商品，因此 2 月份比一年前增长了 3.2 倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rakuten Rakuma，乐天运营的跳蚤市场应用程序表示，当月其与海外用户的交易量几乎翻了五倍。由雅虎日本运营的一款跳蚤市场应用程序也观察到了类似的趋势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 Mercari 的说法，角色玩具，包括 Hello Kitty 的角色玩具和新世纪福音战士动画系列角色的可动人偶，特别受欢迎。它说，对于基于女性偶像团体的口袋妖怪交易卡和商品也有相当大的需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昂贵商品的交易也在增加，香奈儿设计师品牌包包和精工手表公司生产的手表Mercari 表示，Citizen Watch Co. 和 Citizen Watch Co. 交易活跃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该应用程序运营商表示，稀有交易卡售价超过 100 万日元（7,100 美元）的情况并不少见，其中许多人偶售价为数万日元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了应对不断增长的需求，Mercari 表示将增加在中国大陆、美国、欧洲和台湾的销售。 2 月份成为 Mercari 合作伙伴的电子商务公司 From Japan Ltd. 以 10 种语言（包括英语和中文）提供其应用程序上列出的商品的描述。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据日本产业省的一项研究2021 年，中国消费者在与日本的跨境电子商务上花费了 2.1 万亿日元（150 亿美元），同比增长 9.7%。来自美国消费者的此类交易增长了 25.7%，达到 1.2 万亿日元（86 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行业专家表示，随着海外中产阶级人口的增加，跨境交易仍有很大的增长空间用于兴趣爱好的可支配收入在增加。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获得更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 13:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Singapore, Hong Kong could emerge as crypto hubs as US cracks down on industry]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3222810/singapore-hong-kong-could-emerge-crypto-hubs-us-cracks-down-industry?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/819daa3a-2a0e-461c-b5b1-9b299a528bdc_2011f5ab.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;亚洲金融中心香港和新加坡处于有利地位，有望成为新的金融中心行业高管表示，在美国公司受到打击后，全球加密货币系统将受到影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国证券交易委员会 (SEC) 已对加密货币借贷公司处以罚款和其他处罚，而银行官员已发布政策声明，使加密货币公司难以获得信贷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年市场动荡导致数家加密货币公司申请破产。多年来被视为最可靠的公司之一的 FTX 加密货币交易所在 11 月几乎一夜之间倒闭，其创始人 Sam Bankman-Fried 被指控策划欺诈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管它一直是加密货币中心，美国尚未出台一套全面的法规，允许加密货币和区块链公司透明地运营，而不必担心监管行动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但香港和新加坡似乎走在了这场游戏的前面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港证券及期货事务监察委员会已确定规则，从 6 月 1 日起允许散户交易加密货币。该规则将允许持牌交易所向散户投资者出售具有大市值和高流动性的加密货币，并允许平台开始申请&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;尽管有加密货币禁令，但中国的科技人才仍能驾驭全球 Web3 浪潮&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新加坡已经制定了一套法规，这是全球首批法规之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“香港很自然地被定位为金融中心，并有望成为加密货币中心。它靠近中国意味着公司不想错过这个机会，”RockX 的联合创始人兼首席执行官陈竹岭说，RockX 为公司提供访问区块链的基础设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新加坡一直在规定。至少在过去的两年里，公司一直在将业务转移到这座城市，”他说。 “现在香港可能会看到类似的活动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这两个城市对待加密货币的方式不同。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“香港对待加密货币就像金融资产。他们带来了处理金融资产的所有经验，”Chen 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡正在将加密货币视为一项新技术，并承诺为构建 Web3 提供更多自由，Web3 是一个基于区块链的去中心化网络生态系统，用户可以在其中使用可以保留其数据的所有权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen 表示，新加坡将从拥有一个庞大的 DeFi（去中心化金融）和 NFT（不可替代代币）社区或区块链上的资产中获益，这与实物货币不同无法替代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加密货币交易所也在积极寻求在香港开展业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们正在与几家交易所进行讨论。我预计香港会发生一些事情，”陈说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，对于美国是否可能在最近的监管行动后出现人口外流，意见不一。虽然一些人预计最终尘埃落定，但其他人表示其最近的行动将推动公司退出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“除非美国政策出现 180 度大逆转——而且很快——将会有未来几年，大量区块链公司将退出美国，他们需要将创新和纳税资金转移到其他地方，”澳大利亚最大的在岸区块链咨询公司 Labrys 的创始人兼首席执行官 Lachlan Feeney 说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“东南亚和澳大拉西亚没有理由从中受益，”菲尼对香港的新规定表示欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;越南和印度等国家/地区的消费者一直是全球消费最快的国家之一适应加密货币，但除新加坡和香港外，其他地方的当局尚未找到有效管理数字资产的途径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bitget，一家在香港推出 1 亿美元基金的加密货币交易所4 月份投资于该地区对 Web3 友好的风险投资和初创企业，对这两个城市的前景持乐观态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“（该基金）背后的想法是我们已经注意到潜在的增长在亚洲市场。原因之一是香港和新加坡如何将自己打造为加密货币中心，”Bitget 董事总经理 Gracy Chen 表示。 “我们现在看到了一种从西方向亚洲的转变。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司希望将香港发展为运营中心，尽管“香港一直是金融中心，因此存在挑战但不是技术中心”，她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港靠近深圳等中国城市，深圳有时被称为中国的硅谷，这一优势超过了劣势，陈说。她补充说，该公司已经签署了投资协议，但现在披露还为时过早。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其他人表示，现在说对亚洲进行大规模调整还为时过早。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“虽然的确，一些人正在关注香港和新加坡等亚洲市场，大规模转变的证据充其量只是传闻，”Xapo Bank 的董事兼监管事务主管 Joey Garcia 说，该银行将传统银行业务与比特币相结合&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;企业将从这两个城市的法律确定性中获益，但制度上错综复杂的差异也为套利交易留下了空间，加西亚指的是困扰该行业的跨境风险。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;但加西亚补充说，香港金融管理局鼓励银行根据风险评估为该行业提供服务可能会吸引公司。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 12:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong-trained vets 1 step closer to being allowed to practise in city as university seeks international recognition for course]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3222851/hong-kong-trained-vets-1-step-closer-being-allowed-practise-city-university-seeks-international?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 12:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/03/355b0308-39f6-41e5-8c90-f63a6d1d5a68_e39cd030.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港首批本地受训兽医预计将于今年开始执业唯一的兽医学院获得国际机构的认可。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该兽医学院于 2017 年由城市大学创办。首批 11 名学生预计今年毕业，必须在法定兽医委员会注册后才能执业.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但要获得注册，学校的课程必须获得国际机构的认可，例如英国的皇家兽医外科学院（RCVS）或澳大利亚的澳大利亚兽医委员会（AVBC）。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港兽医管理局主席程柏中说：“城大知道需要寻求国际认可，以确保兽医学位符合国际标准。”他补充说，他对课程充满信心&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ching 表示，RCVS 和 AVBC 的代表将分别前往香港，对城大兽医学校进行最终评估。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果该项目获得认可，我们将认为该计划已达到最高标准，允许毕业生在香港执业，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ching 表示，如果获得认证，将进一步使香港高等教育与国际接轨标准，董事会很乐意考虑将学校添加到其资格列表中。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港制造的牛奶？大学在城市推出唯一的同类饮料&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;根据课程，学生必须在学习的最后两年接受临床培训。渔农自然护理署表示，已接纳 14 名学生到兽医实验室执行各项工作，例如与动物有关的检测、疾病控制以及进出口动物检验检疫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港目前拥有超过 1,100 名注册兽医，其中超过 800 名持有有效的外科手术执业证书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年，立法会修订兽医注册条例，将城大的课程纳入其中，让学生可以完成实习”赴港留学，表示校方提供足够的实践机会，包括在嘉道理农场照顾动物、在大学经营的奶牛场了解奶牛，以及在城大兽医中心观看手术程序，让学生选择自己喜欢的&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan 被分配到诊所学习如何处理小动物。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;大学农场让香港人品尝当地的乳制品2 年来的第一次&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们相信，随着学校的发展，它会好起来的”，他说，而不用担心与外国培训的学生相比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ching说本地兽医和非本地兽医之间的唯一区别是学生能够接触的物种，因为本地人遇到河马或大象等大型野生动物的机会较少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说这种“地域限制”不应是能力问题，认可机构应考虑香港的情况。他补充说，国际组织对学校的学术水平相当满意。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 12:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong mall murders: 2 victims of brutal knife attack lived ‘just 300 metres’ from Abby Choi village house]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3222887/hong-kong-mall-murders-2-victims-brutal-knife-attack-lived-just-300-metres-abby-choi-village-house?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 11:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/15bc905c-b81e-4b44-b54d-8ac177c00f1e_bc0828c4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;震惊香港的可怕购物中心谋杀案的两名受害者住在大约 300 米处据《邮报》获悉，模特蔡天凤在村屋被杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消息人士周日称，这两名年龄分别为 22 岁和 26 岁的女性朋友在一次明显的随机袭击中被刺死在钻石山荷里活广场，同居大埔龙尾村。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据传，二人与村里一栋三层洋房中层的一对夫妇同住。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;这所房子距离 33 岁的 Choi 在 2 月份的另一起谋杀案中被肢解的三层楼房只有 300 米。警方在房子的底层发现了模特的头骨、腿和一些断掉的肋骨，但她身体的其余部分仍然下落不明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;村里一位不愿透露姓名的居民说最近一起案件中的两名受害者通常开车上下班。 “这两个女孩经常开她们的车，这是一辆可爱的车，”她说。 “他们会一大早就离开家，很晚才回来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周五下午 5 点可怕的袭击发生之前，在同一家购物中心购物但离开的居民说：“这是在我和我的家人离开购物中心几分钟后听到这个消息真的很震惊。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港对购物中心的双重谋杀感到震惊。邮报看看你需要知道什么&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;她说好莱坞广场是一些村民的热门停车换乘地点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;受害者本来打算参加一个生日聚会据一位消息人士透露，当晚，另一位不愿透露姓名的村民表示，她的基督教信仰帮助她应对了村里发生的悲剧。 “我一点也不害怕，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，一名有心理健康问题的 39 岁失业男子在商场的一家商店买了一把 30 厘米的刀，然后冲向这两名女子从后面在一分钟内刺伤了这名 22 岁的男子至少 25 次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的朋友试图推开这名男子并将受伤的受害者拖到安全的地方，但袭击者追上了他们并继续他的猛攻。惊恐的购物者只能惊恐地看着，一名挥着凳子的厨师与该男子对峙，警察制服了他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;受害者被送往观塘基督教联合医院时昏迷不醒，随后被宣布死亡。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;警方表示，初步调查显示嫌疑人不认识受害人。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在患有“精神分裂症”的男子杀死 2 人后，香港将审查精神卫生服务&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;另一位熟悉的内部人士案情显示，该男子与父母同住慈云山慈乐村，2020年因家人受袭被确诊患有精神疾病。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他被送往萧林氏精神病治疗中心，然后是精神病院葵涌医院，并于当年年底出院。然后，他每三个月在门诊诊所接受定期检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;“我很害怕”：目击者回忆起香港商场谋杀案的恐怖和创伤&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;消息人士称男子去年申请结束常规咨询，但被拒绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据知情人透露，他的父母今年早些时候发现他变得容易激动和孤僻，但没有他吵架的报道&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的父亲告诉媒体，他的儿子“非常正常”，但在袭击前一天精神状态不佳。他说，一家人本来和睦，现在却处境艰难。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[‘At the peak of humanity’: Chinese climbers who give up Everest quest metres away from summit to save comatose mountaineer are praised]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3222402/peak-humanity-chinese-climbers-give-everest-quest-metres-away-summit-save-comatose-mountaineer?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/4f3f398d-c02e-41dc-bd34-86bd1cc00f7e_c72a46e0.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;两名中国登山者牺牲了登顶珠峰的梦想来拯救世界距离山顶仅400米的另一名登山者的生命在大陆社交媒体上被誉为英雄。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国南部湖南省的范江涛和谢如祥在省体育协会的一份声明中称赞他们拯救据潇湘晨报报道，珠峰山坡上的登山者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月18日晚，范某和夏尔巴向导在海拔8500米左右时，发现一名女登山者倒地倒在地上不省人事，生命体征微弱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名妇女的氧气供应已经用完，她因极低的温度而颤抖，而她的右手失去了手套，冻伤变黑了。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;范说，他立即开始努力让这名女子活下去，直到找到帮助，并且不再有登顶的想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我的向导多次问我是否真的想放弃登顶。我告诉他，&#39;是的，我的目标是挽救生命&#39;，”范说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范用他的供应给这名妇女重新装满氧气瓶，并对她进行心脏复苏。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当女子完全苏醒后，范某和他的向导扶着她下山。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从山坡上太陡了，他们花了两个小时才下了200米，这名女子又倒下了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范说，他对缓慢的步伐感到沮丧，并开始感到疲倦和痛苦&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在这么高的地方，拿着水瓶也会觉得累。”他说。 “因为我和我的向导已经达到了我们的体能极限，我们不能再移动她了。我只好让她留在那里，自己去找人帮忙。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不久，他遇到了另一位登山者谢某，谢某回忆道：“范某看到我就哭了。他告诉我他想救一个人，但他没有足够的力量。我完全理解他拯救生命的愿望。所以我也决定放弃登顶的计划，加入他的行列，去救那个女人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不管她是死是活，我们都要尽最大努力把她带到我们的身边。”大本营，”谢对他的向导说。 “她就在那里。不救她，她必死无疑。如果我们帮忙，她可能会活下来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;范、谢和他们的向导一起把这名妇女抬到海拔8000米的大本营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;报道称这位女士在几天内幸存下来并康复了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“营救过程中最困难的部分是放弃了我一生的梦想，”范说。 “虽然我们没有登顶，但挽救一个人的生命远比登顶更有价值。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“登顶珠穆朗玛峰是我们的梦想，但无法与其他人相比”谢补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事引发了一波对范和谢英雄主义的赞美。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们没有登上珠穆朗玛峰的顶峰，但他们在顶峰人类的伟大，”一位人士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你们比登顶的人更伟大。我向你们致敬！” ”另一个人补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三个人说：“我听说在珠穆朗玛峰上救人几乎是不可能的。你们是真正的勇者！”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Tech war: Japan’s new semiconductor tool export restrictions throw a major spanner in works of China’s chip plans]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/tech-war/article/3222814/tech-war-japans-new-semiconductor-tool-export-restrictions-throw-major-spanner-works-chinas-chip?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 11:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/02/878d5201-aa2e-4fa7-98f1-ebe588519e20_e6f5014b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;日本对23类芯片相关设备和材料实施新出口限制，将据业内人士称，由于具体项目具有高度选择性和针对性，该措施将于 7 月生效，将扰乱中国的半导体自给自足计划。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该措施要求对 23 种半导体的出口给予特别许可根据内部人士和《邮报》看到的一份名单，向不在 42 个“友好”市场名单上的任何国家销售商品。对中国而言，这将是事实上的禁令，类似于美国 2022 年 10 月宣布的出口限制，对北京推动提高芯片自给率的努力造成沉重打击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国当局对日本政府决定实施限制措施并敦促重新考虑，但几乎没有迹象表明该决定将被暂停或撤销。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本与荷兰类似，在其出口管制公告中并未明确提及中国.相反，东京官员表示，出口受《外汇和对外贸易法》约束，该法规范日本武器和其他可转化为军事用途的商品的出口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;清单上的限制物品范围广泛，将针对先进芯片生产所需的一系列高科技设备和材料。分析人士表示，这些限制超出了美国已经对该国施加的限制。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着与日本、韩国和台湾的贸易减弱，中国芯片进口量减少&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;例如，某些类型根据《邮报》看到的清单，将有一批深紫外 (DUV) 光刻设备使用 193 纳米光源在晶圆上印刷芯片，并可将芯片制造技术推向 14 纳米。&lt;/p>; “我的感觉是，这份清单旨在堵住中国企业可以转向的所有来自日本的替代采购来源，”一位不愿透露姓名的芯片设备投资者表示。他补充说，这些限制对中国的芯片制造行业来说可能是“毁灭性的”，该行业已经因美国的制裁而苦苦挣扎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国芯片制造商已转向非美国供应商，主要来自日本、荷兰和行业专家表示，德国在过去三年中一直在削减中国晶圆厂对美国零件的使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日本是全球芯片供应链的关键参与者，在某些利基领域处于垄断地位，这东京过去曾在与韩国的竞争中使用过。 2019 年 7 月，日本加强了对用于芯片和显示器生产的三种关键材料（氟化聚酰亚胺、抗蚀剂和氟化氢）出口到韩国的管制，扰乱了韩国的下游产业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;出口管制仅止于此今年是东京和首尔修复关系的一年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据联合国商品贸易数据库的数据，日本是 2022 年对中国最大的半导体制造设备出口国，因此北京向东京施加外交压力，要求其改弦更张。上周，商务部长王文涛告诉日本外相西村康俊，日本必须停止限制措施，因为该政策代表了违反国际贸易规则的“错误行为”。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国与日本一样对半导体管制感到担忧&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;台湾经济研究所研究芯片供应链的研究主任 Arisa Liu 表示，日本对芯片工具的限制似乎“比之前预期的更严厉”，这意味着中国未来的阻力更大。 “除了已经受到限制的先进节点外，14 纳米节点和成熟的 28 纳米节点的扩容也可能受到影响，”刘说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;列表中涵盖的大多数工具是所谓的前端半导体芯片制造所需的机械，涉及光刻、蚀刻、薄膜沉积、涂层、显影和清洁。据一位不愿透露姓名的芯片设备投资者称，这些限制还可能涵盖二手设备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;销售用于生产尖端芯片的设备的最大公司在美国，荷兰和日本，例如美国的应用材料公司、荷兰的 ASML 和日本的 Tokyo Electron。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果日本效仿 [与美国] 全面限制 [芯片制造] 的出口机器，中国在 [芯片制造] 方面的研发将被搞砸，”北京一家半导体设备制造商的工程师说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Salt Lake City, Utah district bans Bible in elementary and middle schools ‘due to vulgarity or violence’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3222880/salt-lake-city-utah-district-bans-bible-elementary-and-middle-schools-due-vulgarity-or-violence?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 11:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/04/71df6102-f0e9-4b6f-8382-7bc8dda2a941_eced2182.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;在一位家长因禁止学校教材的努力使一个郊区地区相信，有些圣经经文对于年幼的孩子来说过于粗俗或暴力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;摩尔门经可能是下一个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;72,000 名学生盐湖城以北的戴维斯学区从小学和中学移除了圣经，但在一个委员会审查了圣经以回应家长的投诉后，它在高中保留了下来。根据 2022 年州法律要求学区在决定什么构成“敏感材料”时，学区已经删除了其他书籍，包括谢尔曼·亚历克西的“一个兼职印第安人的绝对真实日记”和约翰·格林的“寻找阿拉斯加”。 ”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;在朝鲜被捕的基督徒面临死亡和监禁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;周五，有人提交了一份投诉，内容涉及犹他州主要信仰的标志性经文，耶稣基督的教会后期圣徒，广为人知的摩门教会。学区发言人克里斯威廉姆斯证实有人提出了对摩尔门经的审查请求，但没有说明列出的原因。引用学校董事会的隐私政策，他也不会说这是否来自抱怨圣经的同一个人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教会的代表拒绝就这一挑战发表评论。该信仰的成员也阅读圣经。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;威廉姆斯说，学区不区分书评请求，也不考虑投诉是否可以作为讽刺作品提交。审查由一个由教师、家长和管理人员组成的委员会处理，该委员会主要是保守的社区。&lt;/​​p>;&lt;p>;该委员会在审查请求的在线数据库中公布了它对圣经的决定，但没有详细说明其推理&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一决定是在保守的家长活动家（包括父母联合会的各州分会）涌入美国各地的学校董事会和州议会大厦之际做出的，他们对以下问题发出警告：学校如何谈论性和暴力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由于该学区的隐私政策，不知道是谁提出了禁止在戴维斯学校使用圣经的要求，或者他们是否隶属于任何更大的团体。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;盐湖城论坛报通过公共记录请求获得的投诉副本显示，家长指出圣经中包含乱伦、卖淫和强奸的例子。 The complaint derided a “bad faith process” and said the district was “ceding our children&#39;s education, First Amendment Rights, and library access” to Parents United.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Utah Parents United left off one of the most sex-ridden books around: The Bible,” the parent&#39;s complaint, dated December 11, said. It later went on to add, “You&#39;ll no doubt find that the Bible [under state law] has &#39;no serious values for minors&#39; because it&#39;s pornographic by our new definition.”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Is Michelangelo&#39;s David porn? Come and see, Italians tell Florida parents&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The review committee determined the Bible didn&#39;t qualify under Utah&#39;s definition of what&#39;s pornographic or indecent, which is why it remains in high schools, Williams said. The committee can make its own decisions under the new 2022 state law and has applied different standards based on students&#39; ages in response to multiple challenges, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An unnamed party filed an appeal on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Bible has long found itself on the American Library Association&#39;s list of most challenged books and was temporarily pulled off shelves last year in school districts in Texas and Missouri.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Concerns about new policies potentially ensnaring the Bible have routinely arisen in statehouses during debates over efforts to expand book banning procedures. That includes Arkansas – one of the states that enacted a law this year that would subject librarians to criminal penalties for providing “harmful” materials to minors, and creates a new process for the public to request materials be relocated in libraries.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t want people to be able to say, &#39;I don&#39;t want the Bible in the library,” Arkansas Democratic state Senator Linda Chesterfield said during a hearing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parents who have pushed for more say in their children&#39;s education and the curriculum and materials available in schools have argued that they should control how their children are taught about matters like gender, sexuality and race.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;EveryLibrary, a national political action committee, told Associated Press last month it was tracking at least 121 different proposals introduced in legislatures this year targeting libraries, librarians, educators and access to materials. The number of attempts to ban or restrict books across the US in 2022 was the highest in the 20 years, according to the American Library Association.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If folks are outraged about the Bible being banned, they should be outraged about all the books that are being censored in our public schools,” said Kasey Meehan, who directs the Freedom to Read programme at the writers&#39; organisation PEN America.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong air-conditioner sales, demand for repairs surge as mercury soars, while subdivided flat tenants among hardest hit]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3222848/hong-kong-air-conditioner-sales-demand-repairs-surge-mercury-soars-while-subdivided-flat-tenants?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 10:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/04/0c240963-b295-41c6-822f-a1817027314c_f9eec5cf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Sales of air conditioners have jumped in Hong Kong while demand for urgent repairs skyrocketed amid rising temperatures, with those living in subdivided flats among the worst affected, according to two online platforms and an advocacy group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Online marketplace HKTVmall said sales of air conditioners had risen by about 30 per cent between May 21 and 27 compared with the week before, while total transactions for the appliance last month soared about 260 per cent from February.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Papabo, a Hong Kong-based platform that connects customers with home repair workers, said the recent heatwave had triggered an influx of job requests related to air conditioners.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong hiking expert tells trekkers to &#39;listen to your body&#39;&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Its app received close to 1,000 requests last week during the soaring temperatures, compared with about 500 a week before, according to a company spokesman. More than half were related to air conditioners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Papabo said 41.6 per cent of the requests were regarding cooling issues caused by clogged filters, insufficient coolant or defective parts, among other problems&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 27 per cent of customers on the platform said their machines were leaking water, and another 23 per cent reported they needed professional cleaning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Without doubt, the heatwave has brought us tremendous growth in job requests related to air conditioners,” the spokesman said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong reported record-breaking temperatures for the month of May, with mercury reaching a year-high of 34.7 degrees Celsius (94.5 Fahrenheit) on Wednesday last week, largely caused by Mawar, a storm hovering northeast of Taiwan and heading towards Japan&#39;s Okinawa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Observatory forecast the hot weather would linger this week, at above 31 degrees, and said expected rain would do little to ease the conditions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city&#39;s poor have suffered as the hot weather sets in, according to Sze Lai-shan, deputy director of human rights advocacy group Society for Community Organisation (SoCo).&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Summer is a very difficult time for people who live in subdivided housing, because not only is there heat, it also brings out a lot of rodents and pests,” Sze said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong issues year&#39;s first &#39;very hot weather&#39; warning&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“The temperature in many of these homes are usually several degrees higher than it is outside, because they are so small and cramped and the air has nowhere to go.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said SoCo had been advocating for higher government subsidies for these residents during the summer so they could afford to turn on their fans or air conditioners.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong Yim, a 40-year-old stay-at-home mother who lives in a subdivided flat on the top floor of a nine-storey walk-up building in Sham Shui Po, said she had been feeling as though she was “being cooked at home” for the past few days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The sun shines directly onto our unit so it gets really hot in here,” she said. “When we turn on the tap, the water comes out almost boiling.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wong, who lives in a 120 sq ft room with her 15-year-old son, is currently in Hong Kong under a “two-way permit” for mainland Chinese residents to enter the city. Her son is a Hong Kong permanent resident, but since he is under 18, he is not eligible for public housing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She revealed she spent half of her HK$6,000 (US$766) per month in government subsidies on rent, leaving little for food, transport and utility bills.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are very nervous about turning on the air conditioner because we don&#39;t know how much money it racks up,” Wong said. “In the summer, I turn it on at around 10pm before bed, and turn it off at 4am, but the home heats up very quickly.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the day, while her son is at school, Wong stays out of the flat as much as possible. She said she had “nowhere to go” and would occasionally sit in the local McDonald&#39;s for relief from sweltering conditions outside.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong can sue bosses who don&#39;t follow new heatstroke guidelines: minister&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Leung Wing-mo, former assistant director of the Observatory, said Hong Kong had now officially entered summer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked how people at home could save on energy bills or make their air conditioners more efficient, Leung said flats facing west were more likely to encounter heat problems, especially if there were large windows, as they would have full sunlight most of the day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That&#39;s why in Hong Kong, you always want to live in a flat facing south,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For those who did not have that choice, windows with heat and light reflective technology had proven effective in lowering indoor temperatures, Leung said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s deadly train crash renews questions over safety as government pushes railway upgrade]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/south-asia/article/3222883/indias-deadly-train-crash-renews-questions-over-safety-government-pushes-railway-upgrade?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 10:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/04/a624d10a-bc97-4dff-9b4c-c61bf72acf5e_3207f810.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;India&#39;s prime minister had been expected to inaugurate an electrical semi-high-speed train equipped with a safety feature – another step in the modernisation of an antiquated railway that is the lifeline of the world&#39;s most populous nation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instead on Saturday, Narendra Modi travelled to eastern Odisha state to deal with one of the country&#39;s worst train disasters that left over 280 dead and hundreds injured. The massive derailment on Friday night involving two passenger trains is a stark reminder of safety issues that continue to challenge the vast railway system that transports nearly 22 million passengers each day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;India, a country of 1.42 billion people, has one of the world&#39;s most extensive and complicated railways built during the British colonial era: more than 40,000 miles (64,000 kilometres) of tracks, 14,000 passenger trains and 8,000 stations.从北部的喜马拉雅山到南部的海滩，它遍布全国，也是一个因数十年管理不善和忽视而被削弱的系统。 Despite efforts to improve safety, several hundred accidents happen every year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From 2017 to 2021, there were more than 100,000 train-related deaths in India, according to a 2022 report published by the National Crime Records Bureau. That figure includes cases in which passengers fell from the trains, collisions, and people being mowed by speeding trains on the tracks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official data also suggests derailments are the most common form of rail accidents in India, but have been on a decline in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to India&#39;s Comptroller and Auditor General, Indian Railways recorded 2,017 accidents from 2017 to 2021. Derailments accounted for 69 per cent of the accidents, resulting in 293 deaths.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report found multiple factors including track defects, maintenance issues, outdated signalling equipment, and human errors as main causes of the derailments. It also said lack of money or non-utilisation of available funds for track restorations led to 26 per cent of the accidents.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even though the railway safety in India has improved compared to earlier years when serious crashes and accidents near unstaffed crossings were more frequent, scores have still died and hundreds have been injured.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2016, a passenger train slid off the tracks between the cities of Indore and Patna, killing 146 people. A year later, a derailment in southern India killed at least 36 passengers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Modi government, in power for nine years, has invested tens of billions of dollars in the railways. The money has been spent on renovating or replacing the old tracks laid by the British in the 19th century, introducing new trains and removing thousands of unstaffed railway crossings.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The train Modi was supposed to inaugurate on Saturday was India&#39;s 19th Vande Bharat Express, connecting the western city of Mumbai and the southern state of Goa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The modern trains are designed to help reduce the risk of crashes and derailments. They will be paired with a countrywide automatic train collision protection system, a technology that will make travel safe, according to Railway Minister Ashwini Vaishnaw.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the system was not yet installed on the track where Friday&#39;s crash took place. It wasn&#39;t clear what caused the trains to derail and an investigation has started.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts suggest that the country&#39;s railway system needs to prioritise safe tracks and collision protection.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“India has achieved some success in making train journeys safer over the years, but a lot more needs to be done. The entire system needs a realignment and distributed development. We can&#39;t just focus on modern trains and have tracks that aren&#39;t safe,” said Swapnil Garg, a former officer of the Indian Railway Service of Mechanical Engineers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Garg said the crash should “shake up the whole railway system” and prompt authorities to look at the “lax safety culture.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I don&#39;t expect authorities to turn the key and fix things quickly. The Indian railway system is huge and it will take time to make it more safer. But there needs to be a will,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 10:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Dubai’s booming housing market attracts Asia’s rich, with ‘clear demand-supply imbalance’ set to push prices up further]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/article/3222784/dubais-booming-housing-market-attracts-asias-rich-clear-demand-supply-imbalance-push-prices-further?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.04 10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/02/316b037d-ab0e-4725-bcc9-e42498a5c768_1b399e69.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Japan, Canada or Dubai? Hong Kong marketing executive Simon Cheng had been carefully weighing his options on where to buy real estate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Japan, he was worried about the tax, the location and the local economy. Between Canada and Dubai, he found the glitzy financial hub of the United Arab Emirates the more attractive of the two.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Rental yield in Hong Kong is around 2 per cent, versus 6 or 7 per cent I expect in Dubai” he said. “It&#39;s a better long-term investment. I&#39;m not worried about being unable to rent out my property in Dubai. People are rich there.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The city is one of the world&#39;s most affordable luxury residential markets, according to Knight Frank. US$1 million can fetch a 226 sq ft flat in Hong Kong, or a 1,130 sq ft home in Dubai, according to the real estate consultancy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it remains to be seen how much longer Dubai can hold on to that title, as the city&#39;s property market is picking up momentum. Home prices in Dubai increased by 5.6 per cent in the first quarter, climbing for a ninth consecutive quarter, Knight Frank&#39;s data showed. Luxury homes in particular surged 44 per cent last year, the highest globally, compared with the 1.3 per cent decline in Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With only 289 homes in Dubai&#39;s prime districts expected to be delivered by 2025, Knight Frank expects the “clear demand-supply imbalance” to further push up prices by another 13.5 per cent this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The growth has prompted expatriates like Mrs Lau and her husband, who moved to Dubai from Hong Kong eight months ago, to buy a town house after renting for four months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mrs Lau, who did not want to use her first name, was keenly aware of the skyrocketing rents in Dubai, which rose 25.8 per cent in the first four months this year, data from CBRE showed. “If rents and prices keep rising, buying a home here for our own use is not a bad thing,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She is not alone. “Many new arrivals start looking for homes to buy within the first two months because they see how prices are surging,” said Stephanie Yim, an agent at Bemine Properties in Dubai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The influx of ultra-wealthy investors has boosted transaction volumes. Last year, the city emerged as the world&#39;s fourth most active market for luxury home sales, with 219 homes worth over US$10 million sold for a total of US$3.8 billion, trailing behind New York, Los Angeles, and London, according to Knight Frank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first quarter of this year, 88 such homes were sold for over US$1.63 billion thanks to strong demand from ultra-high net worth individuals – those with a net worth of US$30 million or more. Average transaction prices rose 16 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the whole year, Knight Frank predicts US$2.5 billion to flow into Dubai&#39;s real estate from individuals with a net worth of over US$3 million.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Knight Frank said a large part will be coming from China, Hong Kong and Singapore, as its survey found that 90 per cent of this group is interested in buying this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Clearly there is an element of revenge spending mixed in there as we saw elsewhere in the world when the Covid restrictions were scaled back,” said Faisal Durrani, partner and head of Middle East Research at Knight Frank. “We&#39;re likely to see that from locations such as China, in particular.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the start of the year, real estate consultancy Juwai IQI has been fielding growing inquiries about homes in the UAE from mainland Chinese buyers. The Gulf nation climbed three places to rank as the sixth most popular destination, its highest ever, according to Juwai.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The interest from Asia&#39;s wealthy has prompted Dubai-based agencies to tap buyers from the region. Huaxia Real Estate hosted presentations in Malaysia and Singapore last week and organised tours in Dubai, while D&amp;B Properties set up a China-focused team in May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Dubai&#39;s property market is not without risk. It has been on a roller-coaster ride over the past two decades and is highly correlated to oil prices, UBS said in its report on the global real estate bubble index in October.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Swiss bank said Dubai&#39;s home price growth is likely to remain high in the coming quarters thanks to looser residence requirements, but growth will gradually recede amid higher financing costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the long term, with existing oversupply and new construction continuing to outstrip population growth, Dubai&#39;s real estate ride will most likely remain bumpy,” it said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Dubai can be a gateway to Middle East for Hong Kong firms, officials say&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Dubai is also vulnerable to global macroeconomic conditions, Knight Frank warned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Its survey found that while global investors were keen, they are concerned about rising inflation, economic slowdown, oversupply and conflict in eastern Europe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Azar Zaidi, a Post editor who relocated to Dubai in February, is on the lookout for a house but said he “will wait until things calm down a bit”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It seems that the market is super hot right now, and we don&#39;t want to overpay,” he said.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 04 Jun 2023 10:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>