<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Can gaps in Hong Kong’s psychiatric care be fixed by tighter control on patients? New orders could help, but concerns remain over rights: experts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3223669/can-gaps-hong-kongs-psychiatric-care-be-fixed-tighter-control-patients-new-orders-could-help?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 23:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/63d15897-545c-4017-a58d-99554cfeedaf_4d5968bb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港可以通过强制要求患者住院治疗来解决其处理精神病案件的漏洞医学专家表示，社区中有很多人没有接受治疗，但必须采取措施缓解人们对权利的担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们发表上述言论之前，卫生当局宣布了一项计划，审查是否有必要引入如此-本月早些时候，一名精神失常的男子持刀横冲直撞，导致两名年轻女性死亡，因此被称为社区治疗令。该想法是加强该市精神卫生支持措施的 10 项提案之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些命令是一项法律规定，旨在确保精神障碍患者在不接受医院护理时遵循规定的治疗过程.如果患者不服从，可以强制要求在医院接受治疗。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港考虑对社区精神病病例制定新规则&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;2017 年对本地精神卫生服务的审查裁定选项不合适。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前约有 1,300 人有条件出院，这是该市唯一的强制性治疗机制。但该措施仅适用于有暴力倾向且已从精神病院出院的患者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;香港心理健康协会创办人兼会长、精神病学家林美龄医生表示，社区治疗令可能修复这个漏洞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前非自愿入院的要求是，该人（通常是罪犯）必须被诊断出患有精神障碍，不了解自己的精神疾病，拒绝任何形式的据精神科医生称，门诊治疗有伤害他人或自己的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年，有超过 3,700 名患者非自愿入院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有了社区治疗令，当患者无法满足所有标准并入院时，医疗保健专业人员仍然可以做一些事情[以确保该人接受治疗]，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但精神科医生 Ivan Mak Wing 医生- chit 警告说，如果执行不当，这些命令可能会适得其反，尽管他同意讨论是在正确的时间进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“患者和他们的家人可能会对受到限制感到不舒服。它还可能影响医患关系，引发人权和患者权利的争议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mak 表示，如果该措施在香港实施，卫生当局将必须明确说明可以实施或取消该命令的条件。这些措施可能包括患者提出此类请求的上诉机制以及每个命令的时限。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港妈妈被控谋杀仍在精神病院的女儿&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;患者权利倡导者林志友也质疑这项措施在促进病人康复方面的成效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些病人可能因为精神状况而没有意识到需要服药，”他说，并补充说这项措施可能会给已经承受巨大压力的照顾者带来额外的压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不应要求患者自己承担唯一的责任。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自多个学科的额外人手他说，包括社会工作者、医生和非政府组织的工作人员在内，需要密切监测病人和支持护理人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还表示担心医生会更倾向于进行社区治疗由于担心如果患者实施暴力行为会承担疏忽责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;袭击香港摊主“可能是出于商业纠纷”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Crystal Yuen Shuk-yan社区组织协会 (SoCO) 的社区组织者，表示担心该措施可能会阻止患者寻求帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“措施越强制，患者就越不愿意寻求治疗”袁女士说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她又指出，海外经验显示该措施未能有效降低再入院率，而香港也缺乏精神保健人员协助执行命令。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;尽管在包括英国和澳大利亚在内的许多国家越来越多地使用该命令，但其在降低再入院率和凶杀率方面的功效仍不确定。批评者将其描述为家长式和歧视性的行为，同时也削弱了精神疾病患者的选择自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港购物中心发生残忍持刀袭击事件，2 名妇女被刺死&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In在英国，政府在今年早些时候被敦促取消对大多数患者的此类措施，除了那些在刑事诉讼中或被判刑的人，因为这些措施不成比例地用于少数民族成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个加强精神健康服务措施清单的主要建议是缩短较优先个案的轮候时间，同时分配更多人手和引入副作用较少的新药物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医院管理局的数据显示占总病例数 5% 的精神科门诊新病例的平均等待时间为一周。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些具有第二优先级的病例，占对于 20% 的案件，不得不等待三到四个星期。但稳定病例可能需要等待 18 至 65 周，最长的需要等待 95 周。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前卫生部长兼现任香港重要决策机构行政会议成员的高永文博士，表示当局应考虑为家庭医生提供精神科培训，并让他们以公私合作的形式处理轻症病例。这样的安排可以让公共部门的病人以补贴的价格向私人医生寻求跟进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他指出，精神科护士在接受适当的培训和指导后也可以处理此类案件.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这种机制将有助于筛选他们的转介信，并根据患者病情的紧急程度和严重程度进一步对患者进行分类，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;叶伯强医生心理健康谘询委员会成员，表示卫生当局应聘请更多私人精神科医生加入公私营伙伴关系，以进一步减轻公营医疗系统的负担。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 23:50:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elon Musk’s SpaceX hires 14-year-old for ‘dream’ job]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/americas/article/3223661/elon-musks-spacex-hires-14-year-old-dream-job?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 21:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/5e099d4e-407c-40f1-807d-62532410a5c5_f9a54843.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;SpaceX 最新招聘的一名软件工程师通过了“技术挑战”和“有趣”的面试过程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凯然夸子的不同之处在于他只有 14 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他周四在 LinkedIn 帖子中说：“我将加入作为 Starlink 工程团队的软件工程师，地球上最酷的公司。很少有公司没有将我的年龄作为成熟度和能力的武断和过时的代表。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这篇文章是在他从圣克拉拉大学工程学院毕业前不久发布的，成为最年轻的人这样做，西雅图时报报道。据报道，他计划与母亲一起从加利福尼亚州的普莱森顿搬到位于华盛顿州雷德蒙德的 SpaceX 工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Quazi 的非凡旅程始于两岁，当时他可以完整地说话句子。据《洛杉矶时报》报道，在上幼儿园时，他正在向其他孩子和老师讲述他在收音机中听到的新闻故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 9 岁的三年级发现他的功课不够具有挑战性后，据报道，他的父母帮助他进入了加利福尼亚的一所社区大学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我觉得我的学习水平达到了我应该学习的水平，”他告诉《洛杉矶时报》。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;同年，他的家人告诉 BrainGain 杂志，在一项智商测试中，他被排在总人口的 99.9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Quazi 在几个月后进入英特尔实验室，11 岁的他转到圣克拉拉大学学习计算机科学与工程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，他在网络情报公司 Blackbird.AI 担任了四个月的机器学习实习生，根据他的 LinkedIn 个人资料。根据他的个人资料，他帮助设计了一个“异常检测统计学习管道”来标记社交媒体内容是否被操纵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Quazi 告诉 ABC7 新闻：“我认为我缺少一种传统的思维方式关于童年，但我认为那不是真的。我再次认为，这种心态会让我现在中学毕业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看起来他已经通过获得 Starlink 的工作实现了一个抱负。他在 LinkedIn 的个人简介中写道：“我的梦想是拥有一份解决具有挑战性的问题并实现激进创新以服务于公共利益的职业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Starlink 是 SpaceX 的卫星互联网服务，于 1 月开始运营尼日利亚——它的第一个非洲市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Starlink 没有立即回应 Insider 在正常工作时间之外提出的置评请求。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Is this the hoped-for thaw in China-US relations or a new era of managing differences?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223642/hoped-thaw-china-us-relations-or-new-era-managing-differences?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/eb27c13f-1000-4a5a-b6f4-b680b0b01e39_4e50a62b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;最近几周中美高级官员之间的会谈给中美两国之间的紧张局势带来了希望世界上的两个大国可能正在放松。在关于中美关系的第一篇文章中，Orange Wang 探讨了最近的重新接触是否标志着一个更稳定关系的转折点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国气球事件使两国和解的尝试破灭近四个月后天空中，一系列涉及中美高级官员的公开接触似乎带来了希望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月下旬，两国在拜登政府领导下的华盛顿举行了首次内阁级交流，中国商务部长王文涛与美国外长吉娜·雷蒙多会谈，随后在底特律会见了美国贸易代表凯瑟琳·泰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在创纪录的五个月空缺之后，北京终于派出新任大使谢峰前往华盛顿上个月。谢于 5 月 25 日会见了美国副国务卿维多利亚纽兰，并于 6 月 2 日会见了财政部副部长杰伊尚博。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据报道，美国国务卿安东尼布林肯也将在未来几周访问中国，此前美国助理国务卿丹尼尔克里滕布林克东亚和太平洋事务国务卿以及国家安全委员会中国和台湾事务高级主任莎拉·贝兰本月访问了北京。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但两国专家警告说，尽管最近高级别的接触，仍然很难看到美中紧张局势隧道尽头的曙光，相互之间一直存在深深的不信任，华盛顿和北京几乎没有时间来修补他们的紧张关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，他们说，这两个大国可能正在进入一个新的现实，在这个现实中，接触的目的只是为了管理利益重叠的分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月下旬，在拜登的国家安全顾问进行了 10 小时的会谈后，杰克·沙利文 (Jake Sullivan) 和中国最高外交官王毅在维也纳表示，美国总统表示气球事件是“愚蠢的”，他预计“很快”就会与北京解冻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国现在似乎美中对话倡议组织高级研究员丹尼斯·怀尔德 (Dennis Wilder) 表示，他们正在努力利用去年 11 月在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行的拜登与习近平会面时获得的势头，通过内阁级别的访问“在战术上有所改进”前中央情报局中国分析师和白宫官员怀尔德说：“但双方都没有把自己的目标定得很高。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;时殷弘，一位北京人民大学国际关系教授表示，最近的事态发展并不等同于中美关系朝着实质性、明显的改善方向发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对话和沟通——以及它们产生的结果——是完全不同的事情，”中国国务院前顾问时说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，从 11 月在巴厘岛举行的双边会议到在广岛举行的七国集团峰会之间，中美紧张局势一直在加剧上个月，他没有看到任何单一重大争端有任何显着、持久的缓解迹象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鉴于紧迫的美国总统选举周期，专家们对修复关系的可用时间也持悲观态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“拜登政府不希望任何人认为它在竞选期间对中国软弱，”怀尔德说，并补充说这个窗口将在今年年底关闭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢中国社会科学院 (CASS) 的美中关系专家向则更加谨慎，预计现在已经进入“最后阶段”的窗口只会持续到 8 月底。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“未来两三个月有改善的可能吗？我认为还有一线希望，”卢说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然，我们不知道美国是否真的感到紧迫。现在是考验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“未来三个月可能是中美关系最重要的三个月。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;幕后外交的回归为中美关系带来希望美中关系&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;直到最近一轮高级官员会晤之前，多方面的紧张局势仍在加剧，包括台湾、科技战争、南中国海和人权问题。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;在戴与王会面前一周，美国贸易代表办公室于 5 月 18 日宣布，美国和台湾已就其“21 世纪”贸易倡议的第一部分达成协议。北京表示坚决反对此举，并敦促美国“谨慎”处理与台北的经贸关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约在同一时间，世界两大经济体之间的高科技战争随着中国的升级而升级已禁止销售总部位于爱达荷州的美光科技公司的产品，声称这家美国存储芯片制造商构成“国家安全风险”。华盛顿表示，这一说法“没有事实根据”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在日本举行的 G7 峰会上，美国及其盟友同意发起一项新举措来对抗中国的“经济胁迫”。他们还表示，北京在南中国海“扩张”的海洋主张没有法律依据，并对中国的人权状况表示担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京似乎保持冷静，区分更多&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及最近的接触是否标志着双边紧张局势的“转折点”时，中国外交部发言人毛宁于 5 月 26 日表示，“重要的是美国不能要求沟通与中国的合作，同时以一切可能的方式损害和遏制中国的利益”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说两国“保持必要的沟通”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bonnie Glaser，亚洲项目主任美国的德国马歇尔基金会怀疑任何一方现在都期望重新设置他们的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国和中国对对方国家意图的评估不太可能改变；相互不信任根深蒂固，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她还预计，最好的希望是恢复两国之间的对话，以处理双边分歧和利益重叠的某些形式的合作。&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;怀尔德还将“极度缺乏信任”视为健康和可持续美中关系的“最大障碍”，并补充说，只有持续的高层接触才能消除相互误解。&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;美国和欧盟为人工智能和其他新技术制定规则，但在中国威胁问题上存在分歧&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;这种不信任反映在高层的言辞中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3 月，中国国家主席习近平直接指责美国怂恿其他西方国家帮助打压中国发展。自去年以来，拜登政府将中国称为“唯一有意并有能力重塑基于规则的国际秩序的竞争对手”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国财政部长珍妮特耶伦表示，美国无意利用贸易限制来扼杀中国的崛起。不过，北京在 5 月初指责华盛顿实施出口管制，不仅遏制和拖垮中国，而且遏制和拖垮大量发展中国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登政府一再表示，它不是在寻求另一场冷战或与中国发生冲突。华盛顿最近与其盟友结盟，声称其寻求降低风险，但不寻求与中国脱钩，北京不接受这一信息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月在欧洲时，中国外交部长秦刚仍在警告“某个国家”——显然是指美国——正在发动“新冷战”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济关系也有所缓和，美中贸易似乎有所缓和根据美中贸易全国委员会 5 月 25 日发布的一份报告，经过数十年的稳步增长后，去年略有下降。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普时代对价值数千亿美元的中国商品征收的关税在贸易战仍在继续，而拜登则保持对特定行业的排斥程序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中美关系仍处于谷底，仍处于非常危险的状态，中国社会科学院的卢说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“大多数国家都非常担心中美之间的冲突进一步激化，当然，中美也有同样的担忧，”他说，并指出稳定和建设性的中美关系这符合中国的利益，也是北京一直追求的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管美国最近发表了期待“解冻”的言论，但中国更看重美方言行一致，他说，并补充说，美国正在走上负和博弈的道路，这也伤害了自己。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢说，两国很难一次解决所有分歧，他们不应该期望有空间改善双边关系立即变得非常大，但双方可以在一些实际领域迈出第一步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢说，贸易可以是一个起点。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国考虑到中亚国家37亿美元宏伟计划&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;华盛顿布鲁金斯智库高级研究员瑞恩·哈斯预计，北京和华盛顿在未来几个月内将更多地尝试加强外交沟通渠道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些努力不会解决两国关系中的任何潜在挑战，但它们将使双方更容易应对挑战，”白宫国家安全委员会前中国事务主任哈斯说。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;哈斯在上个月发表的一篇文章中建议，如果美国官员想降低与中国的风险，他们应该就具体问题提出具体计划，例如避免进行会产生轨道碎片的反卫星试验， &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国应该暂停与北京就处理关系的危机管理机制和原则进行谈判的努力，因为现有的谈判没有取得进展的余地他补充说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China-US reengagement]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/series/3223662/china-us-reengagement?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 22:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_series/public/d8 /images/2023/06/10/eb27c13f-1000-4a5a-b6f4-b680b0b01e39.JPEG&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 22:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pope recovering well from hernia surgery but to skip Sunday blessing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3223658/pope-recovering-well-hernia-surgery-skip-sunday-blessing?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 20:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/f04aa9a5-86e3-4361-961f-2faec4eb8658_ec3e665b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;教皇弗朗西斯的手术恢复顺利，但医生建议他不要分娩周日在医院的阳台上进行祝福，以避免腹部拉伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，首席外科医生塞尔吉奥·阿尔菲耶里 (Sergio Alfieri) 在 Gemelli 医院向记者介绍情况时还表示，这位 86 岁的老人已与医生达成一致，将在医院停留 20 天。至少下周整个时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，弗朗西斯接受了一次三小时的腹部疝气手术。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;教皇弗朗西斯在三小时的疝气手术后清醒并开玩笑&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;“才过去三天。我们要求圣父谨慎行事，避免（站在阳台上）紧张，”阿尔菲里说。 “每次他起床坐在扶手椅上时，都会对腹壁施加压力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将网状假体插入腹壁以帮助其愈合，医生希望它能够正确固定和附着他补充说，以避免在手术失败时进行另一次手术。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你可以理解，这对他和我来说是多么不愉快，”阿尔菲里开玩笑说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梵蒂冈发言人马泰奥·布鲁尼 (Matteo Bruni)说教皇会在他的医院套房里做传统的中午三钟经祈祷，信徒们可以同时念。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alfieri 说，教皇在星期五停止了静脉输液，并开始使用半流质饮食。他补充说，所有医疗参数都在正常范围内，没有心脏问题，腹部疤痕完全愈合大约需要三个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梵蒂冈说验血结果很好，胸部 X 光显示没问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;方济各 21 岁时在他的祖国阿根廷因病切除了部分肺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;手术后医生说教皇康复后旅行和其他活动应不受限制。他将于 8 月 2 日至 6 日前往葡萄牙参加世界青年日并参观法蒂玛神殿，并于 8 月 31 日至 9 月 4 日前往蒙古，这是他将访问过的最偏远的地方之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布鲁尼重申所有的观众都被取消，直到 6 月 18 日，但之后教皇的日程将暂时保留。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教皇传统上会在 7 月休假，周日的祝福是他唯一的公开露面，所以他会在葡萄牙之行之前有整整一个月的休息时间。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[China and Thailand to expand military ties amid Asia-Pacific ‘security challenges’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3223655/china-and-thailand-expand-military-ties-amid-asia-pacific-security-challenges?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/a6a7b373-43a8-4139-b542-e4359b5637f0_6d531caf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国愿与泰国扩大军事合作，维护地区稳定，一系列举措计划于今年举行的联合演习。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，中国国防部长李尚福在北京会谈时向泰国皇家陆军总司令纳龙潘吉开泰提供了保证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“中方愿与泰方一道，切实落实两国领导人达成的重要共识……推动两军特别是两军合作取得更多成果，”国防部援引李&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次会晤距离中国国家主席习近平和泰国总理巴育在曼谷亚太经合组织论坛期间会面大约七个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李说，今年两国计划举行各种联合演习，包括“突击 2023”和“和平与友谊 2023”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在亚太当前面临的背景下中方愿与泰方共同维护地区稳定，确保地区长治久安。”他补充说，两军关系发展势头良好。&lt;/p>;这些安全挑战包括中美之间日益紧张的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李克强上周末在新加坡向国际观众发表的首次演讲中说，“一些国家”正在亚洲加剧军备竞赛，并且在紧张局势不断升级的情况下，北京和华盛顿都需要寻求更多的共同点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，Jitkaewtae 表示，根据中国国防部的声明，泰国“赞赏并坚定支持中国在维护地区安全与稳定方面发挥的重要作用” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他补充说，两国是好朋友、好伙伴、好亲戚、好邻居，在经贸、人文、高层交往等领域合作成果丰硕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;11 月，习近平和 Chan-o-cha 签署了一项合作计划，共同推进中国的跨国基础设施项目“一带一路”倡议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们还承诺为中国和东南亚建设一个安全繁荣的地区亚洲国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国公主玛哈扎克里诗琳通本周也来华进行她的第50次访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国大陆被誉为中国“国际友人”的诗琳通会见了高层王毅外交官承诺继续促进泰中友谊。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong Observatory issues amber rain signal on Saturday evening, warns of heavy showers in coming days]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3223656/hong-kong-observatory-issues-amber-rain-signal-saturday-evening-warns-heavy-showers-coming-days?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 20:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/10/a5cf7530-214c-4321-a2ef-36eae388fa75_d0dc1a07.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;香港天文台于星期六晚上八时发出黄色暴雨警告信号，因为预报员提醒市民做好准备迎接未来两日的大阵雨和狂风雷暴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预报员还警告说，周六大埔和西贡的雨量可能会特别大，预计降雨量将达到每小时 70 毫米，并有发生严重洪水的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南海部分北部湾附近的低压区和中国南部沿海的另一个低压槽将导致天文台解释说，该地区有阵雨和雷暴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在北部湾附近的低压区将在雷州半岛附近徘徊。预料下周一、周二将穿过粤西沿岸及其沿岸海域，并可能向珠江口附近靠拢。”开空调但最差还是闷热&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“下周后半段，活跃的西南季候风将继续为广东沿岸带来多变的天气。此外，热带气旋 Guchol 将在未来几天穿过吕宋岛以东海域，向日本南部海域移动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guchol 以密克罗尼西亚语中的姜黄一词命名，位于截至周六下午 2 点在菲律宾海。随着气旋逐渐向日本南部海域移动，预计不会直接影响香港。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;天气预报员于同日下午约五时三十分发出雷暴警告，并延长至晚上九时三十分。 &lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;香港登山专家告诫登山者要“倾听身体的声音”&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;天文台警告说：“如果你待在户外，请寻找安全的避难所。” “离开水。不要在户外游泳或从事其他户外水上运动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不要站在高处。远离导电性强的物体、树木或桅杆。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据天文台九日天气预报，香港星期日大致多云，间中有阵雨及局部有狂风雷暴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，从周一到 6 月 17 日，该市预计会出现大阵雨，离岸大风的速度可达 40 公里/小时（24.8 英里/小时）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计本周的气温也将下降气温在 27 摄氏度（80.6 华氏度）和 32 度之间波动，而该市的最大相对湿度将达到 95%。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 20:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Pakistan looks to sign cooperation agreement on China-led moon research base]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3223585/pakistan-looks-sign-cooperation-agreement-china-led-moon-research-base?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/09/f3b6e1d4-6ecf-433f-a598-8466f861279a_31752ceb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;巴基斯坦希望确定它在中国主导的国际月球研究中可以发挥的具体作用据其航天局负责人称，该站即将与ILRS签署合作协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;SUPARCO主席Amer Nadeem在参观位于中国东南部的深空探测实验室时发表上述讲话上个月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计到 2050 年，ILRS 将成为一个成熟的月球科学探索长期基地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nadeem 在其任职期间听取了该项目的进展情况简报参观位于安徽省合肥市的实验室，并与中国月球探测计划总设计师兼实验室主任吴为仁“进行了深入交流”，据其网站介绍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们欢迎巴基斯坦充分参与 ILRS，与实验室建立密切的合作伙伴关系，为共同建设人类在外层空间的共同未来树立榜样，”吴说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴基斯坦是其中之一自中国国家航天局于 2021 年发布第一份 ILRS 路线图以来，已有 6 个国家和国际机构签署了意向书或合作协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国还与其他 10 多个国家就吴在实验室于 4 月组织的国际深空探索会议上说，有可能参加。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国和美国的目标是月球的同一区域。他们可以合作吗？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;三十年来，巴基斯坦和中国一直是航天领域的战略伙伴。自 1992 年以来，中国帮助巴基斯坦研制和发射了通信卫星和遥感卫星等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为中国“一带一路”倡议的一部分，两国在 2019 年签署了一系列太空探索协议。其中包括中国帮助培训巴基斯坦宇航员并将他们送入太空，以及新落成的近地轨道天宫空间站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴还表示，巴基斯坦立方体卫星 ICUBE-Q 的工作进展顺利这将成为中国嫦娥六号探月任务的一部分，并在 2026 年从月球轨道寻找水冰痕迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中巴是好兄弟、好伙伴，有着悠久的传统吴在与纳迪姆会谈时说：为月球基地提供动力的系统&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;其他国家航天机构（包括委内瑞拉和巴西）的高级官员最近几个月也参观了合肥实验室，并表达了加入 ILRS 的意向。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Meanwhile, Spain recently became the 25th signatory to the Artemis Accords – a separate, US-led multinational effort to send humans to the moon, eventually Mars and beyond.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China and the United States are racing towards a new era of space exploration, and both powers aim to land astronauts on the moon before 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s largest journalist group faces financial strain, plunging membership as outlets close and reporters leave, re-elected chairman says]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/politics/article/3223652/hong-kongs-largest-journalist-group-faces-financial-strain-plunging-membership-outlets-close-and?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 18:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/10/b37c2752-49e1-42e2-9e2d-bbc9a5c53d58_78e07471.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s largest association of journalists is struggling with financial difficulties and plunging membership as media outlets close and reporters leave the industry or city entirely, its re-elected chairman has said, issuing a warning over the group&#39;s survival.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ronson Chan Ron-sing, who was re-elected as chairman of the Hong Kong Journalists Association (HKJA) at the group&#39;s annual general meeting on Saturday, said that only about 220 full members remained, while the total including other categories was between 300 and 400.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He cited news organisations of different sizes shutting down, journalists changing jobs or leaving the city and students opting not to join the industry after graduation as some of the reasons for the poor figures.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police slam journalist body for &#39;unverified speculation&#39; in statement&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“Our number of members is far fewer than that of three years ago, which has had a huge impact on us,” he explained after the association&#39;s meeting, where a new executive committee was elected. The group also faced financial difficulties, he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan in 2021 said that the group had more than 600 members.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, HKJA held a special meeting to discuss the organisation&#39;s future, including the possibility of disbandment amid mounting political pressure, but in the end it decided to still operate for the “foreseeable future”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During Saturday&#39;s meeting, the association increased its total number of executive committee members from seven to nine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It also accepted cartoonist Zunzi, whose comic series was axed from Chinese-language newspaper Ming Pao last month amid accusations of bias by city officials, as a lifelong permanent member.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Separately, the Foreign Correspondents&#39; Club (FCC) in Hong Kong expressed concerns over the cancellation of the cartoons by Zunzi, whose real name is Wong Kei-kwan, in a statement issued by its new leadership.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The FCC notes that the decision to stop publishing Wong&#39;s cartoons is a further blow to press freedom in Hong Kong,” the club said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It noted that the government had repeatedly said that freedom of the press and speech as enshrined in the Basic Law, the city&#39;s mini-constitution, and the national security law, was not at risk.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The FCC supports the right of media professionals to continue to enjoy those freedoms under the laws of Hong Kong,” it said, adding that the club had reached out to Ming Pao over its decision.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The newspaper axed the series by Zunzi in May without giving an explanation. The decision ended his 40 years of contributions to the publication. His two daily cartoons were known for blending humour with current affairs criticism.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Journalist not given benefit of doubt in Hong Kong vehicle check case: judge&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Several senior government officials, including Secretary for Security Chris Tang Ping-keung and the Secretary for Home and Youth Affairs Alice Mak Mei-kuen, had hit out at the cartoons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chief Executive John Lee Ka-chiu earlier said that Hong Kong media should ensure their coverage did not include false, biased, defamatory and misleading information. He also defended a decision by public libraries to remove books by the cartoonist from their shelves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The FCC last month elected its new board of governors, with Lee Williamson, regional head of Gen.T, a platform under lifestyle magazine Tatler, taking on the role of president. He replaced Keith Richburg, director of the Journalism and Media Studies Centre at the University of Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 19:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 arrested in Hong Kong after 4,400 dodgy credit card transactions made to buy HK$2.7 million worth of goods for resale]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/law-and-crime/article/3223651/3-arrested-hong-kong-after-4400-dodgy-credit-card-transactions-made-buy-hk27-million-worth-goods?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 18:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/10/d9938fca-9452-4891-a7b6-f5af55802644_6ad01dd3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong police have arrested three men who allegedly used stolen credit card details to buy daily essentials worth about HK$2.7 million through more than 4,400 online transactions for resale, with officers warning merchants and the public to be extra cautious over internet purchases.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three suspects, aged 20 to 29, were handling infant formula and laundry detergent at a warehouse in Sheung Shui when officers disguised as couriers tracked them down on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Investigators uncovered the syndicate, which had been active for about a month, after receiving a tip-off from a local retailer over unauthorised transactions, police told a press briefing on Saturday&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyday goods were bought at online shops of Hong Kong-based retailers using credit card information stolen from holders in France, the United States, Saudi Arabia and New Zealand, Senior Inspector Mak Wai-kwong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The goods were set to be resold for profit, the police investigation found.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong police seize HK$115 million worth of illegal drugs – some inside biscuits&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Mak said more than 4,400 transactions were made with a combined value of about HK$2.7 million. “The fraudsters hoped to evade the banks&#39; surveillance through transactions of smaller amounts, which also are harder for cardholders to detect.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trio, all of whom were mainland Chinese residents who held travel permits to visit Hong Kong, were arrested on suspicion of conspiracy to defraud and breach of conditions of stay.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They remained in custody as of Saturday and more arrests were possible, police said, adding that the investigation was continuing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The force will work with Interpol to gather intelligence and share the latest patterns of credit card scams with other law enforcement agencies.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Phishing messages from fake &#39;Scameter&#39; app prompt Hong Kong police warning&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Superintendent Rick Chan Wai-kei urged banks and online merchants to expand their use of one-time passwords to ensure credit card holders were fully informed of online purchases regardless of the amount.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cardholders should also avoid using the autofill function for one-time passwords. Banks always describe the purpose of the passwords in the text messages and people should read that clearly before manually entering the passwords,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Members of the public should beware of phishing text messages and consider using cards with lower spending limits to contain financial losses in the event of information theft, Chan added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The arrests came days after the banking regulator, the Hong Kong Monetary Authority, announced seven measures to better protect credit card holders after a surge in complaints over unauthorised transactions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Banks will be required to ask for the customer&#39;s consent for any change in credit limits and provide online self-help “buttons” for holders to instantly deactivate their cards, under the measures unveiled on Monday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong cyber fraud victims lost HK$830 million in first 3 months of year&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Credit card holders can also disable or set a spending cap for card-not-present transactions under the new rules.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The regulator received 382 complaints about unauthorised credit card transactions in the first five months this year, near the full-year tally of 391 for 2022. Just 88 such cases were reported in 2020 and 51 in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last December, the authority ordered Standard Chartered Bank to investigate a surge in credit card fraud cases involving local customers, after suspected victims flooded the lender&#39;s social media accounts with complaints.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 18:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Thailand’s first pet-friendly cinema opens to four-legged film-goers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/southeast-asia/article/3223649/thailands-first-pet-friendly-cinema-opens-four-legged-film-goers?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.10 17:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/10/97906e92-e69b-49b6-9c90-7735eb99d579_69962fe5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;A fluffy white cat in a yellow dress perched on the top of a Bangkok cinema seat while, nearby, a Chihuahua in a Sebastian the Crab costume geared up to watch Disney&#39;s &#39;The Little Mermaid&#39; with their owner.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One terrier even channelled Ariel in a red wig and mermaid&#39;s tail.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They were among dozens of four-legged film-goers that arrived in strollers Saturday for the opening of Thailand&#39;s first pet-friendly cinema on the fringes of the capital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The country&#39;s pet industry is considered the second-biggest in Asia, behind China&#39;s, with some 8.3 million dogs and 3.7 million cats in 2021, according to industry data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pet ownership grew further during the coronavirus pandemic, and now some businesses are trying to cash in.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mano, 37, had brought his rescue cat, Kati, to the cinema.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We take him to work sometimes … today is like an experiment,” he told AFP.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are seeing &#39;The Little Mermaid&#39;. He will enjoy seeing all the fish on the screen.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The animals had to wear diapers and sit in bags while the sound and lighting were adjusted for their comfort, Major Cineplex spokesman Narute Jiensnong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Bangkok is not a very pet-friendly city,” Narute told AFP, adding that the concept built on their child-friendly theatres.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;South Korean man who had 1,000 dogs at home suspected of animal abuse&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Narute noted some pets acquired during the pandemic suffer separation anxiety now that owners are no longer working from home or in lockdown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the kid cinemas, kids will be running around screaming or shouting … I think pet cinema will be the same. Everyone who comes will own a pet and be understanding (if dogs bark),” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is not the only business opening its doors to furry visitors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier this month, Swedish furniture giant Ikea announced that small dogs and cats were welcome to visit its Thailand stores, as long as they sit in prams.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Outside the cinema, there were howls of disappointment as a 62kg Alaskan malamute named Tungchae – who arrived in a 1.5-square-metre dog trolley equipped with a fan – was considered too big to enter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the cinemas&#39; animal welfare safeguards, not all pet owners were thrilled about the idea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One long-time Bangkok expat said that, while her cat frequently falls asleep beside her on the couch watching TV at home, she would never take her pet to the cinema and thinks the concept is “unnatural” and “torture”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Being zipped up in this cage, I don&#39;t know if that&#39;s enjoyable for the animal,” she told AFP.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It&#39;s so ridiculous dogs are not allowed in (most Bangkok) parks but they can go to a movie or cafe. What comes next, you bring your dog or cat to a massage parlour?”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 10 Jun 2023 18:20:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>