<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Chinese military tests advanced 055 destroyer Dalian on evacuation mission skills]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3224083/chinese-military-tests-advanced-055-destroyer-dalian-evacuation-mission-skills?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 23:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/24860ce7-873b-4d3f-82d4-704a803b99d0_9f2bcef4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国最先进的海军驱逐舰之一已经接受了数天的模拟训练从饱受战争蹂躏的国家撤离中国公民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家广播公司中央电视台报道的未注明日期的演习是已知的 055 型导弹驱逐舰首次参加此类演习。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;“大连”号船员模拟疏散程序，包括对抵达外国港口逃离战时国家的中国公民进行安全和身份检查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;96小时的指挥演习还评估了大连号大副冯博文舰长的反导和海战作战情况。据中央电视台周一报道，如果通过测试，冯就可以在万吨级大型驱逐舰上担任指挥职务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对于非战争军事活动，时间紧，任务重，海不熟悉，”冯告诉中央电视台。 “对这些项目进行测试有助于检验我们执行多样化军事任务的能力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这样的训练让中国海军能够开展更多的人道主义工作，他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CCTV表示，模拟演习测试了机组人员在执行疏散任务期间在时间限制和后勤挑战下的表现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频显示，演习是在位于中国南部广东省湛江市的解放军海军基地举行的，该基地是其总部南海舰队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国一直在利用撤离和维和任务等人道主义任务来改善中国人民解放军 (PLA) 在国内外的形象。在去年面向国际观众发布的英文宣传视频中，解放军将自己描述为“热爱和平的军队”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月，解放军海军派出一艘补给舰和一艘 052D 型驱逐舰前往苏丹撤离 1,000 多名中国以及巴西和巴基斯坦国民，以逃离敌对将军之间致命的权力斗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是继 2011 年利比亚和 2015 年也门之后海军的第三次此类撤离任务 – 与&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京远望军事科技智库研究员周晨鸣表示，疏散同胞是解放军的必修课，055型驱逐舰是其中之一将参与此类任务的海军舰艇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“撤离国民关乎速度和安全。附近有哪艘船就执行任务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说，执行此类任务没有固定编队，因为最重要的目的是尽快到达动荡的国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;据央视报道，大连舰还参加了预警机、战斗机和潜艇的模拟作战，与052D型多用途驱逐舰焦作舰、柳州舰编队航行。 054A 型护卫舰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据中央电视台报道，解放军空军部署战斗机充当大连舰船员的假装对手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大连舰是 8 艘 055 型驱逐舰之一中国海军舰队。这些舰艇设计用于包括反潜和陆地攻击在内的一系列行动，也有助于提高航空母舰群的防空能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它们还可以作为指挥和控制其他舰艇的旗舰不护送承运人时。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 23:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: Russia steps up aerial strikes killing at least 6 amid Kyiv counteroffensive]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/russia-central-asia/article/3224090/ukraine-war-russia-steps-aerial-strikes-killing-least-6-amid-kyiv-counteroffensive?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 22:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/86ef7398-35b6-4a35-9b04-8b9f1cc2110f_2c1b9141.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯军队向乌克兰南部城市敖德萨发射巡航导弹并炮击顿涅茨克东部乌克兰地区官员表示，周三早些时候，该地区至少有 6 人死亡，数十座房屋受损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰军方发言人表示，俄罗斯军队在近 16 个月的战争中加强了空袭，而据报道，该国武装部队在反攻初期收效有限，目的是夺回俄罗斯控制下的乌克兰近五分之一领土。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在敖德萨，三名食品仓库员工在一次罢工中丧生该地区政府在 Facebook 上表示，这还破坏了该市市中心的房屋、商店和咖啡馆。另有 13 人受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;普京考虑：俄罗斯是否应该再次尝试占领基辅？&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;搜索小组正在仓库废墟下寻找可能的幸存者，它说。 p>;&lt;p>;政府表示，从黑海对港口城市发动的袭击是一周内的第二次袭击，涉及四枚口径巡航导弹，其中三枚被防空系统拦截。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;在乌克兰东部，顿涅茨克省省长 Pavlo Kyrylenko 在 Telegram 上写道，在 Kramatorsk 和 Kostiantynivka 的炮击摧毁了 7 座房屋并损坏了数十座房屋后，至少有 3 人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前线的 10 个城镇和村庄据乌克兰总统办公室称，随着基辅军队缓慢推进，顿涅茨克的防线遭到袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一枚导弹击中了基辅军队总部所在的乌克兰控制的克拉马托尔斯克市，炸死两名平民，炸伤两人，同时造成破坏总统办公室说，有 29 所房子。它补充说，俄罗斯对 Kostiantynivka 的炮击造成一名平民死亡，57 栋房屋受损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰武装部队总参谋部发言人安德烈科瓦洛夫表示，随着基辅部队的加强，俄罗斯军方增加了导弹和空袭沿着战争 1,000 公里（600 英里）的前线发动袭击，并在反攻开始时取得一些适度的进展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在简报中，他说对哈尔科夫、顿涅茨克和基洛沃格勒地区的袭击，在除了敖德萨地区，还涉及 Kh-22 巡航导弹、海上发射的 Kalibr 巡航导弹和伊朗制造的 Shahed 无人机。 9 人被拦截。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科瓦洛夫说，乌克兰军队在几个地区取得了进展，战斗仍在顿涅茨克省至少两个社区或附近继续进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另外，市中心的市长乌克兰总统弗拉基米尔·泽连斯基的家乡克里维罗伊省表示，一天前俄罗斯袭击一栋公寓楼造成的死亡人数已上升至 12 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰当局继续从乌克兰南部被洪水淹没的地区营救人员上周 Kakhovka 大坝遭到破坏后，俄罗斯部分占领的赫尔松地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰控制的第聂伯河西岸共有 28 个定居点仍被水淹没，近 2,800 人已被带走总统办公室表示，到目前为止安全状况良好，并补充说救援工作是在俄罗斯的无情炮击下进行的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰控制的赫尔松地区在过去 24 小时内遭到炮击 57 次，总统办公室说。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 22:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Xiaomi’s fight against New Delhi’s decision to freeze its funds is set to continue, amid ongoing geopolitical tensions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3224069/xiaomis-fight-against-new-delhis-decision-freeze-its-funds-set-continue-amid-ongoing-geopolitical?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 22:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/7294b995-1d3e-4fed-a6e7-51800dad9d5f_eba1629b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国智能手机制造商小米将继续在印度就新德里的决定展开法律斗争据一位知情人士透露，将冻结约 6.7 亿美元的资金，延长一场已成为进入该国的中国企业警示故事的战斗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在最新的发展中，印度执法局据路透社上周报道，已就小米涉嫌非法汇款向小米及其银行（包括德意志银行、汇丰银行和花旗集团）发出通知。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度金融犯罪机构指控小米的当地部门非法汇款据路透社报道，通过冒充特许权使用费向外国实体汇款，据称银行在没有获得必要文件的情况下处理了这些汇款。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》周三联系到小米时，小米指出了一份声明小米印度公司去年 10 月在 Twitter 上发布了一份声明，表示将继续使用一切手段保护其声誉和股东利益，同时继续致力于与各部门合作解决这一问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;小米在印度的挑战销售暴跌和资产冻结&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;一位熟悉北京小米情况的人士表示，他们没有收到任何通知，他们将继续他们解冻印度账户的斗争。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，小米在印度当地银行冻结了大约 6.7 亿美元的资金，并要求解除冻结。它的申请于 4 月被印度高等法院驳回。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小米并不是唯一一家在印度面临监管审查的中国公司，其在另一家中国智能手机厂商 Vivo 的账户也在去年 7 月被冻结。然而，德里高等法院后来解除了对 Vivo 账户的冻结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小米在印度的转变对于其他希望在南亚市场取得成功的中国公司来说是一个危险信号。在取得早期商业成功后，2020 年夏季这两个亚洲巨头在喜马拉雅山发生边界冲突后，许多中国企业的情绪低落。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小米曾连续五年成为印度顶级智能手机品牌，排名根据行业研究公司 IDC 的最新数据，2023 年第一季度仅次于三星电子、中国品牌 Oppo 和 Vivo，仅占市场份额的 16.4%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国政府已经没有公开评论小米在印度的纠纷，尽管此案引发了一些中国网民的愤怒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果印度真的没收小米资金，大多数外资企业可能不得不离开该国，”一位用户在中国金融门户网站新浪网发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国应该制定法律禁止其企业在印度投资，”另一位名叫夏风的用户在该网站上评论道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 22:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU lawmakers approve plan on bloc’s future AI rules]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224089/eu-lawmakers-approve-plan-blocs-future-ai-rules?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 21:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/0d423ad1-806e-4694-8afb-cb4e26f907d6_75101ead.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧盟立法者周三投票通过了构成未来法律基础的关键文本监管 ChatGPT 等人工智能系统，同时旨在促进技术创新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧洲议会和欧盟 27 个成员国将于周三晚些时候开始就最终法律进行谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;如果布鲁塞尔实现其在年底前达成协议的雄心勃勃的目标，这将是世界上第一部规范人工智能的法律。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管欧盟的计划可以追溯到 2021 年，但规则草案的意义更大去年 ChatGPT 突然出现时的紧迫性，展示了 AI 令人眼花缭乱的进步和可能的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;你会被你的 AI 克隆取代吗？也许有一天，但还未完全到来&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;随着西方政府面临越来越大的压力，要求其在一些人称之为保护人类的战斗中迅速采取行动，在大西洋彼岸监管人工智能的呼声也越来越高。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;虽然 AI 的支持者为这项技术将如何改变社会而欢呼，包括工作、医疗保健和创造性追求，但其他人则担心它有可能破坏民主。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; AI 用途的鼓舞人心的例子包括使用该技术创建的“披头士乐队的最终记录”，而总部位于美国的 OpenAI 的聊天机器人 ChatGPT 已通过商业、法律和医学考试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使欧盟雄心勃勃的立法目标得以实现，该法律最早要到 2026 年才会生效，迫使欧盟推动与科技公司达成自愿临时协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法律将根据风险级别对 AI 进行监管：风险越高例如，对个人权利或健康的影响越大，系统的义务就越大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟提议的高风险清单包括关键基础设施、教育、人力资源、公共秩序和移民管理中的人工智能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;在满足高风险分类之前，议会为此增加了额外条件，包括可能危害人们的健康、安全、权利或环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有特殊的对生成式 AI 系统（例如能够生成文本、图像、代码、音频和其他媒体的 ChatGPT 和 DALL-E）的要求，包括告诉用户内容是机器而非人类生成的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;立法者还提议禁止使用生物识别监控、情绪识别和所谓的预测性警务的人工智能系统。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;议会立法负责人 Brando Benifei 周二告诉记者，会谈是否考虑是否加快法律的实施或更早地为生成式 AI 制定规则。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们还可以考虑缩短某些 AI 的时间，例如基础模型和生成式 AI，”Benifei 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;在他的推理中，他指出布鲁塞尔和美国计划发布人工智能共同行为准则，以制定民主国家的标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立法者称赞他们的法律草案是“具有历史意义的” ”，并反驳了批评者，他们认为欧盟的计划可能会损害而不是鼓励创新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟内部市场专员蒂埃里·布雷顿 (Thierry Breton) 对投票表示欢迎，并坚称“没有时间可以浪费了”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“AI 提出了很多问题——社会、伦理和经济方面的问题。但现在不是按下任何‘暂停键’的时候，”布雷顿说。 “恰恰相反，这是关于快速行动和承担责任。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Casket of Italian ex-PM Silvio Berlusconi brought to cathedral for his funeral]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224101/casket-italian-ex-pm-silvio-berlusconi-brought-cathedral-his-funeral?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 21:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/d820352a-9a6a-4be2-a13c-647f60fa91d7_d29be7a2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;周三，西尔维奥·贝卢斯科尼 (Silvio Berlusconi) 在米兰的 Duomo 大教堂举行了国葬，并在此度过了一天全国哀悼，因为他的遗产——无论是正面的还是负面的——在意大利人中引起了激烈的争论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大教堂内外数以万计的人爆发出热烈的掌声，以示对贝卢斯科尼披着鲜花的棺材表示敬意被吊出灵车，送入大教堂。当棺材被放在祭坛前时，他的孩子和同伴泪流满面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大多数意大利人认为贝卢斯科尼是意大利最有影响力的人物，他是媒体大亨、足球企业家和三届前总理近几十年来。但他们在贝卢斯科尼的影响是好是坏的问题上仍存在严重分歧，并延伸到这位三届前总理是否值得所有的大惊小怪和仪式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贝卢斯科尼于周一去世，享年 86 岁。他在米兰医院接受慢性白血病治疗。周二，他的家人在贝卢斯科尼位于米兰附近的一处别墅举行了私人守灵仪式。在 1994 年进入政界之前，贝卢斯科尼曾在米兰作为一家媒体帝国的掌门人赚取了数十亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治对手不仅质疑Giorgia Meloni 总理的政府决定举行国葬——所有前任总理都可以享有这一荣誉——但同时宣布全国哀悼日，这一点很少被援引。在后者的情况下，降半旗，所有不涉及慈善的政治事件都被搁置，但除此之外一切照常。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“贝卢斯科尼分裂了意大利，他侮辱了对手30 年来，他将治安官定为犯罪，他不承认法律。我们在谈论什么？”记者 Marco Travaglio 是贝卢斯科尼的长期批评者，也是 il Fatto Quotidiano 日报的联合创始人，他在周二告诉私人 La7 电视台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管如此，成千上万的意大利人还是挤满了米兰大教堂外的广场通过两个巨大的视频屏幕跟踪葬礼，而身着盛装的宪兵在外面等待载着贝卢斯科尼棺材的灵车抵达。与此同时，家庭成员、政治盟友和反对者都聚集在里面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;匈牙利总统维克多·欧尔班和卡塔尔执政的埃米尔谢赫·塔米姆·本·哈马德·阿勒萨尼是出席会议的最高级别外国政要之一。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;梅洛尼作为贝卢斯科尼联盟的部长获得了她的第一份政府经验，她也将与联盟领导人马泰奥萨尔维尼一起出席，他的政党长期以来一直与贝卢斯科尼的意大利力量联盟结盟。预计反对派政客也会对一位与许多人发生争执的政治人物表示尊重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意大利力量委员会女议员、欧洲议会的一次性候选人芭芭拉·卡切拉里 (Barbara Cacellari) 表示抗议如何正式马克贝卢斯科尼的死表明缺乏尊重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个人本身必须受到尊重。他是代表这个国家历史的人，”她在大教堂外说，并补充说：“我认为没有人是没有污点的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贝卢斯科尼被广泛认为是那种类型的先驱民粹主义政治后来让唐纳德·特朗普在美国掌权，两人都利用他们作为商人的高知名度进入政治舞台，一路上一如既往地颠覆政治。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贝卢斯科尼遗产的支持者引用他的在 1990 年代的“清白之手”腐败丑闻导致战后政治格局崩溃后，成功统一了意大利中右翼。他们还将他作为领导人的岁月视为稳定时期，经过多年快速轮换政府，同时钦佩他大胆的打破规则和不敬，也许尤其是在面对其他全球领导人时。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他做了很多贝卢斯科尼所在政党的参议员、已故意大利领导人贝蒂诺·克拉克西 (Bettino Craxi) 的女儿斯特凡尼亚·克拉克西 (Stefania Craxi) 周二对私人电视台 La7 说：“无论大小，都遭受了只有在他之前的克拉克西才经历过的调解和司法侵略。”她的父亲因参与非法政党融资而被缺席定罪后，于 2000 年在突尼斯流亡期间去世。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贝卢斯科尼的政治损害的批评者名单很长，包括与他的媒体帝国有关的利益冲突，数十个审判主要是为了商业交易，他在米兰附近的别墅里举行以性为燃料的 bunga-bunga 派对的揭露，以及可疑的关联，包括他与俄罗斯领导人弗拉基米尔·普京 (Vladimir Putin) 的持久友谊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他不是帮助我们的领导人成长，”Corriere della Sera 的长期驻外记者和作家 Beppe Severgnini 说。 “他利用了我们所有的弱点：道德、财政、性，一切。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周三的国葬之后，他的棺材将被送回米兰附近的圣马蒂诺别墅，等待火化。葬礼在亚历山德里亚市附近的 Valenziano Panta Rei 火葬场举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据路透社报道，他的骨灰将被送往位于北部城镇 Arcore 的别墅内的家族陵墓。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 21:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Countries can follow ‘various paths’ on human rights, says Chinese President Xi Jinping]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3224096/countries-can-follow-various-paths-human-rights-says-chinese-president-xi-jinping?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 21:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/791f7a55-af3a-49ba-be3b-dfeaa48344df_b0989ca8.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;中国国家主席习近平周三表示，各国可以采取“多种途径”来保护人权在北京的一次会议上，来自发展中国家的代表也听到了对西方人权观念的批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平在致论坛的一封信中发表了讲话，来自 58 个国家和联合国的代表出席了论坛联合国和非洲联盟，以纪念联合国促进人权的文件《维也纳宣言和行动纲领》通过 30 周年。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;随着人权谈判的恢复，中国面临欧盟对维吾尔人待遇的批评&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;习近平在信中表示，“全球人权治理面临严峻挑战”，中国正在走“符合自身国情的人权发展道路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[我们提倡]保障各国人民通过各种现代化道路公平享有人权，”习近平说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平补充说：“全球文明倡议，深化文明交流互鉴。” /p>;&lt;p>;此次活动由国务院新闻办公室、外交部和负责国家对外援助的中国国际发展合作署联合举办。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据与会者名单，论坛嘉宾主要来自参与“一带一路”倡议的发展中国家，这是习近平通过贸易和基础设施加强中国与外部世界联系的标志性项目&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平及其领导层正寻求在人权问题上发出更大的声音，而中国因其在新疆和香港的行动以及对待持不同政见者的方式而面临西方国家，尤其是美国的批评。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;外交部副部长马朝旭在活动中表示，“中国必将为全球人权治理作出更大贡献”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马朝旭没有点名批评一些西方国家，称他们“忽视了自己严肃的人权”人权问题，像人权老师一样四处乱窜，诬告别国，干涉别国内政，遏制别国发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马云还说：“一味抄袭其他国家的模式只会适得其反，甚至会导致灾难性的后果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国际开发合作署署长罗照辉在会上表示，中国对全球人权的贡献包括提供粮食和&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;论坛的其他主旨发言人包括负责乌兹别克斯坦人权事务的高级官员 Akmal Saidov 和赤道几内亚副总理之一的 Alfonso Nsue Mokuy，他们都&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在开幕词之后的讲座中，一些中外学者也对中国在促进人权方面所做的努力给予了高度评价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，维罗妮卡联合国人权事务高级专员办公室主任比尔加没有像其他发言者那样赞扬中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;联合国人权事务负责人巴切莱特拒绝连任，“与”“无关”中国&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;相反，她在活动中表示，“越来越多的国家正在采取措施压制不同的声音和意见，包括对记者和人权捍卫者进行威胁、恐吓、暴力和刑事诉讼”，最后呼吁“就人权问题达成新的全球共识”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3 月，联合国人权事务高级专员沃尔克·图尔克 (Volker Türk) 对西藏、新疆和香港的人权状况表示“严重关切”孔.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 21:20:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Li Ka-shing’s Three UK to merge with Vodafone unit to form Britain’s biggest mobile provider worth US$15.7 billion]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3224097/li-ka-shings-three-uk-merge-vodafone-unit-form-britains-biggest-mobile-provider-worth-us157-billion?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 20:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/4b4a3dd3-00b3-4476-b879-b2f0e83e6a10_60c11479.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;长江和记实业，香港首富李嘉诚的两大旗舰公司之一嘉诚表示，将把其英国电信业务与沃达丰的国内业务合并，创建英国最大的移动运营商，总价值达 124 亿英镑（157 亿美元）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项酝酿已久的交易涉及经过一年多的谈判，沃达丰将拥有合并后公司 51% 的股份，且不支付现金对价。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，合资企业将承担 60 亿英镑的债务，沃达丰将承担43 亿英镑和三个英国占剩余的 17 亿英镑。交易完成后，Three UK 欠长江和记黄埔的 16.8 亿英镑债务将以现金偿还。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Three UK 和 Vodafone UK 目前自身缺乏必要的规模来赚取资本成本。长期以来，这一直是对 Three UK 投资和竞争能力的挑战，”CK Hutchison 集团联席董事总经理 Canning Fok 在伦敦提交给证券交易所的一份文件中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将共同拥有为英国提供一流的 5G 网络所需的规模，为我们的客户转变移动服务，并为英国各地的企业开辟新的机会，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;交易将合并英国第三和第四大移动服务提供商，预计这将引发英国竞争管理机构的严格审查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些公司一直在努力与规模更大的竞争对手 BT Group 和 Virgin Media O2 竞争，后者是一家Liberty Global 和西班牙 Telefonica 的合资企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这笔交易是在欧盟委员会否决了 Three UK 对 O2 的收购计划 7 年后达成的，理由是消费者价格可能上涨以及对服务质量的潜在负面影响服务，因为移动竞争对手的数量减少了。这笔交易将创建英国最大的移动运营商。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;CK Hutchison 将与瑞典 EQT 组建新的意大利电信公司&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Liberty Global 和 Telefonica 同意合并其英国电信部门——Virgin Media 和O2 分别在 2020 年 5 月成立了 50-50 的合资企业，一年后英国竞争管理机构签署了该交易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vodafone UK-Three UK 交易预计将在明年年底前完成年，须经监管机构和股东批准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unite 工会反对该交易，称这将导致英国消费者的手机成本更高，英国工人失业。沃达丰于 5 月宣布计划在未来三年内在全球裁员 11,000 人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;交易完成后，该合资企业将在未来十年投资 110 亿英镑建设其独立的 5G 网络。这些公司还表示，他们预计到 2030 年将为 82% 的英国家庭提供移动家庭宽带服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;李嘉诚旗舰公司公布利润增长，展示多元化投资组合的实力&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>; “对于沃达丰来说，这笔交易改变了我们国内市场的游戏规则，”沃达丰首席执行官玛格丽塔德拉瓦莱说。 “这是对英国的信任投票及其成为未来技术中心的雄心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与沃达丰的合资企业标志着 CK Hutchison 的最新举措，其业务包括港口运营、基础设施、零售和电信，通过“轻资产”战略重塑其在全球的移动业务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020 年 11 月，该公司同意将其欧洲无线塔业务出售给西班牙移动塔运营商 Cellnex Telecom 100 亿欧元（108 亿美元）。该公司同意在 2021 年将其印度尼西亚无线电信业务与卡塔尔 Ooredoo 的本地业务合并，组成印度尼西亚第二大移动运营商。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5 月，CK Hutchison 表示将与瑞典私营企业组建新的合资企业- 股权公司 EQT 将在意大利提供批发移动和固定通信服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;CK Hutchison 还在 3 月份表示，它正在积极讨论涉及其在丹麦和瑞典的业务的潜在交易，金融时报报道它正在与斯堪的纳维亚电信公司 Telenor 进行谈判。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 20:50:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU orders Google to break up digital ad business for ‘abusing its dominant position’]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224085/eu-orders-google-break-digital-ad-business-abusing-its-dominant-position?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 19:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/14/caa091b0-c794-40bc-873d-0623decfd55d_57077295.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧盟反垄断监管机构针对谷歌利润丰厚的数字广告业务做出了前所未有的决定这家科技巨头出售其部分广告业务以解决竞争问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为欧盟行政部门和最高反垄断执法机构的欧盟委员会表示，其在调查后的初步观点是“只有强制性的谷歌剥离其部分服务”将消除这些担忧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟委员会周三表示，谷歌“滥用了其在在线广告市场的主导地位”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟反垄断负责人玛格丽特Vestager 表示，谷歌可能不得不出售其部分广告技术业务，因为行为补救措施不太可能有效阻止反竞争行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我当然知道这是一个强有力的声明，但它反映了市场的性质、它们的运作方式以及为什么行为承诺似乎是不可能的，”她在新闻发布会上说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谷歌是世界上占主导地位的数字广告平台，拥有 28% 的市场占有率。根据研究公司 Insider Intelligence 的数据，广告收入占全球广告收入的市场份额。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，广告技术业务占这家科技巨头总收入的 79%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;其 2022 年的广告收入，包括来自搜索服务、Gmail、Google Play、Google 地图、YouTube 广告、Google Ad Manager、AdMob 和 AdSense 的总计 2245 亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟高管邀请 Google 现在对这一初步调查结果做出回应，在进行了为期两年的反垄断调查后，最终得出了最终结论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟 27 国领导了全球打击大型科技公司的运动，但此前它依赖于开出重磅罚款，包括对谷歌的三项价值十亿欧元（美元）的反垄断处罚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是欧盟首次命令科技巨头拆分业务关键。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谷歌现在可以辩护在委员会发布最终决定之前提出自己的理由。该公司表示，它不同意反垄断指控，并将做出相应回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该委员会的决定源于其于 2021 年 6 月启动的一项正式调查，调查谷歌是否违反了欧盟的竞争规则，偏袒自己的在线产品以牺牲竞争对手出版商、广告商和广告技术服务为代价来展示广告技术服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;与大型科技公司的斗争：欧盟数十亿的罚款和严厉的法律&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;YouTube 是该计划的焦点之一commission&#39;s investigation, which looked into whether Google was using the video sharing site&#39;s dominant position to favour its own ad-buying services by imposing restrictions on rivals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Google&#39;s ad tech business is also under investigation by Britain&#39;s antitrust watchdog and faces litigation in the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brussels has previously hit Google with more than 8 billion euros (US$8.6 billion) worth of fines in three separate antitrust cases, involving its Android mobile operating system and shopping and search advertising services .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company is appealing all three penalties. An EU court last year slightly reduced the Android penalty to 4.125 million euros (US$4.46 million). EU regulators have the power to impose penalties worth up to 10 per cent of a company&#39;s annual revenue.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reporting by Agence France-Presse, Associated Press, Reuters&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s Cathay Pacific offers junior pilots chance to rise through ranks at HK Express in bid to retain talent]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/transport/article/3224086/hong-kongs-cathay-pacific-offers-junior-pilots-chance-rise-through-ranks-hk-express-bid-retain?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 19:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/88e06ad9-25a9-4e73-a4ce-af492117cd6b_22feb704.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Junior pilots with Cathay Pacific Airways can apply for senior positions with its budget arm HK Express as part of a bid by Hong Kong&#39;s flag carrier to retain talent and rebuild flight capacity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Second officers with Cathay would be allowed to serve as first officers with HK Express for two years, before returning to the lead airline while retaining the higher rank, the Cathay Group on Wednesday announced.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Captain Chris Kempis, director of flight operations, said the voluntary scheme was aimed at satisfying the budget airline&#39;s short-term need for pilots, while giving those flying with Cathay Pacific a chance to move up the ranks.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;New aircrew at Hong Kong&#39;s Cathay to earn up to HK$20,000 a month as flights grow&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;HK Express is seeking to expand the number of destinations it serves, and hire 180 new pilots and more than 300 cabin crew by the end of this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This arrangement will further support our growth trajectory, providing more promotion opportunities for our current first officers to become captains,” airline CEO Jeanette Mao Jie-qiong said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March, the airline said it expected to operate 500 flights per week by the summer and cover about 22 destinations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The budget airline maintains a fleet of 27 aircraft, which are all narrow-body airliners produced by Airbus, with the low-cost carrier receiving the first of 16 such planes in March.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Paul Weatherilt, chairman of the Hong Kong Aircrew Officers Association, which represents about half of all Cathay pilots, said he supported the new promotion plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the association chair noted that Cathay was still short of captains, with the flag carrier contending with a flight crew training backlog.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked if the new scheme would help retain talent, Weatherilt said: “It isn&#39;t second officers that have been leaving. Cathay currently has the same number of second officers that it had pre-pandemic.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was not clear how HK Express&#39; compensation package for junior pilots would stack up against Cathay&#39;s, whether the scheme would be attractive enough or what the return path back to the flag carrier would involve, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An internal Cathay memo seen by the Post said those who flew with HK Express for two years could get promoted sooner than if they opted for the other airline&#39;s training plan. According to the document, applicants looking to switch to the budget carrier would need at least 1,000 hours of flight experience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, a junior Cathay pilot who declined to be named raised concerns that those joining the scheme could face an overall pay reduction with more short haul flights under HK Express&#39; conditions of service.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Hong Kong faces &#39;difficult&#39; task in rebuilding role as aviation hub, IATA says&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;While both factors could deter more salary-conscious pilots, some who were eager to fly might be interested in joining the scheme, he added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cathay&#39;s newly minted junior pilots on June 1 started a trial programme that aims to broaden their induction experience by taking up duties at the city&#39;s airport, such as receiving frontline customer training across different positions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cathay Group is currently running at about 50 per cent of its pre-Covid-19 passenger flight capacity, with the company aiming to reach 70 per cent by the year&#39;s end and 100 per cent by the close of 2024.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid reduced travel demand during the pandemic, the company axed 5,900 jobs, closed its regional arm Cathay Dragon and initiated a HK$39 billion (US$4.9 billion) government-backed restructuring plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cathay Group also introduced cheaper employment contracts for pilots and cabin crew as part of cost-cutting measures.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Flight risk: unpacking pilot grievances at Hong Kong&#39;s Cathay Pacific&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;As part of measures to boost staff morale, Cathay Pacific on Monday said cabin crew from July could see their monthly earnings increase by between 3 to 8 per cent due to productivity pay, which is tied to hours flown.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The airline in January raised its base monthly salary by 3.3 per cent and increased pilot allowances, while a new outport turnaround allowance was launched a month later.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Morale among Cathay staff suffered last month after three crew members were sacked for insulting the English-speaking abilities of some mainland Chinese passengers on a flight to Hong Kong.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the time, the flight attendants&#39; union described morale as “extremely low” and in need of desperate attention.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident came after Cathay pilots were warned against slowly taxiing on runways to clock more hours and boost their pay. Authorities had accused them of contributing to congestion at the airport.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hong Kong stock exchange operator will help city become ‘world’s leading green finance centre’, says Financial Secretary Paul Chan]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3224088/hong-kong-stock-exchange-operator-will-help-city-become-worlds-leading-green-finance-centre-says?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 20:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/b4293c69-4824-44b7-ab0b-66cf99ec145d_87389d55.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Bourse operator Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) will continue to develop products and services to help the city in its quest to become “the world&#39;s leading green technology and green finance centre” and an offshore yuan trading hub, said Financial Secretary Paul Chan Mo-po.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan unveiled his vision in a keynote speech at a ceremony on Wednesday that marked the 23rd anniversary of HKEX as a listed company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As the world moves towards a green and low-carbon transition, there is a lot more that Hong Kong can do to contribute,” Chan said at the ceremony, which was attended by hundreds of guests including stockbrokers and representatives of listed companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have set our sights on becoming the leading green technology and green finance centre of the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are pleased to note that HKEX is an enthusiastic contributor to green and ESG [environmental, social, and governance] development, including the launch of [a voluntary carbon-trading platform] as well as setting out proposals to enhance climate-related disclosures.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan mentioned the launch next Monday of the new Hong Kong dollar and yuan dual-counter trading service that will allow investors to trade in either of the two currencies in 24 companies. He described this as an important milestone for the internationalisation of the yuan and was confident there would be no hitches.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There will be no Monday morning blues next week, I can assure you,” Chan said. “Next, we will press ahead with the inclusion of yuan-denominated securities under Southbound Connect scheme, so that mainland investors can trade Hong Kong shares using onshore yuan funds.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ceremony was the first time HKEX has marked its anniversary with an in-person event since 2018, before the social unrest in Hong Kong in 2019 and then the Covid-19 pandemic that prevented the celebration for four years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HKEX, which runs Asia&#39;s third-largest stock market, will officially mark 23 years as a listed firm on June 27. Chan was the guest of honour at the ceremony on Wednesday, which was hosted by the stock exchange operator&#39;s CEO Nicolas Aguzin and its chairwoman Laura Cha Shih May-lung.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chan, Aguzin and Cha sounded the ceremonial gong in Connect Hall, which functioned as the exchange&#39;s trading hall before 2017.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Besides green finance and yuan products, Aguzin said HKEX wants to attract more international firms to list and more global investors to trade in Hong Kong. That is why he and Cha have visited the Middle East numerous times this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Around the Middle East, there is a tremendous amount of savings. The sovereign wealth fund system there has US$4 trillion, while they have only invested about 1 to 2 per cent in Hong Kong, which is tiny,” Aguzin said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China represents 80 pre cent of the world&#39;s GDP, they should have 10 to 20 per cent of their funds invested in Chinese companies channeled through Hong Kong. We&#39;re talking about US$1 trillion, which is such a great opportunity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That&#39;s why we are spending so much time in the Middle East. There are also some great companies in the region that may want to potentially look for funding sources in this part of the world.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HKEX has come a long way since its formation in March 2000 via the merger of the stock exchange, the futures exchange and three clearing houses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was listed in Hong Kong on June 27, 2000, at HK$3.88 a share. As of Wednesday&#39;s market close, its stock stood at HK$313.20. A purchase of 1,000 shares for HK$3,880 (US$500) on the day of its listing would be worth HK$313,200 now.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of companies listed on the exchange that HKEX runs has risen as well, from 790 at the time of the listing to the current 2,600, while the total market capitalisation has risen sevenfold to HK$32.79 trillion as of Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The exchange&#39;s average daily market turnover has risen nine-fold in the 23 years to HK$118.9 billion through the first five months of this year, while average daily derivatives trading has increased 37 times to 1.4 million contracts as of May.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HKEX&#39;s business has diversified over the years. The bourse operator relied heavily on stock trading in 2000, but now its derivatives products are also heavily traded. It has also expanded overseas by acquiring the London Metal Exchange in 2012.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The stock market was dominated by conglomerates and finance companies in 2000, with the two sectors representing a combined 71 per cent of the market. Today they account for only 44.5 per cent, according to HKEX data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Information technology and healthcare, which were not on the list in 2000, now represent a combined 30 per cent of the market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hong Kong&#39;s main board was the top venue for initial public offerings worldwide seven times over the past 14 years, thanks in part to listing reforms introduced in April 2018.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reforms allowed companies with multiple classes of voting rights, as well as biotechnology companies without revenue, to list in Hong Kong, which has attracted many technology firms and healthcare companies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To be exact, the reforms opened the door for 86 companies to list in the city through March this year. These companies raised more than HK$580 billion, representing more than 40 per cent of the total funds raised through listings in Hong Kong during the period, according to Secretary for Financial Services and the Treasury Christopher Hui Ching-yu.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among them were 56 pre-revenue or pre-profit biotechnology companies, which raised HK$116 billion and made Hong Kong the second-largest listing centre globally for such firms, behind Nasdaq.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 20:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3 dead after firework blasts hit apartment blocks in Chinese city of Tianjin; suspect detained]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/politics/article/3224074/3-dead-after-firework-blasts-hit-apartment-blocks-chinese-city-tianjin-suspect-detained?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 19:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/f0de3194-c8af-4fd4-94ef-3a1ababbe023_aff89071.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Three people were killed and “many” others injured when explosions tore through two residential apartments in the northern Chinese city of Tianjin on Tuesday evening, police said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A man suspected of using fireworks to cause the blasts in two complexes was detained, according to a police briefing posted on Wednesday on an official WeChat social media account.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two blasts, which went off some time after 8pm, happened in the city&#39;s Hedong district, home to over 900,000 people, including many ethnic minorities, according to Tianjin&#39;s yearbook.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two buildings are about 1.6km (1 mile) apart. Tianjin is about 100km (70 miles) southeast of the capital Beijing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The injured people had been treated, police said, without providing further details.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A police briefing did not state a possible motive for the 46-year-old suspect, surnamed Ma, and it was not clear if he was known to the victims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The incident came about a week before China holds its annual Dragon Boat Festival, where fireworks are often part of the celebrations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Chinese authorities have strictly regulated fireworks due to safety concerns, and the Tianjin local authorities have imposed restrictions on when and where fireworks can be used.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s Ministry of Public Security recently kicked off the latest national “zero tolerance” crackdown on illegal guns and explosives, according to an official readout of a meeting from last Thursday.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;US$1.5 million Chinese funeral with fireworks sparks debate on lavish customs&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;On Weibo, China&#39;s version of Twitter, commenters said that the explosions felt like a “terrorist attack” or “revenge against the society”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While it is rare for someone to intentionally use fireworks to cause harm, China has seen many deadly fireworks accidents over the years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, four people died in Hebei province as officers at a police station inspected illegal fireworks that had been seized.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;Two Hong Kong men arrested in connection with illegal fireworks display&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;In January, a person in the central province of Shanxi was injured when a teenager lit fireworks which had been bought from an unlicensed store in a public square. A court ordered the teen&#39;s family and the owner of the store to compensate the victim financially.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2009, a hotel on the site of the recently opened headquarters of Chinese state broadcaster CCTV was gutted by a fire caused by an unauthorised fireworks event during a Lantern Festival celebration. One firefighter was killed and at least 30 other people were injured.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:50:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>