<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>南华早报</title><description>南华早报全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.scmp.com <item><title><![CDATA[Harvard morgue manager charged with selling stolen body parts]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224116/harvard-morgue-manager-charged-selling-stolen-body-parts?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 05:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/f64f8682-debf-49a4-aed0-174fc82e7345_891bb9a7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;据称，美国著名的哈佛医学院的太平间经理从他的工作场所取走尸体部分美国检察官周三表示，未经许可然后将其出售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宾夕法尼亚州中区的美国检察官杰拉德·卡拉姆 (Gerard Karam) 在一份声明中表示，55 岁的塞德里克·洛奇 (Cedric Lodge) 被控贩运被盗的人类遗骸.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有些罪行令人难以理解，”卡拉姆说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“特别令人震惊的是，这里有这么多受害者自愿让他们的遗体用于教育医疗专业人员和促进科学和治疗的利益，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lodge 与他的妻子、63 岁的 Denise Lodge 以及其他五名涉嫌参与“全国网络”的同谋一起被指控买卖人类遗骸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官说，从 2018 年到 2022 年，塞德里克·洛奇“偷走了器官和尸体的其他部分，这些器官和尸体的其他部分在尸体预定火化前被捐赠用于医学研究和教育”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他被指控将遗体从波士顿的哈佛遗址带到他在新罕布什尔州戈夫斯敦的家中，在那里他和他的妻子将遗体卖给了另外两名被告——卡特里娜麦克莱恩和约书亚泰勒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有时，洛奇“允许麦克莱恩和泰勒进入太平间……并检查尸体以选择购买什么”，律师办公室说。检察官说，马萨诸塞州塞勒姆市 44 岁的麦克莱恩和宾夕法尼亚州西草坪市 46 岁的泰勒随后转售了这些遗骸以牟利。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;坦桑尼亚人因在致富计划中出卖女儿换取身体部位而被捕&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;据《波士顿环球报》报道，起诉书称麦克莱恩将人皮运给泰勒，让他“将人皮晒黑制成皮革”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洛奇为哈佛大学的解剖学礼物项目管理太平间。哈佛大学在一份声明中说，他于 5 月 6 日被解雇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“得知如此令人不安的事情可能发生在我们的校园里，我们感到震惊，”哈佛大学医学院院长乔治·戴利 (George Daley)教职工和医学教育学院院长爱德华亨德特在一份联合声明中说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一名共同被告据称从她工作的阿肯色州太平间偷走了遗体，其中包括两具早产的死婴尸体被火化并归还给他们的家人。另外两人被指控相互买卖遗体，在线支付超过 100,000 美元。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 05:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[No bail for exiled Chinese businessman Guo Wengui]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224115/no-bail-exiled-chinese-businessman-guo-wengui?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 05:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/87d2d957-7e02-4ad3-8112-4f449ea90fcb_dfc8d517.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国曼哈顿上诉法院周三表示，流亡中国商人郭文贵应该留下联邦检察官称，他因涉嫌诈骗超过 10 亿美元而入狱等待审判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国第二巡回上诉法院表示，初审法官没有“明确而坚定的信念”拒绝郭提议的 2500 万美元保释方案是错误的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭的律师没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭，中国共产党的批评者和前任的商业伙伴美国总统唐纳德特朗普的一次性顾问史蒂夫班农自 3 月被捕以来一直被关押在布鲁克林。他的审判定于 4 月进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官称，郭骗了数千名投资一家媒体公司、加密货币和其他企业的追随者，并将部分收益用于奢侈品，包括价值 3700 万美元的游艇、价值 3.5 美元的百万法拉利和一座新泽西豪宅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;又名何云国和 Miles Kwok，郭对包括证券欺诈、电汇欺诈和隐瞒洗钱在内的 11 项指控拒不认罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3 >;中国流亡者郭文贵被勒令在美国游艇案中支付 1.34 亿美元&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;在拒绝保释时，美国地区法官 Analisa Torres 于 4 月 20 日表示，检察官已经确定，如果释放郭文贵将面临严重的逃跑风险，并构成对社区构成威胁，并且无法保证他会出庭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭的律师辩称，他没有潜逃风险，曼哈顿地方法院已释放已故骗子伯纳德麦道夫和 FTX 加密货币交易所创始人 Sam Bankman-Fried 的保释条件比郭提出的限制要少。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 05:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[To Hel and back? Not on bus 666 after Polish operator changes number]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224113/hel-and-back-not-bus-666-after-polish-operator-changes-number?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 04:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/31aaaa6e-e32f-4ed8-9ab1-3810c4722ad6_0ec86288.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;乘坐高速公路前往Hel的乘客将无法再乘坐666路公交车在受到宗教团体的批评后，当地的公共交通运营商改变了前往这个受欢迎的波兰海滨度假胜地的服务数量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hel 吸引着度假者，他们被其沙滩和森林小径所吸引，与永恒诅咒的火坑几乎没有相似之处，它的名字在说英语的人的脑海中唤起。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;游客和当地人早就看到了这个名字有趣的一面，对于许多 666 路公交车来说，它指的是“数量与撒旦有关的野兽”是一个无害的笑话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，并不是每个人都觉得它有趣，而且这项服务遭到了一些人的批评，他们认为这冒犯了他们的宗教敏感性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“管理委员会在发送给我们的信件和请求的重压下屈服了，这些信件和请求的数量可能不是很多，但多年来一直周期性地要求更改线路编号，”当地巴士公司 PKS 的 Marcin Szwaczyk 说格丁尼亚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该公司现在决定将号码改为 669，Szwaczyk 说，并补充说近 10 年来，个人和基督教团体都收到了投诉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018 年，天主教团体 Fronda 将这个数字的使用称为“邪恶的愚蠢”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“地狱是对人性的否定。这是永恒的死亡和痛苦，”该组织在一篇文章中写道。 “如果你根本不明白它是什么，你只能嘲笑这个现实。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;法国牧师在教堂的钢管舞表演后受到​​死亡威胁&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;新的 669 夏季服务666 号线将于 6 月 24 日开始运行，但 Szwaczyk 不排除在乘客要求的情况下恢复 666 号线的可能性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果事实上反应足够大且足够强烈以恢复 666 号线，看来我说我们会听取乘客的意见并更改这个号码，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 04:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Canada halts ‘government-led activity’ at AIIB amid claims of Chinese Communist Party control]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3224114/canada-halts-government-led-activity-aiib-amid-claims-chinese-communist-party-control?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 04:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/6475cc5c-b01e-4e07-b28c-4889699042ba_e617dc64.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;加拿大副总理兼财政部长宣布该国立即停止所有“政府主导的活动”在中国主导的亚洲基础设施投资银行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三，渥太华二号官员克里斯蒂娅·弗里兰 (Chrystia Freeland) 的披露是在这家全球银行的高级公共关系官、一名加拿大国民几小时后披露的。 ，因社交媒体指控该银行的关键职位由“共产党黑客”担任，并且“西方公众”没有“因他们在亚投行的成员身份而得到服务”而辞职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“政府加拿大政府将立即停止所有政府主导的银行活动，”方慧兰说，并补充说她已指示财政官员审查渥太华在亚投行的成员资格，并声称该银行由共产党控制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我今天宣布的审查将迅速进行，”她说。 “我不排除项目完成后会出现任何结果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚投行在一份官方声明中否认这些指控“毫无根据且令人失望”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国驻渥太华和华盛顿大使馆没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三早些时候，亚投行全球传播总监鲍勃皮卡德在社交媒体平台 Twitter 上指责该国际金融机构的“有毒文化”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;皮卡德担心自己的安全，他说，并“尽快离开”，因为“党内的人经营着银行，我的担忧是众所周知的，这不会让我在那里很受欢迎”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;但亚投行反驳了他的说法，称皮卡德于 2022 年 3 月加入，在他的整个任期内都得到了该银行的“支持和授权”以“履行他的职责”。&lt;​​/p>;&lt;h3>;安大略省教师失去了亚洲高管，同时基金暂停中国交易&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;据加拿大财政部网站称，加拿大于 2018 年 3 月正式加入亚投行，以促进“包容性全球经济增长”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拿大总理贾斯汀·特鲁多遭到反对来自保守党，是特鲁多自由党的竞争对手。长期以来，保守党一直要求渥太华退出亚投行，称其为北京输出威权主义的工具。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些人认为亚投行是世界银行和亚洲开发银行的中国替代品，亚投行成立于2016 年在北京为铁路和其他基础设施融资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它有 106 个成员国政府，包括大多数亚洲国家以及澳大利亚、加拿大、俄罗斯、法国和英国、日本和美国不是成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;“我们为我们的多边使命感到自豪，并拥有一支代表 65 个不同国籍和成员的多元化国际团队，”亚投行在其声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路透社的补充报道&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 04:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Roger Payne, scientist who discovered whales can sing, dies at 88]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224112/roger-payne-scientist-who-discovered-whales-can-sing-dies-88?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 03:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/1c19fb10-269b-4018-95e6-73598ead3e20_59543b55.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;Roger Payne，一位科学家，他发现鲸鱼会唱歌，已经死了。他享年 88 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佩恩在 1967 年前往百慕大进行考察时发现了这一发现，当时一位海军工程师向他提供了一段奇怪的水下声音录音，当时他正在聆听俄罗斯潜艇的声音。 Payne 发现了鲸鱼互相歌唱时令人难以忘怀的音调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他认为鲸鱼歌曲的发现是激发人们拯救正在从地球上消失的巨型动物的兴趣的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Payne 于 1970 年制作了专辑《座头鲸之歌》。这张专辑出人意料地大受欢迎，引发了一场全球运动，以结束商业捕鲸行为并拯救鲸鱼免于灭绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Payne 是从一开始就认识到，鲸鱼的歌声代表了一个机会，可以让公众有兴趣保护一种以前被认为只不过是一种资源、好奇心或滋扰的动物。他在 2021 年的一次采访中告诉 Nautilus Quarterly，他第一次听到录音是在一艘研究船嘈杂的机舱里，几乎立刻就知道这些声音确实是鲸鱼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管有噪音，但我听到让我大吃一惊。很明显，现在终于有机会让世界对防止鲸鱼灭绝产生兴趣，”他告诉该杂志。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佩恩周六死于盆腔癌。他和他的妻子、女演员丽莎·哈罗住在佛蒙特州的南伍德斯托克。 Harrow 说，葬礼尚未安排。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佩恩与动物学家凯蒂·佩恩 (Katy Payne) 的前妻有四个孩子，他与凯蒂·佩恩 (Katy Payne) 合作。两人在 1960 年代后期使用原始设备录制了座头鲸的声音，座头鲸有时会连续唱出怪异、复杂的歌曲超过半小时。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;脊椎骨折的鲸鱼游近 5,000 英里km 做蛙泳&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;鲸歌的发现对新生的环境运动的影响是巨大的。当时许多反战抗议者将拯救动物和环境作为一项新事业，“拯救鲸鱼”的字样在手提袋和保险杠贴纸上无处不在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鲸鱼歌曲将进入流行从 1971 年的 The Partridge Family 剧集到 1979 年的 National Geographic 杂志，其中包括一张 flexi 光盘，其中摘录了座头鲸之歌。它仍然是历史上最畅销的环保专辑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佩恩于 1971 年成立海洋联盟，倡导保护鲸鱼和海豚。该组织至今仍在马萨诸塞州格洛斯特开展业务。它在鲸鱼保护史上的分水岭时刻发挥了作用，例如 1972 年美国国会通过海洋哺乳动物保护法和 1982 年国际捕鲸委员会通过商业捕鲸禁令。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;佩恩的长期合作者、海洋联盟首席执行官伊恩克尔说，随着佩恩的去世，世界失去了一位环保巨人。佩恩两年前退休。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他的影响力和与人们建立联系的方式使他们献身于保护鲸鱼和我们的地球，”克尔说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;佩恩出生于纽约，曾就读于哈佛大学和康奈尔大学，并获得博士学位。在他作为生物学家的早期职业生涯中，他研究了蝙蝠和鸟类。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1991 年，他在伦敦特拉法加广场举行的鲸鱼保护集会上遇到了他的遗孀哈罗。他们在见面后 10 周内结婚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他的思维方式是一种持续的快乐，”Harrow 说。 “他一直在寻找答案，似乎是不断提出的问题。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 04:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US Federal Reserve pauses interest rate hikes after 10 increases in a row]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/united-states-canada/article/3224111/us-federal-reserve-pauses-interest-rate-hikes-after-10-increases-row?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 03:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/6c7225a4-c91f-4122-bf86-591eaac7d417_bcd2a06f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;美国联邦储备委员会周三投票决定暂停激进的加息运动，尽管“ “通胀升高”，同时表明年底前可能需要大幅加息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在连续 10 次加息后，美联储利率制定委员会投票决定将基准贷款利率维持在 5.0% 至 5.25% 之间%，中央银行在一份声明中表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联储表示，保持利率稳定让联邦公开市场委员会 (FOMC) 的政策制定者有时间“评估更多信息及其对货币政策的影响” .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此举大体上符合分析师的预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但 FOMC 成员还暗示未来还会有更多的货币紧缩政策，上调了本月底的利率预期中值年再增加半个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这表明美联储可能需要在年底前再加息两次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国经济已显示出放缓迹象，随着美联储最近预测温和的衰退将在今年晚些时候开始。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;各国央行冒着全球经济衰退的风险加息&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;但是，尽管美联储采取了紧缩货币政策，但年度通胀仍然“高企”美联储表示，高于美国中央银行 2% 的长期目标，同时失业率仍然很低。它补充说，最近的指标还表明“经济活动继续以温和的速度扩张”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联储周三还发布了最新的经济预测，将其 2023 年 GDP 增长预测从 0.4% 上调至 1.0% %。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的通胀预期中值小幅下降至 3.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;核心通胀（不包括波动较大的食品和能源价格）升至年率美联储表示，利率为 3.9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周三的决定之前，联邦公开市场委员会成员对最佳前进道路存在分歧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在即将召开的会议上不加息将使委员会能够美联储理事 Philip Jefferson 上月底表示，“在就进一步紧缩政策的程度做出决定之前，先查看更多数据。”这样的举措“不应被解释为我们已经达到了本周期的峰值利率”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但其他 FOMC 成员表示，需要采取更多措施来应对通胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;举起还是坚持？美联储不能在加息时保持自动驾驶&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们不应该被几个月的积极数据所愚弄，”明尼阿波利斯联邦储备银行行长尼尔卡什卡里上个月表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我们的通胀率仍远高于我们 2% 的目标，我们需要完成这项工作，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联储自上任以来已将基准贷款利率上调了 5 个百分点2022 年 3 月开始加息以对抗通货膨胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周三它表示必须进一步降低通货膨胀率。&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获得更多RSS ：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https //feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 03:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Germany takes aim at ‘systemic rival’ China in long-awaited, first-ever national security strategy]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3224110/germany-takes-aim-systemic-rival-china-long-awaited-first-ever-national-security-strategy?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 02:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/212419a2-fb7d-4436-9f8a-410e2984e509_f735b6ea.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;德国周三公布了其首个国家安全战略，指责中国“反复行为与我们的利益和价值观背道而驰。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柏林在其期待已久的政策文件中将中国称为“系统性竞争对手”，对北京使用了比过去更强硬的措辞，点名和暗示世界第二大经济体构成的威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它的发布是在预计将于 7 月发布的针对中国的新战略之前发布的，并为政府间磋商设置了一个可能棘手的阶段下周柏林和北京之间的对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据这份长达 75 页的文件，“中国正试图以各种方式重塑现有的基于规则的国际秩序，越来越积极地宣称地区霸权”有六处直接提到中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“地区稳定和国际安全面临越来越大的压力，人权受到忽视。中国故意利用其经济实力来实现政治目标，”它补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该战略是在俄罗斯入侵乌克兰之后制定的，这在柏林和欧洲开启了一个强有力的地缘政治新时代。在该战略中，柏林承诺将其 GDP 的 2% 用于国防，这是所有北约成员国的预期目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在欧盟发布前一周，它还深入探讨了国家安全的经济要素它自己的经济安全战略——这个最近被接受的术语被用作减少对中国风险敞口的简称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家安全意味着拥有可靠的供应链、支持民主以及以人权等价值观对待外交政策-中心，该战略称。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;德国公司对中国业务的火热态度掩盖了北京的魅力攻势&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们生活在一个日益多极化、系统性竞争加剧的时代.与我们一样，绝大多数国家都致力于《联合国宪章》和基于国际法的自由国际秩序，”报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“然而，由于他们对系统性竞争的看法，一些国家试图破坏这一秩序，并实施他们关于势力范围的修正主义观念，”它补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们将人权、公民自由和民主参与视为对其权力的威胁。”&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;在柏林举行的新闻发布会上，外交部长安娜莱娜·贝尔博克表示，德国企业已被告知，如果中国发生大规模危机，政府将无法救助企业在很大程度上。她补充说，在评估对中国的依赖性时，公司得出了与政府“相同的结论”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该文件在经历了大量拖延后终于面世——这是执政联盟内部分歧的产物。德国马歇尔基金会研究员 Gesine Weber 表示，这些冲突意味着该战略“可能是各方能够达成一致的最低公分母”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该战略一方面表明中国正在重塑全球秩序，而且没有它就无法应对全球挑战。这与政府以前的立场非常一​​致，”韦伯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然中国“利用经济实力实现政治目标”，但它“仍然是许多全球挑战和危机中没有这个伙伴的伙伴”无法解决”，报告称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下个月的中国战略预计将更深入地探讨对外投资管制、供应链压力测试和台湾等项目的具体细节。它可能更贴切地反映了德国外交部的观点，德国外交部被认为比德国总理对中国更加强硬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年 11 月的一份草案文本称，德国将“与德国保持密切和良好的关系”台湾在很多领域都想扩大。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们一个中国政策的框架内，我们支持台湾参与国际组织。我们认为：台湾现状的改变只能通过和平方式并在双方同意的情况下进行，”它写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;中国准备与德国的关系达到新的高度：李强总理&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;中国政府各部委将于下周抵达柏林，进行自冠状病毒大流行以来的首次面对面联合磋商。 Politico 报道称，德国政府已要求中国缩减其代表团的规模，因为它“极力避免给人留下它张开双臂欢迎中国的印象”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一天，布鲁塞尔，欧盟将推出自己的经济安全战略，旨在“降低”与中国贸易关系的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Frank Müller-Rosentrit，自由民主党议员、联邦议院外交事务委员委员会欢迎德国战略将重点放在经济安全上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“通过确保我们的贸易和供应链的安全来确保关键原材料和药品的供应与评估和持续减少我们对中国的依赖同样重要”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“尽管我们仍在等待中国战略，但与中国的系统性竞争维度已经浮出水面。”&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 02:50:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Germany takes aim at China in first national security blueprint]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/3224108/germany-takes-aim-china-first-national-security-blueprint?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 02:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/0d0f0e25-88e8-491a-a4ff-2ba0926d4bba_5ebd6042.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;德国周三称中国为“合作伙伴、竞争对手和系统性对手”国家安全战略，指责北京一再采取违背欧洲巨人利益的行动，以重塑全球秩序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理奥拉夫·舒尔茨的联盟准备的文件抨击中国将地区稳定和国际安全“置于日益严重的威胁之下”施压”和无视人权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国正以各种方式重塑以规则为基础的现有国际秩序，以前所未有的力度确立地区主导地位，一再与我们背道而驰利益和价值观，”该战略文件说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，它承认这个亚洲巨人“仍然是一个合作伙伴，没有它就无法解决许多全球挑战和危机”。 “这就是为什么我们必须特别把握在这些领域开展合作的选择和机会，”该报称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国总理李强到期前几天，人们期待已久的战略蓝图公布了访问柏林。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及这份文件向北京传达了什么信息时，肖尔茨在新闻发布会上说，“关键是中国将继续经济增长，中国融入世界贸易和世界经济关系不应该是&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但与此同时，我们必须考虑到安全问题，”他说，并补充说德国“不希望脱钩，我们希望降低风险”。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;该战略文件是在外交部的牵头下起草的，涵盖了国防承诺，例如北约 2% 的支出承诺、供应链安全和网络攻击。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;俄罗斯声称它占领了西方国家坦克，随着乌克兰军队向南推进&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;它引用俄罗斯“目前是欧洲-大西洋地区和平与安全的最大威胁”，抨击莫斯科入侵其邻国乌克兰。&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;俄罗斯的战争深深震撼了德国，迫使其放弃长期奉行的和平主义政策，转而大幅重新武装军队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这场冲突还促使柏林加快计划，以减少对中国的依赖，在冠状病毒大流行敲响了警钟，提醒人们依赖这个亚洲巨人获得外科手术服、口罩或药物等健康必需品的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去几个月，德国一直忙于实现多元化进口或将半导体芯片等关键部件的生产带回本国。但德国的出口巨头对中国的转移表示担忧，担心疏远这个巨大的市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在对德国公司的明确警告中，外交部长安娜莱娜·贝尔博克强调，柏林无法摆脱困境如果与北京爆发危机，与中国有着深厚联系的大型工业集团。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她补充说，在与德国公司的讨论中，她和舒尔茨强调，必须从俄罗斯对乌克兰的战争中吸取教训。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;与此同时，她强调了在双方都能同意的领域加强与北京合作的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个关键领域是气候问题，这个亚洲巨人的合作将是如果世界要成功地将升温限制在 1.5 摄氏度（2.7 华氏度）以内，这一点至关重要。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;没有中国就无法解决气候危机：德国环境机构负责人&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;“我们显然以完全不同的方式看待世界。但认识到气候危机是最大的安全威胁……我们与中国有重叠，”贝尔博克说。 “你不能说你想拯救世界的气候，但不想与中国交谈。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，分析人士表示，该战略并未包含任何关于德国将如何应对最严重气候变化的答案。紧迫的威胁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该文件包含许多处理多极世界的聪明想法，并考虑了超越军事核心的全面安全理解的重要方面，”Tagesspiegel 日报指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“但它没有针对当前世界局势中最紧迫的威胁制定任何行动方案，”它说，并指出如果唐纳德特朗普再次当选，“最重要的安全支柱可能会在 2024 年破裂”作为美国总统。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 02:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[EU cuts 3 Chinese firms from sanctions list after Beijing vows to stop flow of military goods to Russia]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3224109/eu-cuts-3-chinese-firms-sanctions-list-after-beijing-vows-stop-flow-military-goods-russia?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 02:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8 /images/canvas/2023/06/15/43485ae8-1cfc-40a7-a249-4a5c1cd21f1f_9145f8bd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;欧盟缩小了中国和香港公司的名单计划对向俄罗斯军方输送违禁欧洲商品进行制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据几位熟悉此事的外交官和官员称，仍有五家公司在制裁名单草案中。这比最初的 8 个有所下降，但最终的数字并不是一成不变的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些措施是更广泛的一揽子制裁措施的一部分，总共是第 11 次，旨在惩罚俄罗斯入侵乌克兰.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在布鲁塞尔与中国外交官会谈后，三家中国公司被暂时从名单中删除。中方表示，将努力确保这些企业停止转售欧洲制造的高科技产品，这些产品正流向俄罗斯的战争机器。&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;欧盟考虑对被控帮助俄罗斯军方的中国公司实施制裁&lt;/h3 >;&lt;p>;其余五家企业被发现是在中国经营的俄罗斯实体，将保留在名单上。然而，这被视为一种不稳定的情况：如果中国公司继续向俄罗斯军方买家出售被禁的欧洲商品，它们很快就会被重新添加。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两位欧盟外交官表示，这种安排可以被视为一种检验中国是否真诚行事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在某些情况下，这些公司被指控运送用于巡航导弹的微芯片。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;讨论发生在中国大使到访之后欧盟的傅聪公开抱怨说，布鲁塞尔没有提供证据证明这些公司（其中一些公司位于香港）正在提供漏洞，使欧洲高科技产品可以通过这些漏洞转移到俄罗斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国威胁要对任何对其公司的制裁进行实物报复，但也提出帮助欧盟阻止公司提供漏洞，如果它提供证据的话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当涉及到这些公司时，让我成为非常明确：如果欧方对中国企业实施制裁，而没有向我们提供任何确凿证据表明这些企业从事可能规避或已经规避欧盟对俄罗斯制裁的活动，那么我们肯定会进行报复，”傅莹表示。上个月英国杂志《新政治家》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但我还要强调，我们希望以合作的方式解决这个问题。我理解这第11轮制裁主要是为了防止规避。如果欧盟方面有证据表明中国公司从事此类活动，请向我们出示证据，”他补充说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第 11 套计划因一个成员国的抗议而搁置——据信是匈牙利——关于其自己的公司被列入由乌克兰政府运营的匿名登记处。布达佩斯希望欧盟向基辅施压，将匈牙利实体 OTP 银行从名单中删除。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，外交官们希望周一在布鲁塞尔举行的大使会议上能取得突破。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;This name-and-shame list – known in Kyiv as the “international sponsors of war” – contains six Chinese companies, more than any other nationality, with tech companies Hikvision and Dahua Technology added last week. Comnav Technology, China State Construction Engineering Corporation, Xiaomi Corporation and Great Wall Motor are the others.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 02:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[HSBC reaches revised terms for sale of its French retail banking business]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/business/banking-finance/article/3224107/hsbc-reaches-revised-terms-sale-its-french-retail-banking-business?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.14 23:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/7c888056-e9f3-403c-a1f0-d6a02c9dc731_bd491fde.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;HSBC has reached revised terms to sell its French retail business to Cerberus Capital Management-backed My Money Group after the lender said earlier this year that a sharp rise in interest rates in France had made the deal “less certain”.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The revised terms will see HSBC&#39;s European business, in part, retain a portfolio of €7 billion (US$7.6 billion) in home and other loans originally expected to be transferred as part of the transaction. Those loans will be serviced by My Money Group post-closing and HSBC can pursue sale opportunities at an appropriate time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HSBC is expected take an estimated pre-tax loss of as much as US$2.7 billion on the transaction, with a pre-tax loss of US$2.2 billion expected to be recognised in the second half of this year when the business is reclassified as held for sale. The final loss will be determined by prevailing interest rates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The board of directors of HSBC Holdings believes the terms of the transaction (as varied by the potential changes) remain fair and reasonable and in the interests of shareholders as a whole,” the London-based bank said in a stock exchange filing.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;HSBC&#39;s sale of French retail business in jeopardy&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;HSBC first announced the sale of its French retail banking business in June 2021 as part of CEO Noel Quinn&#39;s plans to streamline the bank&#39;s operations and shift capital from underperforming businesses in the West to faster-growing markets in Asia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, HSBC, the largest of Hong Kong&#39;s currency-issuing lenders, warned in April that the deal was in jeopardy after an unexpected rise in interest rates since the transaction was agreed, had “significantly increased” the capital requirements for the buyers at closing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following the revised agreement, HSBC said the net asset value of the business will be set by reference to the prevailing mortgage interest rate and the 10-year mid-swap rate at closing, capped at €1.72 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Depending on the prevailing rates, HSBC&#39;s European arm would receive a profit participation interest of up to €509 million in exchange for investing capital in the holding company of My Money Group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The revised memorandum of understanding includes a long-term agreement for HSBC&#39;s European arm to license the Crédit Commercial de France brand to the purchaser.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As part of the revised deal, funds managed by Cerberus will also inject €225 million of additional capital into My Money Group ahead of closing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The revised deal is expected to be completed by January 2024 and is subject to regulatory approval.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sale of the French business is one of several moves by Quinn to reshape HSBC and double down on future growth in Asia in recent years.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;What next for HSBC after stopping Ping An from carving up top Hong Kong lender?&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;Under his leadership, the bank has exited its mass market retail business in the United States and agreed to sell its businesses in Canada, Greece and Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bank agreed to buy the UK arm of collapsed Silicon Valley Bank in March and has reportedly agreed to buy out its partner in its mainland China fund management joint venture, the latest move to consolidate control of its onshore businesses.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The turmoil over the French sale also came amid pressure from Ping An Insurance Group, its biggest shareholder, and other frustrated investors to consider dramatic strategic changes, including potentially spinning off its Asian arm.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;HSBC&#39;s management prevailed in a contentious shareholder vote at its annual meeting in Birmingham, England, in May after a minority group of shareholders had pushed to spin off the Asia business.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bank generates the bulk of its pre-tax profit in Asia, but its management has argued its international network of connecting businesses between East and West is core to its strategy.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can AI give China the upper hand to surpass the US and become the world’s top economy after ChatGPT changed the game?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3224050/can-ai-give-china-upper-hand-surpass-us-and-become-worlds-top-economy-after-chatgpt-changed-game?utm_source=rss_feed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023.06.15 00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_twitter_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2023/06/14/87f71abe-ba22-4fdb-a488-a9f0389e7ef1_d871e576.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;p>;When the San Francisco-based OpenAI unveiled ChatGPT to the market in November, hailed as the so-called iPhone moment for artificial intelligence (AI), it cast a shadow across the Pacific.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China&#39;s internet giants, though, have been quick on the uptake. Baidu launched its Ernie bot in March followed by Alibaba Cloud and Kunlun&#39;s Tiangong in April. Alibaba is the owner of the South China Morning Post.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Smaller firms are also jumping on the bandwagon every day, with AI and its application increasingly the new lane of competition between China and the United States.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“[We] have to be quick, to catch up with the times,” Zhou Feng, CEO of NetEase&#39;s translation software unit Youdao, said during an interview with domestic media DuoZhi earlier this month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“What we are facing is a revolution at the technological level.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world&#39;s two largest economies have already been fighting for economic supremacy with a tit-for-tat trade war, the US-led supply chain decoupling and tech containment in the past five years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And while domestic academics largely estimate that China will overtake the US to become the world&#39;s largest economy around 2030, the weak recovery from the impact of the coronavirus has raised speculation overseas that it may never happen, just like the former Soviet Union in the 1970s and Japan in the 1980s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is now seen to be betting on generative AI, regarding it as a strategic tool in the Fourth Industrial Revolution that would not only save the national economy haunted by a debt mountain, coronavirus-related aftershocks and demographic challenges, but also refuel its bid to topple the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Developing big models of AI is a historic opportunity that China cannot afford to miss,” said Kai-Fu Lee, the former president of Google&#39;s China operation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Fourth Industrial Revolution represents a fundamental change in the way we live, work and relate to one another, according to the World Economic Forum. But it is about more than just technology-driven change, it added, as it is an opportunity to help everyone harness converging technologies to create an inclusive, human-centred future.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AI could lead to around US$13 trillion in additional global economic output by 2030, resulting in an overall 16 per cent increase in global gross domestic product (GDP), according to US global management consulting firm McKinsey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And professional services firm PwC believes that China will benefit the most from AI, with the technology contributing to a 26 per cent increase in its GDP by 2030.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Combined with the US, this would account for nearly 70 per cent of the global economic impact.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing&#39;s capacity to deploy its large and economically connected domestic market and talent flow could provide a stable base for the development of computing power, added Microsoft Research Asia founder Lee, who went on to open venture capital firm Sinovation Ventures in 2009.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese economy is so connected in all aspects that its government can do a better job than Western countries in facing resource deployment and work organisation,” veteran observer Lee told the Zhongguancun Forum in Beijing at the end of last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AI has long been high on Beijing&#39;s priority list, and it is considered as one of the core drivers for high-quality economic development, according to China&#39;s 2021-25 development guidelines.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking at a Politburo meeting in October 2021, President Xi Jinping pledged to “fight the battle for key core technologies” and achieve a high level of self-reliance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi particularly mentioned the use of a new whole-nation mechanism, which would see Beijing rally every possible resource for its development, similar to what it did to develop its satellite, nuclear weapons and space programme in previous decades.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since Beijing approved a mega data transfer plan last year to move user data in the east of the country to the western region with its abundance of energy and vacant fields via eight national computing hubs, more than 400 billion yuan (US$56 billion) has been poured into the plan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Western countries, on the other hand, tend to count more on private entrepreneurs, and some government incentives to support tech investment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to gain the upper hand, Beijing has embarked on an all-out effort to harness the potential of generative AI, with an emphasis on new infrastructure, to propel its computing power and close the technology gap with the US.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China, though, still lags behind in a variety of technical dimensions, as the US has 3.5 times more private investments, half of the world&#39;s language models and the highest repository citation count, according to a study by Stanford University.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The United States is still ahead in terms of AI conference and repository citations, but those leads are slowly eroding. Still, the majority of the world&#39;s large language and multimodal models (54 per cent in 2022) are produced by American institutions,” said the report.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But China is quickly catching up by producing the most AI journals, conferences， publications and leading industrial robot installations, surpassing the total in all other countries combined.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the escalating tech rivalry, both countries are engaged in the highest volume of AI research collaborations, which have quadrupled since 2010. But the pace of cooperation slowed after 2020, resulting in a modest 2.1 per cent increase by the end of 2021 compared to a year earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Amid Washington&#39;s ongoing tech sanctions, Beijing is seen to have both the resources and determination to scale up its computing capabilities with immense technological infrastructure investments to help narrow the gap.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Computing power is seen to be becoming increasingly crucial in AI, helping it to rapidly process mountainous amounts of information, revolutionising the speed and accuracy of system analysis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The rivalry between the United States and China may well be determined by computing power,” said historian Chris Miller, the author of Chip War: The Fight for the World&#39;s Most Critical Technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China accounts for 33 per cent of the world&#39;s computing power, which is only 1 percentage point lower than the US, according to the China Academy of Information and Communications Technology (CAICT), an affiliate of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technolfogy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s focus on increasing its computing power certainly provides an opportunity for China to catch up to the US in AI,” said Nestor Maslej, a research manager at Stanford University&#39;s Institute for Human-Centered Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But although the gap might narrow, China is still far behind the US in terms of AI technology due to its superior investment environment for AI companies, higher quality research and dominant AI model.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, the US outproduced China in producing AI machine learning systems by more than fivefold, creating 255 new significant systems in comparison to China&#39;s 44, according to Maslej.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Boosting the level of computing power is likely to help Beijing take a short cut to AI development, as the release of fundamental models is viewed as a flawed factor limiting the country&#39;s AI development.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The advancement of fundamental models requires large amounts of data, computing infrastructure and funding, resources that are inherently available to a greater extent to industry actors than those in academia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China increasing its country&#39;s computing power will likely give a larger subset of actors, like universities and even industry players, the opportunity to train these increasingly important foundation models,” Maslej added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the CAICT, for every 1 yuan (14 US cents) invested in computing power in China, it will drive 3 to 4 yuan of economic output.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chips are playing an important role in the increase of computing power in China, with the share of graphics processing unit chip computing power in the computing field increasing from 3 per cent in 2016 to 41 per cent in 2020, according to CAICT data.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Washington&#39;s choke point on China&#39;s chips is similarly besieging the development of its computing industry, as the performance of chips directly determines the efficiency and performance of computer systems and devices.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s domestic AI industry is now generally short of computing chips, and if the US further sanctions China&#39;s chip technology, it will definitely affect computing power development in the short term,” said Li Yangwei, a technical consultant working in the smart computing industry in Shenzhen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As Chinese chip technology gradually becomes more autonomous, the impediment to the development of domestic computing power caused by chip shortages may be eased, Li said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I would estimate the impact of the chip shortage on computing power development to be mitigated in two to three years at the earliest and five years at the slowest,” Li said.&lt;/p>;&lt;h3>;7 takeaways from China&#39;s 2022 population figures&lt;/h3>;&lt;p>;The construction of data centres requires a large number of high-performance computing, storage and server chips, which is undoubtedly the challenge China encounters in dealing with massive amounts of information.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China&#39;s computing power improvement faces multidimensional challenges, and there is still a huge gap in the transformation from chips to computing power,” CAICT said in its white paper on computing power development released in November.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The government think tank suggested that China should take advantage of its “mega-market and new national system” to enhance its computing power, while also promoting chips and other developments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US tech decoupling, along with the fallout from the coronavirus pandemic and its ageing population, is seen to be one of the new factors holding back China&#39;s potential growth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Zhang Xiaojing, head of the Chinese Academy of Social Science&#39; Institute of Finance and Banking, US tech decoupling will lower potential growth by 0.3 percentage point each year over the next three years and 0.5 percentage points each in 2026-40.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Those three new factors are going to postpone China&#39;s overtaking the US to the year of 2033 from the baseline estimate of 2031,” Zhang wrote in an article published in April.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite the fierce competition between China and the US, many politicians have warned about the challenges brought by the AI and have called for cooperation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Former US secretary of state Henry Kissinger said in an interview with The Economist in April that the fate of humanity depends on whether the US and China can get along, while the rapid progress of AI leaves only five-to-10 years to find a way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“AI is not a contest of two countries,” Kissinger told a close-door meeting hosted by JPMorgan in Shanghai in late May, adding that AI is a new era of human consciousness that requires collaboration between the US and China to understand its potential and risks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite this, an AI investment frenzy has now unfolded across China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shenzhen government announced in early June that it would set up a 100 billion yuan (US$14 billion) AI investment fund to vigorously develop the city&#39;s computing power and turn it into a pioneering AI zone in China.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tech hub also plans to accelerate the use of AI in undergrounds, airports and hospitals, aiming to serve as a computing platform for the Greater Bay Area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Greater Bay Area refers to the Chinese government&#39;s scheme to link the cities of Hong Kong, Macau, Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Zhuhai, Foshan, Zhongshan, Dongguan, Huizhou, Jiangmen and Zhaoqing into an integrated economic and business hub.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai has also spent over 250 billion yuan on new infrastructure over the past three years, with private capital accounting for more than 30 per cent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The increase in spending has encouraged many China forecasters to remain upbeat about the country&#39;s development path.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And Liang Haoguang, executive director of the China Centre for Modernisation Research under the Chinese Academy of Sciences, is convinced that China&#39;s economic growth will be increasingly driven by technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Judging from a tech innovation perspective, the Chinese economy is likely to catch up with the US size in 2028,” he told a seminar in Beijing last month.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:20:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>